greetings, Carl Barks fans,
You are about to listen to the very first episode of Barks remarks.
If you are new to the podcast, you should know that this first episode is pretty rough. And I have learned a lot about audio quality and sound editing since recording this one. And also the form of the show has evolved quite a bit. As I've figured out what really works in these episodes
So if you want to start at the beginning, that's great. Welcome aboard. But if you're if you're listening to get a taste for what the podcast is like, I really suggest starting with a slightly later episode. Maybe choose one of your personal favorite stories that we were recorded. The audio quality on this one is pretty rough and there's some background noise. Both of which are issues that I've pretty much addressed in future episodes.
That said, thank you very much for giving a podcast to try and hope you stick with us
have
Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks, the podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks, creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge Comments of all time. Join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks.
And I'm Mark
Mark's Severino a long time Carl Bark fan
going back to when I was about eight years old, last
last
episode, we talked a little bit about Barks.
Who he is, why people love him, and I am joined
today
by my guest host
eric,
who is gonna be filling the role hello Eric of casual fan.
Tell us a little bit about your experience with Carl Barks stories, please, Eric.
Hi. Mike experience Barks.
Well, I was familiar with Inducks stories for Al long time, Barks, houston to the Crow Barks aspect of,
but having gone read through them, and what be show because there's some of the story lines
from those
and and the arts, and I've just been really appreciative
the history and the work that you put into
creating
the
universe
which particularly
who is one of my all time favorite
just characters,
Whether it's comics cartoons,
all around just fun
nuance
characters.
Right on.
And
today, we are going to be talking
about Carl Barks very first long form adventure story
called Donald Duck finds pirate gold.
I probably didn't say the exclamation point there, but there is an exclamation point in the title.
Eric, had you read this one
before
we planned the podcast?
I don't think I did,
but I was familiar with So I I don't know. Maybe I had back in the day and read it somewhere. I don't know do you have a copy or if I saw it on a reprint? Because I know
Disney on occasion
for free home day,
the first Saturday they May
would always issue some old comics and rei small comments I have some. That are rei.
Of some of the classic disney, comments stories from Barks and them from back and yesterday.
I don't know if I had this one or would, but I was reading it it all... Felt really really like, I like I know the other. I've seen him before.
Yeah. Now that you mentioned that this one might have been one of the free common day ones. But, yeah, Let's let's dive in to a background.
On that and this story was originally
published in October of nineteen
forty two.
In
the old comic series four color, this was four color number nine. This was before
they started publishing under the imprint of, like, well Disney comics and stories,
And so, Eric, I've
decided to
have a little bit of context for what was going on at the time.
I mean, historical context or like.
That's right alright. So
nineteen forty two, I mean, thing is...
Me think I don't think eight is going on a little bit. It's pretty calm peaceful times.
Yeah. We... Well, we know we're we're in the height of World War two around this time. So it's an interesting time to be enjoying a funny comic
story
okay funny the animal story, but people needed entertainment.
Of course.
So
I looked at a couple
of be
other events.
Something that I thought was interesting, this is when the little golden books
started to publish.
A little golden but. Yes. So, who hasn't read the Hook puppy. Yeah. Well, was I I was a big fan of Tony Sc line. That
i that's good.
So I... Anyway, that's feels very, like, appropriate.
Sure, you know, goes along with the funny animal books.
Other
notable things in real world,
this was during the time when Roosevelt had just in... Implemented a big wage and rent freeze.
It was the debut of the Mighty mouse Cartoon.
Not really.
And then white Christmas was topping the charts at this time. So
a little more background.
This is a very long
comic
compared to most of the bark stories.
It clocks in at sixty four pages
like most ways it's been reprinted.
Quite a few times.
I read this one as part of the Gladstone
reprint, and they they did a giant album of it.
That was
a pretty neat release.
You know, this one draws a lot of attention just because
it is
you know, this is our first step. So so this is the first of the
long adventure stories but
one of the misconceptions about it, it is not carl Barks very first comment
mh. But she might hear people
share as a fact. He actually had one other before that called
Pluto saves the ship. I've never read it. So Okay. But this was his first dot.
What was this the... Was this the first jump comment? Like, I i
his first
was it he first
Ducktales?
So I know that they did like... There was... There were newspaper comments strips before this, and I don't think they were
collected or anything beforehand. So I don't know the answer to that.
So the... This had a a bit of an unusual background
and source
compared to most Barks po.
This is actually
based on an
animated
story board for
a Disney
feature
that was
abandoned
based up.
Yeah.
At one point, Disney was going to do a feature that was gonna be called Morgan's ghost.
K.
And
they abandoned it, and at some point, they were kind of honeywell around for story ideas to include in their comme line.
Carl Barks was brought on because he he was working in the animation department.
At the time.
So
they
passed him
along
with
Ga hannah.
Is the other artist who worked on this
to
adapt this story. And
have in the part. So,
yeah. This one definitely had
a
more unusual
background than most but it was well received enough that Mh
publisher
would end up coming back to Barks and ask asking him to return to the well for for more stories.
And this, you know, is what became
the beginning of his his legendary career, really doing mostly these Ducktales com.
Okay. Right yeah. So
as we go into these, I'm kind of working out the structure of the podcast a little bit, but I'm thinking we'll mention if there are any notable appearances.
Before we actually dive into the substance of the story,
So
apart from the nephews
and Donald,
the the most
notable character and this is gotta be yellow. Right?
I'm thinking
no it's p, obviously.
The villain the the classic Disney belt who shows up and everything thing.
Yeah. It isn't it weird to see pee in
in a Ducktales story. It it really is that he's like well, I think, obviously, this this his first time out, it would think he's gonna go through the well of, okay. Sure where the balance that we have that is the
comic first and, you know, at this point pretty much just paid.
Alright. And Huey, universal so they like, you know once transfer over.
Even his
his
Huey,, you gotta think later on just be big boys.
Where if you think about it,
realize, I think he's supposed to be a cat, but we can look at the
type of what he is how he's drawn
He kinda see how the big boys are living bit her model off of him. The big bur
are hoping kind of a character who's should,
but not always
the
intellectual rival, if you will
bureau
story,
but I always.
I enough?
I'm a huge
and personally.
Do you know my favorite trivia about
about pete
No. What's your favorite attribute about? He actually pre dates mickey mouse.
They were... They they used Him a little bit before Mickey was introduced and some very early cartoon. So
key goes way back,
formerly peg leg p, but, yes. Black pete is one of the big characters
in this one. And then you mentioned is Hen. Do they only name one of them as Red Eye, I think. Oh, I don't even know. I can't remember. I just... Yeah.
The generic
mouse type billing guys that seem like they're an archetype of...
Hang on. More,
more yeah.
Yeah. They look a lot like I I think they had to have been model after more.
So anyway, that's that's
some of the backgrounds
about this story.
Are you ready to dive into the a plot of the stories such as it is?
Sure. Excellent.
So
lot. But
Donald Doc finds higher gold
has donald and the Nephews cast
as fishermen
at the beginning,
and they're out in a big storm
fishing
and they're they're making their way towards land,
and
they've gotta get in because a big storm coming.
I really like the little site gag where he's still rolling.
As a... As they've come when land on the dock. It it feels like a cold open for the covid is what it does. Right. You know, should done a whole bit with that, hey, the the you'll good your leak just popped up when they were there.
By having the whole storm and
stuck on there feels like something very out of the cartoons
of the era. Yeah. And and I think that's very much like a cold open.
That's what we're gonna see a lot with this one. Right? Is is that it's gonna be really remnants reminiscent of those cartoons ins.
It's the classic that dark and stormy night.
Including
the mysterious
stranger
that shows up
They hear... They hear Al loud knocking on the door they open the door, and at first, they don't see anyone,
and then we meet yellow b. Do you wanna describe yellow for us
that be the
peg lake harry pirate
medicare.
We and everything.
Just the very
archetype of auto part are i'm gonna use
not Al term some throw around pirate jargon,
right? You're too excited for adventure. He demands some food
and
they give him slim going.
Had you ever heard of S?
Don't think I have
This is the only place I've heard that term.
I guess it's like a a a low class beef stew, like, pepperoni or something.
Donald tries to make it fiery hot. He ends up loving it. And then we kind of fade to
realize that he
yellow is being followed by black pete
and his hen.
And well
Donald ends up hiding him
from pete kind of reluctant.
Pete goes in and and into there, like,
see s or whatever.
And he tries to get some intel, and it's obvious that,
you know, he's pursuing him for some
nefarious purposes,
and
we end up learning
more about what
yellow
motivation is.
Do you wanna mention
what he shares with the nephews? Do you remember that well enough?
Well, Just that, you know, there's treasure and and that there's a...
They can the key to the treasure of the map the treasure is in that very room. So yeah. Pretty convenient,
you're well yeah.
Doesn't love a good adventure with this she involved.
Yeah. So he's got the classic treasure map,
and
He tells them about Morgan, the the treasurer of the ghost of Henry Morgan.
And so he
convince the nephews to help him out
and they find that clue in that very room as you said. And and meanwhile black pee has been
ea dropping and figuring out kind of their next steps.
He learns that they're gonna need to hire a ship
So I I really like this part. He...
He races ahead
to
disguise his ship which is the black Mara mariah
as the white lily.
And
the next day,
Donald and boys and Yellow beak. They go to higher ship.
And who is ready to rent them a ship, but
black pete and Disguise as a little old lady.
And
he's got a whole cover story
about
why he why she has been left widowed
and
she sells a pretty good socks story, and they end up
renting the ship
and taking black pete and the sky.
You gotta Al lovely bit classic.
True address on. No. Of difference.
Oh, yes.
Incredibly convincing.
And I don't know that I'm gonna get two in detail with
kind of their sea voyage because I think this is kind of the part where
the
the pacing of the common really
kind of changes a lot, and it goes from, like
setting the table and telling the story to just showing the story.
Right. You know, we've got some really good, like visual site gag here
of
black p sneaking around trying to figure out trying to get a hold of the map
and yellow be trying to hide the map and the nephews kind of realizing what's going on. Any of the little
scenes in this that you really liked that you wanted to
mention or anything?
I mean, the dining the gun white tag is always fun.
Right He's like, oh, tell you that then goes back and then there's the nephew
working Inducks sleep. Like, these kids are such prank that even want to be blocking.
They're frank so they know it. I like the aspect of. It's like a montage, But this one, you have the artwork
That looks really good. What the peak is
backlit.
Sneaking into the opening amp for the door. It's just very subtle but very clear what it is. It's having a great story.
Artistic. It takes... The store takes its time It doesn't feel like he's padding it. He's having fun
going into detail showing what's going on. It's not me it's not like, well written, but it's well story board. Yeah. And feels like.
Doesn't. Yeah.
And and I think it's a lot more spare.
Storytelling
then
that I'm used to, I think. Oh, sure.
I mean, when you tell that this the this these are not heavy on dialog.
Basically that is gist
what's going on in the story
by reading. I mean, if you took about all the word bubbles out of this thing, probably still get the gist a story. It's true. I think a lot of kids probably learn to read
through these comments Back... Oh, yeah. Absolutely.
But yeah. It really goes on. This this segment goes on for pages and pages. And,
you know, finally,
pete is revealed
his his weight comes off and
then there's a couple more pages of
honestly a a pretty cool
kind of battle fight sequence that has some real danger, you know, pete is wielding a knife, his hen are willing a knife and they're really going for the kill. That's one of the things that I like about some of these
Al depictions of the characters is that they weren't
afraid to kind of imply danger violence. Right. But I mean,
they're cut. Not well. They're they're just bad guys bad days for kids and up I guess for those just. They're just generally bad guys and, you know, their Barks guys work for a reason.
And so at some... Eventually, they do catch donald and you'll be in the nephews.
And they hit another of the pirate cli cliches, they make them walk the plank.
But
the band up tricking, them, the
cashed them in a make shift
ralph,
and
they're allowed to sail
off and then we come to learn that while p has...
He believes that he's gotten the map.
In fact, it's missing a key part
and that would become important later.
They take a wrap.
They take the draft to the island of Henry Morgan.
Again, there's another side guy that I think works pretty well where donald wakes up and they've already landed and he else land a h. I really like that. That sequence.
Yeah. The next segment of the story is them
trying to beat
pete to that treasure.
They
they are searching for a while. They eventually find the next part of the treasure map, but Pete has arrived. They see his ship in the distance.
And then they had Al plan to sneak back and where the ship so that they can get the rest that now, they do so, they encounter that he has
has already left the ship once they get there you he left a pretty funny note
on his bed that says,
if he doesn't come back, please oblige and send his remains to my to my old mother and pitt blake. I I love how he writes that out in nice cursive script. My my mother
and it's boy. I'm just how actually Barks on. Yeah.
And so they go back to the islands
and
pick up the trail again.
And they eventually find the cave mentioned in the map
and find a chest that's, again, very conveniently labeled with Henry Morgan's name.
You wanna talk us through what happens when they open the chest? That's when they find the ghost pops out he says, hey, here's the map.
Just go take care before we don't disturb. It'll be... I thought a resting place and
I'm tired of being bothered. I'm, like, I like day it goes here Inducks cave go away. Take my Barks. Leave
And
once again,
i I love how i'll a on
obviously have a ghost,
could be anybody else under here. Some of these cliches I have to imagine aren't weren't as beat to death and back then. But you know, April probably that it's it's a kid's topic. So it's it's fun it's it's fun to have that realization. I mean,
yeah. Kids like to know feel that, like they're
more in the o than the characters.
So, of course, that ghost is actually
pete and disguise
and
They're trying to track down
the... They're trying to let them do the work.
Sure finding the treasure for them while they stay in the shadow.
There's a.
Right. There's a couple of cool segments here.
Where yellow reveals that the missing part of the map is actually tattoo
right on his torso. I thought that was cool. And then they have to site through the eye of a skull to find the the final sight of the treasure. I I thought that was really neat to. That's kind that the fun. That's the fun trope.
Yeah. Understand how you need Al score or something. But okay
And so they dig got the chest meanwhile Pete and his abdomen
are waiting in the background
letting them do all the work.
And they finally come out
once they've done the the grunt work.
You wanna talk us through that final segment where they're
rather. If i get to go like game. Have we got it. You know, donald
finds the treasure
which
nowadays can understand that if doesn't find something, you know that's not of the story because it's gonna be
resolve have foil, and so there they are and they take it from them.
But if you looking at that we have like how guys, well it's just donald and yellow.
Yeah. There's three...
That pretty little.
And all of a sudden, coconut start falling from the guys.
And just simple that the net
a typical batch come in and saves the day
by bunk everybody on the head. And I like the the immediate reaction of the hen is to celebrate that they only have to split it two ways.
You realized.
Like you they also
not got the captain and gave them Yeah. Rich is over where the where doesn't it came from? Yep. And and, of course, two more coconut joined.
And so they have
They've they've done it. They've gotten the treasure. They've secured it for themselves.
They want the bad guys back in
bound
and they start to argue Donald starts to get up on his high horse about who's responsible for finding the treasure
you know, he accuses yellow of bundling the whole thing, if not for my nephews,
and
Yellow beef starts to accuse him of a mutiny
And when they go up to the top deck after they're on the ship, there's a fun little site gag of
the nephews have have taken the command of the ship and and they're the captain now.
I and they captain the yes. And there's a really panel at the end.
That just shows the ship failing on the distance.
Well...
Yeah. That is a really power. But if you look at it, it's kind of a reflection. There's another panel earlier when they get at the island.
They ship out in the bay, and it's very
similar. Oh, yeah. When they see pee.
When they see me put less... It's still farther away, but it's a very similar shot of using money down service.
Dark against the sun... The the the sunset
and it's very picture picturesque. But
just a very, I think, Al atmospheric ending
rather than, you know,
seeming like it's
concluding things in kind of...
Yeah. It's not really closure
more just an end.
Yeah. So
that is the story of donald duck finds pirate.
And again,
you know, this was
originally
conceived as an animated
film. It was adapted from the story board, and so I think it has a lot of limitations
because of that.
Sure. I'm I'm gonna wanna talk So one of my favorite things about the Barks stories is that I I feel like I learned a lot from them growing up as a kid. We talked to that first step episode
about how, you know, you can learn a lot about mythology and history. Mh. And and a lot. And so I wanna take some time in these episodes to talk about kind of some of the educational aspects.
But I have to say I don't think that was really too much
to learn
about in this one.
You know, Barb didn't write it. He had some pretty cool
illustrations.
But
apart from learning the words stun come
and just some generic nautical terms I didn't really... There wasn't anything that really piqued my interest in in
in any of those areas. How about you?
No. Not really. I mean, it really anyway it get a whole lot of a sailing,
but it doesn't
really get into that. But i know what?
It's fun. And I think he gives him little chance to work on, like, he was mainly he's doing in the art, and this was based off of some other, but somebody else's the story.
Right. So I mean, if you look at it from the criteria, just as our work.
Here's has a very good job.
Yeah. And and here's here's the thing about the art too. Because, again, this was a collaboration between him and Hannah.
And
I I read a lot of background in this from that graphic novel that I mentioned the Gladstone published.
And their editor at the time had had really cool
write ups of some of stories.
So I'm gonna refer to some of that, but
Hannah was apparently responsible
for most of the inside
scenes. He did the art for those that took place inside and Barks focused on a lot of
outside natural c's and the shit.
Okay. That's how they kinda divided that up. So let's talk a little bit about
the general consensus of this story,
I'm gonna be referring in these episodes to the ratings on the website index. That's i n d u c k.
And that's a fan site where they aggregate
people's thoughts and information for a lot of the
the Disney comic stories.
So this one has a rating of seven point three out of ten
which is good for six hundred and forty first out of over forty thousand worries.
So that'd be what in the top five percent or so. But
relative to most of the Barks stories, it's pretty low.
I would say that this
this story is is generally regarded
pretty well, but mostly as a notable
story and a little bit of a curiosity.
I'm sure it has its fans.
But, you know, it... It's it's the first Barks story. So it's gonna be notable for that reason.
As far as my personal opinion of this story, you know, I didn't talk about my memories up. But I do remember getting this album
and being really excited because the cover looks. So
It it really grabs me, you know? Right the pair and the treasure chest and Donald
and I was I enjoyed it because I enjoyed all of these comments, but I definitely remember a little bit of a sense of let down
because it was so different from the other Barks stories that I'd read. And I didn't realize that it was his first one
until after I'd had read it.
And it it definitely made a lot more sense at that point.
I really... I think I liked the beginning
of the story the best kind of the setup and all the table setting and the the really suspense moment where Yellow
appears and and pete is Ea drop. I thought that was
some pretty cool mood.
I also
really like some of the kind of
geography the little how they set up the island
itself and some of the cool landmarks. You know, I didn't talk about the skeleton tree that they had to follow, but I thought that was some really neat part.
Yeah.
And then, you know, the the middle sequence, it kinda runs together a bit because it's...
It's got all that
action
without any dialogue, and that's kind of a double edged sword. Right? Because it's really neat to see
but I I find it's easy to really flipped through it
kinda quickly
None of it really stuck with me. I hadn't...
I hadn't read this one in many many years and I
I barely remembered,
you know, I only really remember the beginning. I think that's what had the only part that it really stuck out
in my mind, the whole
from Going
and Al that senior. Makes sense. So I mean in in general, I I don't think this is a great story,
but
I I appreciate it a lot. I enjoy it as, you know,
showing Carl Barks potential what he would go on to do.
I do like some of the art a lot
How about what was your impression of this? Well, logged me when I first I was like, wow,
they did the dumb like version of Treasure island.
The whole, you know,
old pirate that comes in. I've got a secret with people are after, you know, kind of a deal and I need someone to take me out of shit, let's go get some random kid and of people involved and you'll find a ship. All of the shit is by pirate
who. We have now smart them and get the treasure, but then they give treasure, but then we get it back. It's like, okay. And again, you're pointing out that
call Barks just in part on this.
So I don't know if... I mean, just my line as a capital fan, because that count as a Carl war story
right, quotes? Or is it just his work? Because he didn't write this and his writing especially later on because he's very different with how he does as as its adventures.
This deals... The story
people's formula,
but it's still fun.
Yellow a big is a great character. I don't know. Do know... You tell me favor friday? You'll be Barks any other form? A Disney or Mickey mouse or anything?
What.
He he does come back a little bit. We'll
we'll talk a little bit about that. Oh Okay. Should be here. No. I'm I'm glad you asked about that.
Because he seems like a fun character particularly you know, the question of...
How do you
tattoo to a pair?
The i came to mind mind am my.
That's gonna be interesting.
Oh. And you know, I'm sorry to interrupt you. I I forgot to mention that I I liked Yellow, but I also found him in incredibly
unsettling.
Right? Because he is a parent.
And and he's parent sized
And I didn't really know how to to read him because most of these Ducktales. These animal characters are not the normal size.
So, like, am I supposed to read him as, like, being a human like character or a parent like
Like, at first, I thought Huey, was just a but the pirates talking.
Right. Okay. Yeah. And
and
acts, like,
just the regular quote human character like all of them do. So i I found him
pretty weird.
And and like from the moment. Remember the Red cactus this shoulder, but it's still a crew member.
We, the the the cactus there, it happens to be a very essential period that is
there. And... That's that's on saturday and think about that because with these, you know,
we think it
changes
you don't usually think about them as being done.
Yes. This story made me think about him, and that that definitely brought me out of it.
That that makes sense. I think sometimes he was much the least in various economics. But... Yeah. No. I i think that head now... So
you know, this one was always gonna be a little bit different just because of the nature of the story.
Definitely a notable one. Some some reflections, I'd like to take some time in in these episodes to talk about
how well the story holds up if there's any thing archaic or dated. And you know, this one because it's so episodic, I I don't feel like you. It it almost feels like it could be of of almost any time, you know? I mean, there's not a lot of, like, modern
indicators or anything that pulled me out
the way some stories do. But I think that might be more Al effective just how how spa.
I mean, I would think nowadays if they're doing it, I think you'll be easier to have pee being old man.
Sure and and that kind of a thing instead of making him a woman. Yeah gone a little bit. That definitely a little bit out of style.
But, again, that was just par for the course
But I don't think there's anything that really needs to be kind of
explained
That was just... That was just, you know, part of the time.
Yeah. I needed to disguise it's it's fine.
Had asked
about
other appearances
So I wanna talk at this point in the episode about appearances and other media. I'll jump a little bit to okay.
Other appearances
for Yellow beak. So so the weird thing that they did is they recycled this story a lot in Disney economists.
Oh, really?
This wants to? Like, they would basically
reprint this but with different characters following this sketch. Like,
They used the
peter pan characters.
I think Captain Hook basically played the black p role and one of the
later four colors
I think there might have been some book adaptations of it or something. But I thought it I found it to be very
weird that they kept going back to this
very cliche shade like, bare bones story.
That's true. Yeah. Yep the one had some kind of popularity that we weren't aware of.
Yeah. Or it did this a story that Disney owned, and didn't have to pay for another rider to do.
Yeah. That might be the case.
There was a sequel to this that was published
Barks didn't do it. I don't remember. I don't think it was a very notable
story, but they they did bring him back
for a follow ups story at some point.
And then
I have not seen this personally yet You know, we we're gonna talk at this point about if there's
ever been Al appearance
a reference to the Ducktales,
which, you know, is it can be a little bit divisive among Barks and some of them really appreciate
those some don't, but
he never appeared in the first series. But apparently, he has a pretty notable appearance in the third season.
Right. And I Seen the thirties yet. I'm waiting for it to finish I can stream the whole thing. Right. I've only seen it on what what they have on Disney Plus myself.
So that'll be Al episode to look forward to. It's called the first adventure.
Do you mind if I
what
four part of it? So
apparently, he appears as a re
skeleton of himself.
And he is the villain.
And and it sounds like it's a reference to, you know, Barks for a story calling that up. So first adventure sure. The
people may not like them or barton do had appreciate or it have their own opinions on them, but from what I've seen in that cartoons,
the guys behind it, are fans of not just the original that, but the original
of a lot of the references. The Barks our spectrum background are they have in there. And. And and maybe devices, but
you know what if you're family you're trying to get it in there? I think that's good after you can't
hard to things everybody all the time. But... Oh, I definitely there. Agree. I agree. I appreciate the Barks references.
I sometimes feel a little bit weird about where they go with them. But
you know, I I enjoy it as it's own thing.
The the other media
is the
Barks does a lot of oil paintings. We have talked about this. I'd mentioned this in the previous episode. So if there's a corresponding oil painting, I'm not gonna go to in because this is a podcast
and is not a visual media.
There is an oil painting titled returned to Morgan's Islands that I think is really cool.
I'm hoping to get a Facebook page up for these So so I'll post a visual for that. But but look up that one.
I think it's a really neat one. It shows that cool skeleton tree. In the round of it.
I also took a look for this episode out at the going rate for the original
print four color number nine.
Just for reference right now, the the lowest ebay listing I saw was six hundred and ninety nine dollars.
And
up to twenty six hundred dollars.
Depending on
on the condition.
Let's see. Like the d collectors you gotta pay for that. That's sure. Oh, yeah. Well, this is definitely an an important piece of, you know, Barks
history, Barks more yeah. Look at the pricing of these, but like, there's a lot. Well when you think of the history of them and actually, how well Mean that's
That's a nineteen forty two.
That's the what... Yeah. Year old almost made go to comic.
Maybe yeah. Shouldn't would be worth that much. Those are that expensive and so rare. Definitely golden age.
So I'm trying to think I I think I covered everything that I
looks to talk about. I'm not trying to be exhaustive, but,
you know, any any closing thoughts that you got about Donald Duck name's Clerical.
I mean, as I've mentioned before, and I don't want... I can know what that do in the head.
The
art in this is
tremendous.
Even just the the minor characters, that it it's all well done. The facial reactions
but it's the big scenes that are obviously Karl Barks the codes
and some of the silhouette, it's just tremendously done
for that error
for the detail and expressions
and
if you look at some of these shots, I don't... I'm looking at one where the boat is coming over a wave
The the water's moving. There's moving the water. It's coming up as the. The sales are full
and you see a pot of dolphins out ahead of the boat as the sunset goes behind it these pink
the pink sunset out the yellow scott, and I look at that, and I'm like, yes.
Obviously, he's going to the oil painting slate on Al light because that is.
Just not a beautiful
scene.
And he has several of those with the of the irish particularly
I'm thinking
think Barks really like higher boats. I that. This kinda seems he must have enjoyed this and had some real fun.
You don't often get
just beautiful arc Inducks con book Nowadays it
this his comic has goes all over the place it's kind of experimental
like you said, I I think that's really cool you pointed out about the facial expressions. There's some pretty pretty great facial expressions in here. I I kinda got hung up on the lack of detail on some of the backgrounds.
But that's very. But I do think you're right. There's some really cool artwork. And you know, Barks famously loved to refer reference old issues of National geographic.
And I know he did that with some of the nautical stuff for this. Awesome. Well, Eric, thank you so much for joining me for this. I really pleasure.
I'm I'm excited to to keep going.
Our...
Our next
episode is going to
talk about Donald Duck and the mum ring
So please join us for that one. And if you have any thoughts or comments, you can drop us Al line at Barks remarks at g mail dot com. Mh Good email. Yeah. Fancy. Right. Well, thank you again. You're welcome, Barks and we'll stay next time.