can have
Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks, the podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks, creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and sk comments of all time. Join us, as we explore his long adventure stories in their chronological
publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context and how well hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Alright.
I Al Mark Sever,
a grown man who likes to talk about
Inducks com,
and
I have with me today, if you can introduce yourself.
I'm Ryan Bailey. I like Mark. And I'm largely I'm familiar with Dot com.
Yeah. So you're gonna be filling the role the newbie role this week.
And
we are going to be talking this week
about Donald duck and the monies ring.
So my my background,
I am
a super fan of Carl Barks. I've been reading the stories since I was, like, eight years old.
Have
pretty much every one of them
and
got it in my head to do a podcast to explore them in order because that's something I've never done. And, again, I could talk and talk about them.
Growing up this is most of what I read. This is most what I was into at least common wise.
Ryan, do you wanna tell me a little bit about
your background with Barks and con in general.
I know almost nothing about Carl Barks except for
kind of his role
being Al an early
creator of of this whole world here. I actually didn't read that many come
growing up.
It wasn't until
like the two thousand eight recession. I was
I was well into a adulthood, and
I had a lot of comics that I gotten from a friend and I just started reading them at night, and I was like, oh, I really like this.
So
for last two years I've had, like, the Marvel unlimited subscription and everything, and I've actually keep track of what i've read. I recently passed four thousand
issues of Marvel
in the last five years.
So I usually read about a thousand
comments a year, but almost exclusively marble.
Not necessarily with the the quote funny animal comics. Yes. Exactly.
I'm
in at least a couple of the Dot com,
the super superhero ones are are lamp a little bit so super snoop. So
that's awesome. I I
Al glad that you got a chance because, you know, you and I have known each other for
since the beginning of high school, we've been friends for a long time.
And I mean, you probably heard me talk about these a lot.
I I don't remember if I lobby you
to read them or give them a try. Do you remember if you ever gave them any any try?
I don't recall ever actually sitting down and and reading one. I'm sure there must have been some point probably in high school where you were you, you know, thrust it into my lap and was like, read this.
It's amazing. And then I probably did And was like, yeah. That's pretty good.
You know, for someone who's such a big fan, I've I've actually always been really reluctant to trust or voice them on people because I think there's always a little bit of of embarrassment
misplaced, but
nonetheless, a little bit of embarrassment about about what they are and, you know, growing up, it was definitely
cooler to be into the marvel
or other superhero comments. My I read some of those too but these beads were my first love. It's very exciting to me to kinda talk about them in the real world and to have this built in excuse to make the people that I know
give them a shot. I am gonna go over some of the details about this story. This one, again, as mentioned is called Donald Duck, and the mum ring,
and this is
This was published in September of nineteen
forty three This was originally published in for color number twenty nine.
It has been reprinted many many times I I think most famously though, it was
The cover art for the very well received Coral Barks in color library
The interesting thing about this story, know that last episode, I had Eric on who you... Were we're mutual friends. You know, him well, and we talked about the first Barks story, but that was kind of a,
I think because Donald Inducks finds pirate is only partly a Carl Barks
story. It was based on a cartoon script. It was not written by Barks was only partially
done by him. So this is really the first
opportunity
to get into a Carl Barks story that is a hundred percent his this was created entirely by him and so this represents kind of an early look at his his independent style What he would go on to do.
Before we get into the story and our thoughts I'd love to take a moment to kind of go back in time a bit and talk about what was going on, what what our historical
context is.
There's gonna be a few of these stories around this era that are... You can't escape the fact that were in the the side of world war two still. We've got I I checked on with Wikipedia. This is about when Jack and these tournaments
really began in earnest. So there's a a pretty sad fact for you.
On on a little bit of a lighter note, this was when ride waters
of Pink Floyd and Gloria gay. We're both born.
So there's that.
And and then for the purposes
of our
podcast today. I think the interesting thing is that the United States and a lot of the world were
reenter
one of their waves of egypt of Romania.
Do do you know much about
about these cycles of Egypt
Ryan?
No. I don't.
I I feel like
It's... I've seen it as more as an individual thing where a little kids get really into Egypt for a while, and they wanna learn more about far and all that. And I didn't realize a hold culture did the same thing. Tell me more.
Yeah. Absolutely. I i think the Us was one of those little kids
several times throughout our three. You know, when every time there was a big discovery, I think,
you know, in in Egypt, since some anti antiquity,
the country and a lot of the world went through these,
like, Severino
friend
where
the Egyptian called are both modern, but mostly ancient was very evo and it entered the pop culture and, you know, this was, of course, you had the the money, boris carl loft, the mommy is the most famous one from this era.
That came out in nineteen
thirty two.
So
it was... It was a decade old this point, but it it left up big mark on on pop culture.
But, yeah. Just egyptian war
is something that the Us kind of fell in love
every couple of decades.
So that... That's kind of what this
came out of. I wanna take some time during each so to talk about if there are any notable appearances
wise in these stories,
there there aren't really a lot of recurring care directors and this one. You do have a couple of notable
kind of one off characters
in the the Bay Al da
and his beneficiaries that will get into.
To me the interesting thing is that just like in the last story. You have
the old Disney standby
villain
black pete. Or at least someone who basically
looks like him is kind of the person causes
a lot in trouble. Oh, I guess they they never actually named him do they in this coming He's just a guy. Yeah. Right. Yeah. Did did you read him as being? I did. Yeah. That was my initial thought.
Yeah. So I think, you know, early on Carl Barks was just figuring things out and and it's kind what Disney did. That they like we need to villain, we're gonna use p
I I really delighted last episode in when I'm telling Eric, one of my favorite Disney facts, which is that peg leg pee actually pre dates mickey mouse. That's how long they've been going back to that well. So
I think Barks is gonna be out of that habit soon. I can't remember specifically if we see any more peep alike, but,
you know, hey is it's interesting that he's just their generic villain. So
let's see. I I guess this is the first time in one of these episodes that I'm gonna get to go into
what I hope is a recurring segment where we can just talk a little bit about the educational value that was in this story. But I'm thinking
as I go, that I'm gonna kind of wait and talk about that
afterwards a little more reflective.
But I I will mention that Carl Barks did something in this story that he becomes famous for, and this is gonna be a great example
that he
famously
really loved to dive into
national geographic and other sources for some of these stories to get some awesome some background
and to really ground it and something that he was interested in. So this is gonna kinda set that template,
and we can talk about some of the things he includes
by the end.
So Ryan, are you ready
to
dive into
the money... The money rain.
Yeah. Yeah. I I I was gonna ask you as the as the expert experts
how much
how much of this art style and and even characterization is
original Barks and how much of it is what he had to continue from what Disney was using. He didn't he didn't create donald. Right?
Right. Oh, these are great movie questions.
No. He didn't create Donald. Donald had... Donald been around for a few years at this point,
he was originally
in he first appeared on screen in as a side
wise little hen, I believe, and I think
I think an Italian artist Al tell fe is the one who
may have used him in
print first and kind of shaped the character and print a bit. But but that's a good point. Right? Because he's proud
going with a bit of the Disney house style
early on. You know, that's what he definitely did for the story boarding, the the last one which is based on
story board
work.
But But I definitely think you can see
him creating his own style. I I think you'll see as we go forward,
I'm excited to have you back for more of these, and I I think you'll see that this art is really
not who distinct from what he's gonna go on to do later.
You know, he's definitely gonna
develop his own style
and
really refine it.
I I myself notice I find the Nephews,
here doing Louie, some... Some of their in the panels, some of their cheeks are all kind of puff out in a way that I don't think he or other artist usually do. So I didn't notice that reading it this time.
But, yeah, that that's a great question. Looking at how is... I... I'm so excited to look at how is our and his style
is gonna evolve over these comments.
I will say.
I guess maybe the most
Barks background I have is
Ducktales was very big
when I was a kid, and it
completely blew up my second grade, I'm gonna say,
and we were all
arguing doing with each over... Each other over what we thought the Lyrics of the theme song said,
which is hard to decipher for as a seven year old or whatever we were. But I do recognize I do recognize the art style just kind of the way
the way the line's kind of bend and the way like, their feet bend is they're walking and everything it's very fluid.
And and it is very much the same style that we get in the cartoon show
forty years after this forty five years.
You're definitely right. Right? To show took a lot of
notes from the comic. It's based largely on it.
Something to know is that I I think the shows,
it ranges from being well liked tolerated
by Barks fans. I of course, loved it growing up as a kid. And I discovered Ducktales and Barks comments around the same time. I probably started watching
the show within a couple of months after I'd read my first few Barks comics.
But yeah. They're not... They're not really that well loved among the the Comics fans,
which, you know, is kinda to be expected because
they make a lot of concessions for Saturday morning.
Which is to say we're definitely gonna talk in these podcasts about things that the episodes might have used.
But
it's not gonna be a a major emphasis of it because it's just not what Barks fans or are really that into.
Yeah. But but again, I'm not I'm not proud to admit too proud to admit that I still enjoy both both of the
iterations of the show. Any other thoughts or questions
before
we talk about the the story beats and the plot.
No. I don't think so. Excellent. Let's do it. So I... I'm gonna go through. I've mentioned to you when we were planning for this that this was a challenging
part segment from me last time
because Donald Duck finds pirate gold was you know, it was like the Cartoon story board that was based on. It wasn't...
It was very hard to summarize was very Gladstone. This one is much more
well plotted.
I think so I'm gonna go through page by page.
And summarize the major and importance for beats. But feel free to chime in if you have something to say if you wanna talk about it by all needs.
So
the beginning of donald dot, Donald Duck, and the monies ring, we
see the nephews
our pest trained donald is sees reading the morning paper.
Donald is reading about an a museum exhibit
that says the headline says bay bell data, sends two Al series to bring back mum of his and sisters.
So the Nephews have decided
to go to the museum and see the mum
and Donald reveal that it's gonna be their last chance because the money are gonna get moves taken away the next day.
There is a reference to
purse that's been placed on
anyone disturbing the money,
which
I I've gotta imagine is not the the old Cli
for us that it is at at this time by by now, but that compared to Barks when this was written.
It was probably in that Barks car movie you mentioned. Right?
Yeah. I I've never actually seen... But I think every every money movie is about a purse. Right and upsetting the tune. Right.
So on the way to the museum, so we're on page two on the way to the museum,
they get backed and by
sc looking. I think you could only describe miss Bum. A guy who's trying to sell them a elegant ring worth fifty dollars
the guys very persuasive.
Donald declines
the ring and the guy just goes ahead and gives it to him and he lose to having bad luck ever since he swiped it.
So they take a look at the ring and they noticed that it's got a symbol of three serpents on it, and they assume that maybe it belong to one of those mum.
And this is the moment when the peak look alike
approaches from behind them and starts to harass them
about the ring.
He starts
to
man handle, Donald. He's gonna take the ring, but the nephews
intervene by poking a a hot roast peanuts stand in them and they get away. They figure this is gotta be the mum ring because they're seeing bad luck from what they supposed purse.
Donald skeptical,
but
Hue has put the ring on and it is stuck on his finger.
He definitely never played any dungeons and dragons because you know, don't just put a random ring
on your finger.
It might be cursed and you might Severino take it off again.
I also...
I thought it was interesting another thought I had was after reading the first issue that you read with Eric,
and it ends with them
being rich beyond their while streams from all the treasure they found. And here, they're just walking around. He doesn't wanna blow, fifty cents on u. I'm gonna ring this worth fifty dollars. And I was wondering about continuity and when continuity was invented.
These these are very
There's very little continuity
in these,
you know, Bark himself was kind of working anonymously.
There was never any, like,
idea that he was going to get to... You, you know, there are not gonna be any, like, continued
in the next story, a story lines. There's definitely no marble cinematic universe. To this. So there there will be characters
that aren't lights and he's gonna come back two, but he just figures that out very organically. It's like so many shows like the Simpsons
where
they kinda hs sketch things
back to the status quo. I also Al struck by how different donald is in these issues. From my perception of what Donald is as a character.
And I I think of him as more kind of a a goofy like character
kinda fumbling around and and kind of hap.
And in this, he's like this tough street wise you know,
working class guy, and I think the first thing he says, in this issue is he's working on improving his mind,
which seems like an doesn't seem like something, you know, nineteen sixties
Donald Inducks would say, and a and it Isn't too, and you know? Definitely. I I love this because,
you know, I'm so used to these. This so this is the default donald for me. But I love hearing the things that come to mind for you as your us for the first time. This is what people really like about the bar version of Donald. You know, he's more of an every man.
He's not the, like,
simmering all of it. You know, he's got a temper in these. Definitely. You gonna fly off the handle.
I... I'm struck by... I mean, even
when Pete or whoever this is,
is picking him up and, like, has him up off the ground holding him by the neck with two hands.
And he's saying, what did you do with the ring? And Donald says I forget.
Because he's just like this stuff. He's he slips it to Hue behind his back while he's talking to pete.
I think in and sort of this post depression
storytelling,
Americans really liked there are characters to be very scrap, you know? And
self reliance.
Donald got a lot of faults in these, but he's he's much more complex than he was. And and he's gonna evolve Al lot after this one. And pretty pretty quick time. Alright. So we're gonna take up back in the museum or they're gonna arrive at the museum. It transitions quickly into the play that they're looking at.
I really like the arts. I I think you can tell that
this is one of the scenes were bar was, you know, referencing
something that he saw because the
the art
of the egypt egyptian
exhibit
is really striking on like the perspective here. They are in front of a couple of sa ka guy. I think that's how you plural that. It is.
And they kinda dare themselves to pee. Side and they do, and we don't actually see more than a glimpse of the money that's inside.
But they do see a money and they see some evidence of some of a robbery.
They see an empty box that they guess some course funds to the ring that is stuck on Hue finger. Then we
see that there are a couple of very sinister. A looking guys dressed in
we're meant them is Egyptian ga are behind them.
They have to get out of there. So I wondered how much of this was was I can try and still Al the plot move along and how much of it is, how different the culture is
in the early forties, but that these these random sc can just walk into...
They they probably bought a ticket in the museum, but then they just walk into some other wing where there are no people and where there are these mondays on display. There's not a security guard. There's not even velvet rope. They just kinda walk up lift it up, take a peek inside. What's going on in here? Or anything of value?
I also find it remarkable that Hue is already wearing an egyptian ring that matches this stuff right now and Actually my first thought as the two guys showed up behind him is he is going to jail now. He's going to jail because
they have the thing open. He is obviously wearing some ancient
jewelry, and it's a very plain that he's probably taken that from inside the the sarcophagus and his story that a above this to me on the street for free, probably not gonna fly with the authorities. But luckily,
luckily no and apparently noticed that.
Yeah. I remember
I remember reading as a kid feeling a little bit stressed about that. I was like, oh, no. He's gonna get caught. But I think I I think it really is the case that people were a lot more cavalier
about
you know, anti Barks and not that they would have allowed things to be stolen. Straight out of the museum. But have you ever seen those pictures of people like climbing on the pyramids
and just the way the gradual way that people treated stuff back in the day. So on the next page we find out about those two
Donald calls some tough looking guys. I'm gonna imagine that they're talking to the museum curator.
He tells them that these are the beneficiaries of the bay of Al,
and he explains that they are the ones getting the money ready to ship back to their end such for homeland, and they find out that the bay of Al
has been
he's
characterized as being so at modern life and wanting to restore everything
back to how it was in ancient times.
So now he's taking everything that he wants under the threat of starting a war. I was gonna talk about this later, but I just... I think it's interesting how
when we read this ryan, I think we're supposed to, like, feel like the bay is really overs stepping his bounds and
can you believe that he's acting that way. You know, now we we kind of understand that a lot of the stuff in our
has really been stolen
from other cultures
and there's a big rep
movement. So I I definitely read that differently
than I did when I was a child.
Yeah. My note... My note I have here is why is the bay of Al so far at the pill of his culture heritage?
Yeah. Yep. Pretty much. So at the end of this page, Huey, realizes is that he has
left his cap, probably in the money room and he needs to go back and get it. So on the next page, he circles past the two emi who are just looking with severe expressions that that anyone could. And the last we see of him at this point is him looking to see if it fell into the star sarcophagus
cut to donald and the other nephews
waiting outside And, you know, to me, it's amazing that an adult would like let the kid go back in the museum all by himself. But again, kids ran around from morning till dust back in the day. Even even in our day. I mean, I just I was only child. I was just writing my bike around the neighborhood by myself. Yeah. Check in and make sure you're back by the time the sun's gone down. I know. I I had that child. I had a childhood a lot closer to the one that he was doing louie had. And and, of course, this is Hue who has the ring on his finger. He's gone missing at this point. The Donald and the nephew, the other half user searching for him, we see them in museum. On the next page,
there's more sequence where they're searching
and they're in the room with the sarcophagus.
And suddenly,
it tremble and it moves.
And Donald
runs out in tear after he's just given some about how rude he is. And apparently, they're too scared to go back in because they think they've just seen evidence on the money.
So they go to report it. To the police.
Although it's worth pointing out that after the Sarcophagus moves,
Donald is the one who disappears like a lightning flash, and the nephews are like, oh okay. Just kinda fuck out.
Donald is the one with a clear Mommy pho.
Right.
Perhaps there was some scarring event with the money when he was kid. And
he's never really gotten over it. And he may not be the the ball of rage
that he is in the cartoons, but he is done definitely and the one who feels... He he he does fly off the handle more in these than the nephews do. So they they report to the police, but the police base we go with the old diplomatic community saw. We keep couldn't arrest those men. They're they're just generally skeptical.
It's up to donald and the boys and on the next page,
they go back and they probably beat the curator
about the location of the.
And he reveals that they have left
they've taken the money and
they've left for their ship,
which is called the amnesia Castle. I don't think that's referenced at all and the rest of the story. But they they know what they need to do now. They need to get to that ship. And again, the the cab driver lets them know that, oh, you're not gonna be able to get on that ship unless you're an ambassador or something. On the next page,
Donald Spot
something, which we find out Al a cost shop pulls over and
they acquire some pretty ridiculous costumes,
you you would accurately
call parts of this story orient
is probably the term that we use today to describe kind of the hodgepodge
of
eastern
tropes and dress and attitude.
So their address and kind of random...
Someone's idea of kind of eastern get.
Yeah. A very rich
Indian
some kind of leader,
whatever, you know, whatever the equivalent to the Barks would be, I would say he has a sas. Right. And then then the nephews have Turban on some reason as his attendance so, yeah, They... They've never met real asian people before, but they've heard about them on the radio. That's what this costume is. Exactly. Yeah. So they tried to blast their way onto the ship
and the the guard c's right through them. I I really like the line when he kicked them out of all the pho I ever saw. You guys are the funniest yes
And so the Nephews have to go with plan b and on the next page,
they just offer themselves up. As as workers.
But Hands.
Jack cans. They offer themselves up as stack hands and I feel like this is one of those historic things where there was a time where a man could just offer himself up as a deck and see the world.
Maybe this still goes on in some countries, but
this to me is very archaic.
Now you need three references
and
a linkedin page.
Right. And you need to have
ten years of experience in this programming language that's been around for five. Exactly. Hopefully, you had some unpaid internship for a while as an intern while you were getting your bachelor's in in Inducks handing. Right. So sorry deck hands are
working on the ship. The shit still still at the dock. So their their idea is that they're just gonna get in find Huey, and get out and unfortunately
one of the sees
snoop around and
they asked about the series and he tells them to get back to work mine they're own business and this point, the ship has failed. So they're really in deep. I have some... I have some nephew thoughts
Yeah.
I've I've noticed they
they
have statements that they would like to make, but they each make a third of the statements.
That one of them will say the first part and then one of them say with the middle of the sentence and one of them will say the last part of the sentence. Yeah. It reminds me of there's some
less famous x men characters called the the Stamford.
Who are these
blonde qui,
their teenagers,
and they all have very powerful tele powers, but they can
kind of merge their tele powers and kind of direct it all, you know, in the same place or whatever.
But they will actually talk this way sometimes l they'll one of them will start a sentence and the other one will finish it. And it made me wonder if if the nephews here are also Tele, and if so
they should use their let to find where He is and say, you know, they'll re q his mind to see where he is. He's inside something dark.
And I also I also thought that maybe from this point on in the story. Dewey and Louie should each say a third of a sentence and leave the last third of the sentence implied. And just have... Just have this vacant spot where where he would have finished his. Okay. Very more in full kinda of looking at the camera.
Yeah. That's great. Maybe maybe they're just too young and they haven't fully owned their
psychic powers. Yeah. Another of those examples where this is just the way that they're written and I'm used to they interact. So it's a who's Severino
you kind of, like, highlight that thing that
is is really background
to me. This is this is how the nephew top. This is what they do. So
we're on the ship at this point it's after hours, it's time and and they can go snoop.
And there's a scene where Donald is fine through a one of the windows
and
describing what he sees to the other nephews,
who are obviously
undergoing some pretty bad c sickness because when he talks about the food, start to get nauseous
and eventually have to
leave donald Prop up prop up by a chair so they can go throw up. We assume a neat site gag. But by the next page,
they're not there to be lookout for Donald. So he gets discovered
again by that porter. And you get put on Galley duty. Galley, of course being the k the kitchen were and they have to peel
scores and scores
of onions.
And I was confused by the fact that they're crying when I was a young kid because I had never cut
for.
So I didn't understand that that proves tears.
I actually thought they were peeling potatoes until you until you said, but I see the bag actually says the word onions on it. So...
So while they're in the midst of this, it's a very dramatic
where the door opens behind them, and we see
a money just to figure wrapped in bandages,
sign only appears behind them. Raises is fist men
and stripes all three of them in one fell smooth knocking them out. I was totally bought when I read this as an eight year old, I was like that some mommy. This is really freaky key. Loved it. This was a one of the scarier stories I probably read. Up to this point. Yeah. I... My perception is that he I think I... My perception is that he
smack because all three ducks are in sitting closely together in a row, and that he smack Donald head hard enough to kind of
bump up. They hit hit them in a row like those, like
you call.
Yeah. Totally. Yeah. It's So we get a long transition that says minutes past, so they've obviously been knocked out for a while.
And they noticed that some sausages have been stolen and while they were out.
They assume it's some hungry still away, and this gives them the impetus to go crowley. So Donald is hungry. He gets himself a sandwich
And while he's distracted,
hand reaches out of one of those part holes,
wrapped in bandages, and steel his sandwich,
kind of an interesting transition from that like
erie
seen last page to this. This looks pretty slab stick and goofy feet to me. So Donald sees that the sandwich is gone and he wants to look through the port hole. And on the next page, we see donald looking through
and he gets an expression of
tara he start
s and indeed the porter and the emi
come out and see him s came with the nephews trying to calm him down and he cries when he's ask what's wrong. He says that the money, the money they're sitting up and their cases eating my sandwich, and the Emi beneficiaries look on
in kind of
confusion. And, you know, before I go to the next page, I I thought this page was pretty striking because
He just looks,
you know, it's a really good depiction of fear. In this. Yeah. He definitely doesn't look like he's
you know, working a khan. Or would have with these guys. He's terrified of something.
On the next page, the,
they are a convinced and they call out for food for their ancestors.
All the best dishes brought out and left near the Barks off guy. They explain that this is something that we we all learn about in grade school that's when, like, far
were buried that they were
very next to to find food and stuff so they could take it into the land of the dead. And,
you know, they they complained about their loved ones have lane in
museums
in the western world for for century.
And the nephews
have a moment of skepticism
at the end of this page
saying they've never heard of money eating.
I'll also point out this even just on this page, you get a good example of Barks writing different voices to where people talk very differently from each other. And...
Yeah. Feel like the missionaries have the best English of anybody in this issue.
They they talk like very highly educated people. This one here, you correctly,
correctly uses the past participle of july have Lane
which yeah which pete at the... You know, at the beginning of this of this issue would not have normal would donald have... And even the kids, you know, they they use kind of contractions and everything Mum Et, ea a t i and apostrophe.
And and it shows how, you know, all these people are from different places. They have different backgrounds different.
Education levels, which is
you know, class. Yeah. Most
authors of novels would take care to to do in their novels, but you wouldn't necessarily expect Inducks economic Yeah. I really... I really appreciate you pointing that out. That's a a great thing that I think I just
absorbed, but didn't ever... Yeah. I've read these since i was eight. So this is kinda of part of my Dna, but that... That's a really good point.
I think you can definitely
hear their voice is. So
on the next page,
Donald and the boys,
they are sent to the bridge. One of the Nephews
I think it's Louie
explains that,
you know, this is clear what's going on now. They're not real mum. One of them,
one of them they've surmise
must be hue
and he... He's been smuggled
out of the museum wrapped like a month, and they're asking an themselves, who who's the other mommy they're just... There there's a lot going on a lot of the, you know, the rhythm of the story. A lot of the deduct of the story goes on in these four panels where they figure out that the other mommy must be a kid number you must be after the ring. And and
in the last panel of this one, Donald realize is that they they've got a time constraint now that they've got to tell them what's going on,
or they risk
having
hue and the kidnapped are being sealed up forever
And
before going to the next page, you know, I think that this one is really an interesting really thing because
this could have been much more of a mystery.
Right? And he just chooses to have the the characters figure it out even though it was structured like a mystery before that.
Yeah. This was one of my favorite pages in the issue where
for one thing, they're not thrown off Al at all by having just been thrown in the break. They're just like, okay, let's figure this out, and the three of them sit down and start kind of debating it with each other. Yeah.
With some pretty sound reasoning, you know,
I think, you know, based on their observations, they come to some pretty sound completion. I think it
makes them more charismatic as the heroes
of the story, you know, you want your hero to be
sharp and and able to kind of figure out what's going on?
I I agree completely. I like...
I like that the characters seem really sharp and
here.
I find it really
infuriating a lot of media where characters
are
dumb for no good reason. Like, this does seem like something they should figure out and they do.
On the next page, it's the next day they find out that the bay... The base
have already left
So they are realizing that they've got to
risk their next to to save them and they they dive off the ship to leave and to have a chance to catch up with them. And it's
pretty dramatic.
I really like these couple of panels where they make that decision.
Yeah.
I like
the the frame right before they die where they show the the try
sailing away. I feel like is where they really
start to
convey this sense of a much bigger world than than their little town,
and it's full of Al of interesting things that we just haven't found yet, and it's just kind of this
mysterious
parallel world to ours. And I also like how Donald checks with the nephews first.
He's like,
we we have to risk risk our next to save him
And they go, yeah Okay. Let's do it.
And that you're right. That's a great panel, the the galley or whatever. Just...
I I'd love the r in that one. And we definitely, I think feel like we've arrived somewhere else.
And, you know, I think I kinda of criticized it earlier for orient,
and and there's definitely
a lot of that in this story, which is the nature of the time, but this panel to me really shows that Barks had an interest in this place and and depicting it
in a way that was at here it and
and very loving, I think because, you know, the camera really loves this... The the virtual camera or whatever really loves this
Panorama.
So on the next page, they
are
escaping, and it... It's a big escape actually for just couple of people, you know, deck leaving the ship
because they've got
bullets being fired at them.
They have to run through some alleys
where just some of the local stray dogs are nip at their heels.
And at some point, they they stir up a mob that runs after them. So they have Inducks down kind of a a little Barks Al.
And
they can't hide there.
So
we we kinda kinda away to from the point where they're hiding,
and
there is a local and direct the the local police
after them
and there's a, you know,
this is a pretty unfortunate
panel
where they've dressed as locals and they... The artwork shows them having darkened to their skin.
And, you know, they they redirect them.
They're posing as locals basically, and they
they mis direct
them so that the mob runs off.
And just do Al still all still speaking English, of course. Everybody in this situation is speaking English. As the Egyptian cops are asking,
apparently, egyptian fisher people
I I also think... I mean, just the first three frames here. It's first
some kind of machine gun fire coming from off off frame, maybe from the boat.
And then the second frame is
dogs they're chased by dogs, and the third frame is a mob, which is not even in the frame. They're just saying there's a mob after us.
And and I think, you know, in anywhere else... I mean, in a movie, this would be a a ten minute
action set piece.
But here, it's just... We gotta hurry through it because we got more story to tell. And they're just, like, here's some danger.
Yeah. And going forward, you know, it's there's not gonna be this kind of, like
pasting, I think, as much. This this is more of a hallmark the early Barks stuff.
So the next page
has them finding a a a ship an abandoned
a F,
I don't know if that's how you pronounce that, but an egyptian style
ship. Again, Barks clearly got it right.
And they've venture up nile.
And this is like the tour part of the story. Right? Or all of a sudden
the the Inducks and we get distracted and and become sites sears.
And
they start to look at the sides things on the bank of the nile.
They dash their ship,
and they they lose some time and they have to remind themselves okay. We're
dedicating our ourselves to getting Hue, and they they end up drifting that night in a wen
period. And then on the next page,
Louis
has the bright idea to hook
on a passing
steam ship or freighter or something and they make much better progress
of nile
by the time
the other Ducktales woken up, they've made... They've navigate three hundred miles up the nile,
and they've approached the base barge off the port bow.
And then on the next page,
they approach, we kind of see Al,
which is a cool looking ancient city. They are approaching as there's a ceremony that they surmise is for the return of the mum.
And as they approach, they are attacked by a hail of arrows
so they've got circle back and think of another approach. There's so much
payroll
for the kids in this
this comic.
We have... We have, you know, just two pages ago, we had the the guns from the
from the, you know, cruise ship or whatever that was, the dogs, the mobs,
and now Arrows being shot at the kids, and all of this is to save Hue
who is going to be buried alive Yeah.
As as a mommy,
And
I think man, like, there's no
I think even when I was kid, maybe the the cartoons and stuff didn't have this kind of
mortal danger for the kids.
Did the eighties Ducktales show have, you know, they're gonna get swept off Al cliff and eaten by sharks or something?
I mean, I I don't think there was this much like human directed violence. you know?
I don't think... I think these older comics,
especially in, like, the forties
and and so forth, we're a lot more violent in that kind of like, you know, with fist knives and stuff like that. I I'd I'd like to... I like to tell people about the old Mickey Mouse comics and and how
how incredibly violent
those are.
But, you know, you were talking about the the Hayes code before we started recording. I don't know if you wanted to to mention that or if you were
saving that powder for for later.
Yeah. I I was thinking when I was reading it, I was thinking about, you know, there's a lot of... This is some kinda rough stuff, and
I was thinking... Is this violate the the Comics code authority? And so I looked up
when that was, and that code is from nineteen fifty four. This comic, of course is from nineteen forty three as you mentioned.
So we still haven't
gotten to this kind of
regulation of of the comics for people who maybe don't don't read as many comments. It's...
The government started to get really concerned about how
comics we're influencing kids
and, you know, brand watching them into
being violent criminals and everything just like rap music did in the early nineties and
video games are doing to us now and
everything every kind of media needs to be
regulated for for its violent brain watching effect.
So
to kind of get ahead of it,
the Inducks industry
impose this code
upon themselves and and decided this would be how, you know, all the comics that get sold and mainstream shops would need to meet these
these standards.
Yeah. And
great. Thing to read about it, like, it's fascinating that that attempt on that regulation and and what it did to the industry. And, you know, I I hadn't thought about that at all
until you mentioned it, and I do think it's gonna be interesting to see, you know, as we approach that dividing line if if that really affects
Barks
stories at all, obviously, the the funny animal books for probably a lot more immune that that wasn't they were being directed Al the old like,
the the Ec Prime
And the superhero stuff.
But I've I've gotta imagine there are some knock on effects. Right?
Yeah. Yeah. And it's... I mean, it covers
most of the history of comics. Like I I tried to find out when it ended. And it started to get a little softer in the in the eighties and nineties and stuff. And and then in two thousand one,
Marvel submits the next force comic to get approved by the Comics code authority, and they said no. This is this is too violent to something you gotta take take this thing out, and Marvel just said I don't think we will. I don't feel like doing that. And so they just stopped submitting them and that was how it ended it. Two thousand one from nineteen fifty four.
That's crazy.
So
we are
back to the the next page cuts to in
in the palace of the bay of Al.
And they are
in the midst of their ceremony they're preparing to bind the case is.
Outside the palace, the Nephews Donald nephews are
pondering how to get past
a guard.
You know, Donald getting into the spirit of things, I guess because he wants to make an old egyptian
when happen and and he makes... They call it a sling shot. I I know it is a sling.
Right, what David used against Goliath and
on the next page, man, he just absolutely
brains that guy. He's definitely dead.
He can just around that big on the side of the head from that distance.
Yeah he's not getting back up from this. He's at least not eating solid food and anymore. But but while there's a lot of apparel, it's at least still a funny animal common.
So
they they rush inside after.
They brain that guard.
And they stop them in the nick of time from sealing the cases.
And the bay of elle Do
is
wondering who, you know, who are these guys and his emi
indicate there some fools who followed them from America,
and they're crazy and
he has them captured and he... Yeah. He he does seem
pretty harsh.
Definitely, his first instinct is... Well, I mean, they didn't even know who was on the boat or what the boat was coming for. And they just started shooting arrows Al it already. But once once the say, these guys are crazy. He says, okay, let's throw him to the crocodile files.
So Donald
pipes up and he
says that the emi beneficiaries can prove that the people in and the cases are alive
He
makes them confirm that the food that they had ordered
laid out was eaten.
And then the base
surprises is emi
but
insisting they'd be released that that Donald at least
be released and the nephews
saying that he didn't attend the Harvard Universe see you without learning that money don't eat. So there was a little just surprise moment where we learned that
the bay while he is
against
western optimization, it's not
through a lack of familiarity. He's at actually been educated at
their analog for Harvard. And he he... Well, his seemed to believe that the money are have some kind of supernatural element to them the way ancient and egyptians did.
Even the bay, who loves ancient egypt and once once everything did you like that again, seems to me not to. He he seems to be have solely sentimental
nostalgic kind of feelings toward the mum rather than
Yeah. You're right. He may not buy fully into it. That's interesting. He he definitely...
They give him some
surprising debt in in a a very quick number of panels, I think. So on the next page, he agrees. Yeah they're there must sp live people in the Barks off guy.
And
then in the next panel after he agreed, and they've gotten their hopes up. His face really Barks
and an expression that I I found really intimidating as a kid, and he said that, you know, those live people then can take the place of the ancestors and he insists that this ceremony must continue. Donald is,
you know, thrown a hail mary pass. He says wait, the little boy, and one of those cases, he he notices the seal of the three
serpent. He says that he's got ring with that seal.
And the bay is shot it comes to him that this is the ring the missing ring of the three.
I thought it was interesting that he let the other Inducks go if he's still going to Bury
Hue. He says I'm going to knowing bury this kid. I know there's a kid in there.
And... But you guys are free to go. You can just hang out here and watch.
Yeah, he's kinda selective about who gets who gets victim optimized here.
So
on the next page,
he is very excited and he
agrees, let's open the cases.
There's affiliation where everyone that that really provides some good suspense here. I think everyone waits silently and the high priest opened the Barks off,
and we do see two figures
donald and the audience
immediately knows that one of them is hue,
and then the other one is a big money
who
weep out of the Barks sarcophagus for this and tries to escape.
He jumps out about.
That looks like it would killed him from the fall. And Donald grabs a bandage
and,
you know, we get a class sick money un fur.
And
we find out as it un referrals what we what most people who are not small children
guest
immediately is that it was the guy that tried to rob him the pete alike who tried to rob him back in America.
They returned to the throne room
and we have just a really shockingly
j
individual meeting with the bay
considering that he was moments ago ordering them thrown to the crop dial pitt
because he is... He's got Hue sitting on his lap.
He's, like, beam, like like a proud call holding the ring,
which Huey, has
returned to him and it's been clear that they've been looking for it for three thousand years. They say,
Q reports in very
economical
storytelling
that
the thief, the Robert had followed them back to the museum,
saw him trying to get the ring.
And basically,
when he heard someone else coming into the room,
stash Huey, himself into the stretch off for this and then was forced
to
disguise himself some money.
He was just really in the wrong place at the wrong time.
Hue mentions that, yeah, Now now he had to keep me fed so that he would only be guilty of kid rather than murders, which is why they were
stealing food on the ship. Of course.
So lot of storytelling on this page, a lot of
quick resolution here. Any thoughts. It's interesting that he we couldn't get the ring off then but
seems to pop it off now out of frame.
Yeah to give to give to the bay. Probably lost
Doesn't
that's probably true. That's actually not a bad not a bad idea the
the winnie need the poo method of
getting
getting un.
That's right. Yeah. And and again, just the Bay has
has become this teddy bear in this span of time,
which
I I noticed as kind of jarring even as a kid.
You know? I I don't think as a kid that I
had expected
I'm sure I knew that it must have been the Robert, but
I know I went into this thinking it was gonna be there was gonna be a real money in this. So there were things as a kid that I definitely didn't pick up on. But I noticed how jarring that was.
Yeah. That's Al that's a hard hand break turn
character character change.
So the next page is the last one, and it wraps up with them sailing back with a a just fabulous
treasure that, of course, is gonna get actually sketched away by the next adventure.
And
Huey, realizes that he has lost his cap again
must be back there in the money case, and they've learned their lesson and they're going to use that treasure
to buy the new one.
And the last frame, they sail past wet what are a couple of very famous
Egyptian monument that I have somewhere in my notes.
And they're singing hail hail the games all here and just a very nice tidy ending.
So
that was...
That was the mum ring.
And
Boy, I really enjoyed.
I really enjoyed
na that and and hearing your thoughts
as a newbie
going over this.
I want to talk about kind of our overall thoughts
about this one.
I think uniquely in this one, the the feeling that I can remember having the first time I read this is a little bit of disappointment. Right? Because this one ends up... It's billed as being about a money.
But
it's not. There's not a real money in this at all. It's just some crook in disguise.
And the... There was a mommy in the sarcophagus
Right. You know, when the at the at the start of the frame, and I assume it's been shoved into a garbage can in the that ip pete.
But there was no living money that that walked around
and had a purse or anything.
So,
you know, that was what I kinda took from this one. Was a little bit of buyers from more. So, oh, man, you know, that... That's kind of a let down. But I I came back to this and I reread it many times.
I think without without knowing
until much later that this was the very first
fully plotted
fully drawn
part story.
And
I I really came to appreciate this one over the years
and I have I much more appreciation
for now. I I really enjoyed
the
the story elements
and
just the plotting and a lot of the way that Barks
into rated,
you know, Egyptian
lo and
egyptian culture
and
know, it really... It really does feel like a travel log once they get there.
So
really enjoyed this one even if I felt like I I was mis direct it a little bit.
I'm I'm really curious about your your thoughts because I can't remember
you reading one of these
and really engaging with it. So so what did you think
overall of the right?
I thought it was cool.
In the modern day, they would have stretched this over a few issues, probably.
This
Indiana Jones
international treasure hunt perilous
adventure
rescue
And and
I think, you know, when I when I first read over it, I was thinking
You know, this is this is kind of a possibly
problematic view of this
this
Egyptian leader who is very backward looking.
And then on the second read, I realized
Car Barks really just wanted a story to take place in ancient egypt. He just wanted to write an adventure that happens in ancient egypt. But he didn't want to come up with some time travel rules or anything.
So Huey,, you know, he gave one frame to He's, you know, he doesn't like the modern world. He likes things
in in
a little more traditional. And and that way, we were able to get the
the kind of event the Barks wanted. I was impressed how capable
Donald is as as the hero here. Like, even in this last frame, they're they're plainly still like sailing up the nile and this little,
you know,
three man sale boat
They're apparently going to sail this across the Atlantic
back back to their hometown and I mean, he is in Al little sailor outfit of it. And a couple pages ago, he was
repairing a a boat that had wrecked.
And it seems like he has some real skills. He's not just some
some goof ball that's
doing his best or whenever he
he has some abilities and he's leveraging them to try and
reaches objectives here.
Yeah. And and again, I... I've gotta to think that after the depression, this is just kind of like
what Americans felt like they could do.
You know, they they i'm long enough needing to to make do. We'll we'll take a moment for a kind of final thoughts. But before... Before we do that, there's just a few other reflections that I want to to do. I... I'd love to talk a little bit kind of specifically. We we touched on how it holds up Like I said, there's some some problematic depictions in this.
I think for the most part this
is
generally
respectful
at least relative to a lot of of media of this time. You know, obviously, there are some things that wouldn't be shown
or presented
today.
But,
you know, a apart from just sort of the general
eastern
orient
mindset
I I think
he he did a pretty good job again in relative terms. Rating on a curve, you know, I think any media that you look gap from this time is probably going to look
pretty dated with some attitudes towards
towards
people from quote the east.
But apart from looking at, you know, stuff that might be problematic, I also think it might be interesting to highlight some things that are just out of time. Right? Some some things that are interest saying
dated now. And and I noticed I don't know if you remember at the beginning of the story.
Donald referenced is doing all his shot at the five and ten when he's getting mug by Pete.
I I didn't know what a five and ten was. Did you catch that?
I I've always assumed it was,
you know, some kind of thrift shop or a pawn shop
Yeah. I up and a five and ten is what you might think it is. It's where everything costs either a nickel or a dime. So it's basically an old school dollar store. I noticed
I
I made note of
when they misspelled kidnapped, the first time they said kid kidnapped, in the museum.
And
then they spelled it the same way on the next page and the next page. And here at the end when we were
doing our exposition dump,
you know, he was still a kid nap
with one pee.
And and I thought maybe this is just
an old time way of writing that. Right. Yeah. I noticed that this time as well. I also,
you know, had to look up the song because I've I've heard those statues of song lyrics
a few times, but
Hell the games all here what they're seeing at the end, which is very appropriate.
I guess it's from Pirates
and
must have been just huge in the popular
imagination at the time. I don't think it's something that we would casually thing anymore.
That's probably true.
I also wanna talk about if there's appearances another media.
So
this... To my knowledge, this was never used as the basis for a
story, which many of them will have been.
But I think famously,
there's a sequence in the opening
That is an homage to this. If you go back and watch the Ducktales theme song.
There is
money
waking up looking at a red glowing ring, and I think that's you know, again, part of the mis inspection because I definitely
seen
Ducktales by the time I read this even if I read Barks stories earlier.
You know, that gave me reason to expect a real money.
There just never was.
There there aren't any
i I haven't talked to you about Barks other a career
as as an oil painter,
but
that's something that I will highlight in these episodes
if he ever base a painting off this one.
To my knowledge, there aren't any big oil paintings.
Taken from this story.
Do you have any final thoughts about this story? Oh, I... Let me let me interject really quick because I did forget
to talk about... We we talked about how we felt about the story, but for the general
consensus
I like to take a look at there's a website called Inducks. I Al d u c k s
that's kind of Al aggregate where they rate all of the
Disney stories, they let users rate them. So they get a pretty good critical consent from any of these stories.
And this one had a pretty strong seven point six rating,
which puts it as two hundred and fifty four out of more than forty thousand
stories, not just Barks stories.
That doesn't put it, like, in the very, very upper echelon on, but that would put this as a pretty well regarded Barks story. So I would say that just,
you know, as is fitting, but this is the first Barks story, and I'll let this kind of be my my final thoughts.
The the this is really the story that
set the templates
for what Barks was going to do going forward. You know, these really
grand adventures where through happens
they get swept up into something
and they have to
figure out their way out a pretty big jam.
And along the way, we
oftentimes get treated to
some really interesting
exploration of another culture
or,
you know, some some cool aspect of of
g.
So I I think it was just a really
really fun to revisit this one. I'm really glad that I got to.
Do you have any any closing thoughts about this.
I think,
you know, for a for a debut
story, essentially,
Pretty impressive. I would I would have expected,
you know,
any any creators first attempt to be a little bit more of a
a bundle and really kinda feeling out. You don't really have the right the right tone yet. You don't really have the right pacing yet.
And
I I think it shows a lot of
creativity.
And
kind of an interest in in, you know, really telling something interesting instead of...
I think a lot of the comments of this era might have been more
you know?
I don't know. It could have been something very
overly tame and
boring because you know, you can sell it for for a dime, and
and they'll just buy whatever, so Why make it good. But he made it good anyway. Right.
Yeah. There's a lot of loving care that's gone into this, obviously.
Well,
Brian, thank you so much. For for joining me I'm. Really thrilled to get to do this. And
looking forward to having you back for some more of these
So if you
have any
thoughts or comments, listeners,
You can feel free to drop us Al line at Barks remarks at g mail dot com.
And
please join us the next time on Mark's remarks when we talk about too many pets.
Thank you very much.
And this is Mark jumping in one last time, I had forgotten to mention a couple of things in my notes.
The fact that Barks copied some of the landmarks
that he
saw in the national geographic article
daily life. In Ancient Egypt.
Some of the sites depicted in this story include the great swings so Gi on page seventeen, the skyline of Cairo on page seventeen and eighteen.
The pyramid of Made doing...
May on page nineteen, the pyramid of Joe sir on page twenty and the mo rate temple of hat chip shit
on page twenty one and twenty two as well as the
of mem.
And I wanted to
introduce our Ask kids segments
So give it a listen. Hello. This is Ryan. I'm back for the Ask a kids segment, and I am here with an actual kid. What is your first name Kate? Penny.
Penny. And what grade are you in? First grade.
Okay.
So
we just read
donald Inducks and the mum ring.
So you have some experience with comics. Do you...
Did you like this one? U.
And did you feel like you understood what was going on?
Kind of? Were there some parts that were hard to understand? No. No.
Was it scary? No.
No. Were you worried for the for the nephews?
Yeah. No. You why weren't you worried?
I don't know.
You knew they were gonna be okay? Mh.
Okay. And
so what was your favorite part? Patrick
answering three.
Okay.
Did you think the book was fun?
Yeah.
Would you
read more of these? If there were more of these?
Yeah. I think I like other books
better. Yeah.
Okay. Okay.
And I like.
That's pretty great. Who doesn't let it?
Alright.
Thank you, Ryan, and thank you, Penny. We'll see you all next time.