Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks, the podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of sc Mc and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comics of all time, join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Hello. I'm Mark Sever. I'm a longtime
Carl Barks fan. I've been to Karl Marx since I was about seven or eight years old
and enjoyed the Donald Ducktales Uncle sc comics, and I am very excited to have the opportunity
to be a grown man and talk about kids comics.
And
I am fortunate to have a returning c
with me today, and I'm gonna let him
introduce himself under. I am
not Al long as work of fan coronavirus. Have many girlfriend
bad Ducktales and
exploration and then comments And I'm looking forward to enjoying my promotion from
guest to get chris.
That's right. Excellent.
So Eric,
gave you a little bit of a kind of a caveat or warning ahead of time that this one is not one of my favorite favorite
comics,
but
I don't want to...
I don't wanna give it short sc
because today, we're talking about kind of an unusual story.
This one is called too many pets
this is
from nineteen
forty three, September,
that's the same month that, we talked about Donald and the mum ring. And that's because this comic book was
included in that same one. This is a very rare case
where there were two full length stories
in one com. They were both published in four twenty nine the the old one shot series. This was the b story, very much the b store
And truth be told, you know i
I debated a little bit about whether to include this one in the chronological
you, list of official
long adventure stories.
And so this this podcast is not that. This podcast is not us sub doing every one of them. The the Barks stories are pretty pretty well delineate in the long adventure stories and in the short, usually
ten page
gag stories.
And this one is not really
much of an adventure
It's not a ten page gag story. It's as long as the adventure stories.
And so, you know, I kind of took the opportunity to sit down and think about what what's my criteria for these longer stories and which ones are we gonna do episodes for? And I decided kind of arbitrarily but not really to basically do the cut off at fifteen pages, which is fifty percent more than the the ten pager. So that might same kind of an obscure thing to worry about, but, you know, I had to make a dividing line somewhere.
This one at least does have some
intrigued some danger
you know, it's not say that it's not an adventure at Al. That that this one is different in a few ways. And so This is a story just like the title suggests in which the nephews have too many pets.
They're gonna get an ultimatum from their uncle Donald
and they have to get rid of them.
But through a,
they convince him that they can keep a monkey that they get from an organ grinder. Donald eventually tires quickly tires of the monkey, and he sells it to a sinister person,
and the nephews realized that he seems to have some plans for that monkey.
Kind of an unusual one
in a few ways
and
we're gonna talk a little bit
about... We talked last episode. I had Ryan on you you and I know Ryan very well for a long time.
We had already talked about
what it happens during this month in history.
Obviously, we're still in the hype
World War two, we will be for a few more episodes.
This one doesn't have cover art by Barks, which is kind of unusual just because it was the b
story.
There was actually even a ten pager sandwich between these. So he was like, really pro prolific it for this specific issue.
And
I mentioned that this one's pretty unusual. This one was actually
started
by another
writer
named Mer Dame.
He
he abandoned the story. Apparently, he got fed up with working on it or he was overwhelmed in his other role, but I didn't know this. He was actually...
He worked with Floyd Got
who did the Mickey mouse comic strip. Mh. So I I thought floyd got and did those on his zone before I was researching this, but I learned that he had a lot of collaborate, including this guy. So
this is kind of like the first story you did where Barks,
you know, collaborated with Hannah
for Donald duck finds pirate. So you kinda are getting slot into these unusual ones here.
Right?
So I I noted in
researching this one too,
that
the... It's assumed that this might have actually started as a mickey mouse story
since
Mari was the one who worked on it. And
they gave... They basically gave it to Barks and he reworked it. He polished it. He developed an ending.
But...
Yeah, I think that's kinda interesting
Sure. I can see that dealing with World two seven tours Al much more of a mickey thing,
I believe. Yeah. It's have mysteries and secrets and stuff
mickey mouse thing and I just don't know how all this would played with the clue of scenario. And
Kudos good jealous or something for that.
Right. No you're right. I I think that's more of a hallmark of the mickey stories. Have you read any of those got and ones.
I don't know. Any Yet have I've not nat familiar with the writers all these.
Right red fifty stuff. Yeah. If you read a.
Chances are pretty good that it was by floyd of God He's he's phenomenal. And and, you know, I'm talking a little bit about floyd god and again because this is not... This one's not the strongest ours works.
No. No not. I But it but it definitely has its merit.
Another little bit of interesting trivia that I found, you know, there was a write up I had
I had a graphic novel that
reprinted this one.
And,
you know, they... The editor of that, he kinda had a little write up about it. And he described Barks having spent a lot of his youth working on ranches,
working around animals.
Barks apparently was fond of talking about how he was...
He he used... Do he spent some time as a mule skinner
but not a very efficient one.
And I don't like that the mental image that that brings up.
Customer.
So let's let's talk just a little bit more background kind of about the the era and the time where we summarize this story. To me the really interesting
kind of time capsule thing, the historical
artifact in this story is the oregon grinder. Have have you ever... Have you ever seen an oregon grinder Eric?
With
and real life. Yeah. Trend think.
I mean, nope know that I have. No. Like in pop culture,
growing up watching pop culture in the eighties,
it felt like we might expect to see Oregon grinder all over the place. But... Right.
And and reading the story got me like, to thinking about it and wondering, you know, how did that become a thing?
And so I got I got a little bit down the rabbit hole with oregon ordinary. Mh.
But apparently,
Oregon grinder became popular in the late nineteenth century, early twentieth century.
And and they were first popular mostly in Italy.
And then they... And then they spread to Europe and then they spread to America.
And
by... Maybe not this time a little bit earlier, I they were probably waning around this time. But
apparently, they were like a huge nuisance in New York City.
And that's
mayor Laguardia,
who my Italian grandmother was very fond of.
He
banned the instrument, the old like barrel organ from the streets in nineteen thirty five because of the congestion and the begging and and, you know, some Italian
italian stereotypes
and and just attitudes of the time. And I guess really organized crime was kind of kinda wrapped up in it and and renting them out to the grinder.
And apparently, the monkeys were a real thing. They usually use cup cap monkeys.
So that... That to me is fascinating. Right? Like that we we talked in our first episode about how that one looked kind of timeless, but this one looks super dated. Yes.
Like, that's that's a pretty big sign signify. Yeah. We're pretty much different now. So for notable, appearances, we don't really have any of all appearances. We've got Donald the Nephews
and then a couple of one off characters, the the grinder that we mentioned and Gin, the monkey and the the spy.
So
let's go ahead go through the story itself So at the beginning of too many pets.
We've got Donald on a classic rampage page.
And I do think this is very Barks. And we'll see a lot of this. You know, he is he's in spring cleaning mode or something, and he is venting and raging at all of the nephews pets
that are
coming up his his cleaning him. Yeah Wonder
there's way kept there. But just keep see them he seeing the panels, any references.
Looks like I think it does bad. Yeah. We've got puppies and turtles and a frog and a Canary or some bird and Al cat.
Yeah. He's... I I kind of understand where he's coming from. It definitely is too many pets.
So on on the next page,
Donald gives them an ultimatum. He says...
Oh, not even ultimatum. He dictates that they're getting rid of the pets.
He is giving them all to something called the Pet society.
They're they're asking are we never gonna be allowed to have pets.
He tells them no and he gives them a pretty specific but broad statement
that, no. Not unless it's something different and he he gives a list of all the common
pets you might have no more cats, dogs, birds, frogs bugs, and my fats, fish or reptile, conveniently
leaving out monkeys.
And indeed... I just... I love just make sure the kids because it's so true kids there with Al everything you say and your ten get my meaning, and they say, no. This is what you said. And didn't say this. That's right. Know everything else. Kids are good or Barks.
Yeah.
I alright. So Donald,
and the next page, Donald goes back in the house and he gets ready to take a soothing bath. He reflects on
on what he said and considers whether he was too harsh,
but just as he gets into the bath or is about to, their fraud that they miss jumps into his robe
and
upsets him again.
And the last panel on this page, we see him cutting a witch,
an old tree branch that they would call a switch to get ready to... And it's... It's it's a pretty funny panel. He says I'll make it up to them now,
but
that's definitely
a a sign of the times.
Right.
Yes. And and again, I don't know about you, but this was a very common depiction. I saw this in comics and cartoons all the time.
And it's you would not see this today. This would
would definitely be viewed as abusive.
Yeah.
The f user t and downtown
looking very for
and they come across an and grind with a monkey.
And I gotta say the monkey really cute. It's I think a nice little bit of art design
we we hear the organ grinder
is talking in very stereotype accent to Al, saying he likes kids,
and and they really appreciate his fro
and they wish out loud that they could have a pet like him.
And at that point, the organ grinder turns around and we get a good look at him and he is just the most Disney
Italian stereotype.
Yes Yes.
Yeah. That you could imagine, and he offers
to... He offers to give them the monkey. And done. But so think of his covers like, yeah. That's really
dated, but knowing the time like i I can see where we're going. Yeah. This was just shorthand for this is an Italian. Yeah. I get a kick out this is as half italian myself. So I really appreciate
stereotype
depictions of
of my people in media. Because it's usually...
It's usually a lot more gentle than
many groups.
Get it. Sure
So the nephews start to pull their money, but he explains that, no he he doesn't mean to sell Jingle that he would like to give Jingle away to them.
Because he just really wants a good home
because he got drafted that same day. Okay. Did...
Yeah. And and this was really striking to me because in most Barks stories, even during this area, you don't really see like a direct mention
of the war.
Right. That's not say there are none of them. But
it's not it's not very common at all to to to see the war in truth like that.
And then before he gives them Django, he does warn them about Jin one low Barks if you put your hands
behind your head in kind of the universal
relaxing posture
he gets in enraged and he throws whatever he can get at you. That's not fortunately. No. No. Not at all. And i'll make sure to to go back to this to to make sure we remember this a couple of times.
You know, this is that kind convenient plot device that.
You know, we don't... We're not opposed to question. This just kinda loose moves the story forward.
So
quirk and it does. It does. And I like Jingle. He's cute.
Alright. So on the next page, the Nephews are bringing
Gin back to... And then they're debating how they're gonna break the news to their uncle.
And they see him with that dreaded switch in his hand.
And and they plan to send go ahead
to kind of
soothe him ahead of time and make him more open to
So
Jin rings the bell. The oregon grinder has explained to them how smart he is he understands almost everything you say. So they give him the instructions to go ring the bell, and he presents donald with an apple. And again,
for reasons of plot Donald thinks that he's a boy, a little boy instead
obviously, he's a monk. And so Donald accepts the apple.
I also like that you know, during this, like, post depression era and,
you know, war scarcity era, apples are a treat. Right? That's something else that I see in in media from this time.
And so Donald
the when Huey, realizes that was a monkey.
He
goes to look for the monkey and while he's distracted the nephews bring him in, and they have
gin served on the nice tray of treats,
milk and donuts, I think.
Oh I like this part where
Gin goes and
starts a record,
because that was kind of a treat seeing an old
and Donald record collection. Yeah, It looks like this version of Donald got
pretty nice
pretty nice setup.
Yeah.
I'm kinda but that out an actual song that they just made it up. Going on the...
That panel.
I I definitely Googled it, and it's definitely not a real sign.
But it is Donald favorite. So...
So I guess that that's Canon. Right? We've just identified Donald Doug favorite on and
one of us needs to update the wikipedia page. Yes. So the nephews used catch Donald pondering out out. This monkey is so helped they rules lawyer Donald into a agreeing to keep Gene. Wouldn't Al lot of pet flash butler. Yeah. Exactly. They are celebrating that they get to keep Jingle.
Donald
tells them, hey, stop celebrating you need to go do your chores. There's some cans that need to be thrown into the salvage box. And again, I I think that might be a reference to
wartime scarcity. Right? That'll go just the hands for the cameras.
So the nephews are painstakingly
throwing the cans in and they got the bright idea
to use gin quirk to have him
throw the cans at them while they're sitting in the salvage box. Yes. I have a okay. I just remembered something the three reinforce that caught device. Dawn all his exercise and on the other side of the window in a way that is kind reminiscent of doing that. And the App use are too late to stop jingle from
shocking Al can through the window and beam Donald on the head Donald is upset of course, and he
demands to know who threw it. All of the Nephews take the lane instant.
The nephews get ready to take their punishment from that switch. They tell Donald that they wanna set example for Django, That's why they fest up so quickly. And Gin, our Donald orders jingle to do the
spanking,
but Jingle refuses he breaks the...
He breaks the switch over his knee, sending Donald into a rage. And then on the next page,
It's basically a sequence where Gin has
gone missing in the house and he's
causing some chaos
breaking a jam jar,
messing up mcdonald's kitchen,
that continues onto the next page there's more chaos.
We're just supposed to get the idea here that
Jin is causing a huge mess in Mcdonald's clean house. Good stuff.
Yep.
I I understand that they will do sometimes what they see.
So eventually, he falls in to the garage. He lights on a very cool looking old fashioned lawn mower, and I like I like seeing Donald crying over his tulip lips, his pants sees his rare, never bloom hypo der.
Which should you know.
I didn't Google that one. I'm guessing it's awesome.
I I I chuckle, never bloom. That's just great. Right? Like, That's genuinely. We've got the consequences,
Donald is furious. And he says you've got to get rid of that. Monk. He tells them they can't even come back into the house until they figured out.
Oh you know what to do with him. And that's
definitely old fashioned, you're not gonna kick your kids out of the house. I hope
They realized that they can't even go back in the house for their coats.
So they order Gin
to go in through the attic,
and I'm a serious man is watching
while they give him these instruction. Now. I do wanna know that first panel
don was too hearted to think. Gin.
Yeah.
But yeah. He was also
wanting ding to make the boys who's exactly we was thinking, which is just I love the...
Right. I would be convenient from the right Child abuse, not animal abuse, I guess.
Right. This this mysterious
guy who, you know, he's he's very creepy looking, but he's also very engineer.
We we just had a couple of podcasts where
some version of Pete
was the villain. Right? The one that you purchased participated in. He was called Black pete. And then the one that Ryan was on, the mummy ring.
It was there was a black pete look lookalike in that one. Think again, old Disney habits die hard. But this guy is just kind of generic sinister.
And he notes that the monkey responds to commands and he wants to buy the monkey. And the nephews are outraged. They don't want Donald sell him, but he goes through with it and the nephew
are
left to cry.
We we learn on the next page, what man's purpose for django is,
he is near a factory
complex and we see him
on on the phone, again, a very old school
style phone
talking to someone about leaving some plans near the window. He's using Jingle
to
to steal some plants. So he's up in very
Military.
Yes. No doubt. He gives him the directions to go in through the window and take the plans, but before he can return him to the window washer station
that the spy is at. Gin starts to miss the nephews
and the spy sees jingle
go in the direction and figures that he's returning to the Like, oh I'm missed those boys. I spent an hour where. I we with them. Yeah. Very very convenient. But they had a great time together. Right? So Sure. So G comes back to the net use with the plans, but they don't realize what it is. They just know that it's thick paper that seems perfect for for making paper airplanes.
And I I thought It was a sign of the times that they were imagining, you know, mine's a p forty seven. Mine's a torpedo bomber. Clearly
right out of the war. And then hue puts a pin on the nose of one, so it'll stick stick up to things. Any jingle throw it. Which, you know, predictably it lands right Donald, but before Donald can get mad, he realizes what the papers were what the documents are, and he becomes very scared. And I can't remember if we've already seen that the plans are for something called a bomb site, but at some point,
they mentioned that that's what the plans are for. And that wasn't in the term that I was familiar with. I assume it's like a precursor
to radar or something. But... Well, in my in my incentive
watching up old two movies,
no bomb sites you know, it's for the bomber. So you wanna be able to get an accurate picture around, where you're dropping with being that high elevation. It's not so much a sensor, like a radar.
But it's just Al location,
advocate the magnification device of how to get a better clear shot around where your boss are gonna go so you can be more
Like doing screen or something like that? Yeah.
With the privilege for the
world war two it it's... The bomb sites get used a lot as the
military, but, you know, designed come in?
Yeah. Because obviously, at this time, they didn't know about, you know, the the Med manhattan Project. So it's just...
What could something general public could be familiar with. Right.
Something did know. Yeah. I'm sure if you're years you later.
Just a few years later these plans would have and having to do with with nuclear weapons notes. So Donald
tells them to hide the plans and he's gonna go after the cops.
I guess he doesn't have a phone at home because he leaves them. And on the next page, they've just hit the plans under the bed when they get knocked at the door. And and it is the spy. And he demands... He... He says he doesn't care about the monkey.
Du monk as he calls him. He just cares about the plans
and the nephews fuse. The nephew start to stall him. She Barks in and he grabs them, and he he ties them up and this is, you know, kind of kinda disturbing. Right? Because he gives him like, a tickle torture and then he
escalate
to
his other method, which is to tie candles
to their feet and let the candles run down.
So while he's waiting for them to talk, he leans back in the classic
relaxation posture. Oh no.
And, of course.
Yeah. We've got Jin who
does what Jin does best
and he brings the guy with a vase.
And
I mean, this is this is a funny animal comic. So it just knocks him out.
But in the real world, that that guy's dead. Okay.
Yeah. So Jin saved the day and on the last page Donald couldn't be more pleased. He's beam.
And he
he leans back to enjoy, you know, the end of a busy day and he puts his hand behind his head and Jingle brains him with a coconut
and the the comic ends with the nephews trying to fan him awake and and saying, oh, yeah. We we should probably remember to tell him about that. And that is
too many pets Any any kind of initial thoughts you have about this one here. Well, really it It's still very stuck Mh here you talked about how somebody we start
this day. Like that's only see that
that okay. This is tara Have to go with it and supply. It feels very
generic. You know, plugged in Al lots of different people that opinion in this unique. Who makes me feel like it's a week novel or Ducktales product, I mean, they pretty angry.
Right. But even he but even then when he
found the plants typically was dog. Gets angry.
He's stays angry he stays hot?
It's just... But it's a good comic. I mean, it's definitely
an example of it's time. I'm not gonna say it's bad. I mean, me it's it's very typical, but it rose when was made.
It seems very fitting. And, you know, the I you're saying is a voluntary aspect that it is a little odd, but I definitely see what you're saying. But this was the second adventure in a you in a comment. Because feels like a second invention, not like, one like, oh, Huey,, guys. Two. That's this is gonna because there's box with that this one. Yeah. There's a mic and did normal story.
Yeah. There's definitely a reason that they put the mummy ring first. You know, that was obviously a labor of love
for Barks and the first one we got to really do everything
himself. I agree with you. This one feels very, like, familiar are in it's pacing.
You know, i kinda like how it starts out
a little bit wacky.
I think one of the reasons that it's nice that we get to include this, even if it's not my favorite is that it it... It's almost a stand in for those ten pager.
Know because there are so many of them and,
you know the album that I read this in that collected this one,
they included several other of the pet stories because Bart went back to this kind of well alarm.
And they wanted those. They were great.
Like
the the three or four other stories in this. I enjoyed them so much more
even though they were quote just ten pager just sc stories. But
but some of those gag stories are
just wonderfully written and and very funny with some amazing art. So
you know, I I don't wanna dump on this one too much because again, he was working within the limitation of of story that was already developed.
And
what I say
yeah. We're just saying he done better and it's just feels what not his best work, and that's fine. Yeah. Yeah. There was not not too much that stood out to this one. And again, like, other stories
that were next to it. We're much more enjoyable to it. I took a look, of course, as we always do
Al the web page index that is the, you know, aggregation page
for
user submitted reviews. And this one had a a rating of seven point one
out of over forty thousand reviews.
It or out of forty thousand some comic stories rather, it was
ranked one thousand nine hundred and
one.
And those numbers don't mean too much on their own. So just for perspective, you know, you and I did hierarchical. That one had a rating seven point three.
And then
Ryan and I did the mommy's ring, which was a seven point six.
If you look at those stories kind of within all of the comics there compared to pirate gold was in the top.
Was rated higher than ninety eight point four
percent of all the stories. And mommy's ring was rated higher than nine nine point three percent. So that one's you know, very highly rated.
This one is is in the top ninety
fifth percentile or I guess the top fifth percentile. So you know, it's Barks.
So it's well regarded, but it's down definitely not rated as highly as those other ones.
As far as how it holds up, I did think it was really interesting
to
get to read this one and and really see a lot of
what was contemporary at that time, you know, see some of those things like the organ grinder
and the references to the world two planes and the casual corporal punishment.
So that that's Always interesting to see.
We talk about to appearances in other media. Obviously,
as is fitting for a comic that's, you know, not nearly one of his popular ones. This is one that's really been adapted.
It's been reprinted a few times, of course, not as much as some of the others.
Barb never did any of his oil paintings or lit graphs,
featuring this and my knowledge, there was nothing referencing this in any of the duct.
But I can't I can't think that there was. But as I mentioned, you know, Barks, this was the first of his pet stories, which he went back to a lot, and he did some great stories featuring those. Sure. I I like to talk about what there is know in terms of educational Al. Some of these stories have some interesting things that we might learn about history or mythology
or,
you know, geography,
i didn't really take anything too interesting to this one. You know, by nature, it's not one of the Barks sort of
travel log ones you know so it doesn't really have that gone. But again, I don't wanna dump on this one too much. It's still... Nice it's a Barks story, and it's still still very worth reading and and very worthwhile. Yes.
So Eric, do you have any other thoughts
regarding too many paths.
Well, like you're saying, like, this obviously, there's the rats or any
based off this book app up this story, and I had to
really agree him like obviously because there's not really any that scenery
those background white type of shots that he uses
whether it's the transitioning from, you know, from the ship to the sea. I did, you know, where the ship seen where we i to get on the ice higher gold.
But there were a couple and know just artistic that I I appreciate it and that is right there that picture you're looking at is Huey, use a couple of uses that I think once twice.
Is the shadow
of the person in the foreground shadow or the person that you reported that in the background is being color.
Just to give you that
emphasis what's going on in the scene.
I'm using them completely in shadow. He doesn't have to do that very
some pretty good
contracts. What's going on. Yeah. It's the scene. And then there's no on where dog is. You have what's like the window and installed and dark.
And the folks talking and the the emphasis the voice and the reaction, I think.
And it's just it's a very neat to see that
That's not stuff. That's generally do or used in a comic
for the kids audience.
Together two pounds I really enjoy.
What's what? When they're were all
boys working like... Okay. Gotta get the down oh god. Appreciate your question.
And they're all over the head and i'll hurt the row. That's all the same. And Gin is right there with the like he's one of the crew. Yeah. That was cool. That's perfectly.
Okay. What doing? She's in on there.
And and then
as I thought that very and then it's the scene where
jin is breaking the switch.
Oh, yeah. We're cracks.
He's very expressive, but our everything there's very much to the the pay. This is a monkey.
He recognizes what's going on.
She's not gonna do it.
And he's bad about it. Yeah. You're right about the expression on this face. And I'm mean
That was really good.
Yeah. Agreed.
And I'm I'm glad that you remembered I had asked for you to dimension your favorites panel, and I forgot to introduce that. But
that's funny because you you mentioned two of the ones that I had thought of which that that switch break can
scene definitely a panel definitely stuck out to me. But the long panel that is on, I think it's on page
nineteen or so, but the one where the nephews are waving by
to Jingle go, It shows them looking for lauren
gin waving back, Donald looking pleased over the the hedge.
That that one has... It's just a really cool
panel and really sums up, I think the story.
Yeah. And it kinda shows, you know, Donald kind of a bit of a villain, not not maybe a bad guy, but he's definitely not a great... He's not a very positive character in this one. And I think that's part of why I don't really care for this one compared a lot of them. And we see this more in some of the earlier ones where that's a little bit more of his
characterization. Yeah. So,
thank you very much. I I always like talking... I I love talking Du.
You know, I told ryan last week that it's so nice to get the chance to talk about these in real life because, you know, apart from you growing up, this was the thing that I was just hugely into.
But it always felt weird being, you know, a teenager who really likes Ducktales stories and I
couldn't really talk about much in real life. So I'm I'm gonna make.
I'm gonna make up for last time.
The next podcast that we do
is kind of getting back to the adventure mold and it is the story frozen gold,
which I haven't read in many years. So I'm excited.
To revisit that. I forgot to mention this episode and last that I looked up the upper value of this comic, you know, this can count for last steps episode two. So There was there's one documented sale of a nine point o condition, which would be like,
really near miss nice. Yeah. In in November of two thousand and eight, that sold for twenty thousand dollars. Lower range. You know, I assume most of them are one point o would be two hundred dollars. So Sure. This one's pretty highly valued because it's got two full length Barks stories hand a ten pager
and as... you know, but it's mainly valued of course for the money. Alright. Well, Eric, thank you again for joining me, and I look forward to having you back soon.
Yeah. My pleasure.