Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks the podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of sc Mid Ducktales and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and screw comics of all time. Join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological publishing order. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Alright. This is Barks Sever marino of Barks remarks. And thank you for joining us. I have a returning host,
Ryan Bailey, You wanna say hide to good people ryan Hello good people. This is Ryan. Your assignment
for this episode was reading the Donald Du story frozen
gold. I was really
excited to read this one because it had been a very long time. I'm gonna give you a little bit of an overview about this comic. We're are gonna be talking as mentioned about frozen gold. This is our fourth full length story
And this one was published. The
cover cover date is January nineteen forty five
and the secured in four color number sixty
two. It's twenty four pages long, and this story is one in which Donald N and nephews use get talked into
flying a life saving pen
to a remote Alaskan village
and then become embroiled in a a plot to find prospect
hidden cache of gold. Little more background. This is weirdly another comment four sixty two that had two full length Barks stories.
I did take a look at the value range. For this one, if you had the the highest
value would be like
near mint could be up to six thousand dollars today. And... That's I know during the like, World War two era comics,
pretty much everybody
didn't really know
how long a comic should be.
If you read some marvel or Dc from that era,
don't be surprised if it's sixty pages
for your nickel. I wanna make sure you get your nickel worth Exactly. And and this
this is... We haven't really talked too much about it, but this specific comic that these were being run for color. Was a really strange series, I think.
Western publishing or Dell, they put it out as like, a one shot thing. And it could've have been like Yogi bear one day, little fan annie, another day, you know, Disney comics, the next So it was very random. So I I think that that's why they did it. Right? Once they had... They knew that they were doing a Donald duck themed comic. They got whatever bark story they commissioned at that time in there.
Pretty quickly, these stories are gonna become popular enough that, you know, they're gonna
spin it off.
And they're gonna turn it into walt Disney's comics and stories.
Eventually,
provision Donald duck will both get their own series. But for for a while, this is it, this weird four color thing. So a little bit of background,
what was going on at this time in history.
You know, previously, I talked about how we were gonna spend some time
during World War two, and there wasn't any way of getting around that. But as it turns out, you know, this issue is is actually gonna be our last one
where the war is still going concern. So I was a little bit surprised when I saw that. It seems like we've sped through it, but it's just because these were only published every,
you know, one or two every year for a while. This month's saw Roosevelt
fourth
inauguration.
This was the month that George, H w and Barbara Bush got married.
We had Hitler's last public speech
and the birth of Actor Tom Sell,
kind of a huge hodgepodge of history there.
But the big historical context
and, you know, I I the the big sub in this one is had of.
Right? Because Pen panasonic was still a fairly new discovery.
At this point, it's gonna be a very important part of the story.
Do you know Ryan? How when kind of someone was discovered? I don't.
No. I don't.
Well, I certainly knew without looking at Wikipedia a couple nights ago.
It it was in nineteen
twenty eight.
And according to my
memory, not Wikipedia,
medical applications of it start in the early nineteen
thirties
and it didn't go into large scale production
until nineteen
forty.
And it it didn't become available, according pdf.
I mean,
my memory, it didn't become available to the general public until March of nineteen forty five.
So remind you of this this comic,
the cover date was January nineteen forty five. Technically, that means it was probably hit the stands in December
forty four. But we're we're actually literally a couple months out before it even became widely available, So
I find that really interesting that, you know, Barks was
incorporating
current events and this
incredible discovery into his comics.
So what what this brought to mind for me was the the famous
delivery of dip ethereum medicine
to know Alaska.
Are you familiar with that story of the sled dogs, ba and to?
No. Tell me about it. Okay. So
very famously, this was a huge story
in
the twenties.
There was a
a big deal shipment of life saving D ethereum medicine
to the remote
city of Known in Northern Alaska.
And you know, it captivated the nation at that point.
There was when we were
probably
middle school high school, there was a
animated movie made about it called Bolt.
I do remember that. Yeah. You remember it. And then last year on Disney Plus, the other sled dog who kinda lived in Ba shadow. Even though he was I think the lead dog
or the main dog to, they they came out with a live action movie, I immediately thought that this this story itself sounded like Barks
doing kind of Al homage to ba
delivery
of the Dip inferior anti Barks and
could couldn't help but think of that.
My impression of of this setting was
Barks want
a really different
by them for for this one then the last time we were in Egypt
and
lots of sand and mum
and he wanted to
contrast that with
the the snowy
Yukon.
Yeah.
You know, kind of the way Star wars has a different
climate on every planet, you know, just to Right differentiate your storytelling. You may be right. In fact, I I read an interview with Barks where he he talked about
wanting
to...
Before he started a story, he literally did what you're talking about. He sat down and thought. Now where do I want
to do a story about and oftentimes he would start from the setting. This one I read in in reference to the next story, which is set in the ever gl.
But,
yeah, I can imagine that he decided he wanted to
write about the north and,
you know, went from there. A little bit more context.
I like that the city that they're
delivering the
the medicine too is called point mer.
It's
direct parody of the city and alaska called point barr,
which has a pretty notable distinction. Do you know it by chance?
The most northern city in the United States. Look at that. Was that a good guess?
It was not. I I knew that as a geography geek as a little kid. And more interestingly, I when I was job hunting a few years ago,
Found an opening
at the Liaison office, I believe in Barks
and looked into a little bit. They're very proud to have the most the northern
American football field in the world,
which is all like sm blue Astro turf.
Because obviously, nothing alive could, you know, survive.
Right. The summers in be Alaska, And if you can even recall it that blue say you can see it through the the of Snow. I imagine.
Yes. That's a awesome bit of
an awesome fact there.
Let's see. The the people of the city and the people of Alaska of course are referred to
as es,
es is an outdated term. We don't really use that.
The that area, we would probably be looking at any tribes or
depending
but and we'll talk about the depiction. I I actually like the depiction of the city quite a bit and the people in it.
Notable appearances in this one. We had the return of a peg leg heat lookalike named foxy p.
And no no real other maiden name characters a couple of silly one offs like Yukon Joe.
Yeah.
I can say...
Sitting down to read a carl Barks comic called frozen Gold. I can tell for sure going to have tons of uncle sc in it.
I...
I'm wearing my top hat, the listeners can't tell, but I'm in a coat with tails.
An excitement in anticipation
of all the uncle sc we're going to get in this comic.
Now we'll
obviously
beginning to uncle Scrooge at some point, but
I can't remember exactly how many, but literally hasn't been created yet. He doesn't exist at this time.
So anyway, without further ado,
the beginning of the story
has Donald in the nephews
shoveling
snow
in the city and being disgusted by it. Donald is grip about how much he hates shoveling the snow,
and the nephews look longing at a plane that appears to be right across
from where they're shoveling the walk.
They they consider that if they had a plane, they could go south
and escaped the winter.
And Donald
sc Al that and he says, you know, how could I get a plane like that? I have to trade my house for it.
And then you just kinda see Donald thought process as that goes from a crazy idea to why not? I'm gonna go ahead and trade my
plane
for that my house for that plain
And so we cut... We cut fifteen minutes later, and Donald is
signing the contract with a very dis looking pilot who's agreed to his terms.
This frame fa me. There's a lot happening here.
For one thing, the pilot refers to him as mister Ducktales.
So we learned that Duck is in fact Donald Ducktales
legal surname
Yeah, which I I
found surprising that it it is not merely descriptive. It's like finding out that Andre the giant's last name is the giant.
Yeah.
Again, if you're if you're a Barks fan. This is just kinda one of those background facts of life, so I like hearing
that that takes you a back.
Any other comments on that panel?
It's hard to tell from the context,
which one of them is being sucker
because
I would think a plane is worth much more then... I mean, the house is worth much more than a little, you know, four person kinda assessment looking plane like this. Right.
But he thought it would be a fool... So would be a fool to take my house
in exchange for that beautiful plane.
Oh I I definitely
I definitely read it as
Donald putting himself over a barrel.
You know, letting himself be taken advantage of because he hates the snow.
I know also trades the house and four used snow shovel, that the ones that he and his nephews were using just now. Yeah. And Glad you mention that because... Because I almost forgot about that. And I think that's just such a great gag. You know, getting that little dig in how much he hates.
That he obviously
specify
that
instead of specifying, you know, the lawn mower that shirley comes with the house.
So that that was a nice touch.
And obviously, this is just one of those moments where this is etch sketched away in in the next one. There's no continuity with this. It's it's in service of the story, but
you know, it... It pretty efficiently
gets us where we need to go.
So don boys
get ready
to use their plane and head south. And Donald is just preparing to remove the skis because this... I didn't mention this is a sku plane right now.
And
mayor fizz budget
tells him to hold on he approaches him saying that you've got the only ski playing available in town. And he's come to
donald
to to undertake a very dangerous
mission,
which Donald immediately
declines.
But the mayor explains that he has the opportunity to be a hero who can save a village full of people from what he calls a fright Scrooge.
And he explains, Donald is
hearing it and he explains that Donald would be tasked with flying a cargo of Pen.
He says to the stricken natives of
and donald butts in before he can finish because obviously, Donald has heard the word natives.
And he's had the association that most Americans at that time, they're imagining
a brass
t
roof hut. In the tropics. Right? And so he
he agrees and asks, oh Am I going to Mexico
and the mayor reveals no. It's little further north. He needs to go to a place called point marrow in Alaska.
Yeah. Yeah.
I think the kids can learn from this issue not to start out your your appeal with
very dangerous.
Yeah. That's the first thing he throws out.
Gonna convince this duck
by letting him know how dangerous it is.
That's right. And and they can also learn to
to to let let your
conversational partner finish their sentence before you.
Before you agree,
I also say before I move on that the panel
before they get ready for the flight is one of the great wins
of all time as Donald was just
shutter with rev know where he's agreed to. So then we transitioned
to Donald
Donald has come to enjoy the attention that he's getting. He's str around town in front of newspapers,
describing him as a hero.
While he's doing that, we've got a couple of sinister figures in the background
discussing the Ducktales their mission and they have the opportunity
to hide a package
behind the seats of the plane.
The the figures then go to a telegraph office.
And
they send a message that reads pete fox,
Point Mer, Alaska, it is coming on Pen
plain
And I wish I looked up how much each word of a telegraph
cost at this time.
So we we transitioned them to Donald The who's getting ready to
go to sleep, I imagine the last night in their house or or maybe the first night in a hotel. I don't know. We don't really learn about that.
The nephews have a feeling of fore voting,
and Donald says
don't don't worry about it. Just go to sleep.
And the next morning,
they take off
cheered by by a crowd. So I was I was impressed at this point in the comic after having seen Donald
exceptional nautical skills
in the last couple of issues.
To find that he already knows how to fly a key playing and then, of course, later in the comic we discover. He's not the only one, who knows, specialized his plane. His the small children that he takes care of can also apply to display. That's right. And they haven't even joined the junior witch. At this point. So they don't have the guide book available or anything.
Yeah. There's there's never really any conversation. Barks doesn't go to, you know, any lines to say, you know, how I learned to fly the plane in the war such as such? It just... He knows how to fly. So
we get one panel before they are somewhere in Canada,
and their wings start icing up and, you know, this is escalating pretty quick. They have to toss out everything.
All of their emergency rations, their suitcases, which they call Al,
know I've heard the word Val before, but I don't think I've
ever heard it except, like, someone trying to sound fancy or old time. Yeah. It seems like
like a black and white carry grant kind of thing.
So the only thing that they
hold on to, of course is the Pen
and one parachute, which will definitely come in handy you later. They even throw the seats,
which seems to stabilize the plane and that enables them to discover that that contra
package behind the seat.
So Donald is is really efficient here and I think in this sequence. He
decides that it's too late to be a bomb and tells them that they'll throw it out if it's nothing valuable
they see that it's a metal lock box,
and it's labeled as the property of Cli
gel.
Yeah. It's interesting.
And from this point in the comic the ducks kind of act like... They already know Al Joe from back home.
Yeah. He's clearly
in this in this story, at least, he's
someone that's well known.
Because Donald explains
he's that queer prospect
that lives... Oh, he says he lives on our street.
And there's a rumor around Warmer street. But... Oh, yes. That's our former street.
And there's a a rumor that he has a million bucks in gold buried somewhere in Alaska,
which, you know, it must be like three and a half billion today. Yeah. That's true. That's an insane amount of money in nineteen forty five.
You think that really is probably like three to five
million I'm guessing. I don't know. I'll look up inflation sometimes. I know that the comic that we're reading costs a dime.
So nice I think you mentioned
the the last step so that we were on that there was some really good, like, efficient storytelling
some point where they're kind of,
you know, what happened with the the mummy and the kidnapping back in the mum ring. And I feel like it's very efficient here that the characters don't spin their wheels.
Donald
says
he he assumes that it's full of legal papers
and he suppose that some thief, you know, hit it
trying to avoid being caught. And I like this because it seems like a pretty reasonable guess and it's actually not that far off from what really happened. And I I feel like characters are sometimes kind of will fully stupid, especially
in media from from this long ago. So they continue their plain ride word we see them flying past the background that seems to have the Aurora
depicted.
And when they arrived, they approach a large circle in the snow and then Nephew who's very acutely asked if that's the arctic circle.
And he explains no That's
a guide so that we can land safely.
And, you know, I definitely
remember thinking to myself. Oh, the arctic could circle. I think I've heard of that. And for a little while after reading this, I did have an idea that something you could see from the air.
And then they soon realized that
village is actually buried under the snow and a very happy looking
person bursts out of the snow and welcomes them to point marrow. Yeah. I like the... I like the visuals. When I
read this to some actual kids,
they did not know what the Aurora was, and
I think they might not have known what the Arctic circle was. So yeah, lots of education happening here. Yeah. I I definitely learned a lot about the north and the From reading the Barks stories.
Little inter, this is the first of at least
three arctic set stories.
All of which are very well remembered and regarded. He seems to really like like this as a setting. So, again, we get some very efficient storytelling
there's never really anything made about them taking the... The medicine. They just referenced it being delivered.
And then they get to stay overnight in the towns big hotel called the Northern Lights Hotel. And
on the way, the Nephews point out a roaring sounds the village
cautions them that they need to grab one of the many stakes that are sticking out of the ground and hold on tight because it's a blizzard that's approaching, and they're not gonna make to the hotel. So
the Ducktales
endure several minutes of blizzard blowing, and then we see
that the
short posts that they've been holding on
are actually the top of some posts that look to be about twenty feet tall, more than two stories tall. And the blizzard has blown off the top layer of snow that's
hiding
buildings, which
all of which are at least two stories tall. Every good storyteller knows it's important to have really big stakes early on for your characters.
Oh, man. You were a... You were whole mom of that. That was awesome.
So the ducks have to climb a ladder up into the lobby. They're exhausted, so they get ready for Bed.
And I have to say I really liked the mechanics of this town
that's just constantly hit by blizzard
and and, you know, going from shallow and deep as a kid. I loved. I I definitely imagined what that might feel like. You know, thinking back. I feel like
there was more of this in the story, but maybe it just stuck with me that well. I also think it's interesting that at the beginning of the story, it looks like the story is about
delivering pen to this village.
And that part is over. That story is over now on.
Yeah. A few pages in delivered the Pen and everyone has been saved from the from the awful scourge
and
I I feel like a lot of other storyteller would have
had a bunch of hazards and they're trying so hard to get to this place, but they've run into bears and now they've run into,
you know, and anything else, any other number of peril on the way to try and try and get this important to mc to its location,
but that's not how they do it here.
Yeah. I I definitely agree. It's it's kind of unusual that the the big thing that drives the story is really just what gets it started.
So
while Donald, M and f you go to sleep, we see a couple of sinister looking figures skull around the plane, and we get a look at the guy who must be pete to fox
and he realizes quickly
that the package she's looking for is that there
surmise that it must be with the ducks. And so he goes to the hotels.
He goes to switch their room. Because he talks in in the best kind of goo speak.
All of the... People probably they learned that in Pitt boy. Yeah. Exactly.
Definitely made to be right aloud.
So he's ran their room while they sleep. He's not being very careful at all because he wakes up Donald.
Who
confronts him and
this version of pete,
silence is donald and brings him out
to
to his accomplish.
And so
the the guy's, like, why'd did you bring that
that done duck? And
he explains that, you know, he saw me so we've got get rid of him. And the... His his accomplished just pulls out a knife
ready to slit this throat right there.
Again, I I love the the pal
danger that
comments from this era
put characters like Donald and Mickey
and someone and... Yeah. I thought that frame in particular was pretty dark. He's just got the knife out and it's
just ready to ready to get him like a fish.
Yeah. And
so
pete is
he explains no, you know, the the constable... We don't want the cons to trace the crime to us. So his plan is to turn him loose to to toy them loose
about thirty miles out of town,
and the cold is gonna be kills him. And so they load him on a sled. And
while he's when they get out of town, they open
the
the lock
and they have found
con Joe's mapped to his gold claim. And they quickly referenced that, oh, the gold cash is buried under under the tail,
which is why no one's found it. Is that like where where the the gold s, like, lets the dirt that you've already pan out? Do you remember that?
Yeah. It's it's basically the the worthless leftovers
the garbage and and junk. So it'll it'll have other kinds of rocks and worthless metals and whatever toxins you use.
Right. To lead, you know,
dissolve the the dirt or whatever. Yeah. Hide it under the tailing. That's that's
what to do.
Also,
speaking of a million dollars in gold, the internet says that's worth about fourteen point seven mil today. Nice.
Even Al like today's crazy price of gold, it's like a mountain of gold. That's like...
Alright. So they're mush on their way on dogs sled
towards the gold until they come to a plain that has a lone tree. Which is what they tie him to.
And
Donald is thinking to himself, oh, you know, he he really hasn't tied these ropes very well.
This this version of Pete
definitely foxy. He's he's like, yeah, that's what I want you to do. I want you to get loose, and I want you to die of exposure
And so he leaves
Donald
to to the cold.
And Donald is
starting to get
starting to remove the ropes when the telltale roar of another blizzard comes up
And Donald despair that it's gonna erase pete's tracks, so he can't track him down.
He has also gotten turned around this tree so much and the course, of the lizard and trying to get loose that he's not confident about which way to go.
So he sets off and
we the reader can immediately see that he's gone the wrong way.
And he's plotting on for miles
when he realizes that he's come to a cr that he doesn't
recognize
and needs to turn around,
but then
the little ice bridge over the Cr
collapses sending him down
So he's down down in this chasm, and another blizzard comes up and
he gets buried
deep in the cr
and manages
to
emerge from the snow
But at this point, he doesn't see his train. He doesn't see the hills.
And he comments that everything looks kinda of misty.
And
he he gets off a good one before he takes off that, you know, at least he's not lost. He knows he's still somewhere in Al last,
which great line, technically true. Yes.
So we get a kind of a meanwhile at this point, the nephews user are may waking up in the hotel, and they realize that their uncle
is gone.
And
so is the box So they immediately
know that something's gone wrong and they need the police.
So they they go to see the
hotel clerk
and say that their uncle uncles been kidnapped.
You know, the town is
responsive. They send out a bunch of sled dog teams.
To to comb the snow
and
the nephew like, well, we've got a plane, you know, let's go ahead and take that
to find
And
before they can take off the constable
correctly points out. You're you're just little boys. You can't go off and fly the plane, and he locks them in their hotel room for their own good.
I'm glad there's a responsible delta around.
Trying and save these small boys.
And so we cut back to Donald when they've been locked in.
And
we we learned that
Donald has become snow blind
he doesn't realize this. He just thinks it's gotten dark, but he's
he's walking and broad daylight his eyes wide open and holding out his hands.
I I always
knew of snow blindness is like the sun bouncing off the snow. Right? Yeah. That's how I think it. That was probably the cause. Yeah. It also provides a good framework for some
mister style hi.
Yeah. And I really like the sequence here. Do you wanna describe this sequence for us?
He's glad that there are no lakes or things to fall into as he approaches is
some kind of f full of arctic water surrounded by puff.
He can hear the ice crunching together,
but the ice flows happen to close up just before he falls into the water, and he walks on to the next flow. And then as he's about to step off another ice flow into the ocean,
he steps onto a walrus that leads him another wall rest that leads into another ice flow
and he can he can hear something breathing
as he surrounded by Walrus.
But he knows that it it's nice to know that there's no animals that live in these latitude. Nothing could live.
Way up here where it's so cold.
Right. And I like here is description of this is like a mister Mi negotiate sequence. That's that's pretty that's exactly what it is.
And it's a nice, like,
Scrooge ball moment, but i I think it's also just a fun
sequence where Barks got to try try out a little bit of different art we're throwing some wild life throwing some very brain. And then we're gonna cut back to the kids that are escaping from the hotel out the back. And
while they warm up the plane they acknowledge that they don't have a lot of gas in the tank and they don't have the time to fill it. And I found that very stressful.
A small plain with limited gas and the frozen wastes. Yeah. They had to... They cut the sn ropes because they don't have time to warm up the motor.
And I assume that any experience world War two pilot perfectly understands what that what those sentences mean.
I do not. Yeah.
So we cut back to Donald, who is still blu his way through the arctic wastes,
and he bumps into an
and calls out to whoever might be inside.
And
oh he's not getting any answer, so he goes on in, and
There is an oc,
but clearly, the igloo has been abandoned because it is
occupied by a bear
Donald
is just having a conversation with the oc.
And we see the bear it's really ferocious looking.
And
Donald launches into
what he thinks his friendly chatter
that, you know, through the lens of time, comes off as as pretty patronizing. Because he thinks this is
some, you know, es he says. And when he feels wet what's really the bear. He's talking about. Oh, you're nice for a code. That that would cost you two hundred bucks in Salt lake city. I'll give you five dollars for it right here.
So the bear
gives him a good smack. Donald is okay, but he realizes he's gotta get out of there. He surmise that it's an es dog,
and
he runs knowing that he's being pursued.
And we can see him being chased by a bear, while the nephews
have
they're in the plane and they've located that tree that familiar tree. So they've decided to use that for a mark and they are gonna circle
wider and wider, but they've only got enough gas to do that for twenty minutes.
After ten minutes of this, they see
a lot of walrus
and they see that deserted old igloo gluten. And when they fly closer for a better look, they notice
tracks in the snow. Yeah. I have to say when they said they only have enough gas for twenty minutes. I thought how far how far are they from the village?
Many minutes do they need to save to be able to fly all the way back to
to the Northern Lights hotel and some safety?
Yeah. Everything about their rescue is very stressful.
So
they they've noticed that it's their uncle uncles tracks. Because they're they're fine pretty low. They can see the Barks tracks as well.
And, you know, as they approach him, their trying to figure out how can they save their uncle
And this is where that single parachute
was gonna come in handy. Because they they're able to secure it to a harness.
And
as Donald approaches
the edge of a cliff that he doesn't realize he's there. He can hear the airplane.
He ends up falling off the cliff, and the nephews are able to capture him in that parachute.
This would have been a great thing to see animated. I think. It would have. Yeah. They've got the... They've got some kind of toe cable behind the plane and they have the the parachute tied to it and just catch them like a catcher or.
Right? And like the expression on the on the bear as it Scrooge to a halt of the cliff edge. So the nephews call him in and And that's where they figure out
because Donald wonders how they found him in the dark. And and that's where they figured out that he's gone snow blind.
So they tend to them. I don't I don't know what they're gonna use in their first aid kits, but they they do whatever they can for him.
And
they're forced to land even though they're not near point narrow because they have a course run out of gas they they've noticed that there's a cabin beyond the ridge. So that that's what they're trying to reach. And fortunately for them, there seems to be a nice roaring fire. They're smoke coming from the chimney, so they're gonna approach that cabin and they they explain what a lucky brain. I like if he has
some
some classic blind guys sunglasses on at this point to signal to everybody that he's blind.
So
just they're luck it ends up being foxy pete who greet them with drawn guns.
And Donald, even though he can't see him. He immediately
recognizes
his voice. He holds them at gunpoint and takes them into the cabin where they can see the Barks of gold that these these guys have already done that Jo.
So he directs them into a back room
and they are listening into to what they plan to do. The hen is like, you're not gonna tweet and loose again.
But he explains no once we get the bold put in sa, we're gonna burn down the shack. We're gonna avoid it down with them in it. And, you know, they're in a really rough spot they're they're nervous about what's gonna happen. The window is boarded up from the outside.
There doesn't seem to be anything.
But that Louie
takes a look at the chimney.
The the nephews figure that they can fit through this very small flu, they take out... Take off their coats.
And so we cut to them emerging
covered in soot.
I I really liked that, you know, he he showed them as they would have come out, they didn't come out all clean. They're able to open the window and let mcdonald out and bring them their they find in in inc Joe's claim tunnel. They find a bunch of really useful items
including a barrel of gasoline as well as a bunch of cables motor. And that must have been Donald figures that was probably left by some other gang, some other acclaimed jumpers.
And he's got an idea. He directs and nephews used to gas up the plane and he's gonna be busy doing something with the cable. Yeah. I like that
Like the last comic we read the the curse of the mum ring, Donald and the and the Nephews had to say Huey,. And in this one, the nephews have un
save donald bacon.
Yeah. If they had stayed,
stayed back in Duck,
and he had just come to do this mission by himself, He would've have stayed in the hotel.
The guy would have carried him off somewhere.
He would have died in the wilderness probably falling off that cliff. Right.
Yeah.
If you hadn't anyone... you know, these would have killed them. Yeah.
So Donald plan, I've gotta say this is Awesome time it's genius and its simplicity.
He he just wraps the whole cabin
in the cable
multiple times like thread on a spool. He says,
And somehow he manages just to tie nice neat, ball on the roof.
And
he he things to himself. Boy, I wish I could see it. I bet it looks really pretty. And, you know what Donald, it does. It looks great. I love this scene.
So the the two robbers, the two thugs
have finished packing their gold and Pete is about to glow but when he opens the door he realizes that they're gone, and he makes to to just run out that door and there's a a great panel where he he bounces off the cables that have and his hen
notices the sound of an airplane
and
Pete
realizes that their whole cabin is moving. And and we cut to a great panel
where
donald in the boys have taken off in the plane and they are just towing the whole cabin along behind them. Yeah. I have to say this is not...
This is not a pro profile was all already familiar with.
The
wrap up the cabin in cables and then it behind your a small plane. I was very surprised at this whole age. Yeah. It was great. It made for an awesome visual.
I thought it was hilarious when he bounced back.
Out of his door, because you could totally imagine him, That's not what anyone's expecting. Yeah. And also they could have they could have made their escape as soon as they get out of the chimney and found the gasoline, but instead they were like, no. We can we can deliver these criminals to justice.
Yeah. It's it's a two for. Again, just like with the delivery of the, we don't see the crux get delivered to justice. It's just kinda referenced off panel.
They kinda na the Donald eyes have gotten better
and they are on the... They're on the plane
flying back home
where they're greeted to a hero's welcome.
The two people that are closest to them are the mayor.
And
Con Joe himself, the mayor is delivering,
presenting him the key to the city.
And Donald thinks and he's like, okay, but I don't have time for that. We're about to fly south as soon as cal jug gets his gold.
And Quan died Joe a really goofy feel looking fella.
He steps up and he tells the crowd that he's been so inspired their hero
that he wants to do something good with his fortunate gold. And he says he's gonna spend the whole million
for more panasonic for these brave boys to fly to more sick es.
And the last panel of the story,
the mayor is commenting that
what's happened to the ducks, they've fainted dead away. So a nice a nice little gag ending to wrap it up
as they clearly are not gonna get to go south any anytime soon. It's a tough tough life for heroes. You know, who knows what they would even want to go home too? I guess they just wanna go somewhere warmer down to.
Contact Joe also looks like a a fantastic stereotype of a g old prospect.
He and he's got this kind of wild white beard and buck teeth and kind of round hunters cap on.
I also have to say
by this point,
I was anticipating another
the ducks go home with untold riches
ending,
like we got in the last couple issues. Right. Because I felt like they were leading up to it. We've got a million dollars of gold on the plane with the ducks.
They come home.
Contact Joe happens to be standing there. That oh okay. They're... You know, they're gonna give it back to Al Joe. That's nice. But maybe he'll be like, hey as a reward, you guys get half of it
have gold new house and new snow shovel to replace the things you traded away for this plane. But
no. He's he's even more of a hero than that. He's gonna
gonna buy fourteen point seven million dollars worth of pen and
save even more people. That's right. Although in my wikipedia reading, apparently, you needed just huge
huge amounts of Al. Like, it it really was a miracle
and it helped people
phenomenally. But until they they
mastered the mass production, it was it was so valuable
and important that they would harvest
patients urine
so that they could recover as much of it as possible. So I hope the second hand pen still was cheaper than the
in the first pass.
Yeah. That that was
the
generic what they sold.
Yeah. Yeah. That's the cheaper cheaper version. Alright. So
that is frozen gold.
I wanna talk about some reflections and how
how well this one is regarded And so I mentioned to you last time we met that
I'm I'm gonna talk about the ratings on the aggregation site
index, which
averages
user ratings for all of the Disney comics. So really, it's the best kind of measure of, you know, how
how these are regarded by fans.
This one has an index rating of seven point six.
That would rank it as number two hundred and fifty four out of over forty thousand
stories
overall, which puts it in the ninety nine point four
per percentile,
Just a tiny bit higher than the mum ring. We'll find that most of these Barks stories are clustered pretty close together. So it's more like ranking the Barks stories
against each other. The lowest one that we've had is the one I did last time with Eric called too many pets, which is not a very... I mean, it's a Barks story. So it's fine. But that's that's probably for a while at least, that's probably gonna be
kind of our baseline
for his lowest regarded story. That's still on the ninety fifth
percentile.
I guess it would be the fifth percentile, but higher than ninety five percent of all the Disney comic stories.
So so again, you know, this one is our our highest rated so far, but only a little bit more than mommy's ring.
I mentioned that it had been a long time since I read this one. So, you know, I definitely remembered it because I read all the time as a kid.
But I had so much distance from it. Was a real joy to go back and read this one and remember the different story beats.
And,
you know, I probably hadn't read it since I was a teenager. So I I loved reading this. I loved the
Again, the danger,
the
setting I thought was really great. I definitely liked the city I thought that the way the snow level changed was kinda reminiscent of almost a video game level. You know, I like to imagine and I like to think about that. So This one was a real winner for me, and
I
I had a lot of fun reading it.
What did you think about it? This one Ryan? I liked it Al lot. I think I also would have ranked it higher than the mommy's ring. Was a good a kind of a simple story, but still like a really harrowing
survival kind of element to it of
man versus nature or duck versus nature and then duck versus also some
goo.
Excellent.
The impression I got, I I didn't see a lot of articles about this one.
Many of these stories have have a lot written about them. I didn't see too much. But my impression is that this one is is regarded as you would expect based on that rating. You know, it's an early Barks story. So it's showcasing what is style, you know, what what the format is adventure stories are gonna be. But it is
very well regarded.
Classic Barks.
I think that this one holds up
generally really well, you know, we've definitely got and stuff that's pretty dated
some archaic treatments of the es,
rather i,
you know, the way that Donald talks to anything
his
is
kinda cringey,
but he does... He doesn't... He does say, hey, es, as he's coming around the side of of the igloo. He knows what what all of their names start. They're always asking. Yeah. But...
Yeah. And and he does he does actually say the line. Oh maybe maybe he's not used to white men. No doubt he's cow in terror. So that's definitely very
but on the whole, I think I think Barks depiction of
point barr as an na village was a very nice treatment of it. You know, they they didn't look very
native
quotes.
It looks like
modern for the time
connected to the world as much they could be. True. I I also
give Barks credit for the fact that
there was not an person cow and terror in the igloo.
Yes. That Al as Donald was walking in there and
saying idiotic things, he was also clearly being an actual idiot.
Just,
you know, trying to buy the fur coat off of the gigantic bear that's in in there with him and and everything. It it was not... He was not the hero in that see. Right. Right. And that's a good point. As far as appearances
in other media or other
our work. This is not a story that Barks he didn't do any of his famous oil paintings for this one. So I don't get to share one of those with you. This one to my knowledge has never been referenced
or kind of featured in either the Ducktales series.
Identifying this one. A very educational. I think this one's the most... The the one that I learned the most. Like, I I can remember
learning a lot when I was a kid from the specific story. So this this gave me some interest in, you know, arctic life and
some terms
for surrounding the the arctic north. Ryan did you
have a favorite panel that came to mind or any any panels that are kind of contenders for your favor?
Although go with the one I mentioned at the beginning with the fifteen minutes later,
so mister Duck, you're ready to trade your house and lot for four use snow shovel in my airplane.
Yeah. That's a good good signing the papers. That's how long it takes to to sell a house in Duck
in nineteen forty five.
Excellent.
So my favorite panel, There were a couple that I was considering. I I mentioned the one where he's str at the beginning in front of all the newspaper headlines.
But I think my favorite had to be
cabin... The plane hauling the cabin
sequence.
The the one where they're they're towing the cabin behind is great.
The one where pete
slams into the
the cables.
And then the other one, you know what? I'll I'll say that my favorite panel is the parachute catch when he jumps off the cliff and the Nephews
grab from the of the bear. And yeah. It spans across the whole page. You can really see like the motion of the plane as it goes up and then down
swoop down to kind of make the make the catch and then bring back up so that it doesn't land and you can see the baffles
bear.
Up on the cliff, watching watching them pull this off. It's a good it's a good good shot. Yeah. And and then the little bulge of Donald in the parachute
any final thoughts for frozen gold? No. I I think it's cool. Like where it's going. I like that it surprises me a couple times. Awesome.
Well, thank you for thank you again for coming back and join about comment up with me.
I'm looking forward
to the next
podcast
because this is one of my my favorites.
one of the earliest ones I read. I hope you'll join us as we go over mystery of the swan. As always, if you have any thoughts or comments, you know, if if there's something that you really wish we had talked about, and we neglected to please drop us line at Barks remarks at g dot com. And we'll see you next time.