we
Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks, the podcast. Where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks, creator of sc Mc and writer and artist of the greatest Don and Scrooge comics of all time. Join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing order. Hello. I am Barks Sever, a grown man who enjoys Donald Duck comics,
and I am joined by my guess another grown man who gets to take the role of Carl Barks newbie. Hello, i'm Ryan Bailey. Excellent. Welcome back. You haven't been scared off? Not yet. I was telling you beforehand that I'm super excited for this
story that we're doing today. Comment is called the mystery of the swamp. And this one is a personal favorite of mine.
It is kind of a bonkers story. Yes. I would I would agree with that. Al little bit of background
about this story and mystery of the swamp. Was published. It had a release date of January nineteen forty five. This one appeared in four color number sixty two, which is the same comic that you and I were doing last episode
because this was the b comment that came after frozen gold. This is something that is very rare. We won't get a lot of comments that release two full lengths stories. So this was all in one... This would have been one issue that someone bought at the new stand. Yeah. Exactly. Gottfredson
gold.
That one had cover art for it.
And then mystery of the swamp never didn't have its own cover art originally. Any any cover are would have been done later on.
So this Al that's a lot of comic for your Nickel. Yes. Yeah. Exactly.
I think it was a dime at that point. You know inflation. Yeah. This one is twenty four pages in length
about average for bark. And
this is the first
of what's gonna be many stories where
Donald and the other Ducktales
encounter
a hidden
civilization
of lost creatures, basically.
So this one is is kind of gonna set templates. For
several stories, many of which are
beloved by fans and and very famous.
So synopsis of this one. This takes place in the ever glad, Donald from the nephews. They're gonna explore the blades
and encounter a
strange race, Al little creatures called the measles.
When you read this one ryan, were you pronouncing it to yourself as the measles or the?
I I
had the G silent.
Al
like, a new
right. Right. So when I was... When I read this for the first time in nineteen eighty seven,
I definitely pronounced it
in my head as the,
but, you know, Have come to realize that, yeah, it's it's gotta be silent.
I mentioned that this one is personal one for me. This is one of the first, probably half a dozen comics I have around,
one of the very first Barks stories
that I ever read. I I read this one over and over. This one really wedded my interest in these
this template story. And a little bit a little bit of trivia about this, but it kinda sets that template. This is also
an example of something that Karl Marx did on occasion
where he would repeat a story that he did, he would basically
rewrite it and use the same story beats in a different tail. And so Al little more than a decade later he is gonna do another story that's very familiar called land of the P Indians.
That one's probably
better regarded. He definitely did it kind of with different eyes in a different attitude.
But this one does hold a special place in my heart. Some of the other ones that kind of fit this
same template where they, you know, bum into a lost civilization, the very famous plane awful will story
lost in the andy land beneath the ground, probably a few more that I can't remember. So last time, I remember that you had mentioned
you mentioned something about the setting and how important how it seemed like Carl Marx really wanted an excuse to
set a story
somewhere and and just explore the setting and I like that. Because... Because I think that's definitely the case. You know, and this one, you can tell you really really wants to
draw the ever Gladstone really wants to explore the ever gl,
and they're very central to this story. Yeah. Definitely.
Yeah. The setting is a lot like frozen gold. It's a big part of what's going on. Right. You can tell because he really goes into a lot of detail with the art. And, you know, it's still a very cartoony, but it also looks like it has a lot of
more realistic
details. He didn't just draw what you felt like we're good swamp plans. I could tell that he was drawing from from a source.
I think that it helps to kind of treat the setting as almost an additional character in these.
And the ever Gladstone
me, this is, like where I learned about the ever glad for the first time. So I always viewed it as this imp
mysterious swamp. And it was kind of a bummer later on to learn that,
you know, the everett blades is a fragile
ecosystem that being over developed constantly.
But a little bit about the place itself, this is the Wikipedia rabbit Al all that I went It is the largest sub tropical wilderness in the United States.
Contra Barks has depicted.
Today, you can view large portions of it on webcam.
It's being over developed constantly.
And I I found this interesting. The that blades themselves have never really been in avid,
but a lot of tribes
historically lived around them and canoe through them constantly.
So
it is interesting to think that it's
un lived if not une explored. And then Po say, dale leon
was mentioned in this story,
he did not really go
deep into the ever
from what I can tell, but, of course, he was in that area.
And did look for the the fable fountain of use.
I also really liked learning that apparently, there's a ghost town within the Ever
called the lost city that throughout history was used either by native Americans
and or apparently Al capo
used it for a time is like the hideout out.
Notable appearances in this one, of course, are gonna be the measles themselves.
And then I don't I didn't know whether to count old nasty face. Since he's not really sanctioned, but but I'll mention him anyway. Nasty face, of course, also spelled with the silent g at the front. Yeah. I should've kept track of all the
all the different Gm words in this.
In and researching this one, I did find that Barks base this one off of... you know, he was inspired by no,
so that's why where the si g comes from. But I just I love that. That expectation.
And
it made it really fun to read every time the measles are speaking. But, yeah, let's let's get into the story itself. This
story
starts out with donald M and nephews.
On vacation
in in Southern Florida. You know, maybe this is the nice
warm vacation that they kept mentioning. They wanted to go to at the during during frozen gold.
I finally took their plan somewhere warm. Yeah. Exactly
So they're they're just fishing on a pier, but Donald is bored. And he
explains that he's planning to be he he's planning for adventure, he'd like to be in explorer, like the old time sailors.
And the nephews point out that there is nothing left to discover everything's been explored.
And, you know, Donald despair that and they're overheard by another fisherman on the dock.
And he motions
at the ever blades, and he says that, you know, there's thousands of
undiscovered
miles waiting to be discovered,
full of strange sites right here in our backyard and the ever blades.
Donald is is skeptical.
But,
you know, this to me is really interesting because
around this time, I think it's it's right at the end of when you could cr say that there's still these, like, undiscovered traps of the earth. You know, today, we have Google Maps, and we have satellites. And we pretty much know what's out there. But all this stuff was really in its infancy. So, like, I feel like these stories were more plausible and this is just
such a throwback to that sense of of discovery. That's why Indiana Jones movies to be set during this period instead of twenty twenty one. Yeah. Exactly. This this is the this is the age of adventure.
So
the Nephews
they mentioned that the ever place is the creep
swamp in the world. I've seen enough photos that I don't think it really looks that creepy,
but I'll give it to him. And the the fisherman eggs them on and he Donald says, sure. We'll do it. So they visit a thinly unveiled Macy's department store called Macy's in the comment, and
I'm Al un
wants to spring for the nicest camping gear.
And so they outfit themselves for this Ever adventure
And as they past the fishermen,
Donald again is really skeptical. He says, hey, I don't expect to see anything
impressive it Al all.
One thing I noticed on this page was
Donald Barks into and says, here, Clerk, outfit is for a comfortable tour of some sleepy lagoon.
But if you look even closer,
you can see the voice bubble is actually coming from the clerk. Yeah. It's just an error the nobody caught? Yeah. And I definitely caught that at age seven and it always weird me out and confused me. So...
Yeah. I'll have to look at the later re reprint and see if that's something they ever fixed. But, you know, I know there's a lot of, like, lettering errors and stuff that that never get corrected. And so I said suppose at some point it's like
fossil and you don't wanna fix some of these errors? Yeah. It's part of the part of the artifact.
So Barks transitions them right into the swamp. He doesn't even, you know, spend any time on their first day, which I think gives you an idea
of of what he's going for that they don't see anything interesting and they're just settling in for the night. They're they've taken up on one of those little islands
sitting little implants Barks. Yeah. And I I found this really appealing as a kid. You know, There's something about the idea of what your own tiny little personal islands that feels almost like a playground or something. So that was an aspect of the story I like. The idea this tent set up on this
island that doesn't look like it's more than a few hundred feet across. And so they're they're really enjoying themselves. This is more like a john t vacation
And
as they put out the Fire and get ready for bed,
the Nephews comment on the need to lock up their camping gear, Donald slide now. We don't need to worry about that. We're way out here. There's no thieves.
Oh, I didn't mention that the nephews use comments
that they are deeper at this point in the swamp than any other person has ever been. So that added to me to the to the sense of fore.
The next morning, they wake up and they find out that their camp is almost completely bare. Everything
that they've set up has been stolen and all they out left is the tent and the boat. When Donald comes out with a shotgun to look around
by the time they turned back, their tent has also been mysteriously stolen. So this one is is setting it up really quickly that something mysterious is going on,
and
it's gonna get kind of progressively
more creepy and weird. Yeah.
It's interesting. There were no footprints either.
Yeah. Is like what sand?
Yeah. The nephews do comment.
So on the next page, they are searching on their little island for the thief. There's some really cool scenery some nice artwork
swamp plans. And an alligator.
They come back to their camp and they haven't found any sign of
anyone. But by the time they come back, they're sleeping bags are now missing as well.
Donald is
getting frustrated characters simply angry,
a comment that boat is now the only thing left
and
really nice gag
just at that moment, the boat starts to move seemingly under its own power.
Now we don't even have that. So they they grab onto the boat, but it's it's not the thief so they think it's just a a darn alligator.
You know, that's a pretty big alligator
to to be
not be scared at. Donald has seen everything by this point. He's so jade. He's just there's... you know, just one alligator, he used to wrestle five all the time.
Yeah. We're only a few stories in and and they're they're already pretty seasoned.
So
so they climb into their boat on the next page.
And
they
decide that they need to
explore
and
investigate the different waterways to see if they can find something.
They use the the word...
I looked up how to pronounce this, but I've already forgotten it. It's Al flu, us.
That's right. I keep wanting to say it is s in my head, but... That makes sense. Yeah. English is nonsense.
Yeah. No. There's a there's a big slew right by my house. There's actually a couple of them. So your understanding of a slew is like a water way which thin within an existing
body of water.
I'm not sure in what way it's not Al like a reef river or a creek because the the one here just looks like a river and we have people pad around and them and stuff and a lot of plant life and animals and stuff. So, yeah, I'm not sure what the what the distinguishing characteristic is. So this is where it starts to get pretty weird. The Nephews use our protests thing that they're going deeper, they're saying that this is really creepy.
They approach a tree that has a large sign on it. And Donald points outlook look. There's a sign up here. You know, And can't... There's not gonna be afraid of.
And the the tree is on a really cool looking mangrove. Or the sign excuse me is on a really cool looking mangrove tree. And when they approach, the sign ominous
says
beware of the measles.
And the kids asked on what measles,
but he's never heard of them, and he speculate
that it must be a gang of swamp kids.
So he's not deter
towards seem to... This would seem to contradict their earlier assessment that they had gone further into the swamp than anyone had ever gone before since there's a sign nailed to the tree.
Right. Right. And he pretty casually. He thought be swamp kits. But
so they they come up to another sign. That's a follow that says you read that sign, Didn't you turn back Donald is not deter he is gonna keep going.
And at this point, his hat
struck off his head
by by an arrow.
And when they go to investigate, they still can't find any sign that there's anyone around. They don't see any tracks.
The only thing they see is another old alligator.
At this point, age seven,
I was
fascinated by Al.
So I watched more about them with the average kid. And they are being pretty casual around space like, twelve
ga.
But
once they give up searching on this little,
they get back in the boat and the alligator
looks at them with kind of a
suspect
expression.
And we get our first glimpse of the measles
as we see
three pairs of feet
beneath the alligator. It's it's a a either dead Al or a costume or something that some little creatures have clearly been hiding
and we figured that that's how they've been getting around undetected.
I like to think that previous campers had come with
Al
life size alligator costume, and they they boosted it off those guys and and are using it now. Right. Because we'll we'll find out that they like to steal and collect things. So
we see the nephews continue
to
go in deeper into the swamp
and we get Al a neat perspective change at the bottom of this page where we see one of these creatures in silhouette.
At the top of a tree
pointing down at them with a really angry expression on his face.
And then it pulls back and we we actually hear from the measles
and they say pepper, the nose k measles,
And and so this is where we get our taste of
their dialogue.
They're every word that they use the starts with end. They're gonna use Al a silent g,
like like the words Nash or nat
or no and they're gonna talk with kind of a hill bayou people accent.
And I really employers the... They have the kind of the standard like, Disney or big round nose, but then you can see their ears or kind of
thin like you would expect on like a dragon or some kind of prehistoric fish or something.
Yeah. Kind of a mysterious
critter to categorize.
Right. I I don't... They're definitely reminiscent of no, but they also look very unique and those, like, weird finn years. They kinda looked Al aquatic to me or something.
Yeah. I I really like on this page the different
perspectives that we get because we see kind of a regular perspective of the Ducktales
Al ground level, and then we go up into that tree and we're angled almost straight down looking at the boat
and then we see the measles
up in their trees. I think it's really cool. Yeah. That's really good. Framing. It's very cinematic. It is and it...
Just the kind of the way that Barks
reveals a little bit more gradually as the is cool. So on the next page, the kids are ambushed
by a hail of aero fire.
Not to worry. These arrows are are all blunt
because they're meant to be warning shots. And
Don and the kids see that the arrows are coming from the trees. They don't see anyone probably because the measles are so high and so small. As they approach
a an old log
that's, like, the Barks from old tree. They Donald is, like, let's
use that to shield cell. And this works out really well and the measles yell at them, they yell to to go back and
We haven't had human creators in the land of the measles for a million years. And Donald Heels back and still doesn't think that there anything special. And then once the halo of arrows stops, they decide to take a peek.
So Donald
wants to look out one direction towards one bank and then after using gonna to look at the other.
And Donald is surprised when they lifted off to see a
small village of hut on s.
And when he tells the nephews to take a look at it, the village has completely disappeared. So these these measles are really good at moving a lot of stuff
very quickly. I think it's also interesting at this point that Dom keeps making his comments, like these are
mischievous kids.
And so far we haven't actually seen anything to
to show that they're not, like we can see out of the their feed out of the alligator costume coming out the bottom of the Al costume. Kinda look like little kids, and then then we see the little guy in the tree and all the other little guys and silhouette. Maybe this is just like a lord of the flies, gang of little kids, you know, Sure. Yeah. There's no reason to think otherwise. I mean, maybe the arrows.
So at this point, they
they continue on
there's a great gag here that really just needs to be red word for word. Donald says there's
those houses didn't didn't just get up and run away. And then on the next panel, they see the house literally running away the still
strips striving across the water and nephew say that Dickens they didn't. There they go running now. I I really like this part of the story where things are just getting... It feels like things are getting weirder and weirder as they go deeper and deeper into the swamp. Like, at this point, in the story anything
feels possible,
like like what that fisherman at the dock was saying, you who knows what's in the I thought
the running
houses on s would be part of the mystery that would get had explained later, but it it never really did. So I'm still here on a subsequent reading. Not sure what's going on in this picture. Are there teams of people inside like like Rowe on an ancient Greek boat? I'm just picturing a bunch of measles
that, you know, they've got their drill. They they don't wanna be
discovered. So they've got some mechanism that's causing it to run along. But to me, it's just supposed to give a little bit more color as it's weird.
We're in the swamp, we're we're in measles territory now. So Donald still doesn't take this seriously. He jumps out of the boat and he is going to to... He's pursuing them with a shotgun.
Before he has a chance to shoot their s off, the one of the measles
calls out to fire at them not with blunt arrows, and Donald gets shot right in the which causes him to drop his shotgun and Barks shot peppers one of the measles,
and we get good look at him for the first time as do Donald and the kids
and they are staring on
with just shock at these little creep critters that again look like no. They've got kind of a weird mix of clothing on. They look kinda like hill
and
one of the measles who has a crown on tells them all to meet back tonight at a place called Me knob. Yeah. Yeah. We do... It is a very
probably intentional parallel here on the two side by side frames of donald leap up and getting shot in the butt with an arrow and the nasal getting popped off of his there, getting shot in the butt by Mcdonald's Barks shop. Okay. You're right. They've got. They've got almost the same pose. It's drawn from the same angle. So On the next page, Donald and kids are speculating on on what the heck they are. And
Donald is puzzled, but he wants to follow them, and they don't they're not able to track the measles. So we transitioned to that night. The nephews user commenting on how scared they were of the shotgun because that's what caused all the measles to to break into the swamp. And later that night, they can hear some drumming from a waist off and they figured that it must be the measles
having a war dance
And then nephews are freaked out, but Donald says, no. We can't leave. We might never be able to find this place again, and he's
he's really determined
to get some evidence
and measles. Because again, you know, he explained at the beginning of this story that he really liked to me explorer.
So I guess that's why he's so determined
to to track him.
And this is this... I mean, this is one of a few places in the story where I'm not sure what is motivating
the characters.
I mean, it if he wants to discover things,
he has...
You know what I mean? And he can he can leave, you know, they're obviously in some danger. They're in, you know, these people's territory,
don't have any more supplies except for the boat that they took back from the.
Probably would've have been sensible to
go back home or at least go back and resume your vacation.
Yeah. I think at this point, he's more motivated by his own stubborn or I'm gonna see
because you're right. There's not there's not a great reason.
Behind this other than to advance the story.
But i I think we see this in a lot of the earlier Barks stories where
that's that is kind of his motivation. So they they follow the noise
to what must be nasal knob when they're are kind of
sneaking up and approaching These.
It's it's really crazy because we can see the measles Barks
square dancing
and they're in front of a large
temple
that what we're about to discover has a large statue of, like, a nasal
deity or an nasal god of some kind. One of the weirdest scenes in any of the Barks stories I And the idol is on top of this kind of short want pyramid kind of aztec looking pyramid maybe maybe like a zig almost. And we focus on the king of the measles
who is cha his people. And he's pointing at the idle.
Their deity is named the old nasty face. And he and treats nasty face to send the lightning bolt to wipe out the human creators and nasty face being Al large stone idle doesn't answer. And the measles they seem to have their...
Their religion seems to be pretty pretty consistent. If they don't hear anything
from him, it is evidence that he wants them to do the job them cells, but they're terrified
of the shooter gun. And Donald and the kids over here the king say we gotta feed them to the alligator.
But before that, they gotta continue their dance. When we transition back to Donald that and then Nephews use you know, they're like, well, of course, we gotta get out of here but Donald is pondering and he has what he describes is a devilish idea they they're gonna
and need to take back to prove
what we've seen. And I definitely got thoughts about turn, but I'm I'm sure you do. So
what way do you think?
He has gone completely crazy from
swamp guests. I'm going to assume or something has
affected his Ducktales mind. I'm surprised and Nephews went along with him this far, but but at this point they're doing willing to voice to their caretaker.
Yes. This is this is crazy. We need to get out of here and get back to a real city
where they're not gonna
sacrifices to their giant statue.
Right. Yeah. So this this is admittedly a a pretty villainous
heel turn for Donald.
Even back then, I didn't like seeing this as much as I do really enjoy this story.
Barks, I think at this time is really finding the character, and I'm sure is really influenced by the old,
you know, cartoons that
that he himself spent some time working on. So Donald is kind of, like an avatar for the kinda main character that he wants in these comics and
sometimes he's gonna be a really noble every man and sometimes he's gonna be kind of jerk. And then this one, he's he's a jerk.
This is obviously a terrible idea. You know, there they're inter here. And he even uses the word kid kidnapped.
So I I don't think there's any... He's not confused about what it is that he's trying to do. And and other reason this is uncomfortable is, like, the measles are... They're not humans. Right? But but they are humans. They're they're just little. They're they're talking. They're they have, like, society, their social there. So
this is coming from a perspective that doesn't speak well of of Donald or attitudes at that time. And,
you know, in some ways, this is kind of like an American perspective. Right? We're we're gonna go in.
And we're gonna do what we want because we're right. He said, on the first page, he wanted to be like Columbus drake
You gotta bring back some specimens to show to to proper civilization. Right? Yeah. The savages that you find out in the out in the new world please. So so an uncomfortable part of the story, but
it definitely advances the plot. They are And in quick time, they encounter
a nasal
sleeping beneath the tree. They decide Donald decides that this is the guy, and they capturing him shockingly easily.
You know, I almost wondered if he is just pretending to be Al asleep there because they can
bind and gag him without him waking up. They take him back to their boat. And
at this point, Dawn has broke and they are leaving, They're gonna try to not leave any kind of a trail for measles.
But
we flashed the nasal who has woken up and with his feet has grabbed a bunch of grapes
and is
depositing
individual grapes in the water, leaving a a pretty ingenious trail that should be very easy for the measles to file. The grapes are are floating like on the surface of the water that leave like a like, a bread crumb kind of trail.
Yeah. I... This
this seemed very con to me.
There's
like, where on earth did those grapes just come from?
He... Like, you can see the panel before where they're carrying him from his sleeping spot. That's not like he had grapes on him when they grabbed him, and there's no grapes in the boat because there they've been stripped clean of everything except their boat. Sure. So he just suddenly has them. Maybe
maybe the grapes were already... You know, maybe there's a lunch in or some... Okay. I don't know. That that doesn't bother me the way that some of the other kind of villainous details in this.
But...
But I think that's a fair point. When I was a kid, I loved this. I thought this was such a neat
neat of of tracking. And Barks obviously, really liked it because he's gonna go back to this bit in that later comic that I had mentioned call land of the Big Indians. But...
Yeah. This is how they're gonna... They're gonna be caught and on the next page,
Donald feeling confident, so he takes off the measles gag and immediately and predictably, the nasal
calls out for help and they can hear...
The name is Napoleon.
They're... They've all got names that start with G.
And so his his fellow measles are not far behind. So they gag him again, Donald tells them they'd that row into the reeds and hide
kind of in a a tough of tall reads.
But the nasal is very resourceful,
especially with his feet. He grabs the shotgun done and bangs it against the boat.
And so they're sure that they're gonna be trapped, but Donald is also very bright. And he tells them that they need to rapidly sync their boat and use some hollow reeds
to breathe through.
That's also very clever.
Right. Yeah. These these were all things that has a seven year old. They just seemed like the height of, you know, outdoor
adventure
survival
pursuit whatever to me. And and so we got a really cool panel next of
the Nephews and the captive nasal
breathing
underwater through reeds
while the other measles are growing
right over them. That I I like that panel Al lot. And so they're in the clear. However, the measles are now between them and the coast, so they don't think that they're gonna be able to speak past them. And the nephews have a good idea Al this point, they decide that they can use the reeds to disguise themselves as measles
which Donald describes is a r idea, which clearly, I don't think you can weave beards and fake hats in that span of time, which is what they do, but it makes for a cool visual
of seeing them disguised as measles And as they're rolling past, we have a moment where we think they've been discovered because the team calls out, but he's just giving them instructions to search and the slew and
they are very relieved. Yeah. I
I like
making the customs out of the reeds and just feels like the exact same category to me as the
knockout out guard as you're trying to escape and then pull him into a, like a service closet and then one second later step out of the service closet wearing his clothes. It's a a standard trope... It's a classic. It's a classic for a reason. Yeah.
So they've managed to get past them.
And Donald is a lookout on the tree. He sees that they've turned back. And he says it's it's safe now to make a cage for our little pet
are the words that he uses. And again, know, I I know the measles are fictional creatures, but this is this is obviously like, super Huey,
on his part because can he... The need, like, has a name, it can speak.
So they
dance you can square down. It can grab it this pop on her and Scrooge below left. They they can make a pretty quick hat they can construct a wooden cage quickly.
While they're doing it, they're talking about how
impressed people are gonna be when they see. You know, I noticed the nephews use his name. Right? They say when people see Napoleon, they're gonna gas and donald
calls him our little pet. So that's Al that's a contrast there to me. And
when they get him and the cage, they Donald removes the ropes. And we can see he's got a pretty sm look on his face and he he just falls over
laughing up uproar.
And he tells Donald that he's his butt as free because he is a swell. I'm sure you were as puzzled as donald was. But we're meant to take it literally because he says he can swell up and
he proceeds to do it. And I love... I love Donald line as he's watching it of all the screw sites
because you Napoleon
breaks through the cage. I'm glad that a sweater would have the foresight to always own
stretchy pants. Just like
just like Bruce Banner
in my comics needs to have the stretchy as purple pants possible.
Some some minor character just making a killing selling selling them to various characters around. Exactly. And And again, this is... This story is crazy. Right? Like, this is this is really odd. This is really weird.
I can't look at this with anything other than my seven year old eyes when I first read this and and just was delighted by this story. So I don't know. Maybe you're you're seeing this and it's just
too weird, but I love it. It works
great for me. And this is something that he's also gonna go back to
in what Lam beneath the ground, one of the characters
and that is gonna do something very similar to to deliver a message.
So it's it's been fun to to see these things that he he likes to return to.
Napoleon
has just
left off this island
and he's bounding across the water like like, a skip stone or, like, a beach ball or something. And
Donald is
too stubborn here because he wants to catch... He refers to him as that free key is gonna fire a shot into the air to spare him so it'll stop. And it does scare him, but only
to hide into the brush and we transition to the other measles.
Because they... They're hearing this shotgun as well. And
now they're heading to intercept the Ducktales
Yeah. Still just donald is more concerned with bringing bringing the specimen back than any symbols they have of safety.
Alright. So they they lied on to the next island that he's gone to in pursuit. But by this time, the other measles have managed to station themselves in the trees,
and they catch donald in a basket.
And I like that it seemed a basket seems appropriate it seems like some some thought that Barks paid into
what
their civilization would use. Right? And they've got all these river
So... And they they h them up into the trees. Donald doesn't realize that he's up in the trees. So he starts to slice his way out the road. He would have noticed flipping upside down by this point, but
Right. Let's I still think he's sitting on the ground somewhere. Right. So by the time... By the time he busts his way out of the basket, he
he plummet to the ground where he is easily captured
and they head Barks towards Me
with him bound.
He is wondering
what's become of the Nephews. He asked the the needle that's piling the boat and I like how the needs will just kinda casually jerk system
backwards and tells them to take a look and that behind you and and we see the Nephews user are tied up. Yeah. I think it's interesting that
the nasal up to this point have been, like, shooting arrows at him and trying to
cause him some harm. And now that he's been effectively or maybe literally not unconscious
They're going to bring him back as a specimen know. That's right. So on the next page, we get a really good look Al me knob in the daylight. And
there's a big crowd of measles with the king on the base.
And it's interesting that the measles have kind of like a range of different
hats. And outfits
from what looked like different civilizations throughout different eras. And we hear some crowd top
They talk about... Someone says that these are the first humans that
he's seen since po Lay from fifteen thirty team commentary about how measles go on forever. And so the king
decree that the nephews user to be locked away in the Al.
Jail. I I was wondering if I was to interpret the the phrase first Huey, I've seen since Punt
was through here. He is saying what he sounds like he's saying that he personally saw po leon. Yeah. That go through there five hundred years ago. Yeah.
Four hundred and thirty years ago at this Yeah. It seems like the measles are very long live. I was thinking you were gonna point out that they referred to the ducks as humans too I noticed that
on
the first or second page, the fishermen was saying, no no human has been back here, and I thought are are these characters humans?
Yeah.
And and they they are in in these stories, the docs and any of the sentient, the dog people, the mouse people,
they're just humans.
So that's something that we never really
to my knowledge, there's never any point where a character
points out. Oh, I'm duck, Huey, humanoid duck, and there a little animal Ducktales
just hand there. That's who they are. So we learn a little bit about
knees law, and Donald is gonna have the chance to get his freedom if he faces off against one... The measles champion.
They get led to, like, an outdoor arena and And this reminded me of the
the, like, outdoor
arenas that the
the Maya
have that they looked real really reminiscent of it to me. He... I built the same thing. Yeah. Yeah. So
He needs the champ, no
with si g as always donald is immediately skeptical because he's he's a pretty tiny will easily even he's super confident as Donald usually is.
But Donald figures out immediately that no thomas is also a swell
He is in his words, the swell swell that ever swelled. So I'm wondering why the measles would make this offer.
I it's possible that they're just one hundred percent confident of how this fight is going to go down and they just want some entertainment, but the prospect of a pardon as they put it where I guess Donald can go back home, that would be disastrous for these guys. They...
I think they've said by this point, or they're going to say later that they don't they don't wanna get,
by assignments all the time. Yeah. They don't wanna get pest to that. Which which they absolutely would. Right? You're right. It would be catastrophe for
I agree I think they like the entertainment.
And
I don't think they see that they could ever lose. And I'm guessing if they did, you know, they've got the advantage numbers.
I don't think... I don't think that offer freedom is really on the table, but No. Another possibility is the pardon doesn't include leaving. It just includes not being imprisoned. And. There you go. They can they can just fade into measles society, they can take up swelling. And any humans are gonna be dead in less than a hundred years anyway.
Right. And yeah we'll move on eye.
Alright. So on the next page, we've got Donald battle against
no.
It doesn't go well for Donald.
The the measles
are
very placid watching this. They know what's going on.
He they see no
deflate as he comes down,
just
squishing Donald, not gonna wind out of them. I noticed they called him No.
Yeah. Like to think I like to think of the way we give our celebrities nickname.
Well No. Yeah. So on the next page, Donald was days, and they set him up for the K cross, the ten strike. But anyway, he rolls himself like a bowling ball and
sp donald onto a platform
in a a lagoon watery pit with very sheer walls The king announces that he's failed when his freedom. It's time to get the Nephews.
And Donald is about to fight bad when he realizes that the platform has been knocked onto is surrounded
by hungry Al. I noticed here he also says, I interpret this as a du sound. Work.
Yes. That's what he claims as he looks down at the alligator.
Yeah. That lack expression is gonna come up a lot in the comics. Again, I don't even think about it, but
du sound. And I guess that's one of the few times we kinda remember that these are ducks.
So on the next page, we transitioned to the Nephews
who seemed to have been watching what's going on from their
cell of high. In the Zig.
They're are pretty desperate. So they decide that they need to try and slip between the bars.
Because there is a couple stories down another cell and so they they form a human chain
and it's it's a pretty perilous and cool looking scene.
I
felt it, you know, as a kid that very very dangerous and frightening, the the height that they're
trying to do this maneuver Al. So I... Listeners should be... Listeners should be picked
that mission impossible to scene where Tom cruise is climbing the outside of that
tower and
And not.
Yeah. That's right. Yeah.
Except it's, you know, eight year olds or
I drove these guys are.
Exactly.
And so they they do make it. Their human chain were they have access to the interior
of the temple. They need to figure out some kind of strategy. Should they go exploring in the interior and they come across the measles like their treasure room, their spoils.
And we can see a lot of different things from again, different areas difference. Civilizations, there's some made American stuff,
like a mace suit of armor.
And
the camping gear
the the Ducktales had along with their pho and records.
Huey, comments that the measles
expect their idle to talk. And so they
he says that they need to get that phone graph into the mouth. And so they head upstairs into the mouth of the aisle with the pho.
And we transition out to the measles. The the king is informed that the legal have escaped have escaped.
And the king
is telling them that, you know, you gotta hunt them down or old nasty Barks gonna be awful matt. And then we
transition into the island's mouth where we can see...
See everything from a distance. They're setting up and they attach a ball of string to the starter switch so they can start it remotely. Yeah. I know the guy bringing the message the king has yet another style of hat that I think of as like a marching band hat
right, which seems to imply that
someone else has been in the nasal civilization pretty recently. I'm assume of fort Lauderdale high school.
Marching band has lost their bad leader.
Made the arrest.
On the next page the king is directing them to find the nephews
But they they show up right behind him, very compliant, and he tells his subjects to throw him in the gator pool, but they remind him that he got asked the advice old nasty phase this next panel
feels like the king is is playing a little bit of a con because he
he he agrees
and you can tell he doesn't expect old nasty face to say anything.
So, you know, I I read this as
the king knows that
whole nasty faces
is
is bunk.
So the king and treats old nasty face,
what should they do and we transitioned to seeing Huey, pull that string behind his back.
And old nasty face appears to break into the song until tells them everybody dan, grab your partners and circle to the left. And the measles are all just
snacks, their hats. There are many different hats playoff off their heads. Like the the universal
signal for alarm, which is your had shooting into the air. And and little surprise lines above your head. I I just love the visual
of this one with with Al nasty face
being so ridiculous here.
The the way that the way that Barks drew Al nasty face to me, like, he's he's not... He's he's a god like measles. Right? Because he's he's got horns. He's larger than life, but he's still not that giant measles knows. So it feels very lived in to me.
I agree. And and so the Nephews are able
to help Donald. Escape they make it back to their boat and they very pre
note that
that someone's put a basket of apples in it and, you know, probably also someone on Saint it, obviously. And we can see the silhouette out of the king
observing them. And as they float away, they start to eat the apples because they have eaten since yesterday, and the king is checkpoint to himself
one of the other measles approaches and wonders, you know, why why do you let them go, King? You were gonna... They're gonna tell everyone about us and we're gonna get esther her to death, and the king is un bothered. He says they're not gonna say anything. That's why I gave them the apples
The other nasal
asked O, you know, they're poisoned.
He says the apples are p.
And the king tells them nope are dope with git juice so that they're not gonna remember a thing that happened in the last two days.
And so we transition to them arriving back at that peer with the Fisherman he asks them what they saw, what kind of magical
strange sites, and they tell him
Nope. We didn't see a single thing.
We comb the ever blades from end to end and saw nothing new or different.
And the last panel donald is saying list. It was some little thing that we Al already for forgotten. And that That closes out the story.
Yeah. Again, very very persistent fishermen on that dock in there.
I didn't even notice this he's... Is he wearing the sam out. It. I believe you I guess why dry a different outfit for a character that's gonna show up on on two different pages
So
some some comments on this. I
I mentioned I have a lot of problems with the Donald, like, villainous turn in this one. You know, he's
it's pretty evil, the attitude that he has towards them,
I don't like that part of it, but I I really love the progression of this story. I love how weird it is. I love how...
I I really felt like I was and turning the ever blades and getting, you know, deeper and deeper.
And that was getting progressively more and more creepy. I love how Barks realize the setting. And then when we see the measles, I like how
again lived in, he makes their civilization feel in a very
short number of pages.
I love the the weird odd touches with
the swell
I love their goofy religion. I love their dialogue
despite the uncomfortable parts of this story. There's just just so much of how Ad audacious
it is
really works for me. I don't know if I'm just like, fossil formalized into my first reading of it from when I was a seven year old,
but this this is probably
my favorite story that we've done so far.
It's definitely among my favorite of Barks.
Very early stories. So
this one this was a lot of fun to go back and read again.
It had probably been ten to twenty years since I read this one, but I remembered Everything
because as a kid, this was, like one of the very first ones and i read this over and over. I get the feeling that you didn't enjoy it as much. What what were your thoughts as
someone new to Barks?
I
I do think you probably are wearing some nostalgic goggles.
Yeah
I'm glad you are aware of how weird it is. It is extremely weird.
We cannot overstate how weird this comic is
I I don't think it has the same
like storytelling chops that the other ones did. You know, The other ones had kind of a really clear
movement of the plot and really clear
motivations for all the all the players. And this one seemed more like
just kind of
a lot of interesting ideas that he had and wanted to use and then he did. Like and like the swelling is really interesting and the big the big God that they follow is interest thing and the like costume and stealing and everything and and, you know, exploring this place that apparently nobody has been in five hundred years. It's interesting stuff and that they have kind of this
hodgepodge of all the cultures they've stolen from.
It's interesting, but I don't know why any of these people are doing any of these things. I will I will give you that it's a pretty dis disappointed story.
To me works because it's it's almost like the way you've transitioned from
civilization quote to deep in the swamp. Right? Where all of a sudden, it's it's gotten weird because you're in this different
unknown place. But but... Yeah, Donald
motivations
are... I think the measles have some pretty great motivations. I think they're
behaving in a justified way. You know. They're just trying to keep inter lo
out, but don
I think I think they do make sense until they catch him. And then everything they do after they catch him, I'm not sure why they doing. Oh, where they they like to watch them for sport. Right. And even even even letting them go once we know where they are, we could just capture them again
instead, we're just gonna give them forgetting apples.
Right. You know, you may be right. I might be seeing this through rose colored glasses.
But but I do love this one.
As far as how it's regarded
among Barks fans, as always, we we take a look at what the index website says. And
so far, this one is gonna fall pretty squarely in the middle of the five stories that we've looked at. Right now, Frozen gold has the highest rating at seven point eight out of ten
and too many pets was our our low watermark with seven point one. Mystery of the swamp is at a seven point five which puts it in the ninety nine point third percentile
of all the storage ranked on on the index.
I didn't really cover the value for this one
because, again, this is...
This is story b in a comment that we already talked about. So we have discussed the value for frozen gold. And, you know, there's a reason that this four color comment is remembered, I'm sure for frozen gold instead of this one.
But
definitely holds a place in my heart. As far as how it holds up, I will readily admit that there's a lot that doesn't work in the modern world about this one. The the attitude
towards the den of nasal
is
pretty awful.
And.
Also, this is... The contrast is so dramatic in the same
cover.
In frozen gold,
the whole thing is they're going to Alaska to bring
needed medicine to the natives
of Barks Alaska or whatever they've called the town. Right And
and he, you know, pride himself on being this hero, doc you know who's saving everybody. And this one is like I'm gonna catch this freak. Yeah. That's some some pretty big whiplash for being in the same episode. You're you're definitely right. So... Yeah, That that doesn't hold up well. I would say that,
you know, the depictions of the measles,
they're very, like, hill ish that's
not something that...
I mean, we don't we don't really care about that compared to depictions of some other people, but I I think if we really analyze that, it's it's not a very kind. A very kind depiction.
I I would like to think
that... Because I was thinking like if they haven't seen me people in five hundred years where they... Where they getting the hill culture from, you know, the they're dancing and everything. And I've decided that's where the south got it. Sounds from these guys, they can't remember having seen them, but they do remember square dancing And now, they're all playing in the fiddle in the the Panhandle
region of Florida. Yeah. My read was that it just kinda ema from from Florida. Self. But Yeah
see up out of the crowd. Some stuff that's kinda dated, but not necessarily problematic is, you know, square dancing. I remember square dancing
and Pe as a kid, but I think that would look... I I read this one to my own kid and she had no idea what square dancing was.
Just the whole idea of the ever blade is a place that's une explored that could be hiding anything.
And then
as far as appearances, you know, this one is not... I don't think that well remembered it hasn't been referenced a lot. He never did any paintings based on this one that I know of. I did learn that there was a mickey mouse comic published
some decades ago in Brazil. Called second child of the Al nasal knob that
had another appearance of the measles
in in mickey mouse. So
I thought this one i had some pretty good educational value. I I feel like I learned a lot about the other blades themselves.
Maybe not like, specific facts, but kind of like, what kind of plants and animals you would expect.
I think there was some pretty good realistic
of things like demand
and and other natural features.
How about your favorite panel Ryan. And did you have a favor in this one? I think
I did like one where we're
looking down the side of the
the prison
peter
president zig
as the boys are
making their escape right, Where they're looking almost straight down. There's kind of a real
sense of of danger of heights. Is that the one you're talking about? Yeah. Yeah. You get a sense of the
the
scale
he has really good
perspective on there. You can see the tiny stairs and tiny people way down there. You out couple hundred feet at least probably. You know, it's like standing on the empire state building? Yeah. I like that one a lot too. I I thought this one had a lot of really great panels. I like some... I like the one on the page before that where he
sees the alligator
surrounding him in that little pit or whatever.
I don't think I could say anything though, other than the
great panel of old Nasty face
calling the square dance.
That one. That one's an easy winner for me.
But I did consider as a strong runner up the the panel where they approach
the first sign where it says be beware of the measles.
I liked the the kind of highlights the way that the mangrove was drawn. And I feel like it had some good, like, atmosphere. Yeah. Let's see
any other
any other closing
thoughts
I can confirm the ever is a Us national park. It is a one point five million acre Wet preserve.
Excellent. Well,
thank you for bearing with me. Has I shared this
really odd
story that I nonetheless love with you. Our next
episode is another personal favorite of mine. It is terror of the River. I'm looking forward to getting a revisit that one. Thank you all for joining us. If you guys have any thoughts or comments, please drop us a line at Barks remarks. At g dot com, and
we will see you next time.