Hello, and welcome to Barks
The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer Al artist of the greatest Donald and unscrew comments of all time. Join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing or order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Welcome everyone. I am Mark Sever, a Grown man who enjoys Donald Inducks
and uncle Scrooge Comments. And this week, I'm joined by two other grown men who I managed to convince to let me talk about these comments And Ryan, if you could introduce yourself. I'm Ryan Bailey. This is what I sound like. And Eric, I'm
currently,
and I do not. Sound like we're on bailey. Alright. Hey, guys, have come either of you ever been on a house about. I have. Yes.
In fact, I remember when I was in middle school, my dad had, like, a company
party that we got invited to. We were all hanging out on the house vote with all his coworkers and their families and stuff. And I remember one morning, my dad and I trying to fish the top of the boat and we were just fishing and fishing and nothing even n our bait, but we could actually see the fish, like, jumping up out of the water That's my house phone memory. So no no giant serpents though,
not that I will recall now. Do was it... Was it is awesome as the
as Donald and the nephews, like, first couple of days on the river before i get attached.
It has... It does have kind of a placid
natural
quality, you know, Well, and, of course, I asked about the house, but because we are going to be talking about the error of the river, two exclamation points this time. My exclamation point for each of your c
Yeah. Yeah. That's alright. And You said you have you have not had the pleasure of being on the house, but I have not. Close the i've denim of waters why Interrupting.
Oh, that's pretty good. I haven't done either. So I definitely
thought it looked like a blast after reading this comment because over and over as a kid. So...
Yeah. But I can live by seriously through donald and the nephews.
This comic...
A little bit of background, this one was published. The cover date was January of nineteen forty six. And tara of the river was printed in four color
number one hundred and eight is the twenty eight page a little bit longer than many of them. And our our synopsis for this episode,
Donald
sneezes at an auction
are mistaken for bids on a house boat
And soon he and the nephews, find themselves sailing down the Ohio and eventually the Mississippi River,
and there they encounter a huge c serpent which they later learn is actually an elaborate submarine
whose captain gets his pleasure from scaring with the Jesus out of people. So I'm I'm very excited to talk about this one. This is very high concept.
And, you know, I read this one
over and over
as a kid. Let's see. A little bit of
background trivia. There there's a really good quote that I found from Carl Barks
about how he really wanted to have a villain that was quote, a mean son of a gun. And so he
tried to
He tried to do that. You tried to avoid having to censor it by making him totally nutty so that it would get by the editors.
Rather than making him murderous.
I created a guy that didn't leave any bad taste and people's mouths didn't cause children any nightmares. But, you know, still had that fear element. So we'll we'll talk about how that worked out, but I I think that the character, the scare as he's referred is really
really fast maybe one to me. I wanna talk to about the value range for this comic. This one had one
recently
sold or a few years ago. There was a document sale of a nine point five great copy, which is like pretty close.
Yeah. That's pretty close to mint.
And that one was sold for ninety five hundred dollars.
So pretty pretty good value.
I also found it notable. I I think you guys probably saw the cover that was drawn by don Yet, I think is that you say name, that shows the c disturbing on the front, but the original
publication
doesn't show the surf it shows the nephews kind of reacting in tear Al. And that cover is actually based on one of Barks
oil paintings, one of those more famous ones.
It usually goes the other direction. Right? Where he makes oil painting space son stomachs?
Yeah. Exactly. So this one, this one was a little bit different. He
he created it for one of the scenes.
But... Yeah. Really I'll have to share the image with you guys, and I can put it up on Facebook for listeners to check out.
Yeah. We can we can show the other versions of covered too. So
in in talking about the background on this one, there's a lot to talk about
for a historical
context.
I kinda dove into a couple of things. Right? Because this one is really about River life.
And and I think a lot of the American attachment to the Mississippi
River,
the Ohio and the Mississippi, And then also just the kind of
war
paranoia
that I think enable this one. Like, when I read these stories,
When I was reading as a kid, I really read them as text.
Right? As, like, funny. It exciting
stories. But as I go back to them later,
I I still try and enjoy them in the same way, but, you know, you can't help but read them as sub now. And
when I think about the timeline of this story in nineteen forty six,
you know, on what's going on in the world, it's it's really apparent that Bart wrote this with the backdrop of, like, submarine, Paranoia.
Right? We we had several years in the North Atlantic with the German u boats,
just like
d
the the shipping fleet and and I think that that notion that something from below
could just appear is whether he was thinking about it or not. I think that's a big part of what this story is
about just, like, the terra that that could lie and underneath the wave.
I don't know. Maybe I'm over thinking this one, but
but that's what I read now. That's interesting.
That's an interesting
contrast to, like, a lot of this genre
media
from this period is about
nuclear stuff
instead of something unknown coming from below.
Yeah. And and I think we're we're very close
to making that transition. In fact, literally our next
our next story after this one is is called Donald Duck Adam Bomb. So that little
a literal transition there.
I went a little bit down the rabbit hole of just kinda looking up some of the information. So the the submarines, of course, had been around for a long time, but it wasn't until World war two that they could actually, like, pursue
follow and and chase down ships.
And I read that about seventy
percent of all the ships that were lost in the Atlantic.
Around this time, we're sunk by you ups.
More than two thousand
seven hundred of them. And there's a quote that kept coming up that said compared with the world war one
submarines in World war two
exhibited greater speed more effective weaponry,
sophisticated
detection
technology and great versatility. And could pursue their victims rather than just lying and weight. So, again, I think that was kind of what was hanging over over this.
And
there were, in fact, a lot of rumors
around the time
about
submarines that were like,
venturing
inland into the great Lakes.
There was even a rumor about one that had a mission to destroy the hoover dam.
Which, you know, it was nonsense, of course. But you can imagine
world war two, that kind of that kind of talk going around. And then
I don't know about you guys, but I I feel like during our childhood,
just the the notion of, like, the Mississippi River and
you know, the story is a Barks twain. I feel like it was more salient still. I feel like that's not as salient these days.
But I think that it it just was much stronger in kind of the American Psyche. Did you guys read
much of that? Back then. No. I don't think so.
Alright Think. But I can tell I can tell that Donald has that. I mean, Eric, Go ahead. I was gonna say the the Mississippi has always had this
mystical
pull on the country as river that goes right down in the middle of it.
And has such a
strong
place in the... Just American honda
I mean, the boats, the gambling, all those things. I don't even know how many johnny cash songs there are about the river.
Yeah. I agree
Ryan, did you have a thought?
I can tell that
Donald or probably more accurately, Carl
has that
sort of
romance
about it, you know, this this vision of
kind of this narrative, I guess, so of the beauty and
American ness of it and and imagine, you know, this paradise. Yeah. I think I think there's little little more American then the mississippi around the ideas
around it.
And and so before we...
Before we go into the story itself. The only notable appearance the only character appearance is the aforementioned character
the scare.
That's how he's, like, universally referred to by fans.
I don't think that they ever calling him that in the story and I might be mis
And
I'm I'm very excited to talk about him. I think he's a
really weird
and unique villain. And I dig it. I'm all for them.
I'm thinking he's a bill without being a bad guy. Is he's he's a foil. He seems... He comes up more is just a prank
an actual
evil villain. I mean, initially,
Right? And until he kinda takes the turn and you realize that he's he's all in because he'll
murder.
To to follow through. But, yeah, I mean, at first he does kinda...
Anyway, we'll we'll obviously get into him.
Let's see. You guys... You guys ready to go into the story? Yeah. Let's have excellent.
Alright. So the care of the river,
it opens up with a splash panel
actually have donald on the house boat,
being terrorized by the serpent, which, you know, is not very common in Barks. So it's kind of like... He's he's laying it out. There's a little bit of a mystery at the beginning, but we get kind of
surprising preview here.
And then it opens the donald
deciding to sit inside an auction house
to get out of the cold
while he seems to be suffering from a cold.
So we've got one of those classic bits where a character is gonna accidentally
buy something
because of a sneezing or a coughing fit at an auction.
It's kind of a cli by now, but maybe it wasn't back then. And so the the auction year shows a picture of one of the auction lots, which is a house boat, and he talks it up as being waived ten thousand at least. Huey, starts bidding at eighteen dollars.
And
by the end of the first page Donald
sneezing fit has caused him to drive the bid up to twenty five dollars with him being the only bidder.
So I was curious about this I... My first thought was, wow, this is a very tired trope, and then I thought was this tire truck back then, or is this the first one? So I looked it up. I'm night.
What I thought of as the accidentally building bidding Al a public auction trump. The earliest example I could find is
a
story told verse in an English book called the tour of doctor Tax in which he he accidentally buys something at a
Al auction.
And then I found
Abbott Case costello joined the foreign legion,
movie you from nineteen fifty, which is notably after this, another movie called Mister Drake Duck where he
accidentally buys the Inducks that lays uranium eggs
because everything has to be tom.
They've i've seen that. I just I just totally flash back into the past. I forgotten
about that, but I've absolutely seen that movie. Of course, you have. And then I I feel like it was in all the like eighties and nineties,
Tv shows and movies and stuff. Yeah. It's a it's a staple. It's the only thing anybody knows about in person auctions is that unless you are a emotion silent statue,
you are bidding on this item regardless of anything.
If is linked too aggressively.
This is now your item. It's definitely the only experience I have with on
So, yeah, tired trope, but
but it it's it's evergreen. It's a classic.
Alright. So on page two, Donald keeps sneezing the bit up,
and he finally manages to mu himself at thirty dollars.
I looked this up. I'm I'm bet Ryan. You might have too.
But that's four hundred and twenty nine dollars and today's money. By my my mile wow.
And and it's still a very cheap boat.
It is. Although it won't end up being obviously.
And then ask to the sale, the the auctions muscle man gives Donald the photo of the house about and bill of sale and demands he pay up
donald protests, and and we get a a great cut to him walking home, clutch the photo and bill
and clearly having been subjected to some brutal violence
by a muscle guy. I I was gonna ask you about that. Because on the next page, he has...
It looks kind of feather or whatever, like, they're trying to draw
long eyelashes or something around his eyes.
And I was gonna ask you is that is that supposed to be black eyes? It probably is as an Yeah. That's that's the the common depiction of black eyes for these characters. Definitely. We obviously got slow a couple of times. Yep.
Alright. So on page three, when he gets home, hue doing Louie c all rough up and they're concerned and they inquire what's happened. And he pi
explains that he bought a house about and they they come to find out that it's Al in city called or a place called Hogan Pure in Flood out, Ohio.
He doing Louie note very precisely that that's fourth two thousand four hundred miles away. And so Don kinda gives it up as as too much and toss is the painting choosing to forget about it. But
as time passes,
they
find themselves thinking about it, and
all the duct start to fantasize
about river life. And Donald
throws the nephews by deciding to give the house loading thing to try. Well, who has it status able live improve her life. I mean, come on.
Slowing down the river and join with enjoying life. No cares in the I've gotta say over the past year, it seems like a pretty
pleasant way to social distance.
That's true. Yeah
Alright. So on page four, we transitioned to their arrival by car at flood out, Ohio.
Which lives up to its name.
It's residents are all hun down on the roofs of their buildings. They're waiting for for a flood waters to subside. I imagine they must have, you know, weekly or monthly floods.
And they get some directions from a local to Hogan
here.
And I I really... I'm sure this is an old gag, but I love... I love his directions are very entertaining. He says that it's two blocks that way and twenty six feet that way pointing straight down beneath the water.
And then they they arrived to find Hogan himself sitting on his pure sign,
and he tells them the boat is still tied to the pier completely submerged,
and they also are that it's five years of war owed
at
cost of a hundred and two dollars and ten cents. Or one thousand four hundred and sixty one bucks in twenty twenty one.
Yeah. Any thoughts on this page gentlemen. I respect the use of the word.
Yeah.
Yeah. I love a good emo.
I think in reading the the Barks
stories, especially the Scrooge ones. I got a lot of great synonyms
for
for money. Right? Because emo and Barks.
Do you guys know how much a saw Barks is? Is it twenty dollars? I believe it's a fiber.
Okay. I can be wrong though.
I I I I do want to point out everybody in this town is still in the town. They're just living on the roofs of their own houses.
Mh There's one one
apparently married couple,
just cooking breakfast and they have the dinner table perched on the on the peak of their of their roof,
like the wood burning stove
cooking pancakes or something.
Just having breakfast, that's just the life. They don't seem upset. I just... I I love the idea that Barks has fun naming
his town's. So it's a very literal... It's flat out of Ohio That's... It gets gonna flood. That's why it's called that and no one bothers to move or anything. It's just that's how it is on the river. I love these high concepts towns that he creates.
We did the episode
on frozen gold
where the... I don't remember that. Oh, it was Barks, I think where i had a similar
seat where the snow
the snow level rose
and fell with the different blizzard. So this is kind of kind of another version of that.
Alright. So
on page five,
Donald again, he wants to give up on the idea of how because it's getting more and more expensive and difficult. But the kids suggest that they should at least look at it when when the flood received. And when it's revealed, they just can't resist over of a good house boat.
So they calculate that they're gonna need a few more dollars for the repairs
and the text box informs us that multi applies into many
until finally, they can sail away with
Hogan and warm sending them off. You know, he's he's turned into a nice puddle guy. Donald at first is very confident
about handling the house boat
but dewey remind him that Hogan
told them, they'd have a lot of lessons to learn.
And lesson number one comes up very quickly as they pass down wind a cold burning ship. I thought I thought at some point in the town, they would... They would be Al line to says,
why the entire town is underwater and why nobody minds or why the water is gone now? It's just what happens. It's not even worth talking about. That's what happens in Flat out, Ohio, sometimes you're breakfast on your roof? That's right. It's day to day. And I I mean, this is a good bit right, talking about how this is parity to the extreme, but the the banks of the these rivers,
they big flood constantly. This is what really happens.
Alright. So
on page six,
the... We see the kids grip while they're cleaning the the craft after
the encounter with the c burner.
And they passed near a large river boat that's gonna teach them less number two,
which is to have a clear channel when riding rough water. And so the... They they end up perched on top of a piling,
and they're stuck until the house both slips off and dunking them in the water.
Oh it continues the picked of donald making
boys work, and gals is like you know what? I've Gottfredson.
I'm gonna sit on the I'm gonna take the sell myself on the deck. Enjoy the river. You three Al legs. Get cleaned. Yeah. Donald knows what's up. That's that's where you have kids for him. Alright? A good captain knows how to delegate. So page seven, he claims that he's learned every lesson he directs a course near the shore where the big boat can't bother them. But Donald gets promptly struck in his chest by an
extremely long branch
of a tree growing on the River Barks,
which is where they learn lesson than three when Severino close to shore, post the look lookout on the bow.
So then they they dropped the anchor for their dinner, and they discussed that they haven't had time to to fish
so while they're talking about that, the current
terms their boat around.
And I... I'm really enjoying these kind of like, this format that he's got. Right? Of
learning a lesson
as they go down the forever. It seems like an interesting way to kind of show us the learning curve of captain a house about.
And I like that Carl had to think of these. Like, I wonder if they're are real things. Or if it's just things that he thought of that seemed impossible.
Right. And it just seem logical to.
Yeah. I'm I'm trying to think of how the this... How they'll however we can change current to go upstream
that far north. I don't think they're like,
turning the other way. I think the boat is just giving a bit of a spin. Right?
That's what I thought. Yeah. I think they're... I think they're still, you know, in the same spot, and the current is still going the same way, but depending on how, like the the contours of the bank, you might you might get a little bit of an eddie that kind of turns you the other way a little bit. Yeah. That was my.
Alright. So
on page eight, while they are eating their dinner of beans,
although in my print of it, it looks more like piece the way they've covered it.
They they discussed their destination. They wanna sail down to New Orleans.
Thousands of miles down the river.
The kids asked Donald if
he is sure that he can find his way, and he sc that he just needs to keep going the way he is going. And that sets us up
to
Huey, doing Louie
looking at the oddly familiar River banks as they as they continue to sail down
what is actually up.
I'm impressed with Donald ability to fire beans into his mouth with a knife without looking. He's looking the nephews, but he's still shooting a bean up at a nice little Barks into his mouth. I assume that's how everyone ate in the forties. Yeah. For some reason, I see this depicted Inducks,
animation all the time with, like, pee
especially.
Yeah. Me keys with a knife. And I remember trying to replicate it as a kid. Couldn't do it. One of those lost skills like fencing or something like that. It's just something everybody knew the old old times. Yeah. The noble art of p railing Alright.
On page nine, the Nephews approach donald, and they break the news that, yeah, They're they're back and flood out of Ohio.
And he realizes pretty quickly what's happened. The chrome must have turned them around.
And he learns the importance of lesson number four. Always take your bearing before Al hosting anchor.
So
they get back underway and kids discussed their lack of progress
but they acknowledge that Donald is... He's a hands on learner. Right? He's not gonna make any more mistakes. Nowadays he's already made them And
now now Donald is much more cautious, much more careful. So he decides to more in Inducks Cove for the night before it gets dark. Yeah. I I like his learning style. Yeah. I like that the nephews
never,
like, get down on him. Al he makes blender after blender. They just say he's learned his stuff. They just they still look up to him. That's true. They've recognized his learning style. Is it weird that the the more adults in this really I mean, I that's established that they're richard is at this point.
But it it still need to see
them put up with him when they like, we can figure this out. Yeah. Definitely. I mean, a lot a lot of these
comics are really great wish full moment, right, For the kids that are reading them.
And I remember really identifying with the nephews, loving their junior wood chuck guide book,
And just just seeing how we're resourceful
and independent they are in in this one,
especially as really cool.
Alright. So
on page ten,
and this where the story gets really good. Right? This is what we've been promised.
This is the tear of the river. That night, the doctor sleep on the river and an ominous shape breaks the surface
His is at the house boat, it is a
enormous
c serpent.
It wakes one of the nephews.
And he looks out the window, and he just possibly acknowledges oh, it's it's only a giant sea serpent. And he goes back to bed before using on what realistic dream. Use having.
I've gotta say that I
love the, like, feature design on this c serpent. I think it's kind of like a mix of
almost Chinese dragon
and classic c serpent.
And I I remember trying to draw as a kid. I think I think he just got a really cool character design here Al looks. It looks really scary. Yeah. Yeah. The are kinda of feather and it has this kind of
Harry sort of ridge down the center of the back. And along For tongue and some really long
eva looking teeth. It looks like it's the little bit a beard too. Mh. Oh, yeah.
Fits the classic c but it's not quite the
luck ness
mustard
type of
Al
or or one of those ancient dinosaur sort things. And it's a nice
variation of what people think is caesar are but should look like without having a big dinosaur. Yeah. I think it kinda matches the, like, Huey, monsters
legends from the old timing maps. But anyway, I I...
Such a cool feature design. Alright. So
on page eleven,
we're we're at Breakfast the next morning,
where Louis is
discussing his very real sixteen
dream
with the other Inducks
until they go outside and he sees the part of the boat where the serpent bent the stan
and dripped mud onto it. And so he and the other nephews
are ready to accept that it's real.
But Donald sc that sea serpents and start segments in the imagination.
And just on queue, the serpent arises behind him,
with its mouth gabe
barring those terrifying things.
I like the a abrupt change and the narrative where we have the four lessons the four problems that are caused by not knowing enough about how to sail a river boat and the fifth problem that's just a giant C Monster.
It's
unrelated to any knowledge that Donald Has or does not have Yeah. Some the four lessons
don't really apply here at all. And now it's... Oh, so you wants Let's move on. So
the twelfth page
Donald
yelp in fright and the Ducktales
trying to beat a hasty retreat, but they forget to un the more line. Donald cuts it loose, and he tells them to get ready to
to help their get away by growing
and
the serpent lunges and they barely
escape.
And so then we
transition they head to the next landing,
and they call the local sheriff,
but he is
immediately skeptical.
He pretty much brushes them off. And and, you know, I'm trying to imagine if I was
a lazy,
River Sheriff how I would react if a bunch of
outsiders
started yelling about a c surface.
I like the Huey, frames it as
Suppose he spent the tax money looking for him and didn't see him. I mean, it's it's pretty tight.
Yeah. He needs to spend a tax spare money. Warming that chair.
Yeah. I I like how Barks draws him and you get an immediate idea of of that guy's whole character,
which is don't bother me. On on the thirteenth page, they so they give up on getting help. They realized that you know, they're not gonna be believed.
And so they decide they've gotta put as much distance as possible between them and the and after a day sale, you know, the disturbance in the rear view, Donald feeling a little bit better about having the surf out of his mine, so he kinda he kinda relax a little bit.
He... Like he mentioned he he lets the nephews do all the work here. He goes off to enjoy an nap, but his app gets interrupted by the serpent rising beneath them and lifting their whole house.
Oh, donald the hero.
Thanks.
I love... I also love just
writing it off entirely. Being like, well, we've gone slightly farther down the river where this monster lives.
Clearly, there's nothing left to worry about. Everything
has been resolved Yep. That's right.
Alright. So on page fourteen,
we see the boat sliding down the sharpen back into the water.
And
donald Bravely fleas.
One of the nephews
launches
a boat
at the surface,
getting a really good direct hit in its throat.
And so
we see the serpent
rising around I really like the art in that panel because it like shows just a great sense of movement. I think, of the boat and the serpent.
The the serpent flips the craft out of the way,
it emerges
then, you know, as they're kinda recovering,
well then that nephew is puzzling over the fact that the serpent didn't bleed where he was hit. Very level headed.
For observation skills for fighting off a c serpent is I hit it instinctively
Oh, hey I did believe. I love how these kids just seem like they're moving the narrative along. You got you always got check for blood. Yeah. I mean in your wood checks are not to be traveled with That's right. Oh man, and we don't even know that they're junior Inducks, I think at this point. Oh, that's true. So, you know, I don't know. We haven't been doing the ten pager. So I'll to look that up. On page the fifteen,
the nephews are they're considering the possibility
that the serpent
is a fake.
And, you know, Donald rules that out, he's convinced,
but
then the nephew pulls
out the boat
When he recovers it, and indeed it's got a a fake rubber scale.
Donald immediately changes his tim saying that he knew was fake all along. And now that they know that it's not real, you know, they're feeling better about things they're less intimidated, and they they agree that they're gonna track the serpents or the fake service
back to its layer. Now now we've realized Al readers too that the sharpen is not real.
Reread this now, I'm like, okay. So we've taken obviously a lot of license with how this serpent act now it moves
because
we couldn't get a fake to to move this convincing. But I think it makes for good story. Yeah. I noticed the line why would anyone build such a monster? That's an interesting for foreshadowing to. There's no sensible reason for anyone to have of these.
That's right. Alright. So on page sixteen,
we
we see that they've been searching all day And so they anchor at another piling,
and they need to take watch
while most of them sleep. Huey, takes the first watch
and he is very puzzled by a humming noise that he hears coming from the water at the end of the boat that's more to the piling.
And he says that it sounds like an electric motor, but then he kinda talks himself into
assuming that it's like an underwater telephone on cable.
In the light of the morning, they wake up and donald
realizes that they have somehow changed rivers
overnight and that they are now on Mighty muddy, Mississippi. Yeah. We get some good
scale shots too. To show how big the river is from the from the viewpoint to the spa or something up here with a big steamboat in the background and a city even farther in the Barks ground. And those are... Actually, if you look up the previous page on that's a pretty detailed picture of some birds. That's...
Yeah. It's true depiction. And
and a side note, I always thought dewey we had the blue hat. If duck
told me to do we have the blue hat and this is Hue in the blue hat. So so I'm wondering if even the author gets confused sometimes. But the arthur didn't get confused Donald got confused.
This is one of those things that fans talk about how
Barks was inconsistent sometimes. And then
Honestly, the colors were just inconsistent. Because these have been we printed over the years.
They're...
I saw some reference a couple episodes ago when I was doing research, that there's, like, a hypothetical fourth nephew you called fo, which is the name that fans use when they give like a random purple coloring
for some reason to the hat. No. Sure. But but that's interesting that you guys both noticed those birds, right, the the perspective shots of the birds because I noticed that this time, and I definitely didn't as a kid that he really enjoyed drawing
drawing some of the birds
in this because there's a lot of random shots,
you know, even
when the nephew he's talking about hearing the humming sound. There seems to be like Gladstone or something flying. And and I looked it up because I was curious if this is possible.
Right, If you could accidentally
change rivers from the Ohio
to the Mississippi,
and no one answer this explicitly because it's a ridiculous question.
But by looking up the the system of of locks and stuff that are in between the two rivers, I figured out that no, you you could not do this.
Even back then when fewer of these locks were in place. So...
Ruin the story for myself
retroactively But that's okay. For the narrative
this has.
Alright. So on page seventeen, Donald goes to investigate that piling that they were tied to.
And when he projects it, they they realized that it's actually a Barks scope. They've have been anchor to a submarine
all night that towed them down river. They they see that the Periscope the subs emerges. And they noticed that there's a trail of bubbles that
lets them know where it's going. So they decide to follow it. And
to be more efficient. Donald gets out foldable din. The phone will ding i'd love to get one of those that's impressive.
I know. It looks handy. There's a neat little gag shot of a scared looking fish diving
out of the way of the bubbles that I really like. Yes. Barks
doesn't do a ton of those little shots, but he he has fun with those. And then,
you know, Don Rose
who writes
stories later, He he really takes it a little farther and he kinda cramp them in. And they're they're pretty funny. We also got a little bit of Cartoon physics as the periscope
pops back down into the water and the and the rope that they tied around it is still hovering around it. Yeah. And it was clearly.
Exactly. It hasn't read the book about how gravity works yet Al why Coyote does. So that's right.
Alright. So on page eighteen,
the nephews are looking on
at Donald
pursuit, but it's over pretty quickly
as the serpent surfaces
right away, and he motors right into its gaping mouth. I really like I really like this shot of donald
freaked out. Even if you know it's a fake serpent, you don't wanna go down that throughout. And then the nephews
are crying out as the serpent fling the boat with its tail right out of the water. I like the donald mix a recognizable
sound as he
he realizes he said it for the mouth. Work
universally yelp of surprise.
And page nineteen, the boat lands in the upper branches of a tree.
And the kids are mu over how they can track
and
capture or send subdue the serpent And they come up with a a plan.
I think it's a really great plan
considering
what they've got to work with.
So they're gonna split up Huey, and dewey are gonna go rent a large tug boat
so that they can yank it out of the water, And Louis gonna charter a a plane to to find that trail of bubbles.
Kids meet back at that newly rented boat, and they're off.
And then they don't really mention it, but this is kind of the last of of the... Their house boat.
Right? Like, we don't acknowledge it, but they're not gonna be in it anymore. And, you know, I guess it's it's kinda of real realistic a realistic touch. How do you get a house
tree? You don't?
Nice house now. Yeah. That's true. Yeah.
There is one point two as they're talking... Discussing their plan in the in the tree. You can see a little nest with a grumpy bird. And it's
scaling at them. That's not where they belong. Another little bird reference and another little site guy. Yeah.
Alright. So on
page twenty,
the kids arrive at the island in the channel where Louis had seen the surface trail bubbles. And they get to searching.
And they're so distracted
by their search that they don't hear a large river but approach
until the river about has to signal a collision by choosing its sworn. They're g River about captain,
chives the Nephews,
He calls them blind river Al, rats,
Well, the Periscope is popped up and looks on. And
this is the first time that we hear some monologue coming from the scope
as the voice sees opportunity to test out the serpent
And so the Nephews are explaining that they're searching for a c disturbance to the captain
who is very skeptical.
And the levels ominous
approach the boats.
A sea serpent he says, S ser r p e n t.
Yes. That's you have to say when you're when you're c.
You can
accent.
Yeah. He does have he
you pay access
Alright. So on page twenty one, as the captain is continuing to tell the nephews off,
the serpent
emerges.
Just utterly
terrifying the ship's passion passengers and crew
and the Frightened and captain calls out for full speed ahead.
And then the nephews cannot
continue their purse pursuit because the boats engine room has been swamped.
And they just sit in the bow
disgusted while the serpent,
the serpents operator sales away, laughing.
I feel like the perspective shot here as the serpent towers over the big the big river boats, the serpent gotta be twice as big. This what's in the previous pages.
Oh, you think we're getting some scale change. Yeah. Could be. Yeah. Al little king con versus
Syndrome, you know? You gotta. And like...
I like that he's playing around a little bit with panel
composition here to kind of yeah.
The surfing in. I don't think he
felt like he could do that. Too much previous to this.
Well, that kinda shot you could expect, you know, you kinda want you wanna be able to do it at a full panel it'd be a great on just a single page, that shot.
But
yet the more story. And you to edited it down. So it's a good way of being creative and not just sticking to just your.
Yeah. You're right. This this one definitely called out for at at least a half page, if not a full a full page.
That one is probably the one I'm gonna pick for my favorite panel. I think it's a great a great panel here. Alright. So on the next page,
twenty two, we transition to the inside of the sub.
We get a really great look
at the right? Because we get a shot of the interior.
We get a shot of the serpents
retract
into the sub from from outside and under underwater. We see how the sub moves on the bottom of the river
with some pretty cool looking tread.
I I really like how we get to learn all about the mechanics of it Inducks, a really barcode number of panels.
And we see a captain Donald and a lee looking man
that we've already talked about the scare
The scare is looking at the steam through a screen. He is just laughing...
Laughing is head off at their Right, he's having a great time. He's celebrating his invention
and he reveals that his mission is to scare
everyone on the banks the river. He wants to just generally soak confusion and tear.
And then he's gonna sc his serpent his machine ultimately,
and he wants to just disappear into legend.
And
Donald ask him why? He says that this is why...
Why why do people dance? This is what he likes to do. This is what brings him joy. It's his it's his hobby.
And he's just looking forward to spending the rest of his life
laughing at all the people and he's scared.
And he also tells Donald. He's not gonna be able to reveal anything because he's gonna bury him
in the river mud along with disturbance.
A lot going on on this page.
Any thoughts gentlemen about the scare, Eric What do you think? So he just wants to be
a really popular anonymous troll as in using today's vernacular.
He wants to
have this one inside joke that he's the only person who laughed Al. And when he fooled everybody else. He's gonna walk out that superior knowledge of I got the best of them because everyone else is an idiot. And that's enough for him. Yeah. I I I read him the exact same way I thought of him Al as, like, a precursor to an Internet troll. What about you, Ryan? I think if I'm him and I'm planning this out,
and I don't wanna kill anybody. I'm picturing Donald.
Setting donald free. And people going Did you see that sea serpent to through a ship across the river like it was it like it was a thumb tag, you know? And and
Donald going up to them and saying, no. No. No. No. It's not a real sea serpent. It's just one crazy guy he's in an underwater tank that just drives along the bottom of the river, and it has a big vacuum pump that inflate a big forty foot c serpent.
And people going you're crazy man. Why are you telling this crazy story? I I saw the sea serpent and it was huge. I think honestly,
the Giant River monster strip is probably more close then the under water saying.
No. He said he would bore it into the ground and it would be buried under the mod and no one would ever find this.
Okay, buddy.
Yeah. Admittedly, it's a pretty...
It's a pretty incredible machine. You know, this the scare,
he's got some real talent. Right? He could've
he could've put it to use in the war effort. But if I know, he he just loves to scare people And, you know, I'm not I'm not in love with the, like, the character design on the scare himself. He's, like, really sc, pretty interesting.
But I'd I love the concept. I think... I think it's a really unique concept. I think there's something very pure about I just like scare
It it it is a nice change pace from the pirate who's using to steal stuff. That ends up being ill and every Scooby doo movie or Ex
episode.
That of a monster to get into
perk game and him. It's... No. It's for Personal fulfillment, which is Yeah.
If. Yeah. He's he's not in it for the well.
He's not even in it for the fame in the sense because he's he's just in it for that sense of self
satisfaction. On
my page twenty three, the nephews are continuing to pursue. For keeping an eye for those bubbles,
and we get to follow the scares
trail of Mayhem and a wreckage,
including a smashed yacht club, an overturned River boat,
and they observed the coast guard searching for
the serpent in in pt boats and they realized that they can't reveal
what they know about tracking the serpent because they see the government would drop death Bomb is newman donald.
The scare is is monitoring
the nephews in their effort. And he brag to donald about how he's never gonna be caught,
and Donald lets this slip that his nephews track him by the bubbles. And then the scare reveals that he can turn those off at any time. You guys know what a pt bonus is? Yeah Will both. I don't I played god ship.
Yeah. It's a patrol
torpedo
specifically, I think. Oh, really? Yeah. This was like, in the earlier days of of tracking subs then would like, I think literally just drop
the depth charges.
Sure. I like how in a single page, Carl has
conveyed
the scares
plans succeeding. That we see frame after frame of all these boats
smashed and over to her and people panicking and, you know,
military searches and although it did seem out of character with all the previous issues I've read to have Donald who usually
is pretty quick about kind of evaluating
situation he's in and figuring out, you know, what what he needs to do to to come out on top to just kind of blow his his ace here and
let the guy know, you know, the only way that that the nephews are tracking it. Gotta imagine he's probably getting little light headed from Hunger or whatever at this point. Yeah. Sure. I I just I look I looked those panels that I did all that pt bone and all Al these things like what ways to taxpayer money searching for c serpent that they may may never find service.
Alright. So on
on page twenty four, the nephews
are passing over the now concealed sub,
and
they they pass it right by. And they missed it.
And they arrived days later.
In the Delta country
near the Gulf of Mexico.
And, you know, we can tell
immediately, again, we can see that transition
from the Ohio Severino the wider
Mississippi, We can now see the the delta style
where we see a bunch of reads
and
a cool sense of geography here, I think as they discussed the fact that, you know, they seem to have missed him and they wanna turn around.
They they decide now we're gonna go around just one more river band. And so when they round that bend, they see an old rec ship and Huey,, if we go by the red hat, gets the idea to h to the stern of the ship and to flow the rack down the river to use as bait for the scare.
Lots more birds in these panels.
Yeah. Also,
Boy, there's a lot of defeat conveyed in the words days later.
I've just... These boys have been, you know, in their rented tug boat, they've crossed pretty much the entire country from top to bottom now,
and Donald is still just tied to a post on
bottom of the river. Yeah. Even Al little transition bubble that says days later somehow looks looks like disappointed or something.
Yeah.
Alright. And
so on the next page,
twenty five,
we also see that the scare
and Donald are approaching the delta.
And the stair decides that it's just about time to go ahead and sc,
the submarine.
The he too is gonna round one more ever band, which sends some fear through Donald.
And as he rounds the band, he's glad that he's waited a bit more because he does see that bates steam through his paris.
He takes the bait
and the serpent emerges
for the last time,
and Huey, doing Louis are so excited that they
They accept their words. These are called spoon.
Hop the bulk instead of
drop out the hulk and wrap grove and... Yeah.
So the scare
realizes very quickly that he's been tricked
and we can see that Donald is relieved. You think he's got a fighting chance here. And then on page twenty six,
the nephews basically have one chance to stop the Severino serpent.
They managed to get the tug line looped around its neck. And then they're, like, locked in a very deadly tug war.
And the the submarine is initially
proving that it's too strong.
The mascara is pulling the nephews back towards the deeper water.
And they're they're alarms, so they signal the tug whistle to call for help. And, you know, I really like this page it when it feels like Al dangerous. You know this this feels like a very deadly deadly game here. Yeah. You can hear the suspense climax
music in the background as you read it. For sure. Pun by the whistles
the whistles sound.
And
so on page twenty seven,
the scare is able to hear the whistle through the serpent
which freaks him out because that indicates that the throw valve has been broken and and this allows water to rush into the submarine.
And the scare turns into the scared now as he
is is freaked out there's a summary is filling up with water. He threatens the nephews that if they keep going, their uncle gonna drown.
But Donald calls through the valve he eggs on the nephews
and
gives them reason to know that he's still alive and Donald points out to the scare that he has no choice, but to stop or he is doomed
and the scare
goes to pull the lever that will stop the sub, and he spares and Huey, Barks someone he can't scare. But then
the scare
realizes that his lever is jammed he believes that he is doomed And, you know, looking at this page, I like how
I like how Barks
shows how terrified the scares become. Right? Very polite. Yeah. There's a lot of sweat coming off of him.
I'm sure it's very humid down there.
Probably.
Problem, you know, Remember water. Come in. I I like how
like in the previous page, he he sent me a concern and he starts with with, but as that goes on, like, by the final spot, he's just
amplifying the wire that's in the sub itself with then all the sweat bubbles coming off and. Yeah. He's getting progressively and more freaked to out.
And then that really escalate on page twenty eight, the last page of the story
where
he's like he's so freaked out that he's pretty much cat.
He collapsed is with Fried. Donald will yell at him to cut him loose so he can stop the sub. And the scare, the pet and loose, And then Donald just smash the battery,
stopping the sub, and then he just bash the scare
over the head, stopping him,
and
then we get a really cool visual
where Donald emerges from the Sharpen throat.
He greet his nephews
with the acknowledgment, how men, you know, because they've really earned that they've proven themselves.
And then we get a a neat transition that wraps up the story
a couple days later after the capture,
the debts have received fame and glory.
But they're they're missing in their house both. Donald tells them to meet him at the pier where Uncle Sam referring to the government is gonna give them a new ship in the net queues are surprised to see when they get there that they've got the scares old sub which seems to be retrofitted into a boat, and now the serpent
The serpent is still there, but he looks a lot more c. And they get played off? They get a a hero send off with the band celebrating with them with anchors away. Is the navy
unofficial Barks song.
And that was the the serpent has smile and its face in the last panel.
Like, almost a proud looking smile. And that that is our reading
of the care of the river before I talk about the the general
consensus.
What did you guys think of this story? Ryan, why don't you go first? I I thought it was definitely
slower, than the other issues I read. I feel like the other ones were much more tightly packed with stuff happening, and this one has a lot more of just floating around.
And
they thinking about things and noticing odd things and learning about voting and
before we get to the, you know, the the final face on here in the in the river with that last abandoned hope. Right on. Yeah. It kind of kinda... The pacing kinda matches
the action of floating down the river. What about you era? Oh, I'm liked to. I thought it was, you know, you know, pretty well done with all the other ones that the...
The long story you have the intro where they're doing something has nothing to do with the actual tear, and then they get dragged in to it, which seems like it's a common thread where, you know, they're just gonna go do something and all of a sudden, they get pulled in some random and the adventure. They're not out there seeking that adventure.
They get pulled into it, and it's it's that I liked it. It was a nice president
with this
the final
the aspect that it was good with, you know, the the it then they had to track it down. So wasn't just finding the bill and and facing him they were actually in pursuit of them. We his donald was peril, which seems to really the nephews apparel and Donald trying to save them. Yeah. I mean, I I like the... I like the real peril and a lot of these early stories. It sounds like you guys both enjoyed this one, but maybe didn't love it. This one I... I'm a big fan of this one. This is probably one of my favorites of the earlier bark stories. And I did get this one pretty early on when I was collecting and reading these side I read it over and over and over. But I really love just the, like, the different aspects of it, how it... It shows, you know, the the romantic aspect of navigating the Mississippi in the Ohio river, and I loved I was kind of obsessed with c sharpen and monsters of that type. So It hit my sweet spot in that way. But I love the the design as I mentioned of the serpent.
I really liked the villain. Even if he himself wasn't that memorable, I really like his motivation
So big fan of this one. As as far as how this one is regarded,
this one is considered a classic by Barks fans for kind of the reasons I've mentioned, you know, it it shows that
kind of classic American appreciation of the rivers.
I think the villain Al well like
the c serpent.
This one on the index web page where users can submit their rankings.
This one's got a seven point seven out of ten,
which puts it above any of the other stories that we've read so far.
Previously frozen wool was the highest rated of these
with a seven point six. This one's in the ninety nine point six six percentile.
Number number one hundred and thirty eight out of the roughly forty thousand
some Disney stories that users have ranked on the site. So this one definitely is very law regard
among the the fan base. I think it really holds up, and I really like this one. I I do think, you know, it it definitely is kind of like of its time. Right? Because it's talking.
It's showing a lot of
the the war stuff is still the background, you know, like the pt boats.
Cruising and just the general paranoia of it. But I I like that there's not really anything that's I I didn't see anything
problematic in this one that I kinda had to excuse
as being of its time,
you know, there was definitely some stuff that was, like, a little dated or archaic.
Just the the pole burning shift that they passed, the whole concept of a p boat.
We still use the term uncle Sam, but I don't think that's very very, like salient these days. And I noticed that that same where they said now we're cooking with atomic gas, that was kind of a two little
thought that you wouldn't you wouldn't hear today. As far as appearances is another media, I mentioned that
Bark did do a painting
of this one that is very well like among fans.
If you guys have a moment, you can maybe Google it on your end because it's pretty cool one It's got
really nice Ducktales to pick
of the c serpent.
I don't think that this one that they ever
adopted this into any of the Ducktales
stories,
I don't think the scare has ever appeared again that I'm aware of, which I think is too bad because I think this would have made a cool concept
And, you know, if Barks brought back villains that he really liked. Right? He brings back to People boys and Gone and magic could is spell, but even if he's not as memorable, you know, his his whole
idea could have made for some some more interesting follow ups stories. I think. Yeah. And and again, it's a shame because the character design, I think so cool on that serpent.
I felt like, you know, I always like, to talk about what I learned from this one,
educational value.
I feel like I learned a lot about
river and navigation she actually. I mean, the rules are not actually that useful,
but kind of the idea that it's it's hard to navigate a house down the river.
And then it's just full of of nautical terms that, you know, things like boat hook hook and Star and the stern and piling
that I'm sure as a kid, that was the first time that I I encountered most of those terms.
So we let's talk about favorite panels, if you guys had a chance to think about it.
I I did tip my hat that... I really love the panel that shows the C serpent
looming over that steam
scaring the the g c captain.
But there's a lot really really neat panels,
all my favorites that are gonna involve that that c serpent. I also really like the one that shows him retract
into the sub
underneath the water. Eric. Why don't you if you have one in mind?
I don't don't know. Just because just give them a fan up the art and
in the other episodes other stuff we've had. I've always looked for those really neat
big half panels that looks this beautiful scene that he to pay and you didn't really get many of those in here. But I did like
when
the the nephew is on night,
and the use of, again, use of silhouette to pay in a very stark and very different kind of issue that you're used these.
And the one where he with the with the sun but the full moon and the bird flying in front of it, and nephew was slightly me shade. I think that just to me that's that's pretty. And I I really like that one. And being a visual medium, I kinda look for the things that catch by eye and yours with the giant surfing over the boat certainly they do, but that one one uses the dark to to pay the picture, it just to me really pops out from the typical color scenes that you see and everything else. Yeah. I'm I'm an easy day. I'm a cheat date. I I love a good c sharpen panel. But I'm I'm looking at the one you mentioned, and you're you're right. That's a pool panel. It's got a really neat erie vibe to it as well. He also does a really good job of using the reflection of the water of carrying the of the boat through onto the water and not just in the that eight there's several other instances were there's a still seeing where he has a nice
using the the
the river itself to extend the make sure. And but we're detailed of the same. Yeah. Ryan, What about you? I think my favorite is
the the couple cooking breakfast on the roof of their house and flat out Ohio. Just casually
sit around. I don't remember if he has the newspaper now. I'd have to go back. But
And then I think my second favorite would be
the moment where Donald turns around and sees the c serpent
right in front of him for the first time and and his mouth is open. His beak is open, like a hundred and fifty degrees probably. It's not quite not quite a hundred and eighty, but he is well And truly freaking out in that frame. And it is very
adequately conveyed in the artwork. Yeah. Both both great choices I I love also the fact that the boys... The nephew you started out this story wearing your typical hats. But once they got the river, they're all wearing sailor just like you're bottle.
That's right they're now
and no longer
adventures like, they wear the hats and every other adventure. Every other time you see, they're always hands the minute they hit the water. The little sailor caps just like mcdonald's completely colors skewed in together. And I just... It's a small detail, but it's finn has stick. Yeah. It's got the little the little details even and Donald not wearing his. He's got a captain hat. I never ever even picked up on that. Awesome.
Any
any closing thoughts from you guys anything that we didn't talk about in this one that you wanted to mention? This this starting to remind me of of some maybe silver age Marvel,
getting a villain like this
who is,
you know, mortally dangerous,
but
also
kind of weird.
Is like something the fantastic four would have fought in the sixties. You know what I mean? Yeah. And
and and and Eric's comments
a minute ago were reminds me of of...
Yeah. Yeah. There's no twenty first century comic that would have
twelve panels on a page for page after page after page. I mean, they are really just cram it in tight.
You know, any any modern comment is gonna have... There's probably one page that's like a double page spread, and there's one that's just one full page, and they're doing a lot of really different things. And this one, you know, we noted when he he experimented with the one panel that's kind of shaped, like, like home based or, like, super superman chest logo or something that was such a big departure from just the square square where all the way down.
Which is very
very dense. Yeah. And I I think I'd read somewhere that early on. They didn't really give him much freedom like it. That it was a Ducktales that he pretty much stick with the traditional panels.
Yeah. Excellent. Well, thank you guys both for
for joining
me today. I really appreciate it.
Hello. I have with me an actual
child for our Ask kids segment. Actual child. What is your name? And Mia. Mia. And what great are you in? India? I'm about to be in fifth grade. Awesome.
So mia, you read tara of the river with me. Can you tell me what what did you think about it? I thought it was one my favorite ones. I liked how the caesar
wasn't really a c It was just someone
inside who built a really cool robot? Nice. What you think about the scare? I thought he wasn't really scary when you look Al him.
He is scary when you... When like he's like, scaring from the inside of the sea serpent.
Nice.
Did you have any other favorite parts of this story. I liked it when Donald the gets swallowed.
Pharmacy
I like that part too. Let's see. Did this one make you feel like you wanted to
try house
on the Ohio River at Yeah.
I think it would be really interesting
to live on a house boat. Excellent
Alright. Well, thank you very much, mia. If any listeners have any thoughts or comments, you guys can drop us a line at Barks remarks at g mail dot com. And I hope you'll join us next time when we talk about Donald Du Adam Bomb. Thank you, everyone.