Hello, and welcome to Barks remark. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks, creator of sc Mc and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comics of all time. Join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological publishing or We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Hello. I'm Mark Sever marino a grown man who enjoys donald dot comics,
and I am joined again by a couple of other grown men.
Why don't we go with Ryan first? I'm Ryan Bailey.
I read a lot of comics, but usually with more explosions than this.
And Eric, i'm Eric hurley. I read a fair of comics with Yeah. Just five of comments. The average number of explosions.
Yeah. Excellent.
So
today for Barks Remarks, we get to talk about a pretty famous story called
Raja Donald.
I'm gonna go right into the background of this one.
This is a comic that was published in early nineteen forty seven. I don't have the exact month for this one because again, this is kind of a weird printing.
It was published in March of comics,
episode number four. And March of Comics was one of those
giveaway titles
that was published
made for
stores and retailers to put their own name on the comic and and give them away to to the kiddo.
And
So consequently,
this one is pretty rare these days because while they printed just tons and tons of copies by by the nature of the comic, parents threw them away. Kids got tired of them. So this one's pretty pretty valuable. Pretty rare.
It is
twenty eight pages
it has been reprinted quite a few times,
including by Gladstone comics for
free comic book day in in two thousand and three, which, they they did that deliberately because it was originally
published as a freebie delay. And
so a brief synopsis of this one. This one involves Huey, Louie trading their way up from Donald started stella a pencil
all the way to a steam ticket to India. Donald the common the ticket and upon arriving in India, with the nephew s away becomes Mah raja for a day and immediately gets embroiled in local palace in tree regarding rivalry between two kingdoms,
prime tiger hunting real estate and very strange custom involving a sacred mobile element So this is Mah raja Donald. Al little bit of background trivia. I talked about how this one was
giveaway similar to Donald Du Adam Bomb. I I noted two when I was looking up earlier printing that the coloring for this one
had the character
skin
being lighten considerably on a lot of the reprint
I think the the Indian character skin was originally printed as brown,
and the sensors probably wanted to avoid an controversy with that one and that that wouldn't have been something that Carl Marx
really had much
much say in. I mentioned that this one's very rare because of the nature sure of it's publishing. I I read somewhere that only, like, twenty one to fifty copies are known to exist.
And didn't find great information on its value, but I did see a very fine condition auction that had valued at four thousand five hundred dollar. So you guys this one had...
This opens with an old trope that I just love. And I remember seeing this in a lot of other, like, kids literature and kids media growing up, the the trade up. You know, the the the big barter, if you will. Had you guys... Did you guys remember seeing this in anything else because this was something that I saw a lot of how about you guys?
I
I have never heard of it as like a a kid game or anything like that, but I do remember in
two thousand, the one red paper guy, who got pretty famous as you try
something else and he traded that for something else. I mean I looked him up heated did fourteen trades and went from a paper clip to a house in in Canada.
And
and so I thought oh, that's cool. But this is like
fifty years before that. I looked it up and that guy was from... It was from two thousand five to thousand six. That's I totally forgot about. Guy. You just brought that back for me. Cool. How about you, Eric. The other one
for all those
is the classic office episode where they have garage sale and the dwight his whole goal is to trade up. And he goes say like some pencil pen or something eat. Ends up trading it up to
everybody else and he gets the telescope
yeah it's the best item there and then, of course, some classic fashion
jim place trained on traits and magic beans. We see quotes
for the telescope, and it's it's a great episode
but it as that whole training up a training up concept and Dwight explains the you're beginning. So that's right. I'd forgotten about that. Too. Does he actually start with a a pen or a pencil? A terribly starts with, but nice.
Alright. So a little bit of the background, you guys know that I I really like to talk about the historical context
that these came out of.
And
this one is, like especially fascinating to me because
Barks created a story in August of nineteen forty six.
And
again, it was published in nineteen forty seven.
I don't know exactly the
the month just because it was published for the giveaway. But nineteen forty seven is a very
significant
date
in India.
Do you guys happen to know or when a hazard to guess about nineteen forty seven in India? It's
out the brits. That that is Indian
independence. Yes. So to me, it's crazy that this
kind of came out right as everything
was
was going on in India. The the I read that the Indian independence movement and hated been building for a long time, obviously,
but this is when it culminated in nineteen forty seven. The partition
happened in forty seven. And so the interesting thing is India before the partition and before
independence,
had... I looked at up about five hundred and eighty four prince
states or also called native states.
Which were not fully and formally part of British India. So you you really did have Al these little
relatively
tiny kingdoms
that were mostly autonomous. And then basically after the brits
partition India.
Everyone kind of fell in line all of the states either
decided to become part of India or Pakistan
or we're basically concord and we're annexed
by one early.
So I I found it really interesting that obviously, this is a like, out there story as far as...
I don't think it is really trying to understand Indian deal geopolitics or anything like that. But
it's crazy to think of India basically having these little kingdoms.
And then I'm curious, do you guys know anything about, like, the term,
Once again. No. So Mah,
I mean, obviously, from context, it's a ruler
in India.
I I did a little bit of a dive into it, Mah har literally means great prints
from Sand script. So the mah part means great and raj eyes like king or a prince. So I'm Al a really exalted
can. And and I learned that it comes from Pro ind European,
the same root word as the English word much, Behind much.
So I thought that was interesting. And then it you know, Carl Barks really liked using Mah har raj does in his stories. He had to he a bunch of them and in different gag stories. So
anyway, some interesting stuff
notable appearance in this one, we don't really have any ongoing characters apart from the depths will make additional appearances. We have... I'd say the mah
Pup pad
is the most
notable character.
And then
I wanted this episode I wanted to kind start to acknowledge
the different versions
of the Ducktales that we get in some of these. Because I think Donald stands out in this one is this is a pretty, like selfish version of Donald. It's very opposition between him and the nephews
for a lot of the story.
He's not really
concerned about them for a lot of it except in as much as it affects him. And I think that's pretty different. From some of the other ones we've read where they've been
less in conflict with each other. You guys have any
thoughts
before I go into
the plot summary.
No. No. Not yet. Alright. Well good.
And as always, if you have any
thoughts in between parts of this sequence, feel free to interject. So
this story opens up with Donald asking an nephews used to clean out the garage. He promises to give them some of the junk that he doesn't want. But he ultimately lets them down by giving them a stub of a pencil.
And the kids decide to see what they can make of the pencil by trading it up. And, you know, at this point, we get that classic kid empowerment
trading sequence that we were already talking about and they managed to par their pencil stud into a ball string, a knife, silver belt buckle,
eventually into a camera. And then finally a pearl that some kids dads sent him from the south seas. And I figured that that kid is definitely in for a pad when he gets home.
Oh, oh, yes. Yes is. Hey. I have one question here. Shoot. And and that is if they cleaned out the garage, and they got everything you didn't want and all the gal was a pencil. Because they just order the garage or is he just giving the busy work because he didn't wanna deal with them. Yeah. I wonder what cleaning it means because they kinda pile up side. Yeah. Yeah sweep out... You gotta sweep out the black widows windows at some point, you know.
Let's that's point get the dust out a little bit. Yeah. That's right. Alright. So
the kids take the pearl to jeweler to get it assessed. And they're they encounter tight
who sees the pearl and decides that he needs it to complete his wife's necklace.
But the nephews are really in it for the trading. So they tell him that they're only gonna trade for it, and he offers them the steam ticket to India that he was about to use to seek out a pearl.
They take it home and they show it off to Donald.
And he points out that it's passage for only one, so he common Barks the tick.
That's a very generous way of phrasing that.
Yeah. Eric move.
Yeah. He's he's a pretty big jerk.
Through most of this story, I'd say. And and I read
a Barks
a letter in researching this. It wasn't simply about this one, But I read about a letter that he sent to some
lady who had written into the comics publisher
complaining
about how
Donald was
or he told his nephews to shut up or something like that. And he kinda roasted her and
said that, you know, these this was how Donald and the kids have gotten more popular than mickey mouse
in their cartoon shorts. In the late forties
and current fifties. So I think really, some of some of that conflict is just timing keeping with the cartoons.
So anyway, on the day that Donald is to set sail he makes it clear that the nephews need to stay at their grandma
and they asked if they can send him off with some bond voyage baskets.
And so aboard the ship, Donald gets settled into his cabin, any he eyeballs the lavish fruit baskets f and nephews
have sent, which have some very suspiciously plate stray fruits and pineapples.
He poke one of the pineapples with a Pin and figures out that indeed, the nephews have s away. I like
their the consistent
ingenuity that they have
of making the best of this situation.
Regardless of how much
donald uses there labor and steals from them.
Yeah. And they don't really seem to to put off when he deals deals with them like that. I really liked as a kid, I really liked just the look of those fake fruit baskets. I thought they look awesome.
And in a lot of her it is. Yeah. Alright. So Donald Ponder what he's gonna do about the nephew s away. And while he's doing that, the ticket purse arrives and nephew have to hide back in their bass.
And while donald
distracted the first decides. He's been swipe a pineapple because, you know, Donald obviously got a lot and he won't miss it.
So he
he inadvertently catches one of the nephews.
And I I really like the
the panel where
he reacts to lifting the nephew up by his pineapple
and the nephew is, like, silently praying that he's not not caught. I i know Cool. Alright.
I didn't catch that. I didn't catch that's pretty he was doing. I love I love the idea. I'm just, like, please don't notice that there is a dot hanging from this time.
Yeah. And
so the purse accuses Donald of harbor s, but Donald just
completely dis
his nephews. Claiming he's never seen the his life. And
So as for result, Huey, doing Louis have to work
during the entire voyage for their passage, and they're not gonna be allowed to shore because they don't have any passports.
I don't know how long
steam ship passage to India lasts, but I've gotta imagine there's a pretty long voyage. Yeah. We got...
We actually got a city in this one. I've I've I think in past podcast, I've mentioned Duck as where they're coming from. Just my memory of
eighties Ducktales.
Mh.
But in this one, they actually named Burbank Barks. Yeah. That's right. True Yeah. And Carl Barks will use Burbank as their
hometown quite a few times.
I don't know at what point he starts to refer to buck to
because he does, but I think it might be around when he does the uncle Scrooge adventures, and then it just gets rep into it.
But... yeah. I mean, Barks,
he, you know, he was part of Disney animation. So
I know we spent a lot of time there. And made sense that Burbank Barks would be on his mind.
Alright. So
as Donald is getting ready to dis
ship. He realizes that the nephews have swiped his passport
and in the process of chasing him, chasing...
Oh, yes. His think then they take his passport too? Yes. I.
He's not gonna be allowed to
to leave. And
they encounter while they're you know, in Chase, they encounter
an Indian man who offers to secure their passports
in return for a small favor. And, you know, this guy just ooze with suspicion.
He's clearing his throats suspiciously,
basically every time he speaks. But he assures Donald that, you know, there's not gonna be anything dangerous about the task. And he asks that the Ducktales join him at his Palace in his kingdom.
And when they're really skeptical, he asks the captain to introduce him, and the cap and announces him as the Raja of Abdullah. I I love the tit tat that these deputies have with the. You know, he's like their ticket, they still wait thinking they're gonna stick him with the bill. He says no you're not. You're gonna work for. I don't know you. Maybe step working and and the, well, we're gonna take take it, so it's the stereo aspect of the relationship well not being enemies is
fantastic of just such honestly
such a family relationship.
I mean, I can't tell you how many times me and my brother to go like, yeah. Screw you. Well we ask for you too? Dang. Okay. I i'll do this. And it just continues on and onward so eventually somehow has to stop, but that that this right here covers it very well and nature that kind of relationship.
Yeah. There's a lot of s escalation here, you know? And I think if you wanted to read into it...
I don't know, he's their uncle,
maybe they're coming terms.
We we've acknowledged that there's not really a a ton of continuity here but I do find it interesting that in some of the stories, this is the kind of relationship that they've got this very conflicted
relationship.
Alright. So
the docs are
encounter the
Al.
And
I didn't look it up, but I... I'm pretty sure that the Palace has basically styled after for the Taj Mahal. Do you guys know? Did you guys do that strike? He was... I would assume that's just what they... That's what people know. That's what they're gonna go with.
It... I can see it being influenced by the Taj mahal. It doesn't look particularly
like i good like this in my opinion Well, it's definitely supposed to look very, very lavish.
Yep. So the the ducks
they they go in and they ponder what their task might be.
And then we see the mah
con kind Sneak between one of his men talking about Donald. Being perfect for the task he has in mind based on his size, so we're getting some hint of it. We're getting a hint that he's being completely set up. So the Ducktales tour the mah
Palace, including his j rooms,
which
he notes that he fills by loan gold to neighboring kingdom,
and then he accepts repayment and diamonds.
He shows them the borders of his kingdom,
and it's especially the nearby kingdom of boom pay. And he despair that they have the finest tiger hunting land but he notes that he'll own it someday.
And he reveals that he holds their mortgage and that by custom they have to make a payment every year in diamonds or in land. But he seems to leave out some detail. And so the Ducktales enjoy
luxurious nights And then the next morning, they dress in fine indian
clothes.
I did also notice on this page, he mentions the first or two times in this issue, if days you could only see me now and I have not seen days you mentioned in any previous issue. Yeah. That's a good point. Daisy appears a lot in the in the ten page comics
that were large actually not gonna be talking about.
I don't think she appears in very many of the adventures stories. There's only one of them that I can think of offhand, but maybe we'll we'll come more. But, yeah. Usually,
usually she's the subject of ten pager.
March even han her is the main character and some of the ten pager.
Alright. So the next morning they learned from another
suspiciously
coughing attendant that they are to meet the mah raja in his elephant yard.
And there they learned their going be riding an old sacred elephant
across the river into the capital city of Bum,
where they're going to find, quote
hospitality different. From anything you expect. So Donald has has qualms. This one's kinda unique. Right? Because it's Donald to seems to have
some inkling that something's not right
instead of an nephews use. But the kids encourage him to take mah up on it. And so they they get on the elephant. And as they get across the river,
Donald Reassure him self that, you know, when he reaches the other side of the river riverbank, he can always turn back. He doesn't like the look of things. But then we cut the mah raja and he's waiting
he's aiming a big artillery gun at them and they realized that, you know, they're in for it, and they have no choice but to continue on. So I I I noticed when he when he said that you'll find the hospitality different from anything you'd ever expect struck me as
just a variation on the in all movies and Tv shows where there's some shady guy and
he's like Can just do this thing for me. And you'll get exactly what's coming to you.
Like oh, that's great. It's money. Right? You're gonna give me money. Yeah.
It says that to me, I'm gonna be like, oh, oh, you're going to kill me.
Like, no. No. No. I'm just saying.
You're going to you deserve
They clearly need to watch more classic television.
Exactly.
Alright. So
they they continue to ride the elephant but, of course, they don't have any choice. And and route, we see that they're definitely passing through some of that prime tiger hunting land because they have to fend off a tiger attack, which the nephews do very briefly. While Donald stays hidden,
and they point out how lucky he is that they didn't stay at their grandma after Al. And
Eventually, they're gonna arrive in the kingdom of.
But first, we we kinda do a a preview cut and we see Bump royal tax collector
and they're regal compile of the deficit,
talking about the terms of their loan. And and this this is very Barks seeing to me these, like, over the top titles,
and I love it. I love those... I love their
their
their jobs.
And so they we we kinda learned that the terms of their loan dictate that if this mobile elephant
returns with
someone very small. They may have to surrender more of their tiger land. They haven't learned exactly the details though
So the Ducktales arrived and they get greeted
with all this like, pom and ceremony,
but
the men are just sc with the whole time. Wall Greek.
Kinda funny. But.
How do they write a mortgage this way? You know?
Right.
I understand it's all a plot device to get Donald in Peril, but
before we... Do you have a person yet but it weighs. You
say out can involved. It's like there's culture, there's an any culture
or supposedly culture i suppose that i no idea how close assistant. Anything they actually
did back then.
Or those kingdoms ever everyday. But then tie it into a modern mortgage. If right,
hilarious.
Yeah. It it's super convoluted. And I think there's a little bit of hand waving about... You know, how how those foreigners
do things
because, you know, people travel less for all you know. This could be true. But it's definitely
it's definitely a funny set up.
Alright. So this is where Donald gets to learn
what's going on. I he he finds out that because he's writing the mobile Ellis and he is now the raja of Bump.
And of course, because he's donald duck, he, you know, swell up with pride immensely
and they lead Donald around his new Kingdom. They show off to him.
This is gonna be that second time that he mentions Daisy and the context of Daisy could only see me out. And then we got a great gag shot of him learning that he has a hare of lives
He also
meets his army of three soldiers.
I guess, I guess, fewer soldiers, but then why
And then finally, he gets to sit down to his lunch, which he initially believes to be caviar,
but turns out to be Barks shot. And when he asked what's asks what's going on.
He finds out the specifics of this weird convoluted mortgage scheme.
But pays mah has to be weighed once every year and if he doesn't weigh as much as a hundred pounds of diamonds,
which by my math is a hundred pounds.
But then bump is loud.
If if he weighs hundred pounds, they're allowed to pay their interest in diamonds
But if not, they get more of their Tiger land fore closed on.
And then Donald further learns that This is not an option. And if he doesn't make the way he's gonna be fed to the royal tigers,
and there's no escape What do you guys think of this
this scheme between gum and?
Well, I mean, on the price side, they was specify the quality of the diamonds, Just a hundred pounds. I mean, you can have
just
s low quality, you know, keep all the license for yourselves, but just go for the the worst possible diamonds you can have. But that's thinking. Yeah. That's true. I don't think the mah really cares about the diamonds
judging from how he talked about him how sick of them he is. Alright. So
I'm trying to figure out who the bad guy in the story is. Because I'm not sure it's would've tricked four ones that Are gonna feel with the tires. I mean, my instinct is that it's donald.
Yeah. I would say everyone but the nephews probably and story it's the villain.
Yeah.
That's something that I'm gonna talk about when when I when we reflect on the one because that definitely came to mind. Alright. So Donald Donald calls out to He doing Louie, and he explains what's going on
and that he desperately needs their help.
And so they ponder possible solutions and ultimately, they ask
for a bag of gold dust. To be sent up because, you know, he is the mara raja,
even if he's definitely gonna be fed tigers.
And they I think I thought this was very clever. You know, they sift it into his feathers,
and they managed to get his weight up to ninety eight pounds. So they just have a couple pounds to make up.
Grabs what he thinks is a hose, a water hose, and that mcdonald's drink two pounds of water.
Unfortunately,
he fails to notice that it's a gas outlet.
And we get a little bit of cartoon logic here.
Because it does not... It does not kill donald,
but rather he is tighter than air
And when the way it arrives, they find him floating mid air.
And the mara
Abdullah, he's also there to witness the way in. And he sees him tied to the scales
and ultimately weigh in at sixty pounds less than nothing.
So, you know, they're their worst fears of them true. They're gonna lose their tiger lands. And oh, yeah they have to feed
feed their my to the tigers.
And then one of the bump money men, he hopes out loud that something awful falls on the.
And we get some nice comic timing where Donald deflate in that moment and he lands right on him. And he... You know, probably because
And then I like this sequence where the Al set
announces
to the citizenry,
the the imminent feeding of their exalted Raja to the tigers.
And they encourage them to rush the box office for tickets.
And then the that piece kicked out of the palace so that they don't try to interfere with things. Yeah. That's a great weight loss program and she can just, you know, suck some gas. And just often
waist sixty pounds
later than nothing.
Yeah. Hear once you stop sucking the gas down the way comes all back.
Alright. There wins.
We get use. They're they're despair, but they don't count have any options
until they stumble upon another stub of pencil and they decide that they're rich.
And so we got a nice book ended trading sequence
where
they're gonna trade up the pencil into something to help their uncle.
And
they they trade first the pencil to an old man, they convince that that he can use it to darken his beard for a good lock charm. And then they trade that a minor bird from a man that they call Pun punjab.
And then they trade that to a British colonial list on his way back to England. For his bin,
and then we kinda skip ahead like we did the first time. Ultimately, they land at five hundred pounds of cats boot. And they Barks. They parked the card outside the royal tiger pin and start to toss it all in. I I did like this. This was a good
a good, like, both a callback to the beginning and
I could show up their own clever the, you know, the one red Paper clip thing is just a satisfying concept on its own. It's just satisfying to watch it. Yeah. I agree. I really like the the book trading here. Well, as i say normally in these touch stories, it's there's some kind of convoluted goo
the story that just kind of falls on the wayside. But this one, it's actually really good for foreshadowing of this how they do it and the fact that the board basically say, they they don't think there's zero pessimism with a pencil.
Yes. We're doing it. They can say not wanna yeah. We can do that again, like, nope we got this down. We are master traders Al this. Yeah. There there are a lot of good callbacks in this one. Right? Because they they call back the joke about staying at Grandma's house a couple of times.
And that they that Barks goes back to, you know, he sets up Daisy, and then he refers to it again. It's it's good rules of comedy. He's he's really following there. Alright. So in the morning, Donald is forced into
the coli
where the crowd gonna watch him be
But of course, the the tiger's w out and they're just too over fed to even give them a second look. And everyone is just disgusted
with their terrible terrible mah.
They're so disgusted that the money men asked what it's gonna take to
just get him out of the country. And
Donald, you know, initially doesn't ask enough, buddy he ultimately fin first class Huey, tickets where he doing louie.
And on their voyage back home, they agree that they are all even. And that
is mah raja Donald.
Alright. So
we're gonna talk about how we felt about this one separately.
I'm gonna ask you guys to give your opinion, but I do wanna talk first about kind of the general consensus.
As always, we like to check the index
website that's tracks user reviews for all disney comic stories. So it gives a good aggregate
idea.
And
this one, you might be surprised
for you or you might not. I don't know.
This one is rated very, very highly. This is a very well regarded story of Barks it has a seven point seven out of ten on the index page,
which puts it right now at one hundred and sixty four. Out of the almost forty one thousand disney comic stories that are rated.
Good enough for the top ninety nine point six.
Percentile
of all stories.
And I think we're eight episodes in now.
And so we've got
yeah. This is our ninth story because of of course last one was a two for. And so this is actually the second best regard out of all the stories that we've done by kind of the general fandom
The only one that's higher and it's just by
very small fraction would be terror of the river. Is still our best regarded story that we we've done. So I I find it really interesting that this one is so highly regarded because this one's not really one of my favorites.
But I guess, I guess it does fall into some of the classic,
you know, things that people do love about Carl Barks stories, which is some of those
adventures
in really far flung places.
Some of that kinda happens stands where the the or kind of fish out of water and become embroiled and something bitter.
I personally
I do love the trading sequences.
That book that book
this story. I thought they were great.
I remember just loving it as a kid and coming back to that part. On the hold, though, I don't really like how cool donald is to the nephews using this one. And like, most of the peripheral characters and the story are also really un like.
I mean, it's it's very za and it's it's a very weird and intriguing like plot device.
So it's definitely interesting. But I remember finding this very off putting as a kid. You know, This was in the collection that I had. They hard bound collection. I think this was the one out of the ten or so stories that I read least.
I do still find this one a bit off putting as an adult, and I also have a hard time getting past some of the kind of orient
trapping things of it. Although I do think it doesn't... It... It's not as bad as somewhere
of that time in regards to how it it treats
South Asia. So that that's my thoughts on this one. Eric, how about you? What did you think of this story? Well, I mean, when you talked about how the depiction... Yeah. This certainly is
you know, I seen the eye raising, but he kinda show like, yeah, that was the time there wasn't Al lot of understanding of other cultures and we making a lot of stuff could do need come on
but but still being, you know, that's still being ridiculous
as comic should be. But I I obviously... As I read through it, I like I can see what I'm donald on the and the Al the serial aspect of it. I didn't like that coming to terms at the end would you remembered, hey, get my nephews
these things and in me and having him say, hey, guys. Hey. We're on it. We'll be work you know, we we we we fight bigger but we're family and we're gonna save you And I thought I thought it was well written just like you take earlier, just the whole beginning the the reoccurring jokes
still kinda to head wrap my head around the hard who legally
needed to make a mortgage of pay by diamonds or hydra land,
which I don't think tigers... I'm not minor understanding ky they need a lot more land than that to roam but if it could story it gets the story. So.
I I liked it. I I it didn't have a lot of the jumps of logic of,
say the
Scrooge little gobble people that live in the swamp and make you forget. I mean, which are very entertaining, but this seems like a classic, you know, fish out of water, you know, that's out of country story and that's the they way be Barks on. Right on. So we're so we're you to surprised that this one is as well regarded as it is. No. I'm I'm I'm not surprised. I I can see. I certainly see what people would like it and how it how it works out.
With its writing and portrayal is it pretty much stick to their portrayal and and some fashion of donald getting screwed and the nephew you saving right on. How about you Ryan? What what were your opinions of this one? There were aspects of it. I liked.
None of them had anything to do with the
time in in the other country. So, yeah, I guess just kind of the nephews
clever and just kind of the way they handle all the different situations, I thought was really appealing thing donald be awful to them as their only caregiver.
I thought was pretty
disheartening.
And then... But but most of all, like, the this society, I guess, we'll call them an Indian society, because that's what we're going for here. They're so they're so bizarre. Like, if it didn't have to be indians. And it I think it would have made more sense if it was not if it was like martian
or like some kind of weird magical
society from travels or whatever that doesn't follow any logical
rules are in there in their cultural
makeup up there because because these guys are so weird.
It's so so weird. And, like, at the end, at the end when they're like, what would it take to get you to leave the country? I was like, well
he wanted to leave earlier, while I just let him leave earlier, you took him prisoner and then you're going to execute him for not being heavy enough
just some innocent guy that some other guy sent over there.
Like what I think the execution was, like their consolation prize. Right? Like, we know he's gonna fail us, at least we can have this entertainment of watching and get eaten. But but I agree, it's not really recognizable human being. I mean, it's not even like like, he had committed a crime or something. Like, he was just a guy it was just some guy. Never were able to leave railroad into it. It's too like. Let's kill him
like and like, why did it why so like the tigers. I'm picturing like, the tigers or the Supreme court, and they they are the ones who decide if he lives or dies.
The Tiger so like know, this guy's fine, this guy gets to live and they go okay. Well, we'll we'll buy you some first class tickets back home
And does he retain a title?
I mean, he's not like easy to coast. Is he... Can you build himself or as me of the corner on her i okay?
Yeah. Think that's that's a good point. He
I get the feeling that the others all ab indicated because they eaten by Tigers. So is the raja and exile.
And if they just wanted to kill him, no other ways to kill him. You know, I mean, they could just get a guy with Al black hood and a big x.
These guys these guys have a stadium just for this, though. They... That's true. They're They do They don't have an execution to city They have a Tiger stadium. Right.
Well, anyway, I I get your points.
It sounds like you... Go ahead. And more thoughts like can't have the Russia for more than a day, like, why not send someone over a week before the way in, and he could, like...
Even if he's gonna die, he can, like, eat some nice meals and you can make a go. Yeah. He can make a go of it and have some, you know, a good a good last run there open whatever have some kind of attempt instead of being like, we're gonna send someone over who obviously doesn't meet the terms. You have, you know,
one Al the as the
of
rules lawyer this and and, you know, making sure that he's showing up without time. Catch and
Let's not just kind the fact that the my of Who do
didn't have somebody in mind.
Until he saw him on the boat.
That's true. I mean, this was clear happened every year. So you would think Huey, have a backup somebody?
Is there no service that you is the on entourage wanna, like oh no tigers for me. Your all
probably gonna be one of them. So it's just the interesting
product. But anyway anyway... It's just gonna
that.
That guy is the the ruler of his country. Right? Is that he's the way who holds the mortgage, and he is personally
going out on a boat from Burbank. To Find the latest guy he can find for that boat.
To sucker into this deal.
And then when, you know, when when they're sailing on there across the river there, he is
manning the howard.
Very hands on Mah.
For sure. Yeah. And, you know, I guess when you got an scheme, you know what you don't wanna trust it to be bought and rock steady. You know, you wanna take take care of it yourself, so it doesn't get screwed up. It's tighter than it's high man. You gotta... Yeah. Make sure you you close the deal. Yeah. Right.
Alright. So we've we've talked about the story. We've we've given our reflections
Let's see. Not not really a lot of appearances,
You know, there media as popular as this one is Sparks never did that I'm aware Of never did an oil painting based on this one.
I'm not aware of any aspect of this story being referenced and any future stories, although someone couldn't enlighten me. I didn't really find a lot
educational about this one kinda like we were getting at the the whole cons truck of the idea of India is very fan.
I wouldn't be surprised if Barks didn't use some Natural and geographic reference for some of the buildings, but beyond that, I don't think it really reflects
anything
accurate here. About india. Favorite panels, this is always a fun feature.
I had a number of panels I liked there were also this was one though where I noticed, there were a lot of panels that had kinda unfinished art, right, or blank backgrounds in this one. So
I feel like he... I don't know. Maybe he was pressed for time on this one. But at any rate, I did really like the
one I mentioned
where the Nephew getting pulled out of the fruit basket.
There's a really cool panel
on the steam ship.
Just
has it sailing over where Donald was saying India. Here I come. I thought that was a really nice looking panel.
I was also very taken by the the gem room when he's showing off his piles of diamonds. And it struck me that, you know, this is kinda one of the times that Barks is tipping is hat to being very interested in characters that a mass, huge amounts of well. Right
introduce uncle Sp, not too far down the road.
And I did really like the panel that we're we're post to, I think really like where the
Palace is revealed for the first time. But I think my favorite one is when the tit is lung at the scared elephant
after they crossed the river, i the perspective on that one.
I like it as a cool action shot. How about you guys? Any any panels really stand out as a favorite.
I like that one the both. The title words the
steam going across in India ga
That's should be bigger shot. But then I I also like the one right next to it, which is now I'll like, I'll go my statement just for dinner. You see in the background
a lady standing the railing, and it looks like you can tell that the is blowing. So it's actually got some movement going on in the background and it's
maybe the sharpest the yellow here on yellow background.
But it was just nice background scenery
on
the boat ride, and the same one with these
leaving
before the boat when he's meeting
synced goodbye a burbank essentially, know, leaving home behind and it's this the distant shore and he's in the silhouette has perspective. I would have loved to seeing these some of these panels on a larger scale a little more finished, but you're saying would been really good. That being said,
the image of the Fan tiger just makes me laugh time.
How you're drilling in. Big belly tongue hanging out, low and like, no. No no. I'm good. I'm inside a funny spot lay down. Yeah.
That you can't... That's some pretty good comedy. Those
very fat happy tigers.
And and donald the one next to it, but both of the ones that show the tigers, the wealth fed tigers
are pretty fantastic panels with Donald just sweating profusely sleep.
How about you ryan any any?
Listen is the India here at.
I feel like it's kind of reminiscent of
like the Japanese flag and maybe you get that kind
really nice blue on the ocean
and then and then a really dark orange sun with yellow rays coming out at different angle there,
which is very pretty...
One yeah made chuckle,
as I read it was when the...
I don't know if he's a Oh, he's the the ticket taker guide. The person
is in their room, and when he discovers the nephews and says still, I get it, then it says, so that's the setup and he he puts his J hughes finger right in donald Barks space and done like his leaning way back and he's got the finger right on his beak.
And it's it's just really great pose but
I thought with well frame. Yeah. You're you're absolutely right. That one's hilarious.
Very nice. He's got the obligatory sweat bead shooting at the side of his head. It's seems being accused to bring on so it's Oh, and then I did forget
to
do... And then in the reflections part. I forgot to
talk about things that might be dated or archaic versus
retro grade. The what stood out to me is dated was it was fun to see some of the old stuff that they traded up, like, the very old style camera.
And then the idea of a young kid having a pocket knife to trade, I know that you Youtube both probably were kids who had pocket knives
but
not not a ton of them that age would today. And then just the idea of taking a steam to India course is very very archaic. As far as things that didn't help don't hold up well, you know, we already went into this. Obviously, the depiction of India. I mean, it's kind of a fine line. Right? Like, it's not great. It's not awesome.
But on the other hand, at least, he didn't
try to use a car accent
with the character
That is true. He did show... He did show most of them wearing turban
and, you know, that that's a common trope, but but those are my understanding is that those are only weren't by seek people.
And then, you know, we had some of Al very orient
probes like har and and feeding people that.
But
but again, on the whole, I I've I've seen worse depictions.
I think that we have pretty much covered
Har Donald.
This one was... I hear have question Mark. Yeah. Certainly. Absolutely.
They never got the gold off of Donald.
Hey.
One of the greatest smuggling gag I've ever seen is
discounts
in gold
and glue and
then get around. So I just Mean, I don't know if that i gonna pay rent.
Well what. But they never... And they never saying how much, but it has
amount. They never have to build those
run around with it. Yeah. I mean, it's it's tap glue, but still that was that was one of my takeaways at this days so came out with from a gold lining in the too.
Oh man.
I you had to go there.
That may be why they look so content lounging on those deck chairs on the way back. Excellent.
Thank you for pointing that out.
Alright. So any other final thoughts before we wrap this one up? No. Not
Got awesome.
Well,
thank thanks to all our listeners for joining us. If you've got any thoughts or comments, please drop us the line
at Barks remarks at g dot com. You can check out our Facebook page as well. And please join us next time when we talk about volcano Valley. Awesome. That's a wrap.