Hello, and welcome to Barks Remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer Al artist of the greatest Donald and unscrew comments of all time. Join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing or order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Hello. I'm Mark Sever,
grown man who enjoys donald dot com,
and I'm joined by another grown person who I've managed to convince to let me talk about Said comme.
If you can introduce yourself.
Hi. I'm Sarah, Santiago.
I am from Phoenix, but I'm currently living in
the land of Scrooge Inducks.
Scotland.
Yeah. Very exciting. Maybe we can get you back to talk about
Scottish step one. But Cool.
But today, we are here to talk about the Bark
story
volcano Valley, and I know that we both have some
strong thoughts about this one.
So
let's see. Before we get into it, Sarah, can I ask you what your background
is in comics.
I have very little background in comments.
It turns out that I have a problem with tests switching
between visual and verbal. And so every time I try to read a comment, I would just get really confused and not know what was going on. And it wasn't until my mid thirties and I figured out that was going on
which makes me very sad because it is such an excellent medium and there are so many stories that I just have people tell me. So this is not like, unusual. I will sit people down and say please tell me this story about deadpool and this.
And then I'll just listen
because I want to... I want to consume the stories. I just can't do it in the medium provide And so I have translator. So you're like you like the story and the Barks, but maybe separately.
Yeah.
Well, we can we can look at those separately
in in this because this is a podcast. So, you know, it's we've got
an auditory medium to talk about something that's very visual, so that should be a good challenge. So you... It sounds like you you like some of the superhero stuff even if you don't read it directly.
I I do...
And I did... I did read... I saw I used to be a part of a podcast called educating Geek.
And it was instead of saying, oh, well, you haven't
seen red
whatever this. You're not a real geek. We would turn that on his head and say, oh, you haven't seen red heard whatever.
Let me introduce it to you. So I was introduced to the sand, which is not a good comic to be introduced to if you don't understand how to navigate
through the medium yourself, but I loved it. And I'm so excited that I get to consume the story
in, like, a movie Tv show. I can't remember what how that's being felt, but I'm really excited for that to come out. Yeah. Something look forward to.
Alright. Well, as mentioned, we are talking about Volcano Valley, and we...
At barb remarks, we start off with little little bit of background about the story. This con was published in the the cover date is May of nineteen forty seven. I guess that means it's actually April forty seven.
In the old series four color, number one hundred and forty seven,
it's been reprinted a number of times. And this one is one of the longer ones, actually, this one is thirty pages.
For a brief synopsis, this one involves Donald accidentally
buying what turns out to be a real plane,
believing it to be a worse surplus model for the net use.
And he quickly sells it to a g from the fictional country of
joins him on a plane ride and basically gets stranded in in that backwards country.
There's a lot more to it than that and we'll we'll get into that in our summary soon. But
a little bit more background
and trivia.
This one saw
it was rep
in a kind of an unconventional format I think the late sixties d's as a width... A Whitman big little book. I'm not very familiar with those, but saw that when researching it. And then
in reading about Barks something that comes up a lot is that
he
he wrote a lot of these
far flung adventure stories in foreign lands,
largely based on his readings of national
geographic.
And is is widely known to not have really traveled very much until much later in his career.
But because he was based in Southern California,
you know,
from his Disney
animation days, he did make it across the border into Mexico for day trips.
So
I think that may have given him some background for this one, but honestly, I don't think the depictions of the characters and this one are they're probably not
based on those visits. They're more based on some
pretty widely held stereotypes.
Of that time, things like speedy ones gonzales and and so forth. I did find the value range for this one. There was documented sale of a nine point four grade, which is a very good condition for seven thousand two hundred and fifty dollars.
Alright. So you know what, Sarah, I I feel the need to kinda take a moment
and acknowledge
that
I don't feel very warm and inclined towards this one and I don't think you do either. It's... You're in the newbie seat today, and it's it's a shame in a way
to to introduce you to Barks with this one because.
I don't have a lot of love for this one. I... I'm gonna go out of my way to find some things that I like about it, but
I am got. I actually didn't have fun with us. The the the content
it it was funny. And, of course, it's funny because this is not happening right outside, you know, our doors. So it's it's funny to laugh at how racist they were in nineteen forty Severino. I did
though
enjoy the depictions of the volcanoes.
Because I did go to school for geology and my husband has Al volcano knowledge. And right now,
I spent most of my time watching
live streams as Al volcano and on Youtube.
So I... We had some really good discussions in our house last night about
salt versus
headache versus
sit and what soda means? Soda versus fantastic and and Al that kind of stuff. It turns out that there's some value in the volcano story.
I'd agree. I think
I I really like the high concept
a volcano valley itself if we're getting past some of the stereotypes. And I I I do wanna agree with you right away. I I... In ent the Internet, you know, it's not too hard
to find people who will defend this. Story. Right? Because for for the kind of the reasons they usually do, and I I get where people are coming from, but
you know, we'll we'll go into why I I don't consider this one very redeem
in a way that that I do can it or some of the other problematic,
Bark stories
that this one's kinda unique, but
I don't want to... I don't wanna go too hard on it because there is a... There there are some fun moments
and some some good humor in this one. So talking about some of the background, you know, we can kinda split this into, like, historical versus
geographical this time versus geological, which is which is fun.
I mentioned this was released in
nineteen forty seven,
and I... I'm gonna think of this kind of Al the era of War ser.
Right? As as the war wound down,
this is something that there's this plot point of the the docs buying something accidentally
as war surplus that turns out to be a full on plane. And this is a trope that I've seen
in a lot of older media.
And, you know, I think that's kinda wound down by now, but in the decades after the war, I think war surplus was like this.
Huge
industry for a while as the government had to get rid of, like, un accountable amounts
of
equipment.
I I told you that there was kind of a crazy coincidence here that right as this one...
Rise were set to record this one.
A a guy for who writes for the
Geek website bleeding cool named Barks Sea.
Published a pretty detailed article about this story and you don't really see a lot of mainstream
stories about, like,
very specific bark comics. So I'm gonna acknowledge that I kinda wrote off his
background on this one.
Yeah. And it was a fascinating loop
researched article as well. Right? It wasn't just talking about the comic itself. Right.
It was talking about how
more surplus
planes were...
Actually the thing that were bought sometimes by the dozens and
and
by
regular people for regular reasons.
Right. And and today that that would, you know, I don't I don't own be too.
Now that the government
stopped using no.
Although, I did look into it and
There are quite a few old fighter planes,
American Endpoint that you can get for less than it would cost to buy a lamborghini.
Wow. I mean, that's an opportunity. You know, you and I both lived in
the Phoenix area for a long time, and I'm sure you...
Like, I did drove past the
the, like, salvage yard near tucson, right? Where they do commission
planes and and and so forth by the thousands? Because because Uncle Sam owns a lot of this stuff. Yeah. So, yeah. I I think I think it's fascinating. I think it's a cool
I think it's cool way to kick off a story.
I wanted to mention a little bit about the good neighbor policy. Right? This was the United States approach to foreign policy.
That
Roosevelt, Franklin Roosevelt kicked off.
When
when the nazis were
ramping up. you know, they they wanted to make sure that they stayed that Latin America stayed aligned
with
the Us.
And
so
there was a lot of, like, friendly relations which kind of ended
ended in the run up to the cold war when the Us became even more pronounced
intervention.
But
it... It's really interesting if you look into like the history of Disney and Latin America.
Because there was, like a a very famous
goodwill trip that walt and a bunch of the big... The big waves that the Disney Studios made.
I think in the thirties,
that was... Or maybe the... Oh, was nineteen forty two. And that was like a a government sponsored
goodwill trip.
That
resulted in the release of Al
And the three Cabal. Do you know those old animated ones?
No. But is that where we get the
three ami.
Like, is that that error?
No. This is... Do you know the, like, Al Ami is Donald with a couple of South American
characters named Jose
Katy, I think from Brazil.
And there's a mexican ru whose name I'm spacing on. These were like their war time film. So they were much shorter
you know, they it was what the studio did to survive, basically.
And, you know, they were taking this government cash to make these and a foster goodwill.
And the...
It worked pretty well. Right? Because those became pretty beloved Disney characters
in Latin America like, a lot of latin Americans really enjoy the
the three cabal
characters. Oh wow. And and so I
Who was the third if it was if it was Donald Duck and Jose Ga?
Oh, man. You're gonna make me remember
hon cheap though. Yeah. On cheap though, it's listed as Peace
here, but I've never...
I've never heard that as his full name. But, yeah, It's it's pretty famous.
It's like a mix of live action and animation.
I don't think it's the best of Disney's movies around that time. But it's worth checking out. You know, if you've got Disney plus. So... Oh my gosh. Yeah. I'm not saying that I don't think that this was like a dictate or anything
as part of that whole Disney movement, you know, to foster goodwill, but it it did come at the same time. So part of me wonders if this is kind of what was going around the Disney offices.
You know, this one doesn't strike me as much of a goodwill piece because
it is it it relies so much on on stereotypes.
And and I think people would fairly point out that, you know, these were widely widely held stereotypes
at the time and still are. That doesn't
excuse them, but it does help us.
Understand them and contextualize utilize them. So So in my research,
I did a deep dive in
the Lazy
Mexican,
the sleeping Mexican
stereotype.
And a few years back
journalist plus out.
Who have Al asked a Mexican fame.
Wrote a really good piece about it giving a lot of
history and context and and and how it's how the sleeping Mexican is viewed in in the Us versus how it's viewed in Mexico
itself. And and just to interrupt the this
specific image you're talking about is the classic one of
usually a Mexican man
like,
Didn't about it running back sometimes against this tomorrow because that's what you do Sure. And is his
is
is pulled down to cover space, and he's he's he's sleeping he's resting.
Exactly. Taking a Si. And and so
One of the things that I found interesting was that obviously, the the lazy Mexican stereotype
pre existed this character
or this this image. And and it's it's a popular image north and south border. South of the border, they they see it as
a man resting rightfully after a hard day's work. But then we get more and more tourism.
To the border areas.
And these images turn into gucci
souvenir and
that
instead of the Americans
seeing it as a a hardworking person
rightfully taking
rest. Yeah.
They apply their
stereotype to. Right. So it's it's losing... It's losing the nuance.
And it's only
packaging
kind of the after version. I I didn't read the same article, but I found some of the same
discussion about this kind of either reclaiming or contextual utilizing that.
Because again... And and there are a lot of
people artists especially who's say... No. We wanna reclaim. We want to
redefine this as somebody who has worked extremely hard and do deserves reps. But of course where Americans
and American Capitalism
specifically says no risk even if you worked hard. And and no Nuance either.
And no no so that's gonna be a hard sell. Right. And Mike you mentioned, you know, the community is not like monolithic. You you find people Right It's not hard to find people
Mexican American people or Mexican people who actually love this imagery. But again, they understand the New ones. I would say. Mh. It it's the same way that money Mexican Americans and mexicans
truly love, like speedy south But, again, you know, there's not a lot of room for a new one. So But sometimes we're just thrilled to see some representation
even if it's terrible
right.
There's also that. Right. When when you're thrown when your throwing straps,
and it's all you've got, it it tends to look better.
So
just a little bit more background before we go into the story itself. I I usually talk about notable appearance because we don't have any long running characters and this one other than the Ducktales themselves. The representative
from
Is major pablo Money
And
you had pointed out, would you mind mentioning what is
problematic about his very name. Right. So
Means it could be morning.
It could mean tomorrow
there along with the lazy person, placing Mexican stereotype.
There's this pro procrastinate.
Right. Right. So I'm gonna put off... Oh, I don't need to do it today. I'll do it money on. And you pointed that out can I... I had always thought of that as as morning. Was that's how I was translating it. So
we've got major Pablo Money, and then we talk... I'm I'm starting talk in these episodes about
what version of the characters we get because Donald is kind of an avatar.
That Barks kinda turns into... He... He changes his personality a little bit depending on what he needs him to do in the story. And in this one we've got kind of the very sophisticated
Donald who's very easily tricked.
But then later on, he's he's more like stubborn and determined.
Alright.
Without further I do, I am going to launch into the story if you're ready. I'm ready. So
volcano Valley opens up with the Nephews asking donald for a model plane that regards to being over overpriced when he says
instead of buying that, he wants to get one from the war surplus people
for much less. So they've got a male off for that. And
weeks later, they get notified that they can go pick up the plane from the Worst
Depot.
And so
they head out pondering, you know, what why do we have to drive out to pick up this model plane.
You know, we the reader probably already figured out, but there's some confusion with the agent
when they go to pick it up, and he reveals that no. They have
purchased a number b one nine seven x dash n g
plane that...
I think it must be based off the b two Barks?
No. B seventeen. A b seventeen box. Okay. So they... They are the proud owner
of
a government surplus
Bomber from the war. For for only two dollars and fifty cents is how much they ordered it for. An item didn't... In
I did the calculations or
inflation,
the original model that they wanted it on page one was fifteen dollars, which would be the equivalent of about a hundred eighty one dollars now. And they're
they're discounted two dollar and fifty cent model would be about
thirty dollars and eighteen cents. Tara. There we go.
So a good a good deal at any price.
So Donald is
Yeah. It hasn't really kicked in for him that he's gotten a good deal.
And
we see in the background a foreigner owner who is easily identifiable as
he's supposed to look Mexican.
Right? He's got this about bay. He's got
not quite a wide brim,
but a white very wide rim hat.
And
he offers to buy the plane
for three dollars
which Donald realize hey that's a nice profit. And before he can do that, the nephews point out, you know, this is military.
Equipment, you can get a lot more from it.
And Donald
says that he's gonna have to do better than that. At this point,
the foreigner
that he comes from vol,
a poor country
and he's gonna make a grand offer of three hundred thousand volt.
So I wanna take some time to talk about the guy who's...
Who met them at the desk and and told them,
no, your airplane is real.
Good luck taking Al home and also no refunds. U.
I have some questions for you. Shoot. Is he the same species as
Pablo ban?
Yeah. So you are in the newbie role. This is one of those things that's just kind of like background to people who've read a lot of these steps dot com, but
these are all humans,
basically. Right? They're they're animal humans.
It's very rarely Barks upon
what they happened to be. But what Barks usually does is he defaults to a dog like character.
When when he's got background characters. That's
ninety percent or something. Yeah. That's the dog knows. We are supposed to read them all as basically humans. They they'll be referred to as Ducktales sometimes. But
but yes. And so
he's very clearly, you know, high status
you know, well groomed. His hair slipped back. Mh. His ears are are pretty well formed. He's wearing a suit and then contrasting him with Pablo,
as a newbie,
I was wondering are they supposed to be the same
species if so, you know, Palo has floppy, less defined ears. He definitely doesn't have a slick back hair. But he does have that circular
dog.
Right. Yeah. I I'd say, yes. We're supposed to see them as both essentially dog like humans.
But,
yeah. I I'd say that's a good pickup on
on the fact that Barks has has drawn them
everything about him kind of Scrooge,
Lazy Mexican. Right? Yeah in the kind of classic stereo.
Yeah.
So they they have some intro introduction Donald.
Again, he he thinks he's getting a much better offer.
We've read enough of these Barks seen enough of these to to know some of the tropes.
Right? And we know it's coming even if Donald doesn't, but
he introduces himself as major Pablo Money,
He says vol Has most honor son.
He gives him the wide of
and
he major Pablo offers to take them for a plain ride if they'll pay to fill up the gas
Donald, you know, he feels like a rich man with this big what. So he
gladly agrees. And then the
gas attendance tells him he owes twelve hundred dollars
Donald
is
about to learn his lesson
because the guy tells him that
Are worth and the stack of these got is conveniently worth about three dollars.
So I looked into
the cost of
fuel at the time. I don't know if Carl Barks as far as to look up jet fuel prices
So he definitely didn't have Google no.
Right. And I couldn't easily find them for as well. So I just looked up gas
which was
about seventeen
cents per gallon.
And oh these seventeen hundred gallon
tanks could give you a range of eighteen hundred fifty miles. So the gas is not quite... The gas capacity and the guest cost may or may not be plausible,
but if they're only flying to Mexico,
and back on that tank of guess, that's totally false. Yeah. I'm not too far off.
Still Al lot of
either way.
Yeah. I was thinking about some Zimbabwe and how their currency just got massively dev Al. Right.
Replacement overnight, and they were carrying around
stacks and stocks and stacks and meal arrows. I was... I was surprised that they
he fit thirty thousand three hundred thousand facilities in In that.
Right. So
Donald in a jam here, and
he basically
is forced to bargain with the guy
to give him his car.
The guy looks at it very app amazingly, and this is already Donald car, you know, where a few dozen Barks stories in.
We're only at our, like,
we don't have too many of the long adventure stories. But this this is the characteristic shape of Donald car.
And I think this is the most detailed that he ever get with it. But this is kind of beloved among fans, the the details
of his car. Although it's usually shown as red and and then blue here. So
And it it instruct me too that he's very, like,
understanding about having been
been taken
by
by this guy because, you know, he's he's still going for his plain right. He's obviously up upset, but not so upset that he's not gonna get on the plane. And we have a little moment of jealousy as they fly over Ducktales, than Nephews are asking. Hey, Isn't he turning south and Donald is too busy trying to see if someone's car is at Daisy house.
I I did
notice that he
called
Pablo Money
mutually
fed crook Yes.
I think I'm bought Al each Lease. A lot of us meaning not just
south and borders. Right. Probably they're delicious.
Agreed.
Probably a lot fewer at this time. Right? I'm guessing it was on too many American.
Non hyphen American
dinner table.
But they didn't have ubiquitous Taco bell. Yes.
Alright. So the plain ride is basically
an excuse to get the
Inducks
unaware of where they're really going because
pablo does loop the loop and they don't have any safety belts back there. So all four Ducktales
land on their head and pass out
for
a pretty significant period of time.
And when he looks outside the window, donald sees that they're flying through a huge mountain range
and freaks out and he goes up to the
cop to see what the deal is,
and he learns that pablo is literally
Al asleep at the wheel. Has it fiesta to time work. That's... Yeah. They we're gonna find out all about both Kenobi and Cs does.
Because he wakes him up
or he tries to wake him up, but Pablo tells him that, you know, we... I've got eleven more minutes
because in Louisville Pan, we always si
until two.
And so Donald tries to take over, but the controls are locked. And fortunately
before they crash into a huge range.
Cs to time is over, and he gently climbs over the mountains.
I will note that the art as they fly through the mountain range and, like, through the waterfall, I really liked the art for this part Alright. So
So the nephews are in a prayer posture,
which we don't always see. Donald and f have been praying for their lives, and
they they yell at
pablo to take them home, but he indicates that he's lost. And then they see some volcanic eruptions,
which Pablo celebrates because he realizes it means that they are at his home in,
they see the the picturesque little capital tucked away in a Valley.
And they comment on how small it is. And and they go in for a landing before Donald can tell him, you know, that
he needs to go home, and he pablo says, sorry, And yours, I must have forget.
His seems of language is really interesting.
Not just the, you know, ee instead of i to right to indicate that he has an accent.
But he had it really funny if you... I forgot to bring it the company had a really funny.
And we get a lot of inconsistent
accent stuff. And and, you know, we just had a story set in India
which I wouldn't say it was like a a paragon of cultural
awareness. But it it really Al least wasn't, like, There was there wasn't much that was, like, overt virtually insensitive, and he didn't go for any kind of pigeon accent in that one. Oh, the and the it was
up at the very beginning when he was...
And he was talking to... When he was offering the them the deal for the for the claim. Mh. He said gee. I will give something.
I will give you. Where that Al wrote is gi is not
realistically accurate
substitution. You know, the I think that one would be a little bit closer than most of what. Right? Because because we don't have a v
not like an English v in Spanish. So I'm wondering if you would d voice that. I feel like, with my regular my relatives,
I've heard it more with like, deep Right. Like, it it's turned into a beef
instead of enough? That might be a little more likely. That... That one is not at least off
off target. Some of some of the accent is definitely.
Right. Like... Accurate.
Kinda character drives my people you get the accent. Right. Yeah. And there are moments where he does some accents in these that are much better than this.
But at any rate.
Alright. So they bring for a landing and Donald starts to see some of the top
of Vulcan
and clearly wyatt it has his name
pablo reassure the Ducktales not to be afraid of these little volcanoes because they won't hurt you.
But we get a nice bit of fore bow
that if the big one over there old
Ever blows his top then you gotta run like the dick. And, you know, I I. The going yeah. Vegan.
And I like to focus
on this volcano stuff because I have a lot more goodwill for this part of the story. Right? I think this is Mh.
There are basically two things that this story depends on the the two platinum elements that it rides on. One of them is the inherent laziness of the people and the other is their geography. And, you know, they can't affect their geography. So Yeah. And it's...
It's it it's not, you know,
common to have fields and fields full of active volcanoes in that way. Usually, it's just one or maybe to do new at a time that are going off
Sometimes you can have different events, that they're gonna be a little bit more of from the same chamber, but they're gonna be a little bit more... They're gonna be closer together
geographically. But he does get it pretty close that, you know, there are very many volcanoes that have this specific shape. Mh Which is, you know, like, kind of tall and pointy. And that they do
sp gases and rocks and and
they're are kind of these like mo, but still kinda solid what they call ph
that they just shoot through the air. They're really pretty to look at from the car. Pretty destructive if you're close to. Clearly for a volcano fan. I I... I Al a fan of volcanoes.
I do like the little baby volcano everywhere which we get to on starting on the next page. Right. Right. I'm a big fan of those too. Yeah. After he worn them about old Photo C, they're kinda
at the different
small volcano and they get smaller and smaller
until they see some cute little baby
and all the Inducks get,
you know, little mini options under their backside size. That's a fun gag. Yeah. And I didn't buy I gloss over. I meant to mention we're talking about the background that, you know, in that leading cool article I read.
He had suggested that the... This fictional country is based on the actual
Al of the volcanoes
in the On dog web volcanic fields of Peru.
That's like the place actual nickname, Al of the.
I I like think that
I also wanted to point out a really interesting
volcano
contemporary temporary to this. And I... You said you you don't think you've remembered this episode of reading Rainbow where they run a story about a volcano that if appeared in the middle of a corn field. But there was this children's story back in the eighties,
and it's based on
a real a real event. For the south and Mexico,
so not close to the border in the Us. But
it's body
is what it's called. It just literally it has them opened up in this guy's corn field.
And the obnoxious
volcanic gases started to
come out of it and then, you know, ash and and rocks and it is turned into Al in the middle of a corn. And that
was the first time in kind of modern history when they were able with, you know, semi more
scientific
instruments and and and methodology and knowledge to what the birth of a avant volcano.
And I mentioned in it Carl Barks had been...
Had it paying attention to national geographic that they would have done some coverage of it. So this those... That that really captured. I think the
could've have captured his imagination in the way that he translated it into this even if, you know, the Mexican volcanoes were
not
specifically
where he said it. I did remember in that water fault that they wonder there was a little
a pocket or a a yam Mh.
Off in the corner. So that does kind of... Even if the stereotype is purely Mexican
geographically, it does look right. And and I would I would contend that this setting is basically
supposed to be like a hand latin, you know, kind of everything thrown into the hopper.
It it stands out as mostly Mexican. But, yeah. It looks very pan latin to me. Alright.
So
the the Inducks
do not wanna stay there
They are freaked out by the all these volcanic options, and they head to the train station to leave
and this is when we kinda run into the big stereotype
that everyone involved Can
is
really
too lazy
to
to do anything.
And the conductor here says that he's not gonna sell him a ticket unless he does something to make himself a National Hero,
Law. Let let me know, Sarah, if you have anything to say
over the next... I might condense these next few pages a little bit, because I don't know that there's
too much to go into Ducktales
in these as they're just
struggling
to
basically get past
everyone's laziness.
And do something to make themselves
the heroes that they need to. I I did wanna point out the caller.
Right the the the set is are are not as detailed as as a real setup. It would be, but, you know, there's the the guy and the blue umbrella with the yellow and red setup and and and there. Oh red setup up with a green,
And then the the potter is obviously
thirty five prints as well.
I I did enjoy those colors splash Yeah. I really like that panel especially where they're where he's pointing out, you know, they could
invent soft sidewalk. For the loafers first to sit on. It's the content is not great, but the panel itself is really nice. And it yes.
And and you can see Donald getting kind of more and more and more angry. And and this is one of the times when I had to Barks switch right? Get over my problem with only reading the words and look at the pictures.
Because he's saying like, you left a shin a lot like this, to come to America,
and I was like, oh, is he being nice to them? Is this supposed to be like oh, I'm I'm really
on their side, and then later on, he says,
to think that with all this
swell countries around here,
you know, we end up here.
Right. And I was like, oh, does he really think it's well? Oh, no. I need the stuff.
Test switch and look at his body language. Oh, yeah. Lynch up is his shoulders are all the way up to his ears. It's fist are cl and he's shaking Right. Yes. Not being...
Yeah. And the sarcasm is he's not confusing there. Yeah. So
so the Inducks are gonna leave they they're just gonna head to the coast, but, you know, they figure out that they have to go through the worst of the volcano fields.
And so we get this sequence coming up where they're resigned. Right? They have to figure out a way to get
to become a national hero. And... Not until Donald takes his first name. That's right. Yes. Which is because he chooses violence.
He says, he says why i can't you lazy?
Look why can't your lazy loafers first do something to benefit themselves pablo points out that rest is good for you.
And then Donald chooses his violence.
Tries to fight pablo, but Pablo pretty easily defeats him and Donald ends up being the one. Right. And he takes Al. I'm unwilling nap I do like the gag that we can't see Pablo
in that cloud of fighting dust. Right? Because it would do look weird to see him actively fighting. So that's a nice. And the the the vulcan
are still, you know, not even lifted. Their heads up. They're still wrapped up in there and still resting.
Unpaid. They're aggressively
aggressively lazy.
So
we we see a couple of their attempts basically
to
impress someone
and and they basically end up
worse on right? They try to impress the president by showing... Teaching them how to milk a cow,
which is pretty insulting.
To think that they don't know how to mill a cow.
We get a pretty great site
of
a
volcano
induced earthquake turning the milk into butter. So, like, if you take out all the background, that's that's pretty funny. I like And and earthquakes are a regular part of
volcanic region life. And and so I I thought that one was just pure purely funny. Yeah. The
earthquake shakes the cow and the milk and. There's... Now there's butter and right outside of the cow.
Yes. Inside the Al.
That sounds unpleasant.
And then I liked his attempt to teach the mayor's wife to to use one of the mini volcanoes to cook.
Yes. It he his it's his next attempt to to become a national hero is to mans
cooking.
To the president's life by suggesting that she used the baby volcano that are everywhere as a heat source. Right. She knows better she warns him that it's not safe but donald is in full on white save mode and this dismiss as indigenous knowledge.
To his detriment because, of course, the flying pit, the frying hand go flying, and then the food lands on the president hit. Yes. Uncomfortable, but true.
And and then the president
is ra from his slumber enough to to clear him a national menace.
I I really like that panel specifically where he's pointing at him covered in whatever was being cooked.
And and that news goes around the town
that he... We've... They've got a national menace, and it's mostly
because everyone is considering how much work it means for them.
Right?
The judge
is bim that he's gotta hold a trial, the x Huey, nurse is the malone that he's got work him in the salt minds.
And Donald is quickly arrested
and brought to a courtroom room
helpful labeled with the judge and the journey box and the council and so forth. I it it's out to me like his detain in Vulcan.
Was kind of extra
until now. Now he finally gets his day in court. Otherwise, they... you know, it's pretty much they were... They were imprison him And now he's finally getting his day in court. Although, they don't really care too much about town, Right? Because it's perfectly fine in
if your council is sleeping.
Or if you only have
a single
juror,
because all of the all of the other
didn't want to be in the jury box because the chairs are too hard to sleep in. Right. And then this is pretty fascinating. Right? We've got some some pretty over imperial where donald.
His is pointing out. You know, I'm an American.
I've got rights
and
I guess this is not really too far off reality right around this time. But
the judge is like, well, you gotta approve it. And,
you know, the next tried asked Donald for his papers.
Yes. Yes.
And and they try to get Pablo to vouch for him, but of course, Pablo has taking the si fiesta and the nephews couldn't wake him. And so they're going... They're going through with this Sham of a trial.
And the only alert guy in there to Donald Dismay is the states lawyer. His lawyer,
his counsel is fast to sleep.
The state slayer wakes up the the j
who turns out to be an ex patriot
from from Texas. Are you
That this is pretty great. Right? The prisoner claims to be an American.
Says the states council. Are you not to on American Texas text?
And and that's that's hilarious.
Texas texts
was is definitely an American at least before he was running out of San Gladstone.
And
the the lawyer asks him as a former American, do you see any wrong in finding this other American guilty?
And text
says that he needs to ask Donald the question. He has that, he Barks him is you all from Texas partner?
Donald says no. And and Tech says he ain't from Texas.
So I'd say the var and could be guilty of anything.
I read that to my husband.
Who is from Texas.
And he was like, oh, great. Now we have
Al
as well as American exceptional.
U.
And I'd say this is in keeping with Barks
depictions of of texas.
And
I I do think it's hilarious
Again, it's it's a big stereotype.
But...
You know, the
I wouldn't call the stereotype if it's true.
They Texas is... I have so much family there. Zach family is from there. Spent so much time for there. And when you're there, you are never allowed to forget that you're there. Right?
Texas this. Texas that like, Texas exceptional,
is that... It's just like a micro quality of America. Right? They the disregard for outsiders, the internal exceptional
And so, of course, the Text exceptional Trump the American exceptional.
Yeah. And I vouch for that too. Perfectly accurate.
As someone who's working
virtually in Texas
I I agree.
But honestly, this is probably one of the, like, nice or more egalitarian parts of the story. Right? Because here we've got text and on American who who has adapted to the
ways.
And he's found his... He's found his home. Or or the volcanic gases have boys and stay along with everyone. Oh, I I like that thesis.
There you go.
Maybe that's...
Maybe that explains Al all.
Alright. So Donald is imprisoned, and the Nephews are
you know, we're very accustomed to the Nephew saving the day, but
it is not to be because they get not conscious.
Again,
by many volcanic corruption.
And Donald, we get a nice site of Donald Severino the kids taking a Cs to two just like the guard. And of course, Donald makes everything about him and instead of being concerned that there are three children
outside of his window who are lying in weird poses.
He
assumes that that they've... That the... Whatever is infecting,
you know, the laziness that's impacting the vulcan
and Has affected his children and it is great with they. Business. Yes. To be a fair doll has seen a lot of what the nephews are capable of. So
it... I'll defend him a little for not being too worried because we've seen them rescue him at this point by by piloting a snow claim by themselves.
He has imprisoned. Right? He is facing life and imprisonment.
At any rate, the next morning,
they wake up to find the jail or come to bring him to the salt minds.
And
he locks the nephews up so they don't interfere. And, you know, at this point, it is nature that Intervene.
But not... But first, they full the same thing that they pull page out of the Karen here in Handbook just like Donald did earlier.
You can't do this to us, we're junior members of the Their club Bear rangers. That's true. At least they're not playing to their Al. Right? This is the precursor that their famous membership and the junior would. Barks hadn't U. Hadn't created that yet.
I did I did find it interesting that, like, we're we are part of this group. You can we immune from whatever is happening because we are part of this group, you know, whether it's wrongful
imprisonment or or what? But it's not that this violates, you know, international treaties is is I'm a member of this group. Yeah. I mean, American Exceptional was very wrong at this time.
You know, I have to, like I keep... I keep thinking to myself i better be careful like, not to not to be too critical
of of our country
in this podcast. And then I think to myself, well, you know, seventy percent of my readers
are from
Scan
and the low countries, which is like,
which is where people care about Disney comics. So Maybe I should. Maybe I need to fashion it even more. I I guess I do like that nature
intervene here. You know, it seems very fitting. Right? Al earth way possible. Yeah. Al earth earthquake of Volcano and
earthquake.
Demolish is the jail, the Ducktales are able to get free.
They dash past their... The jail
and the jail take just a moment to wonder what they're gonna do and realize that, hey. Now they're out of a job, and this is great.
So we can celebrate with what else?
C does. Yes. One big si.
So we are... Have come to the point where
expected old federal
chimes in.
Fe,
the the dreaded giant volcano
is starting to Rumble.
I didn't mention that old Fe
has like a a very grumpy looking visit. Right?
It's very
personified. This is a great panel. Right? It's showing and showing it rumbling.
I do like this one a lot.
And so they remember what Pablo said that they get ready to run like, the dickens.
But they're like, well, let's wake come up.
We can be national heroes.
We'll save their lives.
You know, those are both good things.
But, of course, these walking stereotypes
are
in Si mode and they are not to be woken up. And so they do find pablo, you know, they're the closest thing to a local
friend.
They can't wake him up, but one of the nephews
suggests to ram a handful of peppers down his.
And that does wake pablo up. You know, he opens his eyes wider than he has at any point in the story and economically
punches is throat.
Dives into a fountain
and,
you know, he... He's awake though, and he realizes what's gonna happen with the old Fe.
And they
they devi a plan. They see a bunch of baskets full of some stuff and and they're gonna drop it in the volcano.
To see if they can plug it up and and Sarah as a volcano fan,
what do you think about their plan? Clearly,
that's what everybody is missing. Right? Everybody else in the world. They're building these
retaining walls
in in
to try to keep... To try to Al least channel the lava or
keep it away from certain areas they're worried about for the lava flow.
Affecting
infrastructure and roads cutting off, you know, a road that is kinda
necessary to and nearby town,
had they read this, so they would know. Yeah. They have a good road map. And I'm not
of baskets of whatever.
They kinda done that. And I'm not gonna go too hard
on this because, you know, every
every
episode, we get a little bit of cartoon logic,
Oh, yeah. And and so that's fine.
But is pretty funny. So so they managed to dump those baskets
of whatever in and it seems like they've saved the day. And then they... It occurs to them to fly back and check, you know, hey, what was in those baskets?
And they realized that it was full of popcorn
and of course, we dropped popcorn into Lava,
I'm gonna I'm gonna out on a limb with my extensive volcano
knowledge, which is not much. And say that those kernels are melting on contact.
Oh, they're pricing. Yeah. Although this does give me an idea. We have clients to go visit the on Al
later on in the autumn or the maybe even in the summer. You can bring some popcorn. You you do that. You do that for pablo and the docks.
And
so we get...
You know, this is a pretty pretty fun gag where
Vulcan gets covered by snow,
and the Ducktales are like, oh, no. I'm never gonna be a national hero. I'm still gonna be Al national
Man. I'll never get out of all Ken.
Ben pablo cheerful says, oh, yes, you're gonna get out of Al.
I can't dare show my face there.
Anymore, and he's got a pretty great attitude about
from his beloved homeland. Oh, I mean, at this point, he's gonna be a refugee to Yeah. That's true. If if his he can't...
If he's is fleeing
persecution based on covering his beloved hometown in popcorn.
Yeah. I guess he's got that understanding. Becoming a national menace. I think that's pretty good grounds for being becoming a refugee. That's a good point.
And then at the end, you know, they go to celebrate,
but we get a nice site where the... All the excitement of it all has been too much donald, and
he is taking a Si to at the at the bottom of the plane. And this first time really sleeping sleeping. Aside from being knocked out. And he's gotta a married couple days. He's got a very satisfied looking grim on his face. So I imagine it's a it's a good si.
Alright. So
that is
the story content
of
Volcano Valley.
Thank you for helping me out with that one. We're we're gonna transition now to talking about the general consensus
and our own thoughts.
I always check sarah the the aggregate
website index
which is great because it gets us a pretty good feel for how the and
regards this story as everyone who wants to vote on it. And this one got a seven point six out of ten,
which ranks it as
storing number two hundred and fourteen
out of roughly forty thousand
seven hundred stories that have been ranked on Inducks. So that's very high. Most of the Barks stories do rank very high
but even relative to the other Barks stories, that one is only
out ranked so far by the stories that we've done
for tear of the river
continues to be our highest with a seven point seven.
And last
episode Mah raja Donald has the seven point seven a slightly lower seven point seven.
So this one is apparently very well liked by the fan. So I wanna acknowledge that a lot of people do like this one. In googling
for this story. I do find that there are a lot of people who have written.
Anyone who's written about it in the last ten years or so. There's at least some of the kind of conversation that you and I have had. So I do think it's probably getting some critical reassess, but index has been around since pretty early days of the Internet. So I don't know. I I haven't been
secretive
about this one. You know, I... In researching this, I found a thread with some back and forth between the reviewer and some.
And so there are definitely people who are gonna go to bat for this one. But
I think that to me, it's very obvious. That the fundamental problem with Volcano Valley is that the story is absolutely
dependent
on this racial stereotype. Right? Like, that is...
I mean, it's even kind of secondary even though the title is Volcano Valley,
I would argue that the the laziness
of the inhabitants
is like the main plot to this one. And so for me,
while I do enjoy certain gigs and some of the art and parts of this, that overall makes this one pretty much pretty much you're redeem.
How about you, Sarah? I was thinking about ways that it could be different
and that I would not find it problematic. Right? And and the biggest thing... Like these These gigs aren't
not funny. Yeah. But
because it's
very
dependent as you said on this stereotype
that I'm just woah.
If this... If they were in, like a suburb cleveland one This would be pretty funny. It it... Is it where... If if they were just
sleeping,
they're just sleepy people instead of lazy people even. I think that would be funny because this whole, like,
laziness even if it were not
dependent on a racist stereotype.
Would still become a problem. So if it was just like, oh,
we just want to sleep instead. It doesn't speak to our character. It's just the thing that we like to do then maybe it would be funny. They were right around and there was a volcano about to blow and they couldn't like anybody up. Can I ask you this? You you had a good thought, like, what if what if it was
that it was the volcanic fumes or something or... Or what if, like, later on, Barks will do a lot of, like,
alien races or or hidden underground
race. You know, what if these were like aliens
and they weren't connected
to the specific stereotype and it would have been funny then?
Anything is.
Sure. And you know, as long as they weren't, like parallel
to right if they weren't thinly veil.
Right. Yeah. So it
it could be funny. And i'm sure it was funny sure they didn't see the harm that it did.
I'm sure that there are a lot of people who still can't see the harm that these Inducks stereotypes types do. Right? Because it's not
advocating for, you know, worse things being done to these groups. Right.
They're there are very few your leaf lean clean in the sense of
not based on
racist or even able to stereotype
jokes within this
comment and that
that really would make me rank it quite a bit lower. For try to rank you know, this would be... In... It would be take last place in all of the one Barks stories that I've read.
Sure.
Although
unfortunately, it's also...
What's that?
Unfortunately, it's also the best one you've read. So... Yeah. It will vary easily be disappointed Al the number one that I read. Well, we'll have to bring you one. We'll have to bring you back. Because I'm pretty confident
that
that you'll enjoy. Others of these. And I don't wanna... I don't wanna be too hard on it. I do you think it deserves... I I do think it deserves criticism.
But but... Yeah. You know, I I think back to when I read this one is a kid. And I wasn't very...
I wasn't very just minded as a kid,
what ten year old is, generally. But
but I remember not being a big fan of this one just for story reasons.
So I don't think that my opinion of it is being colored too much. Although,
Again, I do like the volcano stuff in this a lot.
I don't want to dwell on
what...
I usually have all section
here about what is either dated or archaic.
But we already went into some of the cool war
stuff, and then we've
definitely tread well on what's retro grade and problematic with this story.
I do think this is a low water Barks for this one because even though there are gonna be some other
really cri
stereotypes and characters.
This one alone
has a plot that's dependent on it. So fingers crossed.
I don't think there's a ton of educational value in this one and that's not me being
trying to bring it down even more. I just don't think that I didn't really learn much from this one. Sarah, did you have any panels that stood out as, like a favorite panel besides some of the ones that we had already mentioned.
I said earlier, I really liked
the colors
that
show up in in.
And of course, being in Arizona,
I do love
depictions of snow. So that very last
panel on the one page where the popcorn had Right. Made it look like it was snowing on the phone, trees I really liked those. You know, I I'd like to... There was this one where they... Oh, even that pile of rocks as a volcano. This
But was this kind of adorable and then the... When they were all getting boost by the little tiny baby volcanoes?
That was fun. That was really cute. Right. I really enjoyed the court like, just the layout of the court scene
when he's brought for the high cord of Vol. I thought that was a cool panel.
I really like the splash panel that was at the very very beginning.
That shows them
running from volcanoes in general. That one was really cool. And
I feel like there was at least one more. A lot... A lot of the panels as they're flying on their weight of Al. I think I already mentioned the waterfall one. I did like that one quite a bit. And then, you know, as they land involve Ken when they see it in the valley, that's a very pretty one.
Despite what I might think about the country
itself.
And it's depictions. That looks pretty cool. And and... Yeah, like you said, most of these little volcano ones, there... It's just it's a very whim cold.
This is a very Barks part of the store, you know, the things that he does with the ball tandem. So I wish it could have leaned into that and away from the stereo.
Sarah, I really appreciate you coming on. Do you have any
further thoughts, anything that you didn't get to mention that you wanted to say? I did wanna point out that
ice in eyesight. I'm obsessed.
Like they do have a
red that they make using geothermal.
So they obviously don't put it on the volcano. But they have so much groundwater that's geothermal normally heated they will go near to you with their most spraying, dig a hole, wrap up the
red that they're about to Barks in foil and then bury it for a period of time. Nice. So there is cooking.
You can cook with geothermal.
Donald just needed to use more like indirect
Exactly. He shouldn't have used the volcano as a hot. He just... He should have used it as. Excellent.
Yeah. Thank you for that. So again, hopefully, we can have you back for a a good one.
Thank you to to the listeners for joining us. Hopefully,
hopefully, my criticism is this story isn't too alien eliminating
If you have other thoughts, if you'd like to defend this story, then
feel free to reach out
and drop us a line at Barks remarks at g mail dot com. We do have a Facebook page.
And you can join us next time on mark's remarks when
I'm I'm so excited because
I get to talk about one of my all time favorites. Next time, which is ghost of the g. So I think this is gonna be a a a wonderful turnaround
So thank you, Sarah, and thank you listeners.