Hello, and welcome to Barks Remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer Al artist of the greatest Donald and unscrew comments of all time. Join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing or order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Hello, and welcome back to Barks remarks,
everyone. I am still Barks Sever.
A grown man who has
managed to con some friends into letting him talk about his favorite comic stories
in the guise of actually releasing it as a podcast.
Don't tell them, but at any rate, I am joined by my guess toast, Ryan, if you can say hi to good people?
Hello, everyone. I'm Ryan Bailey. This is my voice. And I am easily influenced by my friends.
Well, yes. Definitely.
So Ryan, today, we get to talk about
a a favorite comment of mine. I'm I'm very excited to get to this one.
I've been looking forward to it for a while, we will be covering Barks ghost of the g,
this is
an adventure story that was published in July of nineteen forty seven. In four color number one hundred and fifty nine.
It has, of course, been reprinted many times.
This one is twenty six pages
and
I I thought about it, and I would like to start
asking
you the c hosts to give us
your own synopsis
of the story since I do most of these
narration. So let's let's hear it. What how would you sum up ghost of the g?
So Donald and the nephews are
struggling to Harvest Kelp. And in the process of that, they and hear Al legend of a kidnapping of a small boy that happens every fifty years
the Inducks dismissed it, of course, and
later on, and they're harvesting happen upon a circular reef,
inside which they hope is an untapped kelp forest.
Trying to get over the reef during high tide, they run a ground on it and discover the sunken rec of an ancient Al
Al octopus kaiju apparently lives inside the wrecked.
Sure enough. Dewey is kidnapped by an armored man in the night while they sleep on their boat. Donald and the other nephews find the armored kid napa who talks like a shakespeare character,
Inducks cavern inside the reef and engage in deadly Ski to get dewey back or to signal for help from the town on the Main Island.
They overcome the octopus kaiju And the armored man,
The armored man revealed to be the latest in a line of boys, kidnapped and raised by their kit kidnapped. To guard a chest of gold intended for sir francis drake and her majesty.
Donald is given praise by the town on the island, and the formerly armored man gets the ancient and gold and some hamburgers.
Excellent.
Very capable synopsis.
I like that you referred to the octopus as a kaiju.
Tell us what the kaiju you is, please.
Ridiculously large monster like Godzilla z.
This is the octopus version of God.
Yes, the opt version of God, definitely.
That was great. Thank you very much.
So
a little bit of background
about this story.
I I didn't check into this, but to me, it feels like Barks is kinda picking up his pace here because this was published just a couple of months after his previous pair of it adventure stories. And this is gonna be another of those that has two full length adventures next steps so we'll talk about adventure down under.
But this one gets the coveted
cover
for for this pair of stories for this issue.
There is a little bit of of
of detail in an interview that Barks did
about this one. So in in his words, he said that this story was a rare example
Ducktales that was conceived as a ten pager
for walt disney comics and stories, the the short
gag
publication. And it grew into a longer story for donald Inducks. He said I can remember the first idea I had on that was just trying to figure out something to donald we could do. I thought of him sailing boats and came up with a potential ten pages of gathering c and selling this help, which would give me a lot of gigs with boats.
As I developed more and more things with the story, I think it's quite possible that the ghost of the g is brought in as a jimenez.
There is so much in that. I couldn't have thought of it in a whole bucket full of writing at once. And I I think that probably
bears out in the story ryan because this one does seem like it is a little bit of a sequence of kind of improbable things that happen
But but for me, this one just really works,
and that's gonna... The gonna stem from the underlying kind of mystery structure that he's gonna develop at the beginning of it. But before we get more into it just a little more background
Barks was inspired as he often is by Al nash
geographic article
about treasure Hunting and a ship rack.
The Treasure salvage apparently cut a hole in the side
like the one that the armored man exits from. And they they didn't find any treasure, but he was able to envision
this and kind of run with it.
I noted that this is one of his titles that has a nice use of Al moderation.
Bark is gonna tend to do that a lot. In his stories going forward.
And the the very well known editor Jeffrey Blu has called this one one of has landmark stories. I think that's because it kinda has that modest beginning
that sets up something much more
fancy. As far as the value, this one, you know, we're in that arrow, where these
reprint or the original printing rather go for quite a bit of money. So the highest documented at sale was in very good condition for this one. It's nine point six was sold for seven thousand five hundred dollars. And then, Ryan, you know that I I like to go into
sort of the historical background or the geographical
context for these stories. That's a big part of what interests me. So I want you to
buckle up for fifteen minutes
about health gathering. Oh, excellent.
Yeah.
No. I... I'm not gonna talk about that too much, but I I did I did look it up, and I did find it really interesting to find out that, you know, this is Al thing. This is apparently is where I comes from, this is the easiest way to get today. Yes.
Apparently, this is still the easiest way to get, like, commercial grade iodine.
I happen to live near one of the one of the world's premier
aquariums
where I learned that a kelp can grow a foot a day that's some amazing. So
if if you wanna gather a crop this a good crop.
Yeah. So a little bit just a little bit on the history of that. Iodine
was first extracted from seaweed in eighteen eleven.
This is something that gets used for a lot of different reasons, including treating some health conditions.
I also
actually thought about the title and wondered if people would know what a g is. Do you know the, like, true definition of a g ryan? I like I do. I think of it is
like any kind of under water cave? Yeah. That... That's right. Technically, it's much more expensive. It can be really any cave and I think the official definition says that it doesn't have to be, you know, under underwater or
submit to water, but that's in practice. That is how we use it. We usually talk about, like, caves that are just underwater or or right nearby water.
So, yes, the g itself
of course, is gonna be the underground hideout out of the armored man.
So for notable appearances in this one, I've already named dropped the armored man. We don't ever learn his actual name. I don't believe.
There's no no one else other than the docs that's really noteworthy in this one. I've started to talk about kind of what version of the characters
of the characters we're getting in these stories now. And to me, this is sort of the resourceful
version of Donald. You know, he's very level headed than this one for the most part.
He's very determined once Dewey disappears
to get him back. You know, he he never really loses his head in this one, which is not very typical for donald. It's true. So we're gonna go over our
detailing of the story And
again, as always Ryan, feel free to chime in. But the... This story opens up with a really cool splash panel
and an explanation of
summary of setting up where they are. They're They're in the west Inducks
they have a boat. And as Ryan Al mentioned they've got their own sea gathering business.
So the first page has them...
It shows sort of their day to day harvesting help harvesting c.
And what I found notable about this is that Barks really... I think goes into some nice detail with the artwork. He shows this kind of the mechanics.
Of the kelp gathering with the win and the
the tongs or whatever the the pictures that they use to harvest it.
And they're just talking about their business in general. They they've been talking about how the the beds... The Sea beds are playing out and they're getting less and less. And on their way back, they mentioned that there's a lot of Ce to be gathered in the center of skull i reef. If they could only get to it. And so that kinda sets it up. They passed the reef, Ryan, how would you describe the reef?
It's it's pretty small. And
it's a perfect circle like a donut. So there's water in the center and while all around it and then it's just this
mound
that it that goes all the way around on broken.
Right. And they set it up so that whatever is in the middle of that, you know, you can't really access Al all and they know that there's a ton of Al
in the center. There's a really neat little site gag that Bark has of a very busy bird on the win that Donald is turning. I I like to note that Barks really likes these site guys and I think that they're starting to become a little bit more common
as he goes.
Alright. And sitting you're looking at it, I didn't even notice the bird.
Yeah. And and and keep an eye out for these site gigs because again, he he really does have a lot of fun with those. And then, you know, a lot of people
would say that Dawn Roses is is kind of the spiritual
successor
to Barb, there there are a lot of people who would probably take issue with that. But
he did a lot of sequels to these stories, and he kind of carries that. Tradition on and
maybe expands on it.
So on the next page, you know, the that's kind of right off the possibility of getting the kelp from Skull i reef. And they head back to the island
that they seemed to be headquartered from
And
I I wanna take a a brief moment to kind of acknowledge that the island that they're on It's it's a really interesting place. Right? Because box goes out of his way to depict this very, like, multi multicultural
mix, like a launch of accents. There's some, like, Caribbean
accents
and some French
or cajun and accent
and some, like, Mexican or Spanish, and there's a guy who looks very rich. So The the reason that I really wanted to go out of my way to highlight that is that we're about to enter into
a series of stories.
Many of which are all time classic but we we kind of also happen to be heading into sort of a rough patch. As well where there gonna be some pretty unfortunate
depictions
and and characters.
So I did wanna highlight that Barks is very capable of, you know, depicting this kind of this kind of setting and I liked that a lot. But the the interesting thing the dots are really focused on their their job and what they're trying to do with the seaweed, and they don't notice that all in the background, there are these, like very ominous
rumbling, people talking about
a really terrible event that would means that everyone is every
conversation is about the need to keep
their children locked up somewhere safe. And it's very ominous tonight is the night. They repeat that a couple of times. Tonight is the night french
one man says to another
tonight day the night, Tony.
Another says, and we're gonna wanna remember that line. And so by the end of this page, Donald has come to terms with the fact. That, you know, the only way to get this help is the dangerous way, which he's motivated to. I didn't mention that they they learned that the price of kelp has shot up yet again. I also noticed how he seem to make a point of where like, everybody's from a different country kind of I... The guy the guy who's kind of tying them up when they reach the doc seems kind of American to me. Then we have french accent sent a Spanish accent. This guy in the helmet this guy with a kind of a umbrella looking thing. Right. Yeah. Yeah. It's felt very naturally multi multicultural. Alright. So on the next page, the dots are talking about their plans to go out and some old
sea hand a sailor at the dock over here them, and he, you know, he's he's
gas. He's asking Donald, you know, you're not planning to leave your kids un bombarded tonight. Are you? Donald has no idea what he's referring to and he tells him, but but tonight, maybe, tonight is the night. So we're getting this ominous through line
again
and and he reveals that the reason everyone is talking is that tonight is the night that somebody's little boy will be stolen. And Donald very naturally wants to get some more information about this.
And Huey, he pumps him for information. And the guy just every question Donald asks, who's doing it, why?
Why tonight,
he keeps responding nobody knows. And,
you know, Donald kind of writes him off but another
old salt, another sale comes up and and comes to clarify more information.
He's got a bit of a an accent that maybe be Caribbean
or
or Latino of some kind. All I know is that when I was seven and I read, you have not heard of Eats mystery.
I was confused. I didn't get that it was its mystery. I thought there was something called Eats mystery.
Yeah. The first guy, the first guy has, like, a pipe and a cap feels like
feels like new newfoundland main or something like that.
Of an old, you know, see. Yeah. It looks like with that. Really cloth fish or something. Yeah. There you go. And then the the last guy looks I guess some stripes on his sleeve. He looks like maybe a captain or something. Yeah. Like you say, everyone looks like they're from somewhere else on this Caribbean Island. Alright. So
this...
The second guy, he does a better job of explaining. He
tells about the kind of the curse really of this island is that every fifty years
on this night
a little boy has been stolen and has never seen again.
This is that's happened seven times
since the century when the first one disappeared. And, you know, Donald rightfully is like, well, man, you need to do something about it. And he explained that their their way of doing something about it is locking their little kids up and watching them carefully.
And Donald is not concerned because he tells him, you know, no one's gonna come for him out on skull eye reef where we're going.
Before the Ducktales off, one of the nephews asks if there's ever been any clue about who's doing with stealing.
And the
the old sailor explains that the only clue from a long time ago is a footprint of an armored man. And, you know, this is a moment of surprise for the nephews as they wonder, you know, are there nights in these
and one of the nephews makes the comment that nights haven't been seen. Armor hasn't been worn around here since the days of the Al.
And I liked the Barks kind of snuck that in fore shadow a little bit.
Yeah. Yeah. My... I had a like, a medium brown moments on this page. Thinking, you know, what what is the difference between a footprint of an armored foot versus like, a boot if you had like a horse riding boots? Oh, yeah. That look different in the mud.
So maybe there could be a some impression in the in the metal by the the crafter Right. It. Yeah. Maybe her manager these sealed or something like that. So the interesting thing between these two pages to me is that now we're leaving this island
and the rest of this story is gonna take place almost entirely
on skull i reef. You know, it's not not quite a bottle episode, but it is really
interesting to me that he's able to get so much out of this setting. Because the dots returned to the reef.
And by the time they get there, it's high tide. And this is kind of transformed the reef because the little peaks of it are just poking out as though it's like a little
chain circular islands chain.
And they
they see some channels that have been formed that almost look big enough to flow back into.
Donald picks one to try
and,
you know, feels lucky, and they they basically let a wave pick them up and deposit them with a big thud.
Halfway
onto the reef. Far enough that they can manage their win, they're their pictures to get in and gather the kill. Yeah. Yeah. So
would been pretty concerned about that, but apparently, Donald does not.
Yeah. Especially with a rental
boat.
Yeah. So... But man, he really wants that that's wants that
count. Yeah. Good stuff in there. Yep.
And and the extra dollar on
I wanted to kinda highlight the two panels that, you know, where the boat gets lifted.
I think the water rushing pass the boat looks really neat and then the the thud that they land with is really well drawn i I like that lot. So... Yeah. Yeah. You can kinda see the the way it's flashing up above the the mcdonald's there and
There's definitely some force
here. Right. Yeah. I think it... I think it conveys that movement really well on the the weight of the boat. So on the next page, they're they're on their Mary Way. They are
getting as much Al as they possibly can.
The Nephews are enjoying seeing a
version of fifteen men on the dead man's chest. It's fifteen Barks articles on the Captain's chest. And as the tide goes down, they start to see a little bit more in the interior of the reef
and they
get a really big pile. They get their tongs onto to a big pile of kelp and try to quote yank, the whole mess board. And they see something
underneath the pile of kelp, and it it's revealed to be part of a ship So the docs perceived to yank more and more of the kelp until we cut to a panel at the bottom of this page,
and they've cleared it, and they see that the ship is...
Donald says it's an old gal, and one of the nephew says, or it's a British manor war. Pointing out the gun ports.
No. I think it's... I think it's pretty cool.
The way you know, we're kind of investigating escalating we've already gotten a little bit of the mystery, but now we're escalating the...
you know, what what's going on here
and kind of setting up our the conditions of the bottle that we're gonna be in for the rest of the the issue. Yeah. Definitely. I think there's some really good sort of table setting here.
And I I wanna really note that this is just to me, this panel is gorgeous. The way he's drawn this old ship, yeah. It's half sunk and it looks
very detailed. As does the reef, I think this one
would be instantly
recognizable
to
long time Barks fans. Is a very
beautiful panel.
And then, of course, we're gonna realize that it is the nephew that's right
that it must be a British manor war base on the Al of the rm and man that we haven't met yet. Mh. Alright. So on the next page, they decide to
explore the ship.
And
Donald
takes a raft over
hops onto to the deck, which
is revealed to be rotten immediately
after and if Huey, warned him, he crashes through into the hall.
The nephews
toss him line and donald scratches
down in the hold, and as he's pulled up an immense
Octopus Technical on,
snakes up after him.
And
Ducktales
from the ship
indicate that there's just a massive
octopus in there. And one of the Nephews says a great line. He cats is all that one octopus.
This is at least the third point in the comic where they use some some phrase that I've never heard anyone used before.
And sentinel to know how much of it is is
Disney corn and how much of it is how people actually talk about that? Yeah. I think it's a little a call may and a little bit of call and b. I mean, some of these are just kind of like, forties and fifties speak.
But
if
growing up at this time, this this is like almost my word balloons. Right? I would have mentally say he cats to myself
a couple of times a week because I was so steep in reading these Barks.
Stories. So I was a kid in the late eighties and and early nineties with this kind of, like, mental vocabulary.
So we've got kind of the this other
background
now set up with this giant octopus. And on the next page, you know, the duct acknowledged that, okay, we're not... Obviously, we're not exploring that anymore.
And night falls,
and there's just a generally creepy vibe for the ducks on the boat. As they get ready to go to bed. The nephews have kind of talked themselves into feeling spooked
because earlier in the day, of course, they heard all of this tail
of the ghost kid kidnapping kids,
and then they've just encountered this weird ship and the octopus. So they're rightfully fully creeped out.
And then we
transition to a couple of really nice nighttime panels Scrooge and silhouette
of the
of the ship rack and Barks
in a in a narrative box, he says that the moon
rides once more above the haul of the ancient man war. And we cut to the deck where the door creek ominous
open.
And indeed an armored man steps out of it and says tonight is unite.
And this is another just really. To me. It's stunning panel. I I love the slow setup of this and the ominous.
Creek of the door. And the way that he's drawn and realized and the way the the light glimpse off of his armor
and his sword is
very memorable.
To me.
Yeah. And the his face is still totally obscured except for
his eyes.
As we know Cartoon character's eyes are always visible even in the dark.
So so we're still getting some mystery here. You know. He's he's spoken and he's appeared. So we know he's not just a story.
That the island just still themselves.
But we still don't know anything about even, like, what kind of animal he is necessarily. Also, it wasn't until this reread just now as we're doing this podcast that I noticed the scale on the moon face as the moon is rising above Yeah. That's right. And and that one I've seen mentioned in a couple of write ups Sparks usually kind of,
you know, avoids these, like, ci site gag during serious moments, but it is a little moment of of levi during this kind creepy moment. And I wonder if he, like talked himself into it because this is a very
deeply
creepy
story. Right? Like, this is a a generational sort of kidnapping.
And so, you know, I don't know. Maybe he was just having some fun with it or maybe he wanted to diffuse it a little bit. So on the next page,
it's now the crack of Dawn
and the duct are getting ready for the days business. They've gotta get the ship ready to float back at the right tight again. Donald is giving orders
to his nephews on how to get ready.
We get some pretty good nautical speak here. You know. He and instruct Huey, to start the engine, loo to oil the lynch.
And then dewey is told to stand by the caps and keep the anchor chains str. I don't think I could tell you what that means.
And then Dewey does not respond
and, you know, the audience is immediately figured out that he must have been taken, but Donald is
searching for his his lazy nephew
until one of the nephews thanks to step off the boat onto the little,
you know, at hole or
i part of the wreath that they're on and he sees the tracks of an armored man.
Again, I noticed
Al as we get the caption
the first crack of dawn, it shows the sun just below it rising above the water with the word. Crack. Yes.
Yeah. Thanks for pointing that out. That's another of those kind of note site gag that's always stated in this. And it's just another little fun moment of levi. There's also a a pretty funny looking bird again in the background. I'm I'm figuring out doing these reread now and really focused on the art. That Barks just loved to draw birds or at least during this year. Yeah. That's that's evidence like Barks, any, likes some
terminology as you've noticed. Right.
Alright. And so on the next page, you know, Donald has instantly clocked that something's wrong. There might be something to the kidnapping story. So,
you know, they follow the tracks as far as they can that they disappear into the waves. It's been erased.
And then Donald,
very sen,
says that, you know, he must have been taken back to the island because, like, what other alternative really would there be.
But one of the nephews, wonders, if the armored man could have come from the old ship.
Donald points out that, you know, most of the time that completely under underwater.
And the nephews used rightfully for kids who have just, you know, realized one of their brothers is missing. Wonder if it's a ghost.
And
Donald
says, you know, Fo, he had to come from the island, they're gonna go back and tear the place apart.
And then one of the nephews catches that they can't go back because the large hole has been gouging in the ship, and it might have been caused by a sword. And Condolences says were trapped in his bottle episode until we resolved the conflict.
He didn't really say that. It was implied. It was implied. Absent.
Alright. So...
Yeah. So we're just getting some some good clothes. The flip footsteps that go down to just below the surface of the water and then disappear. That either his strikes were washed away or that was his destination. Right. Exactly.
So the Ducktales are realizing that they're pretty well stuck. And Donald is getting
more nervous about, you know, the possibility that maybe it is a ghost. He doesn't really know what's going on.
But he is continuing to keep a pretty level head. You know, his next move is to radio,
the news to port and get help as quick as possible.
And then he realized that the
wires have been stripped off of the radio.
And, you know, the line there, he says that iron plated Scrooge
stripped the wires off the radio.
There's a couple of other
moments in the... On this page. Where he's starting to use some pretty funny nickname
for, you know, he doesn't really know anything other than that he's Al armored man.
He says that
a guy that runs around in ten pants and a hot climate like this is capable of anything.
And and that was something that I picked up on this reading. He's got some pretty amusing
expressions for for the armored man. But he he they figure that he's probably... The the man probably used the wires to tie up dewey.
So his next step is to ask
Huey, to lights some signal rockets,
and he figures out that they were in the hold, which has been completely flooded with water.
Yeah. So
I like... I mean, this page seems to be just
plugging plot holes. I'm just like, well, why didn't they just why don't they just radio for help or whatever and... Or send some rockets or whatever. And the fact that he probably used the i I would thought, you know, a soldier from four hundred years ago, certainly wouldn't know to
destroy their radio
so they can't get help.
But if he's just looking for something along and and durable to tie his
kidnapping and picked him up with, then
that makes sense. Yeah. I agree with you. I think this this page showed some care and that sort of... As you say, why didn't they this? Why didn't they this and a lot of creators
don't always take the time. And in some stories parks doesn't really take the time to kind of explain potential plot
like that. Alright. So they're
their next best hope then because they're logically going through their options is to light a signal fire. So Donald says they need to go to the highest
ridge
on the reef and he tells the nephews to light it there. And the nephews used discover that there is a hole in that one.
And
one of the nephews used says that it sounds hollow
like, there's a big cavern
underneath or
if you will, maybe A g.
And
Donald is skeptical, but the nephew you says, well, i'll yell down in the hole and you'll hear it echo, and so he... He else hello? This is Louis,
and they here
Hello? This is Dewey,
and there's a a fun moment where the Ducktales
simultaneously
lean in and clunky their heads together. And I thought it was a nice touch that they didn't really even express any pain from that. It's a good gag, but it just shows that they're really interested.
Focused on getting him back. Yeah. I'll also point out for the listeners
that the highest point on the reef is probably
ten to fifteen feet high, and it's not an impressive peak.
But make very little difference. But...
Yeah.
I like... I like the the echo
the echo they expected was different. Was a nice touch. Yeah. I I thought that was a really good game. Alright. So they are...
They're figuring more and more stuff out.
They they know now where he is, and you can kinda see them audibly
exhale a little bit because they know that he's okay and they so they start to plan how they're gonna get down there.
He...
When when he has
tried to tell them,
you know, the situation,
his voice gets muffled,
because the armored man has clearly claimed
it shut his mouth shut,
and
they decide to search the reef for another entrance, thinking that there's gotta to be a hole that's above the line.
But they're not able to find one. So Donald says that they're gonna make an entrance out of this one,
and they're gonna use their tongs on their boat to just yank the entrance open.
And Donald,
closes by saying if you can get the tongs into old ten pants, will yank him out of there too,
which thought was an awesome line.
This is part of the
ingenuity that you pointed out the beginning of the episode where they're using the resources that are available to them. We're getting, you know, the clever donald and he's very determined and very
resourceful and level headed right in the crisis here. Alright. So by by the afternoon on the next page, they've expanded the whole enough to get down.
And, you know, the kids are wondering what she's planning on doing when he's lowered. They asked him, you know, you're not going in there unarmed and donald
has... He's got a shot,
which he calls a twelve gauge can opener
so that I can make a dent in that tin of sausage.
And I just... I love that line.
Almost all the lines on this page are great.
You know, they're they're pretty nervous. They say that this is pretty risky.
I like how determined Donald is here. He says I don't care if there's a found full of Sherman tanks. I'm going down. And then there's a sequence
where he
He says lower me boys as he gets lowered by a line into the hole, and then when he gets down to the bottom of the hole,
he sees
the armored man is lighting an old Canon aimed directly up else h me boys.
And he narrowly avoids the canon fire
and, you know, they've gotta figure something else out. And again, this is just a great gag. It's it's
exciting. It's funny. It's very well drawn. And in last frame for refers to the armored man is Al the boiler breach is Oh, yeah. Another another excellent nickname. Thank you for catching that old boiler breaches. And, unfortunately, Donald has dropped his
twelve twelve gauge can opener her as he as he was clam back up for his life. That's right. So, yeah, he he
the nephews...
He reminds the nephews that
they still need to light that signal fire.
But the man do as zip because he can reach it from here. And, you know, this is like, about the first time we're donald loses this is temper.
Pretty impressive for Donald Duck, and he...
If we've got another excellent nickname here, he says, that's not fair. Come out of your whole and fight you cast iron go for.
And and this is the nephews. The two nephews turned to kind of have a nice level head. They've got a really great plan here. They logically say, you know, he's he's really nervous.
He's scared about them bringing and reinforcements. So what they wanna do is they wanna light a signal i are much farther away, one that's gonna draw them out, draw him out, and then they'll try and grab him with the tongs.
And before as they're lighting the signal fire, they see that the tide come out again and the old ship is now showing. Yeah. And and I think they have learned at this point that it's not a a whole
a whole one farmer Men as one of the nephews
speculated.
Right. Yeah. They know they've got a solitary component. So
They've got the upper hand on him as long as they can keep their head.
Alright? So
this this story takes place over just a couple of days. We see a nice clear passage of time. We get night once again and the Ducktales are just
staring
at the hole because they figured donald at least figures that know, that's the only way he can get out.
And one of the nephews is skeptical because he thinks he heard a creek on the old ship, but Donald is like, no.
Only the whole stair... Stare at the whole
we see the Armored man is exiting from the ship and we see him take a little boat out
through a swinging door in the manor war,
and he uses some of that old English, she speak that sorta shakespeare ex
fo ex with my trusty blade. I must Al for And he says Bonnie Queen best will night me for this nights work. Bonnie Queen best is a nickname for Elizabeth. And so that's how we we can be pretty sure that he's british.
And so Donald again says keep watching
in front of us,
and we get this pretty famous scene of the night onboarding the ship, very men
willing his sword.
Behind the docks.
This was used for the cover
It Barks an oil of this scene. This is very icon I noticed this the armor man's first line on this page is beyond von boat ill. Yeah. I have no idea what that what that means. So there... If we have any four hundred year old listeners,
they can they can comment on your facebook page.
We we can. Yes. I... I'll take a crack at it. Right? Y is just
they over theirs.
Yeah. Right. And I think Al is just to, like, a ras.
Okay. And, you know, boat ill is just Barks bearing you ill will, I think. But I think that this is really just the sort of like,
Robin hood
that audiences
from the forties would have expected.
Yeah. Alright. So fortunately, on the next page Donald gotten hungry and he asks for a tomato from their basket.
Finding it to be. Right. He toss it backwards
right into the armor man's face. He gives the old tiny
swear odd
which I'm not convinced anyone actually said. But apparently Al, like, one of those blasts for me
curse because it's like god's body. Like a a way of saying god's body.
And
they
they realized that he's behind them, the armored man, he takes us slice at them but misses and they have to scatter and hide themselves into the kelp
the the iron man's very frustrated, but at least he can kick their fire, their fire into the c. And this is a very very quick, but action packed page that's very dramatic and satisfying. To me. Yeah. That's very visual. I like that Donald probably would have thrown around tomato went the guy's face if he had known the guy was there, but he accidentally did it anyway. A little happens stands. And, you know, I'm just noticing on this read through right now, how cool it is that the
armored man is generally drawn in silhouette until the last panel of the page is he's kicking the fire, his...
The the glare of the fire really illuminate him neatly in a way that just looks very cool, artistic. Yeah. Alright there's a lot of detail on his armor. You can see all the little pieces on the on the arm. And there's different pieces on the chest and Right The helmet has little flares on it and...
Yeah. Even the sword has kind of a an interesting hilt on it. There's it would've you quite a while to draw this guy and Severino.
Yeah. Exactly. And when you consider that he was doing two full length stories for this month's release, Alright. So on the next page, the Ducktales are regroup.
They figure out that he's left, and so they get back to their boat, and they cast a search light on him.
Not finding him
anywhere.
And and then one of the nephews here is that Creek again, and he turns the light on to the ship, and they do finally see the armored man going into a hole in the stern,
which is the back of the boat. Right? I think I probably learned that from this one. Oh, I bad from getting my canoe advantage at age twelve. Excellent.
It's it's a.
The the Ducktales here are also
in mostly silhouette
for the the top half page. So we just get there. They're outlines and they're lit eyes, of course, and then and then kind of a cool shot with their. One of them holding that that kind of hook pike sort of thing they use for the kelvin one of them manning the search light. Yeah. That's right. It's a boat hook which I learned from last week episode or the the one previous care of the river.
And and it's a cool panel too where they're turning the lights the bottom left panel where they're, like, partially
illuminated and partially Yeah. Partially dark. And same thing with the the armored man. Alright. So they've they've realized they've pretty much figured everything out right now. Right? Donald snaps and it kind of represents the audience knowing everything.
So
finally, now that we've got everything, I think Barks decides that we can flash down into
the armored man's hideout out where he's loading. He's reloading his
old tiny
gun
and talking with dewey who refers to him as jingle joints and what a mess of trouble he got himself in when he kid kidnapped him.
And
the arm man says verily they they say at the,
another line that I really like. And so they lied another signal fire. They're getting ready for the morning.
And Donald says, okay. Well, now we we know we've got to get past the ship so we've gotta think of a way to get past the off to octopus. And by the time low tide comes around, one of the f fuse Hue
says that he's got a plan. He's rolling
a large slab of meat full to the brim with Chili pepper. Saying that that will get rid of the octopus. Seems like a good plan. It does. Yeah. I also like that line from the armored man. It was good. Just like man, this is a lot harder than it was fifty years ago and a hundred years ago.
Old time speak for you're you're not kidding.
Yeah. Yeah.
Also,
this issue provides some practical knowledge on how to def defeat kaiju you if ever you're
confronted with a two hundred foot twelve monster.
That's right. Yeah. Because the
the chill solidified meat is gonna turn out to be very effective
they use the tons to hop
to drop it into the hatch,
and they hear him eating it. And then we get just this
spectacular. I I don't know. Maybe this is devices. But I I absolutely love this panel of the octopus rising and spicy agony.
From the ship. Utterly ob it. It's a a full half page. There Barks sea Barks,
fleeing the dev devastation.
There's a greatest fresh on the octopus face.
And the nephew he says, oh, I must used sprinkle too much pepper.
And when I read this, at age either seven or eight. I was I was pretty much hollow with left between this one and the next panel.
I I do think this is probably a moment of levi that bark, you know, stuck in because he wanted to diffuse this.
Pretty creepy story, but... But I just... I love it so much. Yeah. It's definitely a a memorable frame. I also
Yeah. It's definitely a a memorable frame. I also
didn't notice until we're reading it now, but he's finally doing some like half page splash
instead of just eight of the page eight of the pay eight of the page. Here's some
exposition He's taking some time to kind of save her some of the visuals Yeah. They're few and far between, but sometimes he does get to push the medium. K. So on the next page, we get our last glimpse of the octopus. Using his tentacles to to run away
over
uber the reef and one of the nephews gets off the great line. I wonder what Huey, give for a ton of ice cream.
And this is left the entrance
exposed. The g has a trap door on it. That they figure is locked from below.
You know, they can open it with the tongs, but the nephews are out of idea but Donald got one now. He says he's got a plan, and that Al he needs is a squirt gun and a couple of mice. So they find a single mouse
from in the galley.
The nephews are very surprised that that's all he wants to combat the Armored man. But
Donald
takes a look at the grow mouse and says the likes the grinch in his eyes. And he takes
the squirt gun
filled with roach powder, and he heads off, and
just a really cool line from that you, so I'm gonna read it in its entirety.
Going into battle, an armored man with a square gun and mouse. Do you suppose on mcdonald's in his right mind I hope not. His sensible ideas never work. So Donald arrives at the trap door and asks the nephews used to open it.
And he's getting ready to square the man with the roach powder, but he comes up with a with a gun instead of sort like donald expect Donald is able to duck the shot in the nick of time. He squirt the armored and man with the powder and he falls cla into the g. And Donald
drops down with the mouse who he has nick nickname mont more.
Which again, just a great little random touch the the the ferocious mouse that's sn in his cage.
The other man, of course, is welding. It's like a blender bus. It's not even
any kind of gun that we would have seen in the last two or three hundred years.
The big the big kind of bell
at the end like a like a trumpet. I guess it's a kind of musk, but
I also thought it was interesting
to see a small
realistic looking mouse in a Disney comic.
In in theoretically the same world that Mickey mouse lives in. And I I wondered about the the laws of this universe again.
And again, it's just for a Barks fan, it's just some thing that's total background. You will probably stop thinking about it another five to ten issues in.
So while the man is distracted, you know, with the of
roach pattern his eyes, Donald
drops Sm more and
and says in you go, it's your job to get out.
And the armored man freaks out. He says that damon is loose in my armor.
He's removing his helmet. We see that he's kind of a feeble old man.
There's a panel where Donald yells at him take it off. Take it off, Take it off, and I've gotta say I'm kinda surprised the one hasn't been picked up as some kind of a meme as out of context. It's it's pretty funny.
So the armored man does remove all his armor.
And he comes to his senses. As Donald is standing with his
musk his sword and behind his Canon and says now we face each other on even terms sir boiler shirt and does a final touch mount warranty
sn.
Very fear some tiny mouse.
I have to say, this this was immediately reminiscent to me of
my favorite musical number from another Disney property, fin and Fe. There is an early episode
in which
For for abs older her sister is trying to be on a date, and her Nemesis has cro mccabe some acorns into her pants and two squirrels immediately dive into her pants and run around the inside of her pants to try and find the acorns. And then we have a yes, a fantastic two minute number called squirrel my pads done by two two free style wrappers who happen to be there in the park and think that she
Metaphorically has some squirrels in her pants, and that's why she's dancing so awesome.
And she actually moves a lot like this guy. Like, it's it's kind of the same I guess it's the universal way of indicating.
I have small mammals inside of my trousers.
That's true. I wonder this is how a person moved see. It is it is a another Disney property. Maybe.
What their names,
swamp,
and
trying to remember the finish creators. Dan Meyer? That's right. And Jeff Marsh. Right? Maybe Yeah. Maybe they were big Barks fans. Who knows. That is extremely plausible.
Yeah.
Alright. So on the next page, you know, everyone is reunited, they've rescued
dewey we and the Armored man is despair what's gonna become with him. What is his lord surf Francis Drake.
When will he think of him and he reveals that he was safeguard regarding a treasure, and he didn't keep the gold safe.
Donald sees the the gold and he starts to drool over it and they hear his story because of now now, of course, they can.
They reveal, you know, the the do figure out that this guy thinks that her Francis drake is still alive
and
they kind of all sit around the lantern,
and he explains how, you know, a ship was washed over this wreath.
And had crashed into the cavern above
and that the captain of the ship ended up staying to guard the treasure or the the sole survivor rather stayed to guard the treasure.
This is on to the next page.
He brought the treasure down into the cavern and waited for her Francis drake to return, but as the years passed and he got older.
He
decided to
embark on the kidnapping that wound being passed down from generation
to generation of armored man every fifty years.
Someone would kid another boy off the local island. And so the secret of the kit kidnapping is out.
There's another great download line on here.
There's a couple of them... All everyone's starting to talk to like him now. On the pre... On the previous page, the nephews used the term odds bob Now. And on on this page, Donald asks if the armored man was the sole survivor of the crash four hundred years ago, and he says, no.
The captain was...
And
Donald says, thanks. Now I can start believing you calendar again. Yeah. Yeah. That was I loud that this is not some kind of immortal being that is... Yeah. Living in inside to shift.
That's a good catch because that is also one of my favorite quotes in this one. Alright. So
the secret is out
This is become sort of a generational curse rather than a supernatural one. Donald takes a quick moment to act like, he is her francis drake,
but the guy like no not you. I've got a picture of him in this book. So Donald isn't able to get the gold.
We transition pretty quickly.
To
the depths being fed as heroes on the island for stopping this sort of generational curse.
Donald asks after the gold,
but the guy who's presenting him to the key... The key to the city, the the mayor says sorry, by salvage rights. You know, the goal belongs to the man who was guarding it. And and the last panel. Ryan, Why don't you tell us about the last panel?
He's at Tony's burger palace which appears to be kind of a an outdoor diner or a food truck or something.
And he's in some ridiculous
clothes. This is how I would think of, like,
a very os
billionaire being dressed in maybe the twenties or the teens, I would say,
And he's in some very
ge clothing with a, like a pocket chain and a wide pink hat and very pointy shoulders on his on his jacket and then just a big open sack of gold coins right next to him on the stool. He says another of the hamburger sc nave, They taste mighty good mighty with an at the end good with any at the end after and half century of you fish, and we get the nice little cap. That it is yi end. And so
that is...
That is the ghost of the g.
I I know I've been refusing over this one because I love this story.
Almost everything
about it works for me, you know, there's
couple of, like parts that, like, it's not quite a perfect story, but to me, this is some of of Bark.
At its best. I'll talk about that in a minute. But but, you know, I'm I'm curious just right off the bat. Like, what do you think of this one?
I love it. This this might be my new favorite one.
I like... I like a little mystery. I like that our good guys are good guys. And they, you know, use their clever nest to kind of
overcome the the bad guy and then solve the mystery and resolve the conflict
I thought it was interesting.
This is the first...
This is the first one I've read that involves a large pile of gold of the many that we've read so far that involve Al large pile of gold, where Donald did not end up with the gold, he is he has a key to the city and the thanks of the... All the people whose kids are not getting kicked that now. And
He just has to be grumpy knowing that he's a hero instead of a rich hero. But, yeah, I liked the bad guy. I like that the bad guy wasn't even like evil, he just thought it was his duty, you know, to... Yeah. It's like a legacy. Yeah. I like that it was all in one spot.
I like the kind of elements
and the artwork work, I like the giant octopus and just kind of
trying to beat each other with very limited resources. I mean, this guy just has whatever was on the boat four hundred years ago, And then Donald has whatever happened to be on his boat when they went out to go, get some help for the day,
and
that's the nature of their combat.
That's true. It's like a a really good matching of width.
I'm I'm really glad to hear that you liked this one This one is
just to me some of the best of Barks. You know? I I love the setup as you say, it's really tight even if this came out of, like, a different sort of comic ten page setup up. I feel like it's very organic how it starts out. I love the setup at the beginning.
Where you kinda just hear these rumbling in the background, you know, it sets it up very suspense.
And
those, like,
conversations about the missing boys
make for a really great element of of craziness this. And,
you know, there there are some very silly parts, but this is a deeply dark story. Right? I mean, it's about kid kidnapping that obviously ruined
half dozen or so lives over the course of hundreds of years.
And, you know, the sub text is that these kids were, like, brain washed.
Into this, basically
over over the centuries and grew up with this, like, horrible legacy. So
I like that the armored man gets his sort of freedom at the end.
I think the humor in this is really great. I I think my only real criticism I did feel like the ending was just a little bit too abrupt. In this one, you know, the little transition to the hamburger stand, it happens pretty quick.
But otherwise, I I I would call this one a masterpiece.
And,
fortunately,
the users of the index site would agree with me. You know, we always check Inducks
to see what that user generated
score average is this one is rated very high. This one gets an eight point zero out of ten as of right now.
Good for forty
first place out of over forty thousand eight hundred
Disney comics.
This is our first top fifty story in fact, out of the five hundred some Barks stories. This is
top. This is the top thirty second of all the Barks and the top forty first
overall. So we're we're a high into the ninety nine point ninth percentile here.
This is a beloved bark adventure that really does set the tone for a lot of the stories
that are gonna follow.
Any any other
thoughts about just the sort of,
you know, how the story is before I talk about some other reflections and how it holds up and the other media.
Yeah. It's just...
Like I can tell, it was very well thought out And it's not like trophy. You know what I mean? It's not like oh, this this old thing again they switched to bodies because they both touched mystical object at the same time or whatever, Like,
This is a really interesting
narrative, you know. And and I think it tells it really well. Yeah. I agree. It's it's it's sat on a good
it just has such a good setup and a good flow.
I would say that this one also holds up very well. You know? There's not really a lot that's
kind of retro grade or problematic about it.
You know, I I I guess this is before kind of the stranger danger Era, where I think you know, people would probably look in a scans that a a kidnapping plot like this. But...
But in general, this this holds up very well. The only thing that's kind of archaic is kind of our understanding of of middle English. Right? I don't know if you're aware of this but the use of yee, do you know why that's historically incorrect.
Yes.
It's because
there was a the letter thorn. Right?
That is to make the the the sound at the beginning of the word the. And when it's written, it looks to our modern eye like a y
And so you and I happening upon it would look at it and say, oh, that looks like a year And so we we thought that everyone was talking like that back then, but they would have just said the or the the way we do and and written down in a way that looks like a. Exactly. That's exactly right. Very well said it's And so, you know, we have a lot of, like, European and other international listeners
and and I'm I'm curious how they represent in the translation sort of this archaic speech. But this is sort of signaling to us when we see y old.
We know that it's supposed to be a little tiny. But really, it would be pronounced the old. And in my own kind of mental gymnastics for justifying this, I I would say that over the generations as the... There's been this sort of passing on this burden.
That, you know, maybe one of the kids was taught out of a book or something. He could've have made that kind of mistake and started to pass on the the old use
speed speaking.
So anyway, That's true. Yeah. Then this is not actually a a figure from the sixteen hundred he he played a game of telephone for four hundred years. That's right. Is at the end of it. Exactly.
So appearances and other media. As I mentioned, this was a story that bark to do an oil painting for.
It's well worth looking up. It's it's beautiful. It shows the man
walking out of the out of the sea behind the Ducktales
about to strike and it's it's a very
well known painting of his...
I think it was done in miniature.
The one of the covers for this was That expectation of that. I'll have to share that one with you and I'll put it up on the Facebook page I'm not aware of any other use of the Armored man or any references and Ducktales or anything.
I did see... I I consider this one to be a very educational one in some ways, you know, just learning about
help being turned into Iodine was was
educational for me. I saw some of the mechanics of how tide worked in this. A lot of those great nautical terms
Some of the archaic terms that are used are actually accurate. I like the use of, like, how it
as an ad adverb in the English.
So, again, this is just a masterpiece.
Do you want to nominate a favorite panel?
Or talk about any of them is your choice.
I think I think my favorite panel
might be when
Donald goes up to the hatch with his
roach spray loaded up in his squirt gun, and the hatch pops open with the armored man and his blender bus He kind of
consumes the front half of Donald face with it.
Donald is is halfway halfway into the end of the Front us there, and says, u. I expected you to pop up with a sword. I just like the... Just kind of the... He is in Immortal danger, but he's still not losing losing his
his census, you know, he's still in kind of control of the situation.
He was surprised He's a little off balance. He's gonna figure out how to recover from this.
Yeah. I I really like your favorite panel choices. You have some of the, like, less conventional ones. You know? I'm very drawn towards the show panels.
And I I really do have to go with the ones that are obvious, you know, the one with the armored man
illuminated after or he gets off the ship for the first time. It's it's very show. It screams to to be recognized, but I'm I'm a sucker. For that panel. And then, you know, as you heard me wax on about the
the octopus interrupting from the ship, that that is another great one. But and this would be... When the when the three of them try to look down the cabin at the same time, when do we shout up, and they Al fuck their heads together. That's pretty good. Yeah. That's a fun moment. Excellent.
Well, thank you again so much for joining me for this. I'm glad I'm glad that you got a new favorite. This one
is now the highest rated
that we have talked about.
I don't think it's gonna be for very long because we're about to enter kind of a a a very classic very rich period of Barks work. But
Yeah. There's a lot to look forward to here.
Coming up next episode, we are gonna be talking about
adventure down under.
And
again, to to listeners, I'm I'm just really grateful. I've gotten some nice notes recently
about the show, and we are picking up some steam and getting a lot of international
listeners, and I'm just I'm so grateful for Severino one who gives this a listen. So again, thanks for joining us.
If you have any thoughts or comments, you can drop us Al line at our remarks at g mail dot com. You can also find us on Facebook,
and we will hopefully see you or your hear from soon.