Hello, and welcome to Barks Remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer Al artist of the greatest Donald and unscrew comments of all time. Join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing or order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Hello, and welcome back to Barks remarks. I am still Barks sever,
still a grown man who enjoys donald dot com.
I've managed
to khan yet another friend into
letting me talk about comments with him.
We have a first time guest today.
If you can introduce yourself, please.
Hello. My name is Ben Johnson. I'm a big comic nerd, but not as big as smart. And yeah, I'm excited
to talk about donald Ducktales. Is one of my favorite Disney characters.
Excellent. The bend, do you have any experience with the Karl Barks
stories at all?
No. Not really. I, you know, introduced to watching Donald Cartoons when I was younger and, you know, duck when i was whenever that was on the Disney afternoon stuff. Yeah. Those were great. Right. And and Ducktales was, of course, based on many of the Barks stories.
But
he actually did work on a lot of those early Inducks
cartoons
too before he transitioned over to doing the comment.
Excellent. And
we are here to discuss
adventure down under
which is kind of the mandatory
Australian four a. The
sort of every Tv series or
every adventure series has to have the Australia
episode. Right?
Yeah. You know, it's pretty unique place. And so you can't really have where adventures take place and not do Al an Australian episode or issue. Right. And and we've been... We've been around the globe where just about,
I think ten
episodes in, and we've been along the The mississippi River. We've been egypt, we've been in the West Indy indies.
We've been all over the place. So
Al lot of fun globe t in the Carl Barks stories, you actually
spent some time in Australia
yourself which is a big part of why I wanted this to be your first
episode. Yeah. Yeah. I'm very familiar with Kangaroo, and I was there for two years out in the bush. So
I was pretty much went through all the same things that Donald went through here. So... Yeah. You you to get to be in the Al less less populated part Yeah. Yeah. Alright. So
let's go into a little bit of the overview about this issue.
Again, adventure down under is
from July of nineteen forty seven. This one was published in four color one hundred and fifty nine, which is the same issue that
our last
episode. Our last story, ghost of the g was in, and that one had the cover story or the cover art rather,
but it's it's kind of
note notable, I think that these two
major and very well remembered stories were originally published together. That's not something that happens all the time. It has, of course, been reprinted many many times. I first read it in donald Ducktales adventures number eleven Barks I think in nineteen eighty nine. This one is twenty five pages,
and new to the podcast, I've decided that I should be having our guests offer up our brief synopsis of the story before we go into the narrative later. So ben. Let's hear it. What is this story about
Oh well, you know, it starts off just like any adventure they're sending Al home, trying to think it's something like fun to do. They
walk out of the street and come across a hip test. Which I think all good story
start by people getting ties.
Donald gets hepatitis into thinking he's a kangaroo and filling homes sick So he's they find a way to
Australia
and
meet a
kind of a shady character with a mustache
sends him off hunting kangaroo,
and there's some aboriginal
and all kinds of of hygiene and sue. Yeah. Lot lots of very Australian elements.
And we'll we'll talk about. I I I like that I've got you on and I can ask you, you know, how true some of this stuff rings? Oh sure. Yeah. Thank you for that.
So a little bit of sort of background Trivia.
I mentioned already that this is the b story
that was after goes to the g.
This is the second story that we've done that is
rated in the top fifty and is actually our first to be top a top ten rated story already end up. Which will go into a little bit more.
Another new thing that I'd like to do now
starting this episode, I... I've noticed when doing research
that these stories, the titles get translated in kind of a variety of ways around the world,
and this one seem to have a particular they're particularly wide number of titles. So I wanted to just talk about what some of those were because I think it's fine and I like to try to wrap my wrap my mouth around saying things in languages that I don't speak. Well probably not very successful But in Brazil, this was called I was a kangaroo
or
fu kangaroo
in France. This is
the generic Donald in Australia. Don't.
In Germany, this is Australian adventure
throughout, Al,
I think. In Italy, it's Kangaroo Hunter Al
Dick.
Mexico
is Australian Adventure Ventura, They are Australia.
Netherlands
is
Adventure in the
or Ave
b did
he.
And then in Spain, it's different than Mexico. It was y.
I was a kangaroo.
Another bit of trivia,
the Just on that too, I wanna add if the down under
probably doesn't have... They're they're down under to us, but maybe in Brazil
down under...
That's
like, a little bit to the left over. And I like say. Yeah. They don't I I would imagine that the... That's probably the reason for
changing it in some of those languages and countries
Alright. Is that something that... I I think they do refer to themselves is being down under. Right?
Yeah. I mean, they're familiar with it I don't think they refer to themselves
as being down under, but they are aware that Americans refer to them because they're not down under to themselves. Right. Right.
Making.
Yeah. I mean, and and America has gone through, like, it's Australia
fascination
Right. Or like,
he's with crocodile done and everything anything. And I imagine it must be kind of infuriating. Well, it's kinda interesting to see something in the context of, you know,
for Steve Irwin and
Crocodile Dundee Movies because... Yeah. I think if this had taken place after, maybe it would have a character like that in here. But we don't have that stereotype yet.
It's true. I think this must have been fairly early in the, like, fast fascination with Australia. Right? Because this isn't the late of, and I can't think of a lot of media that is that sort of oh american in Australia
from that era. I I also found it to be notable that the
the app originals in this were among the very first human
characters
that Barks has drawn.
So far. You know, he doesn't usually
characters as like humans he he depicts him as, like, a dog nose usually. And and we'll talk about, you know, there there certainly problems with their depiction but they are sure. Unlike most of the background characters, they're actually those humans. Yeah. It is... I haven't thought about that. I i mean, when I was a kid, I remember thinking... Because there's regular
animals in the in this universe.
And they're different from the ant
animals in it. And I I wondered about that. Yeah. And when I bring people in in for the these newbie,
slots like urine. This is always one of the things that they get focused on. Right? Like are these? Are these animals are these? Any answer is they're Huey,. You know, like, they're there people...
They're duct people on dog people,
and we only occasionally
think about the fact that they're also animals. And I guess this story is one of those rare times too.
Alright. So for the value range of this one,
The highest documented sale was seventy five hundred dollars
for.
Yeah. Nine point six rate. Which is the same Mh. As it was last episode. Right? Because this is from Ghost. This has the same is in the same comic as ghost of the garage. So we're gonna launch now into a little bit of
one of my favorite parts the the background where we talk about some historical and geographical
context.
Again, we are in nineteen forty seven right now, and I think that American
Attitudes from about Australia we're probably not the same as they are today. Right? It was probably
regard as much more remote and, you know, I I think we get a taste to that when, Donald talks about how now it civilized.
And I think there was this feeling that until recently, it hadn't been civilized.
Yeah. It's probably, you know, once
air travel has become like, because I mentioned air you know, few travels there by playing and, you know, and
yeah, That that...
That was weird and I can't remember where it was when it meets that stranger with the mustache. It seemed out of context like comments about
civilized. I was... See I couldn't quite follow what they talking about. Yeah. And, you know, it's one of the things that I think is the tone for a lot of these stories is that idea of civilization
but
it also makes for some very interesting
and adventure stories. Yeah. For, you know, they for children and in in viewing things with a sense of like, civilization versus something worth exploring and I give them a little lay leeway just to seem a little bit more interesting No ben. These stories are
year old
having a podcast.
Oh i clearly. Yes. Yes. Absolutely fully
we we
these are our
stories and fact Rx has put so much
care into them, but I think they've been so well remember. I... It comes up to me, because when I read this, that's one thing I've been...
Especially this app issue is it's brought to the forefront I can tell a Carl Barks He's he's very good at almost like Calvin and Hobbs where it's an adult, but it tells us story from the perspective of a child. There's so much media content that we see now you can tell it's adult trying to write things for children. But you can tell he has a way of making it almost seem like it's from a perspective of a child. Yeah. And and I think... And he never talks down. Yeah. Yeah. Even a little bit. And and sometimes, some of that's just an effect of
you know, in the forties and fifties, like, kids, there was kind of a different attitude
about childhood, and kids were more independent, so some of that stuff is kind of jarring. But...
But it's great that he never never Barks down. Yeah.
Definitely
So for for the background to me, one of the natural things to this on is this just the idea of the kangaroo as the national animal of Australia. And, you know, I think one of the really striking things in this comic is the depiction of them as pests.
Right? I think I think if you're familiar with Australia,
that
is like,
very logical. Right? Yeah. I imagine you have some experience with that. But I think to most Americans when they first read it, It might be jarring to think about their, like, iconic animal as a pest. Yeah. They're
I I wouldn't put them exactly in the same category as a pest. I guess I don't mean like a pest, like,
but but kinda like in the in the same vein as deer for America. Yeah. Yeah. Well, the main the main risk, there was a a small village I was living in that was...
If you or it's about a three hour drive that I would do pretty regularly
for one little town to another town. And if you go at Don or desk, You can't go five miles without seeing a, you know, Barks kangaroo and and they they have the tendency to just stand on the edge of the road and and this look like twitch look in their eyes, like, I'm am not gonna jump. Can I jump? And I think they they think that they can jump over the cars. They're ability to judge how fast they're going and and so it's they're they're a danger for people driving those roads. And they even have... They have... And they install these things called Barks that comes out of the grill and it goes
up above the driver side and sometimes on the passenger side. And it basically... So it just kinda tears the kangaroo and half to either side of you. Rather than going through the windshield and killing it because they jump right before impact going right through the windshield instead of hitting the bumper. So it's They're not... So not really a pest, and they don't go in and, you know, in this in the comic, they're tear they're going in and ruining the crops and you know, they're doing some things that cares, you know, don't really do. They...
And I read a little bit that maybe they don't terrorized
props in this way, but I I think that there have been periods
based on my reading. Correct me if I'm wrong.
Where, like they are a a real menace to to her ranch and to agriculture when they've been Al their, like, over populated kia.
Yeah. By the time I was there, population control wasn't really Al issue mainly. Mainly just
dangerous
for people driving down the roads. Right. Yeah. And I I know. I read that they have, like a calling quota where they there's a certain number of them that are allowed to be killed because they do try so to manage the population. Yeah. They
friends with some aboriginal people there. And apparently, the aboriginal are allowed to hunt them and they actually just
go and you you'll go camping and they'll... And I actually went camping with them a few times and you'd literally just sw over the side of the road and they see one pull out rifle,
and
just shoot one and put in the back of the pickup truck, and that was our dinner.
One there...
Is kangaroo meat. It's Well, you can go to the grocery store. You know, we didn't have a lot of money there. So
I was like, oh, this is way cheaper than ground beef for my spaghetti. So it it's definitely an it's really gaming. Not not very good, but if you have enough
pasta sauce to it, you know?
And then the last thing to say about kangaroo is something that, like, everyone knows at this point, but it kind of bears saying that the the pouch
never works the way.
Works the way that they depicted in the cartoons.
It's a lot go. Right? It's doesn't is the other
background in this that, you know, is is Al little less
fun to talk about is the depiction of of the app originals. Right. Like... And I was really interested it by because, you know, you have to acknowledge right away that it's it's a it's a clearer,
you know, they're using that pigeon speed. They're depicted is Al,
I think, long past
when that
would have been a concern.
I I read a little bit about it and and from what I can tell, there's no greater incidents of cannibalism
in Australia compared to, like, any other
indigenous
society
around the world.
So, that's unfortunate. But the that interesting thing to me was it looks like he went out of his way to, like, visually
depict them at least somewhat accurately.
Yeah. I mean, it takes I mean, obviously the character troy or the over
characterized
depiction is a little
problematic, but it's They have the dot... The dot style artwork
on their bodies,
which you do see an original artwork is that, you know, the the... I don't know. There's a word for it I can't remember, but it's where they, you know, represent instead of lines. It's through dots, there's
snakes and lines that... You know, it's close. It's it's as good as someone
right. Expect from somebody in the forties to do. Right. I'm I'm sure it's like mixing elements.
But the thing is that it really
contrasts with just like, their look is a lot more accurate than, like you know, I think the sort of savage way that he fix them. It... Yeah is kind of a mixture of different things.
There's a... We have a boomerang. You gotta have a boomerang. So that's that's it's a good story. Yeah. Alright.
As far as notable appearances go, we have more full mary, I would say is the most notable one. We don't have any
characters that are gonna go on to be reoccurring And then I've been talking about kind of the version of of the hero that we get. And what's interesting. I I call Donald in this passive Donald. Right? Because throughout this whole story, he's very
compliant.
He's just kind of long for the right. Right at the very beginning, the kids are able to just really easily convince him to go and make patient.
He immediately gets baptized in a passive way. He he gets quickly pressed into bounty Hunting kangaroo cruz,
And then, you know, he's extremely passive when he's taken by first by more full Mary, and then buy the originals,
and then again, i'm more full married. So, like, he's always just kind of being passive, and he's always at someone else's
command or, you know,
control in this language which was in striking to me. I mean he was advertised. He was.
Yes. So Yeah.
Alright. So are you ready to go into the actual content of the story? Well, let's do it.
Alright. So
adventure down under
opens up with
the... Just kind of a very boring
sedentary life Donald than the kids. At home. You know, donald is there's a really nice site gag right away in the very first panel where Donald just reading boring Ducktales
by Inducks blow hard,
looking very.
And the kids are asking him if they can't take a vacation before their school starts up again. And un
Donald
agrees right away and says that they should enjoy some time in Catalina
Island off coast of California. Right? I think that was a much more popular vacation
site once upon a time. I don't know. I lived in California for many years and never made it out there. At any rate, Donald grabs some of their savings and they go to get
some airline tickets and they... And they pass by a outdoor
radio station
broadcast where someone
the the radio and announcer or Dj is introducing a professor
with one of those great Barks ian names Argo Gi i. And this professor Gi is going to him
a volunteer from the crowd. And he's got a great sort of generic mystic accent and says how do?
Then, what do you think of
esther? Barks kim with I there? So first of all, that's, I love his depiction with his fur brow. Like, he... I I'm kind of hepatitis just looking at him. Okay. His eyes just pull me in. And like, I'll I'll I'll become a kangaroo if he tells me too. Yeah. He's got that top hat and a bow tie, but, man, that and hence looked on his face. He was really born for the job. And I have to say I... That... Like I... Like I mentioned earlier about
understanding how kids see the world. I
site guy in the beginning...
I I feel like all kids
see books that adults read as having that having titles like that.
I see that it's like... That's it was hilarious. I mean. I I guess actually laughed out loud. Because a caught off guard when I saw that Donald was reading a book called boring tales. I also just just like you said, looking at the professor
very.
Yeah. That's just a great
it it's exactly what I would imagine somebody in the forties would look like who people on.
Excellent. So
On the next page, Donald, and the kids are approaching and they they hear that whoever
volunteers to get him ties, can expect
ten dollars.
A nice little line here ten dollars and cool cream cash definitely sounds like, you know, an old tiny dj would say that. And Donald is, you know, he's seen that as spending money in Catalina. So he volunteers.
And and we get a a really cool and weird panel here where we get fate
personified.
Right? And and kind of buying and w
and just
fore foreshadowing for us the donald, you're going to be sorry. It it trails off. Yeah. That could've took me have threw me off. I And i had to read it, like, three times I'm like, is that? I've never seen faith fade always is depicted Al like, yeah, This is the way things are going, but fate seems like said that this is the way things are going. Yeah. Interesting. And this is a very unusual panel. I think he doesn't he didn't do this very often. So...
There was some similar stuff in ghost of the g where it was very over. And that just might have been what he wanted to experiment with that that month. But I really like. So Donald is super eager with the the radio Dj. He's anticipating his every question answering what his name is
ahead of time that confirming he's never been h ties.
So
the Dj
sets it up and, you know, ponder, what, what is he gonna
hepatitis him into is he gonna make him a dog or a monkey or a sea going ground?
And we get to see
Donald being put into a trans the professor. It's a the kind of depiction you would expect a little jedi mind trick.
And
there. Yeah. He's got the little wavy fingers.
Classic ge. But we get a great he give... He hits donald with a du.
He tells him you are a kangaroo
and you are very very home sick. And what, you know, what a great great way to set up an Australian adventure story, I think.
Right. Like
Alright. So the the last panel in this page
has the Nephews observing and the and the crowd observing donald whim and crying and he's posture, like the kangaroo. It's clearly worked out really well. Yeah. I don't know. I find it odd that the humid would add the home sick part.
Because I don't feel like that would add much
entertainment value. It's almost like he's... He wants him to just go to Australia. Right? He's gil lily a little bit there. And but I think
maybe he's playing to the radio audience, you know? Yeah. But I I just... I love the setup for this. Alright. So I like the dotted lines going for their eyes and gives just limp arms, like Huey, He's he's definitely there. Yep. So on the next page, we see him
acting like the Homes kangaroo that he believes in himself to be. The the Dj is really selling it. It's talking about him acting homes sick and
facing the west to smell
sniff at the air and dream of far off
Australia. As you mentioned, he refers to it in the far off and.
I think
is just means the, like, bottom half of their earth, but
or or the
inside of.
I had to look at. It's like that region of New Zealand and Australia.
Donald has a thought balloon of him
crying and thinking about kangaroo like him. That's a great panel right there. I love that panel. It sums it up. And all of a sudden, he
bounds off with a happy look in his face stunning the crowd, the hi
professor can't get in contact with him because he's too far away, and he is bounding off much faster and higher than you should be able to. And, you know, the nephews are worried the hi says it should wear off in a few hours, but who knows what could happen this is why we...
Most modern hip just make people find waivers because of stuff like this. That's right. On the next page, Donald bounds off to the
airline office to buy a ticket.
And
I I really like the fact that he is now na. He's got human speech. Even though he's a kangaroo.
He's saying, I'm a home kangaroo, and I know how to go home.
And he explains this to the ticket seller.
Who tells him oh, your home would be awesome kelly. Just a moment to.
And, you know, Donald very kindly
ask soon to make it four tickets so that his kangaroo nephews can come to. And the ticket seller completes the transaction for four hundred dollars. Didn't look up what that would be, but definitely sounds like a lot. And the Clerk wishes him well until he does a double take and and says gracious six, that wasn't a kangaroo. That was a person. Kangaroo don't have four hundred dollars.
I love the a joke was funny because it's the the money aspect of it. That was the part. Yeah. It was funny. There... Wait a minute. That's like saying,
Don't have blue hats. Yeah. And I I remember even as a kid. I loved this interaction. It's just so ridiculous. And totally dis interested.
Clark, literally thinking
Because eyes are just barely open to sliver.
Alright. So on the next page, the nephews have caught up with Donald who beck
them to follow him and he leads them to what he calls the clipper base. I guess that's where these clipper plans take off. This is a pretty cool way to travel. It seems Well, Al rate, they they see him bored the os australia clipper, and they're freaked doubt they've gotta get him out, but he refuses. He says, home to kangaroo cruz is Australia and they asked the captain for help getting him out, but the captain like, why should I? He gave me four tickets to Australia?
So the nephews,
Yeah. You know. Mean can't really beat his logic. He was given tickets.
Yeah. I I know. Very sound. Right. Alright. So the nephews,
you know, they convene and they talk about the fact that, hey, Donald got tickets for all of us, so we get to go to Australia. Hours
pass, a really nice panel, nighttime panel of them descending. The Donald is the first of the Ducktales wake up. And, you know, he he looks out of the plane he's kinda coming too. He's wondering why he doesn't remember getting the catalina tickets and a flight attendant tells him to buckle the lot because they're about to land in Sydney, Australia.
Alright. So on the next page, Donald just realize what's going on and we don't see the explanation which is nice because we know what's going on. It just transitions to to later. And you know what I think is interesting here, we fly into, I guess, Sydney Harbor.
There's a lot of cloud cover there. So we don't really see a lot of the City skyline.
And then the next panel just transitions to, like, a generic city. The only
thing that really indicates that it's Australia is a poster for cricket matches. Yeah. It seems like such a gimme to, like, show, you know, the shorthand for Australia and Sydney Harbor is the opera house and I I realized that it hasn't even built at this time That was by first not too. I when I saw this. I was like, are they
just putting clouds there because They don't wanna draw it. And then I'm like, you know what? Maybe didn't exist yet. Know. Yeah. I looked it up. I I because this this brought me on hindsight, but but it was definitely later, I wanna say nineteen fifty seven is like when the planning commission got away. But
there's not really a lot of other
for here we're in Australia until you are in the outback. Right?
Yeah. You know. It's it's the opera house and the the bridge there.
Yeah. You know, I attribute it. Well, I saw the bridge, and that's when I was looking for the upper house, but I
I mean, yeah, there's not really any distinguishing
features.
So Australia rules football was from the people I knew there was a a bigger deal than than cricket. Maybe carl Barks didn't wanna get confused with Right. Because I don't think they call it A rules football there. They just called it the football. But. Yeah. That would be... So cricket he's like, alright. What do we... What do I got to work with here? And there's a
recognizable bridge and they play cricket there. Well, we'll we'll be in the outback soon, and and you'll be reminded constantly.
But for now, Donald is just g, you know, he's he's in a bad mood pretty understandably.
And the nephews are, like, come on, stop driving. Let's have some fun and, you know, this prompts Donald, i'll just say that you can have any fun in Australia. The country is too civilized. You know, which which seems like a weird thing to say. But I think it's just the setup, right? For us to meet this Yeah. This stranger with the pretty spectacular
mustache, and he is the one that makes the off
to the nephews. He he encourages them to come to his
station.
And his sheep station station being the term for ranch.
And the he'll pay them to hunt
and, you know, Donald is like, pain me when you want me to hunt
and we got a good faint thing ga where he says kangaroo.
Yeah. I thought it was interesting that like, if there were some wild Inducks or or buffalo. I don't know some kind of native Australian and animal. Like, like it for forgets that us that kangaroo exist. I was confusing that he mentions his buffalo and he's looking for something interesting. But he literally was just hepatitis as a kangaroo
then he gets here and, like, oh, if only, there was some kind of wild native animal
anywhere around here.
Exact.
And he's literally
describing, like, the American Frontier.
Right?
And so much American Media at this time was, like like fascinated by the American Frontier.
Right. Could you see all those western
and stuff. So I think some of this is just kind of playing out Frontier fantasy in a different kind yeah. Well, I... Yeah. I I kinda after thinking about it a little more. I think they just wanted to in case we couldn't do it on our own because the whole concept of a frontier
is something familiar, but maybe his readers
aren't familiar as much with Australia. So in one panel, it says,
wild Inducks and Buffalo and then the next panel, Bush
and hunting and then talking about kangaroo. So I think he just wanted to put those concepts side by side. Right. It's it's very Australia one zero one. Yeah. Yeah. I think they're link... Setting a table that maybe we don't really need these days, but they needed problem.
Alright. So on the next page, you know, Donald recovers, and the man explains that
he will pay two pounds for every kangaroo that they bring in and five hundred pounds for more full mary, either dead or alive.
He explains that she is the queen of the kangaroo.
She lost her baby months ago and has been, like, leading
kangaroo
rating on Rancher pasture. And the Inducks decide, yeah, let's do it. We're gonna be kangaroo to hunters.
They're gonna have some adventure and
maybe make the five hundred pounds that they need to... I don't know, get tickets home.
So they they fly out to his sheep station. It's a pretty cool panel depicting the sheep foundation. The
station manager
tells them where they can find kangaroo and he
dives the plane down low. Scatter several dozen them so they can see how overrun with Kangaroo the area is. Yeah. That was
one thing that stood out here is, you know, because
now they use dollars, that they they have Australian dollar. So they'd I was like, pounds, they don't use pounds there, but then I was remembering
Yeah.
They that they originally did use the British pound
and I don't know when... So I guess when this was written, they probably did use pounds there. But they they just use the word dollars now.
Just like we do, but it's the Australian dollar. Right. Yeah. And I thought about that too. I didn't check when they made that transition. But as you say, some sometime after this story. Yeah. That's sheep.
Stations are pretty common there.
I spent some time out on some of these cheap stations. And, yeah, they the legitimately did pay people
you know, they pay them per
pay people to thin out the herd and just
when they get over populated. So that's not an uncommon thing back then. Right. Alright. So as they dive down, you know, they see
they see kangaroo jumping over the wings up the plain
pretty fancy but little any little site visual.
And they land so that they can get to work. And the nephews point out
one of the kangaroo on top of the plane, and the station manager instantly
recognizes it, as more info Mary who has, you know, a pretty
vicious looking Al on her face. She plants herself she jumps on his chest,
and hops away, and
he is upping his anti. He he's up in the bounty out to thousand pounds reward for her high. Again, dead or alive. Yeah. And
I I don't think I saw any kangaroo jumping over airplanes. I was there. But...
Yeah. They get...
I don't know. It'd be interesting to see how... I I know they can go at least, you know, six feet. So... Have read i can jump just
incredibly far. Probably a lot higher. Yeah. I've
seen them jump pretty high, but I like... Yeah. Just like the image of, like,
flying airplane and it's jumping over. Right. Alright. So we transition to the the docs kind of
already having tried for a while
to
trap her. You know. They have obviously been Al it.
They explained that it's really hard to catch her snare and pitt don't work.
One of the nephews is siding through some.
He sees
her on a rock some miles, a mile away
watching what they're doing, which is how she knows what's going on. And he says that she looks sad, but I can't tell whether she's weeping or laughing.
It's really interesting to me that, you know, Barks has created this, like, really interesting
animal character here. Right? And this is definitely an animal. This is not one of the human, like, the people
characters.
So She... She's an animal who's is feeling the sorrow. It's
there it's some interesting path though. Some some
to this. Yeah. Gives us... Well,
and even just the name more more mary gives yeah. It's,
you know, gives the gifts her extra layer of debts. It's it's kinda nice. It's not just doing it. It doesn't I I like that aspect of it because it's not implying that kangaroo
and their native in their nature to go and just
things. You know, they get she has a reason for it. She's trying to find her baby. Right. It's retribution or something.
She's very... I find her very sympathetic.
Yeah. Yeah. Definitely.
And and so Donald
recalls, he remembers. So that that's the reason that they do call her more inform. Because she lost her baby. So that gives him an idea. He drives into town for something. And he asks the nephews to cover one of the pit. With some brush. And I like the line from the Nephew.
Just... I wish On Domino wouldn't get ideas that would get ideas that didn't make so much work.
Sure And then they see him come back. They see his car, but it's actually a kangaroo driving the car. So they think
Yeah. Couple of things here. I don't know if you noticed the steering wheels on the incorrect side of the car they're for Australia
driving vehicle.
I didn't I love. I I love the gag of the kangaroo driving the car Barks
That's just another just great...
Been a little visual.
And like they've got what looks like maybe,
like, ten foot hit for a kangaroo that just jumped over, you know, Right flying airplane.
Right. We don't think about that too hon. Nothing think about that too much.
So they they leap at the the kangaroo, they call in an fed grasshopper, a great little line.
You know, ask, what did you do with our uncle? And then Donald reveal,
that it's actually him in this disguise
saying that, you know, since she's lost her own, baby, she might wanna adopt one. He's gonna stand on that pit and look very
very sad.
And
hope that she takes the bait and crashes into the into the pit.
And they they watch him from a distance. They note that he's putting on a great act because, you know, he isn't experienced kangaroo room now.
And one of the nephews
sites mourn full Mary
spotting him through the bin particulars.
And I like her reaction shot where she's, like, very surprised. I had a a little lost baby kangaroo.
Yes. This is... So I find it. I find it interesting that Donald who has recently been
into thinking he's a kangaroo.
His first
plan action is to
become a kangaroo.
U.
Like maybe there's some residue effects that are still lingering.
He's still feeling... Like, I I still kinda wanna be a kangaroo.
I'm also...
I think it's really
convenient that the station happened to have a kangaroo custom and his size too
Yeah. I don't like thing too deeply about that.
That's true.
Alright. So on the next page, we cut too mourn mary's perspective for most of it. And she's like, squeaking excited and hopping over to him.
Donald feeling very confident in triumph,
but, you know, she stops her jump a little bit short. She's sniffing
suspiciously at the pit as Donald watches on easily.
And then we we see her kind of take a big wind up and just zoom
straight across the pit. Grabbing donald by the head. Right talking.
Yeah. Shocking the nephews
she stuffs him in in her pouch
and and bounds off with Donald calling out for help, and and she's got little cartoon hearts around her head.
And I I just... I loved that sequence. I thought it was whole hilarious. His of surprise.
He shouldn't have been surprised there. And this was very predictable to the reader, but it's still whole hilarious. And I love it. It's one of my favorite Barks in the story.
Yeah. Yes.
That works a little too well
the bait anyways.
Yeah.
Alright. So Donald
kinda straps in for his ride.
He can't get out.
Miles, you know, she goes miles into the bush
with Donald getting stressed. And the nephews are in a pretty bad situation because they have to take off in pursuit of him,
and
they don't really have a ton of water, but they they can't
they have to follow him while the trail is fresh.
And, you know, we start to get
more,
like,
detail of some of the wildlife
and some of the scrub looking
floor
of the Australian bush
And
then
I don't know if you got to hear much of this in the previous
episodes. But, know, Bark used a lot of older national geographic features
Al, like, reference for a lot of these stories. And and so to my eye, he's
gone to some care
to depict some of the Australian out outback. What what did you think of this?
Yeah. Everything
everything...
I mean, you know, Australia, a lot of people don't realize is land mask wise is the same size as the United States. And so they're pretty cool. They have a... They do have a pretty
wide, you know, they're ski resorts in Australia.
There's,
you know,
it's not all
outback. But the... It has a Mediterranean climate that I've heard.
Yeah. And there's the Northern territory that's actually tropical. And so they're, you know, they're
But the outback, which they specifically,
you know, the the bushes and the color of the dirt and the rock formations, all seem
even just the the design of the the sheep station.
Everything
looks
it
looks in place to me.
Yeah. I I really like these outback. I I thought they looked really cool as a kid.
Yeah.
So
finally, Mary stops and john... Donald takes his chance to jump out, and he immediately takes off
But
there there's a great line. He has now when I need to be a kangaroo. No hit and the distance around.
And and he he nick... He references her. And he says back off, you gallo the case.
I like these sort of
nickname for the kangaroo.
But he he takes off the costume.
He reveals that, you know, you know he's not a kangaroo, he kind of
confronts her and she grabs him and puts him over her
and paddle him like an naughty child.
And he's he's realized that,
you know, she loves him in know a mother y way
regardless of what he has at this point.
And he... By the end of this, he says, well, looks like I'm adopted, but how will I get away? Yeah. It's kinda interesting. It's like and know the mom's like, you know,
Okay. It cost... At first, I'm like, well, in these cartoons, the mom, you know, when you dresses it
bugs bunny and dresses up as a girl bunny or a girl version of whatever, you know, thing and they fall and love anyways. And
Yeah. I think, you know, they're they're just a void that was left when she lost her baby and even though
this isn't her baby. She's like, you know what?
You're my baby now. Yeah. She's in full on
mode.
It's we're in this. Alright. So
this is kind of a sequence that makes me feel hot and thirsty.
We cut to the nephews on the next page still tracking them. It's it's a pretty rough tracking because there's so many kangaroo tracks.
They just know that more formula mary was heading west so they keep going that way.
They have to eventually camp out in a in a dune
there is a a random little sequence
panel where there's a kind of a visual of the moon with the
personified face
looking at them. And again, this is kind of out of character for Barks he doesn't do this too often. But he did it in the previous story as well and ghost of the g. And it looks worried. Yeah. Yeah. It definitely does.
And then kind of in parallel way, Donald having a rough time, more mary eating some grass. He's feeling hungry. He pines for some chopped to we. And she she makes him eat grass,
and she's just got a very stern maternal look. So he's gotta do it. I like the the panel a lot where he's trying to to choke down that grass and, oh, oh well maybe it's full of vitamins Yeah. He seems very...
Yeah, like you said passive. Like, he... Like, I don't know maybe it's just because he was some of the advertising is still wearing off because where he's
little bit. He's still eight percent kangaroo. Yeah. He's willing to go use it. He's always just along for the ride this.
So at at night on the next page at nighttime, she's fallen the asleep, so he has the chance to sneak off
and he... He heads off, although he doesn't know what direction.
And by morning, you know, the nephews of woken up and they're they're looking pretty rough. They're
wandering off through the bush. And, you know, that this is incredibly dangerous. Right? Like,
in in real life, you're pretty much dead if you don't have a good supply of water out here.
And and so we cut back to Donald
also in a rough patch. He's walking past some
clumps of grass
hearing some what he thinks to be howell h sounds
and seeing some vis spines poking out of them and in his state. He doesn't realize that it's bush man, it's originals
watching him very men.
I like the panel with the bush with the spears
they kinda tried to match the the little things sticking out of the bushes.
Right. Alright. So the Nephews
are approaching a
pile a big amount of rocks, and they see a kangaroo ahead that turns out to be more inform weeping again
So they figured
that Donald has escaped and, you know, I'll take a moment to feel pretty bad for more
losing
another child there. And so they track down on... Their their uncle uncles tracks, which they find, but they see some originals
footprints also
converging and they can see where he has been captured.
And and so they they run off after him.
Be promoting the fact that he's gonna be eaten by cannibal.
And then we cut to Donald
surrounded by the app originals
they're using some pretty
bad pigeon speak
saying that he's...
He looks hungry. He needs to be found up and donald understands that there's only one reason for that. Well, you know, that... So maybe maybe I'm wrong here, but I feel like he
intentionally
avoided directly
stating that they were going to eat him. It's Donald the only one who mentions that they mentioned that he's skinny and that he will make a fine price
mh But I I haven't seen any indication that they're actually trying to kill him or eat him that comes directly from them. I and I think maybe he did that
intentionally.
To it's it's implied, but not directly stated.
Right. You you think maybe there's some ambiguity.
I... That's a very generous reading. I like that you're being generous but
You know, there there are gonna be a few more stories
coming up that also have some of these, like, savage
du depiction.
This is one of the realities of a lot of great comic creators of this time. Right? Like, I... I'm not trying to call out Carl Barks here.
You know, I've seen, like, twenty thousand leads under the sea from Disney and Swiss Family Robinson
they have these kinds of du depiction of savages in the movies. Go and and Oh dare
in the Asterisk
comet, ten ten, you know, the ten ten common So like, I'm not trying to pick on barb specifically.
But unfortunately,
he's got these really timeless breaks stories that are are marred by
by some of these depictions. And like this is
something that American society was really interested in at this time. Yeah. See it all over the place. It's just that his stories have held up.
So we we end up having to compare them to media from today where we're should be comparing it to other stuff of its time and just kind of understanding
But but we do
recognize that, you know, these these are not great depictions.
We do
as you know, maybe they mentioned,
you know, a price Al the cara,
which is a fun term. I... I'm... I learned that and second grade during our unit on our Australia. It's like a big
original festival.
Oh yeah. I attended one when I was there. Awesome.
How was that?
We didn't have duct
I think it was
sandwiches.
Oh, good. Yeah. Yeah. It was good it was really... It was
cool to see.
Right on. So Donald, you know,
understandably is freaking out and he tries to escape
This is our obligatory Barks
this is our obligatory
boomerang
can't not have that. Can't visit Australia
without a character not understanding
how boomerang works.
And
you know, I guess they make make some effort. Barks me some effort to to not make it look like it does that magic call forward and back. You can you can see some of the arc that real boomerang has. Right? Oh yeah. It doesn't do the direct one eighty
doesn't an Barks to it. So on one quick bit of
boomerang trivia.
Yeah.
There are different types of boomerang. That and they actually
use boomerang for hunting birds
and the primary purpose, they they had two types of boom boomerang. That'd be standard side kind that you see and the purpose was to not hit the birds with these ones, but it you would throw it
around the birds
and it would scare the birds towards you. So then you have a whole flock of birds instead of you trying to hunt them and them flying away from you.
It it gets behind him, makes them all fly towards you. They had another style of boomerang that was shaped kinda like a Nike symbol
that they called... I don't know. Yeah person was told me about it them just called them killing Boom boomerang where they were just blunt. They didn't... They didn't have any arc to them. They were just blunt. And you threw them and they just go straight, and they they would kill the birds.
That makes
immensely more sense.
Then like the the the the arc to scare Barks towards you. That makes so much
kinda stupid Scrooge them towards you. Yeah. Yeah. It's really,
you know,
imagination that Americans, and I I think probably a lot of other people have of boomerang work?
Like
the
that comes Barks to you, obviously, if you strike something with it it's just fall with
and we they used it correctly here to bring a bird closer to.
That's true.
So Donald does have a pretty good pit line after the does bring him down. He says, and I'm the guy that said there was no excitement in this country.
So on the next page, the nephews
have gotten to the point where they can see smoke coming from what they assume must be the bush man's camp.
And they approach donald
where donald been captured.
We cut back to the camp where the aboriginal are
offering him some food
He looks at it, and he says it's scorched
Al.
Al, I think are less or a, yeah. Al an American thing, but whatever. It's a fun guy.
But he's they'd recognize he's American and we're trying to make him himself.
Sure.
And we see it. It's a pretty gross looking
pet
So he doesn't like that. So they offer him what he identifies as wizard. And for whatever reason, Barks doesn't show that that's kept off the panel. Yeah. I'm wondering if
is too morbid to think about eating an animal that isn't generally depicted as food. Yeah or he didn't know... Maybe he didn't have a good reference
photo for Australian and Lizard.
So Donald, you know, is, again, he's
upset, and he must up the strength to try and escape.
This time, they say they're gonna pin him with a spear. He throws back the boomerang,
and by the neck page, you know, it's gonna come sw back and he's gonna accidentally
subdue himself.
Alright. So he's he's good and caught. And we transition to the to that night where the nephews spying at the edge of the camp. One of the nephews is looking at
a large bird roast over the fire.
And the first time I read this, I remember being pretty
wondering if.
But the the other nephew you
for him that that's Al.
In case. Sure wondering,
reassuring him and This is one of the few times that were made to think
about donald as like a bird instead of a human. I think it really kinda it is jarring.
Yeah. When he's looking at the dead, the screeching gel, and then you've got this roasting e
Yeah. Yeah.
Essentially very weird.
So,
you know, as they sneak into the camp. They hear someone breathing
maybe a a century hiding in the grass someone one nephew goes to knock him out and barely stops himself before
striking
bound
Donald,
and they they release him and,
you know, this is another of those
awkward moments where he says dewey thank goodness, those Barks state to me out here, so the police wouldn't find me. I don't think that's meant to be like
as pe as it sounds, but, you know, obviously, it doesn't sound great. This is one of the times that I hear him kind of reference anything like that.
You know, the
most of the that I met they refer to other originals as black fellas. And so I noticed these the work fella here a lot too.
Right. And that that is a common term
and to use the the word black over there well I would never refer to them.
Right That way, they... That is a common way that they refer to each other, you know, even now.
I I also noticed too. I didn't even notice when I first read this the move cooking on the spit when actually the way that they cook kangaroo, and those as they build a pit on the fire pit and the ground, and then they buried the car
in the ground on the ashes, and then we'll leave it for about six hours
and then they'll dig it up and then scan it and everything cooked like that. So sounds a lot more efficient. Alright. So
the the Inducks
have a pretty rough night in morning because they have to make as much distance between themselves.
And
I'm just gonna read these couple lines. One of the f says we've... We've come miles and miles, can't we stop and rest a while. Donald says, no, we don't dare. Those bush men or the best tractors on birth, and they must be on our trail by now. And, you know, this was a a little more respectful. Right? Because that is something that the aboriginal are are known for it. Yeah. Definitely. And and this this this next page has a just an agonizing sequence that, again, makes me feel so hot and thirsty every time i read it. They kinda pull over to a rock to use up their last
water actions because Donald hasn't had a drinks since yesterday.
They... The Nephew looks in the. There's a single drop left and Donald generously poor on the pocket and cuts it half ways. It's it's very funny.
It's also
very very uncomfortable.
Guy. What was that... What was that cartoon where they slice a bean?
Oh, yeah. A single bean
divided equally and
in Mickey beans. That's right. He's... Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. That's what i reminder. That's right
of that. I was his son really contrast to the moon who... The moon seemed worried. But the sun he's enjoying this Yeah.
It's pouring down.
Yeah. That
bonafide sun
with the
the lot. And they keep walking and, you know, there's some pretty cool art in this panel here where you're behind them looking over their shoulders and you can see some heat waves ripping in the distance.
Yeah. I almost feel like this panel is inspired by Airs rock where you've got just...
That's
out right in the middle of Australia, and there's just everything flat for miles and miles. You can't see any mountains or hills And then Arr rock is this giant. What do they call it now though it's been renamed to, like, Lou, I think. I didn't... I wasn't aware they renamed it. It's not called Arr rock anymore. Right. I I think it was the... I think it was named for the tribe. Yeah. Yeah. I could see that. It is kinda of. And again, it's just looking worse and worse for the debts. They've got scavenger your eagles following them.
We see that the aboriginal are
tracking them. The rocks they noticed are the ones seem to be the ones where they saw more full mary, which means they're only one days walk from the station. So maybe they can make it. But, unfortunately,
they turn their shoulder over their shoulder. They see that the bush are only one minute.
So they have to make a break for it on the next page here. And as they pass the rock,
more info Mary is there she observe them. She squeak
excited,
a bunch of cartoon hearts come out of her.
The the Ducktales are bracing themselves for to to be smeared.
But just then of course, more Mary weep in as they throw their spears.
Donald gets in their pouch, the boys climb on their back, and
Donald tells her home Mama.
So he's definitely leaning in here. And and I like that whole
concept when you have. Because this one doesn't really have a, you know, an ant antagonist in
directly. It starts off as more informed air. So I like the... I like the shift when they introduce the second group and then, you know, the original antagonist
comes in and saves the day and so yeah.
You're right. There's no real villain in this one. Right? I mean... The originals are more like Al a force of nature They're more like four nature
there. And I I'm still standing by it. I don't think their plan was to eat them at all.
Alright. They hadn't... They already had an new.
You know, I mean,
I think they were honored guess. He looked hungry. He's trying to feed him.
And now the only reason they're attached because they're... Because they're calling the cops, you know, they don't want them to snitch on them which I wouldn't either, you know?
Sure. You're you're really going bad for them.
Al allow. It.
So on the next page, you know, they're they're making great time
by kangaroo. They figure out that they can kinda steer Mary
And they get back at the station where they were trapping,
one big leap over the fence and they unfortunately land right in one of their pitt,
and and they're all stuck unless someone finds them.
And when they call help, the
the station manager comes
and they're able to show him that more full Mary is is with them now. And, you know, you mentioned that it's pretty ridiculous that this oh know, small pit. You know I changed my mind though because he she was fresh.
She was fresh. When she jumped over the plane. She's been carrying donald and three other dogs, and they've already shown how hot it is out there. Yeah. She's probably just tired.
That's true. She also landed, like, in a way, she didn't expect. Right? So she like old all or something. She attacked a bunch of bush, you know, she's had she said kind of Al been promotional day know.
And so the station manager
does what station managers do. Right? He's sees the opportunity.
He prepares to
shoot her
but the du protest, you know, she saved their lives
she needs to go free.
He protests, I can't let her go free. She's racking my crops, and I'm paying you a thousand pounds. And Donald
very virtually
says that he doesn't want the reward, then he'll keep Mary so that she can go free.
The station manager
uses as an American isn't. He says you've made yourself a deal, and we transition to them on a ship randomly named the s asthma.
Failing from Sydney to to the Us say, the decks are feeling great. We transitioned to the fact that Donald is where he always is. He's got a big crowd around him knocking at the duck riding around in more Mary's, I guess not so more in full anymore. Or less more in full. In her pouch. He says, yeah I don't get tired. I don't find her tire some pet. I do get kinda tired of riding around in her pouch several hours a day to keep her happy. And she does indeed look very happy So nice sweet little ending there. Yeah. You know, I think I'm standing by the... He's still a little bit. He he wants.
He wants to be in her pouch. She wants to be a kangaroo.
It's un
of from what I've seen from Donald to just turn down
that large amount of money
to saver her Al Yeah. I think it's still, you know... So it's his cover story you think. Dwindling
affects
of the Hi h diagnosis. Yeah. Well,
You know, it's it's a very sweet ending to a pretty weird story.
We can talk in in a moment about...
Yeah. And you know what? Let's go right into tell me tell me Ben, what... How did you feel about this story? I know that you're new to this, but I know that you did read a couple of other stories kind of in preparation. Yeah.
Yeah. I... You know, I I like just seeing the...
Like, you mentioned that just the art artistic
depiction of Australia. It's kind of interesting to see, you know, we think of our current tropes and everything that we think of about Australia and stereo, but kinda... So it's kind of fun to see a little snapshot
before we had some of the stereotypes we have now. I mean, there's still kangaroo. They're still boomerang and there things that we just don't have here.
So, yeah, I thought at it was a little bit different. The characters are different than the way I remember them. I just seemed like Huey, dewey and Louis were
kinda pointless. They... Only the real purpose they served was
when he was tied up, and they finally they they did un him. But, you know, like, it seems like Donald did all the work here. He was the one coming up with the traps. He was the one that dressed Al the kangaroo
I don't know. Maybe I'm remembering it wrong, but I always felt like it was like, donald on getting into trouble, and they were always the ones solving things and they're in the in the tear on the swamp one. I mean, they did, you know, they did a whole bunch of problems solving. Whereas this one, they just kinda... Were walking. The whole time. They really Think you're right. Right? They're they're usually a lot more resourceful than this. It's kind of more call that's kind of in that secondary.
Yeah
Yeah.
And so so maybe they just kinda had to step aside for them to
allow this more well Mary to have her story. And know. And Yeah, No. It was... I I enjoyed it. It didn't go where I was expecting it to. You kinda have to ignore some of the bush stuff, obviously.
But Yeah.
You know, for the time, I guess it could been worse.
There wasn't any kind of...
There always seems to be some type... I guess the hip this part of it. Like I don't know. Some like a concept.
High yeah high concept, you know, they're just kinda out in the bush.
So I guess they have the to aspect of it kinda filled out but it's a little bit be just kind of like Australia.
Right? Was was sort of a high concept in this one. Yeah. I guess maybe that's it because I'm so familiar with Australia. It's it's not as high concepts. So maybe that was enough for the time to to for for them. But so yeah, There's a little different... The characters acted a little bit different. Than the way I remember him. But... Yeah, it was kinda fun. I like it. Yeah. You know what? I I really liked this one as a kid. I remember...
It was one of the earlier comments that I had gotten and so I read it a lot, and I definitely still enjoy it, but I don't enjoy it as much as I did. And that's not just because of the stereotypes,
although that's certainly is is a part of it. It's it's a very unusual
story, right? This, like, kind of motherhood
story.
Almost.
It's got some some kinda of weird structure
I really like certain individual parts of that. I love the hip sequence. I love how he kinda launches the story. I feel like the pacing is a little bit unusual. Yeah. I think he does a really effective job of making the outback feel frightening and dangerous.
So, you know, we we talk about the Inducks rating, right? Which is the community website that
people have submitted user reviews for many years. So it gives us a really good aggregate for what the community thinks for this one. And this one I mentioned
the, this is an incredibly highly rated story. This one has an eight point five out of ten. And if you think about, you know, hundreds people rating it, That means like, almost universally.
They're giving this very high ratings, very few little ratings to pull it down. This is the ninth best rated not just out of the, like, five hundred plus Barks stories, but all of the Disney comics that might.
Yeah. So
I I I respect it. I think this is a really cool story. You know, it's got some neat like, sadness. I think the the creation of more is really cool. Her, like, relationship
with Donald is neat Mh. I I don't quite get why this one is as highly rated though. As it is. Because I do think it's a very fun different unique adventure story, but it didn't stick with me the way that some of them.
I think Australia itself has a mass appeal no matter what country you're in. It's a it's a unique place. And so they might and and they might be tacking on their own internal
fascination with Australia to why they like this story. And i see how I would have my.
Yeah. Yes. Exactly. Some of those titles from around the world.
But again, this is maybe one of those cases where, like, hundreds of vaccines can't be wrong, and maybe I'm... Maybe I'm missing something. I I do like a lot of this story. Right? I just...
I just wouldn't put it
anywhere near the top. Yeah. So five red three, and I wouldn't put it in the top of the three that I've read so far. Right. But it is enjoyable. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I don't I don't wanna
harp on it. Because again, as a kid I did really really love this when I do still really think. But I just stack it next to, like, we just read ghost to the g. And in the same issue to me that one is is quite a bit of superior. But different rooms. Let's see.
Other reflections, you know, we've already kinda talked about some of the data Barks archaic things. I don't feel like we need to go to into it. We know what's
retro grade and and what's problematic. I did find it interesting to see Australia before the opera house though.
That that's fun. Yeah. As far as I'm aware, we talk about if there's been any appearances and other media. I I'm not aware of him using any any of these characters again or
or any other economics creators using them He didn't make any of his oil paintings
about this story. From my knowledge.
I did think I had some pretty good educational value
just because it did have some
interesting
Australian terms
and I feel like the outback was pretty well depicted. Oh, yeah. The some Australian things they don't quite get the scale of it Right? And the just even little things like the fact that they took a plane from Sydney to the to the station.
You know, like, yeah, you would do that there's not very many things that are within driving distance semester australia, i I feel like he does a good job of capturing the scale of it. Awesome. Oh, I don't wanna leave out our favorite panel segment.
Ben, did you have any panels that came to mind as as a contender for your favorite.
You know, there's a few, you know, artistic. I like the the character design of the hit the hit
yeah. They the clerk at the travel agency
and the... I didn't care much for the the Australian, you know, sheep station owner.
See Al the characters really good.
You know, I I went through and I was looking and I like the design of the cooked bird. I really wish I could've seen the lizard.
There aren't really any the other ones I've read definitely have some favorites, but I I kinda lump... I love this the rock formations
art style just So I kinda lump a lot of the...
Just to outback, the artwork
There's one I'm looking at now with the rock formation with a creepy little tree with a filter
perched on the top. Oh, yeah. That is a good one. I I just like how every frame
without outback. Just kinda has interesting looking bushes and hills and it's not flat. It just everything it looks like it just has a lot of depth to it and layers to it. I think that I feel like they took a couple short shortcuts because there's a lot of panels where there's just too silhouette work. Are all the comics just this detail from one panel to another because there's quite a bit of detail. Yeah. I mean that Spark does is is known for
detail, especially in these early economics. There will be some later ones where he
cuts back a little bit. He's also known for doing those silhouette and sometimes it might be a little bit of shortcut. But sometimes I think it's done for that effect. I'm noticing
whereas I didn't when I was reading these more casually like going through these chronological, I'm taking note of all that silhouette stuff he does. And i with you. There's some pretty awesome
scenes from the outback in this.
There aren't as many like really show panels in this
Right? There's not a not a time like some of the other issues.
If I had to pick one, you know, hold a spirit in my head and pick one, I would probably pick the one The one with the the email... Not the roasting. The one above that one where they're just purged over.
Looking at the camp below. Oh, yeah. The nephews.
The just because there's some cool lighting there. Yeah. You're you're absolutely right. There's some gray lighting and So something
just pick one of those two frames with the... There's two frames there with the dynamic lighting that just looks pretty cool. I agree. Those are really nice.
I think in the absence of a really shall panel, which, you know, I'm usually a set for. I really like the panel that shows him
and crying
about it.
I I think that one's pretty awesome.
The one of the scavenger eagles also pretty cool yeah. Awesome.
Alright. Well, Ben, thank you so much. I hope to have you back for more of these.
Yeah. This is fun. Alright. So, yeah. A really really good adventure.
Great great story to read. I I really appreciate everyone joining us
If you have any thoughts about this one, you can drop us line
from Barks at g gmail dot com or check us that on Facebook.
Next
episode, oh ben, this is a big one. We are about to do Christmas on Barks mountain.
Mh.
And
as you probably don't know. This is the
introduction of uncle Scrooge,
Dot Oh, No. It's a big one. It is. This is a big deal. So... Yeah. Definitely join us for that. Thank you, thanks.