Hello, and welcome to Barks Remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer Al artist of the greatest Donald and unscrew comments of all time. Join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing or order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Welcome back to Barks remarks. I am very excited for a pretty landmark
episode here. This is a special enough one that we got a couple of returning guests
because I'm excited to talk Scrooge dot. That's right. We are finally at Christmas on their mountain, the Landmark story that introduced uncle Scrooge,
and
let me have my guest hosts
introduce themselves. Ryan. This is Ryan Bailey.
Back again.
Excited for some Scrooge
action here. And Eric. Eric It's a nice ticket and mister Barks davis character, which I'm Al excited for. Yeah. That's right. Where are you guys expecting it to take this many episodes before we had a Scrooge one?
And until I started the podcast, I actually figured
Scrooge is like what Barks comics were about.
So it's weird to have you know, how many... The first dozen or whatever we've done so far, the... I not feature him at all. I honestly thought get him sooner. But once we started, I was like, Oh, we have to talk about all the colleagues done. Oh, I think we're gonna be here for a while because we actually gets Scrooge. So nice to be surprised of that and right. We were in the bs era Al the four screws before he even exists.
Yeah. And it's gonna pivot it pretty quickly here. We're still gonna have a number of Barks stories, but it is gonna be pretty Scrooge centric. Going forward.
Well, let's get into it. I'm gonna talk a little background and then Eric's gonna give us an synopsis. We are in November of nineteen forty seven, still just a couple years post war.
And we're in four color number one hundred and seventy eight sometimes called one shot, number one hundred and seventy eight. I kinda gloss over reprint before. I just wanna acknowledge that including the original four color printing,
there are twelve Us printing listed for this story, which is a lot of reprint. This is shorter one. It's only twenty pages.
I I think this one is kinda spiritually like a ten pager in many ways.
Eric, you wanna give us kind of the synopsis treatment for this story as you? Sure. Darling and that he's are broker Christmas. Don't know what to do. Luckily orientation true who who's that crank killed uncle. We've never given them anything. The screw decides. That's what he wants to have fun expensive family and they could you approve them themselves them or can have fun out getting the out of them.
Invite from this Al bear mountain, but, of course, he's tend to scare them pretend to me where. Hilarious in sue and man up coming together his family at the end.
Yeah, very good synopsis. Thank you for that. That's right. We're gonna be up on Barks Nets Scrooge second most famous property after is mentioned other stories?
No. Oh not not even... Not even a little. There are gonna be whole aspects of screws here that are just never mentioned again. I'm curious before this. Before we get into this, were you guys surprised by Scrooge first appearance here?
His look is really different
then than what I'm used to, obviously, from, you know,
Ducktales or whatever. But
otherwise...
No, Not really.
How about you are A little bit. But knowing this is the first story and not oftentimes with Common yours has to fill them out a little bit before they find the look. And the add going for, whenever there's a common character,
start voice form is Barks intended. But i to that he... He's not too far off from what he becomes later on. So it's
I thought it was a good representation of Scrooge.
Cool.
Yeah. This is kinda one of those backwards origins where they weren't planned to be I think you can tell he wasn't originally planned as an ongoing character.
I don't know if you guys picked up on that.
Yeah. I could I could perceive that. Yeah. He looks like, you know, whoever the submarine captain in or or whatever that that parent that told him that have treasure inside their restaurant, you know, just somebody somebody to drive things forward for this one issue. It like he could be a lot character.
Right. He's Rich old Uncle plot device at the beginning.
Alright. So a little bit of background trivia, actually kind of a lot of background trivia because again, this is a pretty significant story.
First off, this is our second story that we'll do that is in the top fifty as far as fan rating. This is a very well regarded one. As I alluded Barks did not initially plan to use Scrooge as a recurring character
in a sixty two interview. He said he just needed a rich uncle to own a cabin.
So we're lucky that he get a bit of background color there.
And then in a later interview, he kinda talked about the process of making the story and picking out different elements. Right? He got thinking about an old rich on. He said pretty soon he brought in paramount mountain elements.
And then he figured out the reason for that being about testing whether Donald was a brave duck I really like this part. The quote is that's the way these stories built. I have a bunch of things that have to go into a story. And so I just keep feeling around for the best bags that fit in. It's like sowing together pieces of shirt, and that does feel out to me, you know, characters to of this one.
Obviously, Bark did decide to continue to develop str mc dot It would just be five months later when he would feature him prominently in the old castle secret,
which I think feels spiritually like Scrooge or and comic. Have you read that one there? I don't think I have read in reference for read old castle Secret.
I've possibly read about it. And other stories mentioning it. Possibly sql I can't remember. And no enough of it Maybe i happened in the past.
Or I no enough that I think I've read it.
When you eventually read that one, you'll recognize a ton of elements from Dawn roses life and times
because that's probably the biggest single source for it. I would say that it's probably fair to say that Scrooge Deck is going to go on to be Carl Barks biggest legacy.
And article that you read about him is generally gonna mention him in the first line or two that Huey, Uncle Scrooge creator.
This is really his claim to fame this this is more than anything, what got him Inducks into Disney own hall fame early on. This got him ind into the eyes Hall of fame. I mean, his body of work, of course, but I mean, Scrooge is really what he's gonna be remembered for.
So, yeah, this is a very significant story very memorable among fans.
This is a Christmas story right? And holiday stories were really important to Barks.
When you writing a monthly comment. You know, it gives you
a really nice easy hook. So he did like to do a lot of holiday stories.
I read a really good article that Jeffrey Blu, an editor who created a lot of these stories. He wrote about, you know, Christmas was the the biggest one for kids.
So it's hard to get too much mileage out of Easter, you know, halloween a bit more, but Christmas holds such a fast nation among little kids, that he
did. I don't know how many, but he did a lot of ten pager
and a surprise number of adventure lines stories. We're actually an get to cover a decent number of Christmas stories on the podcast.
So you guys starting in last episode, I was having fun delving into some of all titles for the stories from languages from around the world, and I've picked six of them this time. And so if you guys don't mind ind me. I'm gonna ask this all to either embarrass ourselves or may impressed with our pronunciation of the titles in different languages.
Any wanna start off with Chile.
I'll start off with Chile.
And They called it Nav and Also,
Christmas among the Barks.
Excellent. I'm gonna take on France, which I think is
Pas,
which I think translates to isn't that a bear.
Eric, you wanna do Germany? Germany sc Vest,
die probe,
test Scrooge.
Very nice. Let's ryan you already got a Spanish language one, so I'm in snatch Mexico,
which is not and
Which is a pretty exact translation.
Ryan, when don't you take on Norway?
It looks like yu pop,
Christmas on Bear mountain.
Awesome. And Eric that gives you Spain.
So
Christmas of the.
Excellent. I would think that is east
yeah. Yeah. That's what why I was speaking to, but standing staying. They're just gonna do a pain of.
Well, and you know, I just mentally translated these that they were Spanish. And I think too hard on that. I don't know. I guess it would be easter of the Barks. Maybe someone can explain that. Maybe the consensus actually is Spain good a spain Al
awesome. Thank you guys. Hopefully, that's a fun feature to keep. I always like that. So the top value you range you guys for this one is gonna be much higher than most of the ones we've done.
Anyone wanna a guess what... I'll tell you I I found there was one document sale, an issue that was rated nine point six.
And the last one, we did Al episode on ghost of the g and Adventure down under with Ryan and Ben, you guys know Ben. Two separate episodes same issue. So that was valued at seventy five hundred dollars.
What would you guess this nine point six is Al at Eric? Nine point six.
The first appearance of Scrooge
appearance.
Scrooge to make that...
Definitely difficulty it's gonna go higher, sixteen thousand?
What do you think? Ryan.
I'm gonna go eleven five hundred. The document unit sale according to my sources was a hundred thousand dollars. Oh my god.
Is
too?
From what I understand that actually matches the value. It does. That lowers the grade. For the golden age comments you don't want it. If that's what you're chasing. Mark, somebody... Somebody likes these comics a lot more than you
yes.
Alright. So, yeah, this one is quite valuable. And quite special at least for being that foot known in history. So now I'm gonna talk about some of the historical context for this one. There's not a ton of it to go into, but the very obvious thing to mention, right is that Scrooge himself is clearly based on
Sp from a Christmas Payroll.
Everyone knows this, It's not new information, but we gotta check it off.
I would say this is a pretty extreme character version of him pretty hate of everyone I I guess that's in line with the original Scrooge, but the way he's gonna shape up to be doesn't really match the original one. And then it's interesting
Christmas Carol is one of the most adapted media ever. Right? So Barks certainly would have seen this maybe in the movies.
I think the biggest add was in nineteen thirty five, and that one was actually called Scrooge,
and I think that makes sense. That's probably why he went the name.
The other thing when I read this one and I see the nephews get this sort of wish full fulfillment and Christmas right, it strikes me that it sort of matches up with that
war Am america on the rise.
You know, it kind of reflected the American promise of prosperity at the time. Maybe I'm reading too much into it, but I that's been interpretation.
Well, by naming him screws and having screwed be put and had Scrooge public character, a no name and what represents you get a lot of exposition and
of this character. Just for thing that one line, rich on Scrooge, and everything everyone else like
K. You don't have to spend a lot of time with backstory. It just I'm must catch this idea. Finance up. It's a good device that. Way.
Yeah. You're absolutely right. That's a great point. This is incredibly helpful short. And you're right? This is a lot of character development. And one name. So let's see. This is the part in podcast where I usually talk about notable appearances. And I mean obviously. This is the first appearance of Edge in the book. Yeah. You know. A big deal. It's a
incredibly big deal. And the driver. What was the driver's name?
Was it jeans I think it might have been G?
Don't think it was and
I don't know. James James. So my mountain Kevin James. That's right. So obviously, this is our first appearance of Scrooge to Mick dot. We are not gonna take much know of Edge because once teachers have that
never.
And which is ironic because he was the care during this comic who was least likely to be eaten by a bear. You could thought if anyone would return it would be him.
That's right.
Alright.
So we also get to talk about kind of the version of the characters we getting these, and this is one where we get to talk about with donald and Scrooge.
And our version of Donald is one that we get pretty often. Right? Donald in economic distress, a very word donald. But this is passive for donald. There's gonna be a lot of stories where he's poor but he's striving to make something of himself. But here he he's just kinda sitting back. And I don't even know how to describe this version of Scrooge because it's so incredibly disconnected from any other version. Any reflections or question
before we launch into the fairly short story itself? No? Good.
Alright. So on the very first page, we open with the docs just generally bearings that they don't have enough money for with Christmas. And they're wishing that their rich old uncle screwed would remember them. And you know, I like this because he's laying and on really fit Barks is to show how where they are. Donald doing classic showing his empty wallet.
Yeah. Actually opens with Donald saying, oh, what was me woah woah woah.
And then we got to uncle Scrooge and Mansion,
and he is just disappearing Christmas
itself wanted to pass. And we learned that he's different. Everybody hates me, and I hate everybody. He says. I like... I I was impressed that in his very first frame. He hates Kris. Like, maybe the first time I ever Scrooge Mc Ducktales in Mickey Christmas Carol in which he plays
his his name sake.
And and I figured they made him hate Christmas because that's, you know, what what the role is. But that's how he was introduced. That's
the first sentence out of his mouth.
That's true. It's canonical correct. I also wanted to point out in this frame, where he's sitting alone in what he describes as his big lonely dump. I wanted to describe some of the decorations
around him. There's a a base here with the duck on top of it. I can't tell what the duck is holding something round. It could be like a like a base that it would be pouring water out of. It could be like a bowling ball, for all I know, but it's just perfectly random with no detail on it. Then on the back wall, you can see just a framed
picture perhaps a painting, of just money. Just bags of money with bills around and stacks of gold coins, because here's a man who just does not love anything except money.
And so he likes to decorate with what makes him happy, which is money. And then on the far right is my favorite. There's this fancy lamp like a tabletop lamp that's has a around body and on the round body of the lamp is a painting
that appears to be him, chasing another duck possibly donald with his cane, like to hit him, and the other duck is running away with his beak open.
Yeah. A couple of good psych acts. This is like guess the very first of these background art features of money which there gonna be many, many and Barks and other creator stories.
How about you, Eric?
It's top off Scrooge like, wish should to who is. If i
will let the could remember us, but he won't. Because the audience members up the Scrooge. So
So on the next page, we see Scrooge pacing around and is mansion thinking about how everyone else has fun with Christmas and brainstorming how he can have fun. And he decides that he does wanna give a present, but he wants it to be a test of his lazy nephew donald duck.
So he sends on Al the telegram inviting him to enjoy his well stocked cabin on bear mountain, and he adds the code P s, don't let the Barks scare you too much.
So we've got a nice little setup up here. Any comments gentlemen?
How many beers have to be on a mountain to nail it paramount
like, Is it stick with them? Was there that one there that one time?
You know, it's a mis
It's actually a plateau.
I also got the feeling
the very first frame of this page.
Strikes me as as him looking out of his mister Barks window. It looks like he's
It's seemed like the mister burns
mansion or or the nuclear power plants, just looking out the window at the peasants below.
That's what that's strikes. Yeah. Yeah. You're right. It definitely looks like that. And a lot of site ads I'm realizing on this reread, there a lot of site ads with art on this page. So a course here on this one.
Is that Chris present and no longer fun for him? Getting never stuck in the world?
A?
No one to buy him anything he can't him by or
we no given something because challenging to shop for him because he by anything for anybody.
I think in this version, he hates everyone and has never given or received one. Is the cold hard man. The only thing he loves is money and chasing other Ducktales with his cane. Alright. So on the next page, we've got Scrooge talking with his butler about the possibility of whether Donald is brave, and he dismiss it, but, you know, he's planning to have fun regardless.
And then we see the Ducktales journey to the cabin. Nice panel Them arriving, I think it looks like a very appealing place to stay.
And then when they get inside, they see it's been incredibly well provisioned. It's got plenty of toys and games for the kids and a full pantry of delicious looking food for them. So they Al celebrate and she their uncle.
Gene generosity, you've ever seen screws doing any comments he's seizure in.
Because it's all part of the open point before. Yeah. I just know that later colleagues any cent lesson and he still tries to do it on the cheap.
And we have enough lack of continuity that here in there he is gonna be generous in some stories. But you're right for the most part, he's a sting old myers.
If it makes you feel any better, he didn't actually
put any of the food or gifts there just made edge and do it. Certainly.
So on the next page we've got screws preparing cruise tests. We see them enter another room Ask his butler for help. And when Edge comes back, he weep out. He's been dressed in a pretty realistic looking Barks costume him. He scares the heck out of Edge
promptly jumps out of the window saying he's start his vacation now. And like I said, we'll never see him again. He help his death or you decided that that was the last the vacation date. Up. Just on extended article it home. Yeah.
Right.
And so threw heads to the cabin direct is show for James to take him there, and we briefly cut to the docks anticipating Christmas the next day. And Donald is starting to feel uneasy about bears.
And so on the next page, they are looking outside as it gets dark
and starting to see it it's snowing. Donna wants to take a look around, we get a nice little site gag where he mistakes a squirrel a few pieces away for a bear.
And Donald pretty much quiver mess all
before anything's has given him any reason to be afraid. He's hiding up on the light Dish and then we cut to Scrooge,
and the bad weather has forwarded his plans and has to turn around and wait for tomorrow to make it to the cabin.
And he's upset that his nephews are gonna be enjoying everything in the cap on his time.
And he says I've never given a man a free meal in my life. So I love that that the one comment in his invitation of don't worry too much about the Barks was enough to just like plant a seed of une ending terra in Donald brain.
That that plus the the the place name on the map. Right? Those two things
were enough
The last thing Donald said on the previous page was I hope nothing happens to spoil our fun like Barks, I mean.
Set the window terrified by the squirrel. But, yeah, it's just it's the only thing he can think about at this point. It's just Barks. They must be everywhere.
In the time. And I love that the boys are able to tell.
No. You don't really see theirs in this snow in the wintertime. They're sleeping somewhere.
You don't have to worry about that. Yeah. I like that too. I think that's the funniest and best aspect of the story how you just Scrooge over basically nothing.
So on the next page, we see the depths really enjoying the nice feather beds Inducks screws cabin.
And by the next morning, the snow is piled up. They get a white Christmas, they get to have some snow play fun. I like this line here where Donald asks them what they wanna have for breakfast,
either for caviar Lobster New or Ph filet.
The nephews say a dis oatmeal. None of that cheap stuff. This might be the line of the comic for me. He says you'll get Gladstone New bird and like it. Who do you think is paying for this?
And a later on, presume after a lot of Lobster New, they're enjoying a nice cozy fire.
Nephews bring up the one hitch that they don't have a Christmas tree, and they needle their uncle bond going. They say they've come to buy miller woods and cut one for him. Yeah. I like that the kids are too poor to even like or want any of the fancy food. Tips like they're like I'm not used to any of this, this is weird. Please just give me some mail.
Right. I assume they're young kids with an un sophisticated power who are like oh, oatmeal like, every.
Alright. You guys don't how to like lots u verse. Is that... No. I have no. Yeah. Let on of know how to make
The very fancy dish?
No. I know I've heard of it, but I don't know what distinguishes is it from Any other lobster dish? The first time I ever heard of it was reading this issue of this comic. So...
Because I grew up next door to these Ducktales
their same neighborhood. So Alright. So the nephews are really pleading with him to get a tree. They're trying to convince him. There's no Barks out there. They throw an epic tantrum. That's the only thing get him to go out amongst all of those Barks.
And he immediately runs back in saying he's
saying he saw Barks tracks.
When an f go to investigate they see it's just a rabbit repair or something harmless.
And Donald grants the whole way of looking for a Christmas tree they realized that the trees are buried under all of the smell. I can only imagine the kind of
psychosis that would have to be going on in his mind to look down Al they do a good job of conveying how tiny these tracks are in the snow that surely... No.
No bear, even a newborn bear would be able to produce tracks this small much less pose threat to. And I like get the rabbit just like sitting harmless almost the top hills
ridiculous got. I love this the same donald that at one point and Went to a swamp in Florida where they know may caters. Yeah. But at least it wasn't named like gay gold or something that would have been all he could think up.
So the dock search and search and eventually have to settle for a scratch we looking tree. That only has a few branches and a big suggested hole in it. But, you know, it's got some charm in it kinda like Charlie browns Christmas tree? So they cut that one down and carry it back. And again, it is a suspiciously heavy treat. And by the time they get back and Ducktales it with some colorful pop bottles, the next thinking looks pretty good. Donald just looks at it hateful because it nearly cost him his life as far as he's concerned. So he goes to get some more expensive food and the duct Al leave the tree, we see a couple of eyes in the hollow, and a little Barks emerges.
And the bear browse of a toy teddy bear that's about his size. The that's here that and go to investigate.
So this this this page had what for me was the line of the comic.
Where on on its way to the fridge Donald says, after risking my life to get that tree, I need.
One we have pests?
Have decided I'm going to adopt that phrase.
As I'm headed to the kitchen if you'd like kids.
Right. And they do be?
Not not bills.
What we have tests?
And it seems like they do have more
numbers
the bird. I wanna say how fast to how the nephews piles improved, strawberry short fried legs and the winter quail heights
in cream socks.
Here. Sound.
That sounds pretty adventures based on my knowledge of American cuisine
around the the greatest generation era.
And that's not, these are what about eating paddle.
Yeah. We can't think about that too hard I thought about... I actually thought about that Al I was reading this and I thought, you know I eat a lot of mammals.
Yeah. Absolutely.
So said they go to investigate, but it's just the nephews who go because Donald immediately knows it a bear and he jumps on the counter to hide right away.
The bare managed to hide itself by the time the depths are in there, and you know, it's the classic gag where the bear looks like the stuffed animal it's hit next to.
Donald sn around, he says he can smell that there's a bear in the house. He says he's cut Al consultations of the gi, which is the fun way of saying he's freaked out.
And when their Barks her turned again, the bearer goes and finds their strawberry short take.
So my thought was my thought was about
the old the old trope of, like, you'll get your inheritance if you can spend a night in this haunted house or whatever.
And and
And I feel like I know where this is headed you know, and and Scrooge has his Barks outfit fit that he's going to use to
scare the jeep out of them.
And and test their metal, you know? And then
then we get this kind of double fake out going on. I I'm thinking of the movie captain Marvel where Tay the scroll is terrified of the cat and everybody's laughing and how how silly he is be terrified of a cat because he's an alien and he doesn't know what cats are, and he assumes it must be some kind of terrifying monster. And then later we discovered, That's not a cat that is a terrifying monster, and it starts swallowing Al enemies, and I love the the two layers of gag there because each layer is funny on its own. And here we have kind of the same thing here where they hear some harmless noise and donald goes, that was a bear. I know it. And it's because he's totally out of his mind with fear about theirs. And yet he is correct. That's at what point. That is some good comedy there. And he's absolutely right to be afraid based on what most people know that if you see a cup, there's a good chance momma Barks there as well.
But it's only through, like, complete accidental
bone headed writing. That's true. If everything is there, eventually something that bear, you will be right. What did you think about of the gi? That I was gonna say a love old kind phrase. That right up there with hey that Scrooge screws. You're gonna give them the basics to so many colleagues. Whatever you like, Scrooge old. Because you wanna get the papers that Al of the. And my read of this is that it's supposed to sound like out of time
even for this era. I'm not sure, but I I think this is just supposed to be, like, he's he's using a really funny what the saying. I'm trying to imagine him saying that know of that voice, and I don't think I can understand it. So when I read these, you know, in my mind, here, he not using the Donald Inducks voice at all. He's using a classic narrator totally easy to understand voice. And Barks never makes any jokes about it being hard to understand him or.
Ever since that first issue where he was the street wise tough guy. I've I've kind of been reading him this street was tough guy. I'm I'm picturing like an accent from Queens.
Something, you know? Yeah. Yeah.
Alright. So on the next page, you know, the depth kinda hud, wondering what's going on. They see the strawberry short cakes one. None of them of eating.
So we see Donald just getting progressively more and more freaked out. He's back to the fixture,
and the nephews are thinking that he's probably right. But they're brave enough to go investigate.
And then the kids are out of the room, the Bear cub comes out and does some investigating of its own.
Yeah. It's interesting the bare returns to its
hollow inside the tree. Have we mentioned the giant hole in the three. Yeah. I mentioned it, but I probably didn't describe it that well. It's accurately big enough for him to hide in. And so the Barks of lunges at one of the roller skate, at this point, Donald has to excited it's safe to run down. It's not. The bear runs him over and he gets some pulled over. He doesn't see what it is, but it leaves some bare hair. So he cries out and again back to the light fixture.
He
tells his nephews wear the bear headed it and they follow. And then the next page sees the nephew tripping on that roller skate and briefly knock themselves out. Long and enough the bear to hop on and try out the skate. And when their uncle calls out to them, they're they're able to respond. They're okay. And they go to the par where they hear the roller skate. This is a fun. This is a very, like scooby doo kind of moment as they're all bumping into each other and happen to not actually see what the threat is as they are accidentally
knocked out of their senses against the wall and that sort of thing.
Yeah, You're right. If this were animated, it would be easy to sure the classic
from room to room.
Gag Very i question. Could you eat it? Answer me. Timmy should eating. Pretty sure zack goodbye.
So they pursue the Barks on the next page, and it runs back into its tree hollow grabbing the box of chocolates on the way. And they finally figure out what's been making all the noise when it toss the empty box out. One of the goes up and drives the Barks out just explaining
so
I like that just affirm so when you've establish something. I think i'll adopt that. Yeah. That's good. Yeah. Boy. The kids... The kids have really had it. They were... They they wanted a Christmas so bad. They wanted some Christmas presents. And if somebody's going to mess with their roller skate, even if it is an Apex predator, they are having none of it And I guess this will start a pattern of Scrooge being impressed by the nephews or you should be impressed by them. They're always the ones living up to his expectations.
So the gets away, And we cut over to the stump of the tree, which appears to be the top of the Barks hi nation spot because Momma bear
realized that the cubs is gone and emerges,
I should say, absolutely
destroys the stump emerging from it. She is absolutely
enraged as a good mama bear should be.
She tracks her pub uncle Scrooge cabin. Ryan, can you describe her entry treatment?
Terrifying monster.
She tears the door from its hinges, a she still name's the front door? Yeah. She looks pretty fearsome there. So the user still looking and they manage to convince Donald to come down by telling him what a time and significant little Barks.
Level of the whole screwing donald there's no there. There's no There's a pair. Oh, it's just small. It's lot dangerous. Oh, it's a big there.
Of yeah. The mis direct. Yeah. The mis action is pretty good in this one. So they they continue to convince him on the next page of how incredibly tiny that there is, which gives donald the confidence to to venture out.
He rounds a corner and he immediately encounters the snorkeling mama of Barks. Looks genuinely
terrifying. And he gets off a pretty good wine. If that's the berry you saw it, he's grown pretty fast, and we get the cartoon gas. As he, and then and next sleep out of the window and tear. Yeah. Yeah. The the nephew talking about how tiny it is, one of them one of has to be two inches off the ground. If Don can hear the pitfalls, he can hear the foot falls of a lady bug around the court.
So on the next page donald has jumped out of the window, and he says ryan you wanna cover this one? He says give me land, lots of land. Don't fence me in. So I was like, he's quoting something there. So I looked it up all of you western music fans instantly recognize it as very famous.
It's called Don't fence me, written in nineteen thirty four.
Music by c porter,
members of the western writers of America chose it is one of the top one hundred western songs of all time, originally written in nineteen thirty four for Audio Argentina and produce twentieth Century Fox film musical wow. That's awesome. It was performed in nineteen forty four by Roy Rogers,
then slightly later in nineteen forty four by Bing Crosby and the Andrews sister who recorded it in thirty minutes, and it became the number one song in America for eight weeks. And he's not a man to do a second.
So, anyway, this is this was... You said this issue is from forty nine. Right? Forty
seven I think. Forty seven. Okay. Yeah. So this is three years after it was you know, gigantic, smash it. Right. So this is a
reference. Pop culture reference. Yeah. Yeah. And I knew the song. I'll see if I can find a nice snippet of it to hopefully put right
here.
Give me
lots of
to guys about
don't
Let me
The
version is kinda yellow.
And so on the next beach we see the Barks take over. They trash the presence. They enjoy the duck food. You know, the debts are just staring in the window watching their Christmas get destroyed
slash to devoured.
And Mama bear falls
asleep by the fire while they're should outside and I like this page a lot, and it it takes a page of a twenty page story. So maybe it's a weird thing to say this. But almost wish he had gone more gone on further with this because it could been fond Al continue Severino with there's trash and Christmas.
I like that these Barks are obviously hybrid.
And woke up. And, like, oh, I have spend energy. What's the first thing you do? Need to stuff ourselves. Once again to make them for having been interrupted.
Yeah. And there's no hi nation like lobster new hi nation.
After after eating a whole box of junk Barks,
Yeah, that's right.
Alright. So the d watch the mo bear drift off, and the Nephews hotel donald, you've gotta Al slip inside and tire up and he reacts as well as you might expect to this.
But they point out, you wanna be frozen out here,
and so he very
leak goes into deal with Mama bear, while they very bravely go after baby there.
And would be great and famous sequence here of Donald up put mama bear with his knees knocking and tear. And when she lets out to outside, he just absolutely
loses it and faint.
Me actually say not knock.
Yeah.
And so brave was nephews. It's the three of us are taking on that one that's smaller than us, but you have uncle
Oh come on. It's a bear. The other one is Al sleep the thermometer sleep. This is a live waking bear looking at them in the eye.
They are Inducks.
Alright. So in case you forgot Uncle Scrooge was in this store is well because this is where he returns, he gets to the cabin and he's kinda spying on them. He gets into his Barks costume.
He enters an immediate least sees the America.
He leaves behind the sofa in time to stay hidden,
but sees his little brand nephews chasing the far ferocious beast as he calls it.
So he can see they're fearless, but he continues on to try and scared Donald because that's who he really wants to test. He wants to know whether Donald has the of Lion, but he has pal of the because, unfortunately.
Yeah. That's right.
Alright. So on the next page when he does spot Donald, he sees Donald sleeping on the arm of a monstrous g bear, and so he's convinced that Donald just like him. He doesn't know the meaning of here.
As soon as the Barks size again, Scrooge freaks out, he leaves out of the bare skin and runs away. He tells his driver about how brave than nephews our. He wants James to invite them to the feast of their lives that is mansion tomorrow. And meanwhile, he's gonna think of an appropriate present for Donald.
This is this is a great resolution. This is a great moment in any Barks where we get
the kind of combination of everything. Let see. The results of all the
chasing from room to room and
misunderstandings and nonsense going on. And now, Scrooge has incorrectly judged his his
Donald to be the brave stuck in the world. That's right. It's all gonna come together. Screwed the exact same thing. Donald didn't accept oh the Barks side and you're runs away. Scrooge just completely abandoned the very costume, which I don't know if someone's gonna wonder why is their very costume
because I don't you know as much as other Scrooge screw oh my is a pretty Scrooge grand too.
Yeah. Are you suggesting, some hypocrisy?
Although Scrooge ran away from a live bear and Donald ran away from tiny rabbit tracks in the snow. So there there is a differentiator.
Scrooge doesn't know that. Yeah. That's true.
So the last page has the ducks of that celebration. The kids are enjoying some toys, routers is having the time of his life. Right. I don't know what, but it cracks me up. He says, boy am I having final wow. Here, Don have another peanut.
It's very non
of the wine, very un Scrooge like And so after dinner, he's gonna present donald with a pleasant and takes it out with an unnecessary
flourish. The free donald out by presenting him with a genuine siberian silver tip Barks skin, which promptly makes Donald things.
And the nephews used do a good job covering room him by saying, Donald must have eaten too much turkey or peanuts.
And last panel Scrooge rationalizing
this by saying for a moment there.
I thought he was scared.
We get some more good on P from Donald head hitting the floor with a.
Yes. And the trademark x's for eyes to show that he's he's out.
There's a picture of money above the couch? I don't know what it is. If it's a statue of a coin or I Al large base of a lamp. Oh, yeah. I like the Barks immediately really got into the money motif of Scrooge, an element that is only gonna pick up.
Well, wondering if it's just this this the kids comment. We have show direction easiest way choice where it's just that pictures of money around.
Yeah, it's always funny though to see someone who decorate that team.
You guys we did that we talked about
Christmas on their mountain. Scrooge
has now entered the conversation.
What did you guys think this landmark
introduction to Scrooge mc Ducktales?
i'd like to do is good. It was a very simple story. But it was very funny and have the right colleague pizza that donald ding screw up. It's nice how it changed a little bit. I mean, donald, we have least of that that sometimes he's brain, if he has to be. Other times he's coward or other times he's mean and this one, he never changes
he's always a scared cat.
And he tries me for everybody fails.
And and that's okay because that two dollar. I like that. I think it's true, and it's fairly consistent I think? Their select ones where he'll be brave when Barks needs him to be, but it's usually with a pretty good reason. He doesn't usually stick his neck out unless he has to.
Did you feel like if you had read this not knowing what was to come, would you expected any more of this character?
Well, I mean, at least in some of the other once being one shot characters, but we were nice surprised add and expand the family which, you know, introducing characters in common because it's hard especially when you've already established the main manufacturer. To be kind of band aid and start writing these other characters when you have the nephews and donald and it's pretty much set. To introduce the new character, that's gonna be that's pretty bold. I mean, would not expected. Knowing how these come operate. But me knowing that there's one the side character is now the k. Definitely paid it off him. What did you think, Ryan? That's
if I was reading this as a one off, I I could see i Scrooge being
used as the kind of
home base
sort of character sort of kind of anchor for the the family of venturing Inducks have donald and the nephews
going off to check out some mystery or whatever and then, you know, calling home to Uncle
for to help out with some pick them up with Al plane from, you know, whatever Island, they're stranded on or something like that.
I could see him being a, you know, recurring
recurring side character there. Maybe continuing to be sort of an old plot device.
Yeah. Yeah. Right.
Yeah. Like, I need someone to go explore in delhi. May you do that?
Yeah. I'm x uncle knocking and they need for the grinch. Right.
You know, I forgot to mention,
on the very first page, it's weird to see the nephews refer to him as uncles. Scrooge
instead of un.
I I'm not sure if this is the only time that happens, but it might well be.
So, you know, we we always check in on the Inducks,
general consensus is a good way to to see how
the average fan feels about this one. This one is a very high rating. Know, as I mentioned, this is in the top twenty five. It it clocks in at number twenty five.
For all of the Disney comments. If you're only looking at the Barks stories, there only two in the top twenty five that are not parks.
There's like one Gottfredson in store one sorry by Scarborough. So this is, like the twenty third best rated Barks story. It's got an eight point one out of ten, which puts it in, like, the ninety nine point nine
percentile for best.
I would say that it's probably
pretty big inflation. Right? Just because it's such a notable story. Because personally, you know, I I do like this story. It's a lot of fun, but it's a very slight
story. Right? It's it's not it's not very... It's not very deep It's it's pretty silly.
It's just what it is. It's a fun little holiday yarn
and it's got some good slab stick, but I I don't personally regard it as anything special
story wise
other than just coincidentally
kind of having
Scrooge.
I think if you took screws out and just put in, like a generic uncle money Barks character,
This one probably wouldn't be regarded as well as it is. That's not to come down hard on it because I do think it's a lot of fun.
Especially once you get past the fact that Scrooge really doesn't resemble
much of what he's going to go on.
You know, I I think it's interesting too that this is one of the longer stories that has...
Like, it feels like a ten pager to me that's been expanded it out into a twenty pager. A lot of the ten pager
have this sort of theme of the docs having to dealing with money problems.
And we don't see that in as many of the adventure
stories.
I think I think if it had been a a ten pager, I think it would have lost some of the
some of the punch of the
the double fake takeout and the, you know, different kinds of elements
that we got to
draw out and then get the get the payoff off for. I think we would... I think i would lost something. I definitely agree because I think part of why this works is you get to see that steady buildup up of Donald getting more progressively freaked out, which is better to see over the course of twenty pages.
Because I do think it's really funny. This is one of Barks fun stories, at least of this link, which are not always as interested being funny. They're more often interested in being adventurous and exciting.
Because it's not one of those far flung adventure.
Also pretty well. There's not really anything in here that's problematic. We don't have to acknowledge anything that's kind of retro grade.
There is some kind of fun archaic stuff in here. It's neat Severino Donald to get delivered to at the beginning.
The whole concept of, like, a bare skin Al a gift right?
I've seen these skin and old cartoons a lot, but I I don't think that Barks are really a thing these days they except I guess, for centric.
I I am an eccentric billing and I can confirm, yes. That is that is what we're into. Yeah. Well, there you go.
Boy appearances in other media. I mean, even without going into the fact that screws is gonna be a major character for more than just Carl Barks, you know, this story became a huge part of what dawn Roses is gonna base life and times of str Mc Ducktales, his epic telling of Scrooge
history on
because he he chooses to have the final chapter issue twelve, I guess, of that saga is basically all about the period of time in between it starts off when he leaves the cabin, basically
before they have their dinner that night, and it concludes later after this.
So Don rose adult with this day in his own colleagues.
There...
There been a couple other comic stories that have referred to this. There was a sequel someone else did called return to Bear Mountain.
I know I read a long time ago, I can't really remember it. So I'm not sure how well it holds up.
I'll have to take a look.
Barks did do one of his oil paintings on this. It's called Merry Christmas. It's a pretty great image it's a painted version of Scrooge sc
chair from the very beginning of the story.
So I'll put that up on the Facebook page.
I don't think there was really anything too educational about this one. But again, it was a lot of fun. Favorite panel,
I I really enjoyed a few of these panels. I enjoyed seeing how well stocked the cabin was, You know, the panel the fridge full of provisions, the debts were locking that. I I think I mentioned enjoying the panels of Donald getting Frightened.
And then, you know, it's it's hard to resist that panel of donald having painted in the Barks arm. And then I guess some of the establishing panels of Scrooge
and sitting in that chair sc.
By you guys, Eric. Any any panels come to mind? I like to treatment of the monitor very pop head up and whole out, and then just ridiculous this as long ripping part of this company. She's in send back down the door to help establish,
you know, whole thing also america also score
and just over advertising how big and how loud and how scary.
I agree. That's a pretty great sequence.
What about you right? I I think I'm gonna go with... There's one as the bears are eating the chocolates and opening presents.
There's a shot in between of just the three nephews and donald from behind from out in the snow. Looking into the glow, the warm glow of the inner
cabin there of the window just watching
Say say, that's the end of our candy and presence.
Side, and it's just kind of the combination of all our
misunderstandings and and craziness and setups going on. And now they're just
barefoot in the snow outside on Christmas day or Christmas eve or whatever this is. Just you can't see anything inside except for the yellow glow of just the You just imagine all the warmth and christmas y
love and goodness that's inside being demolished by Barks?
Yeah. That is a great one. I looked at that one too. Excellent.
Any any closing thoughts, guys? One or two thoughts on a question. Mark, you said literally on he kinda of goes back and used them for the old capital secret. Do you know if we brought screws back because he won't use to character? Or was this issue solar see that i felt you need to use Scrooge rodriguez? That's a good question. I don't think he got a lot of correspondence
about how well the issues did. Al sure they had circulation numbers on it, but he was he was anonymous for so much of this. Like, they always stamped walt Disney on the comma x. So
no one knew who's is doing these until much later when some dedicated fans sniff him out. I wasn't sure if the came with, come up and said oh a comic and character. And to go back and expand Al it. Right. And I'm guessing it was all based on reading the interviews he did and just how he took on the character. I think It was probably his own re of using the character.
That's why he went back to it, but because he obviously was highly motivated
to use... And the other comment I want to say at this call like these these comments are obviously geared towards kids. And I think that's the reason why the net fees are so common. Touch that row figures comics so they can kind of identify with them. And that statute back in the forty and fifty. So it keeps getting in trouble and this shift not back and down. It also makes you wonder this is the old trope of the wish fulfillment of. I wish I had a uncle that was sweeping from wherever shoot me whatever I needed. And help me have a wonderful Christmas. And you see can you see that in old tiny movies? And it's just that wonderful. Oh, you're the you. Now we can do this. Now We can do that any direction
now these kids are just getting by. Now they can, hey.
Now they live the highlight that's such a kid glitch. Yeah. I think you're right. That's a great way probably one of the more plausible ways to have that kind of wish fulfillment. Right? Is where your your uncle is a a bitter man who's trying to play a trick on you?
Well, going forward.
Yeah. Anything else Gentlemen. No. I don't think so. I think this is the the funniest one I've read so far. I I left out loud a couple times.
Reading this one. They had some solid solid gag.
Yeah. I thought this was good solid writing better than the royal mill. I mean, you're right. I think it's like kinda of kids introduction Scrooge. But, you know, otherwise, it's above average story. Yeah. I appreciate that comment, Ryan. This one is maybe not as show as some of the adventure ones, but it really good well crafted piece of comedy.
Alright. Well, thank you guys for coming back for our introduction to Uncle Screw Mc duck,
and thank you listeners for joining in.
As always, if you've got any thoughts or comments, you can drop us Al line at barcodes remarks at g gmail dot com. We've also got the Facebook page as well,
and join us next time as we talk about the story in Barks Africa.
Thanks.
Alright. So we are back here with a genuine kid for our Ask a kid sequence,
Welcome back Mia
remind us. What what grade are you in?
I'm
fourth about to go fifth grade.
Excellent,
and
you got to read Christmas on bare mountain,
the famous first appearance of Uncle Scrooge Dot
first me out, what did you think of the story?
I like it. I thought it was really funny, and I enjoy this seat can send the story.
Awesome. Yeah. I think this one's really funny. It's not as adventurous as some of them, but it's
it's a very funny one. What what did you think were some of the funniest parts?
At the end of where uncle
screwed
shows Donald
the... His bare pet... The
and he fainted
and in
or.
Yeah. That was a good one.
What did you think of
Uncle Scrooge, this being his first appearance?
I thought it wasn't one of his best twins, but I thought it was... He was really funny in it. Right on.
Right on. How about the nephews? I I thought it was kinda cool how much of the story they were in. What did you think of Huey, doo in Louie?
I thought it was really funny that they were encouraging donald and that they weren't afraid. Well, they weren't always afraid. They weren't afraid of the little cup, but they were kind of afraid of that big one.
Right, which seemed pretty sensible to me.
Awesome. Do you have any other thoughts or anything else you wanted to say about this story? Any other favorite parts or anything?
I like it when Uncle sk is in that bear,
and he sees the little bear, and he is...
He is
in horror and in so much shock.
That was fun.
Alright. Awesome. Thank you so much for coming back, Mia. Mh.
Me
lots
to
about
don't send me in
Let me ride through the white open country that I love.
Don't.