Hello, and welcome to Barks remark. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks, creator of sc Mc and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comics of all time. Join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological publishing or We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Welcome back everyone to Barks remarks. I have here a returning guest host. I'm gonna ask him to introduce himself and also tell us The worst thing he's ever done in pursuit of rare butterfly.
Hello. My name is Eric Curt. I'll me back. And the worst thing I had is the done in the pursuit of we're butterfly, I would have to say is probably through some rocks Scrooge. We're trying to do
biology project in high school.
Where we had the cats do bug collection. I don't know if it was rare. I'm sure it chase butterflies. And when that failed i through some rocks they create because splash are fine. There you go. I didn't I didn't think you'd have an actual response to that. So awesome.
So yes, as alluded to,
regarding the butterfly, we are going to be talking today about darkest
Africa
of fairly unusual
Donald Ducktales adventure.
You know, it kinda reminds me of the, like, what would you do for a Ducktales bar. Right? These these Ducktales
and
and professor Mc are are gonna end up doing a lot and pursue this butterfly.
Yes. I have to say for
a very
poor
Ducktales. Donald gets around the world a lot. Yeah. Yeah. It helps when you're bank by
random
wealthy
butterfly collectors slash ben.
Yes.
Alright. So, yeah, Eric,
let's get into it. Again, we are talking about darkest Africa
And usually,
I mentioned when the story was published.
This is another of those kind of ne ones that was originally published in one of the weird
giveaway comics
called March of Comics or boys and girls, March of comics, to go into the full title. It was one of those that where they could publish it to be given away in, like, shoe stores or or wherever, and they would put the store's name would go on the comic. Right? So so they don't have...
I don't have the actual date for it. We just know that this was published
near the beginning of nineteen
forty eight, and it was March of comics number twenty. And
Eric since the last time I had you on. I've started to mention how many printing are listed in total in English for this one. And
you know, we were last on for
Christmas on Bear Mountain and because that was,
you know, such an important one, that's had a a lot of printing. This one's pretty occasionally printed. Right? Including the original run. There only five printing total. Okay. And and
can can you guess why this one probably
was fewer than many. Just gonna guess the demand wasn't there.
Possibly
some of the art.
Yes well, yeah. There's there's a few... There's a few issues with this one that
have you know, stoked a little bit of controversy. It's it's a little bit of a darker.
I would almost say a little bit cruel comic. Right? I I don't find character very likable in this one. But anyway, we'll we'll get into that. Let's see. This is a twenty two pager.
And
there is
some good background to go into for this one. But before we do that, Eric, would you like to offer us up your
synopsis for this story. Sure. It says
where Al and Duck help his net chase butterflies and runs into a
another collective butterflies and becomes becomes rival and then gets rope into
going to africa to catch the rarest of rare butterflies. Against this
sc
rival collector who sabotage them, they said touch him, Hygiene and sue, they catch the bug butterfly. And the wins. Yeah. That's right. And and I would say no one no one comes out of this one looking particular really good in my opinion.
No. So
I already mentioned that this is a March of comic story. This is our second march of comics.
Giveaway story. Mah Donald was the first one. And
this story also has the distinction of being one of the times that Carl Barks is gonna go back and copy himself. Because he's gonna basically
reuse this plot you know, later donald dot com called called forbidden Valley. And
I like... I like that version, I think a bit better than this one. They're very similar, but
the big stampede at the end we get is a bunch of dinosaurs. So that's pretty cool. That's pretty good. Yeah. Although the elephant stampede pete in this is is definitely impressive. Yeah. This one
was subject to a lot of post
publications
censorship,
which is is pretty understandable because this one does traffic in some pretty unfortunate
stereotypes,
which Eric, you you really didn't get to see too much of. I think you probably saw some of it because it it was really in the stories Dna, and it couldn't...
It couldn't be completely covered up, but they did
do some like, Disney censorship, you know, after the fact where they went back and kinda soften some of the racial
car
and
some of the the terms that were pretty questionable You know, the time frame as to when that happened? I think that it was
immediately after like, when as soon as they went back to reprint it, and I don't know exactly how many years. But I'm guessing was probably within the first decade or so. Okay. That's pretty good recognizing and changing it as soon as they can. So while still publishing something that's
questionable
for recognizing that I give... And that's that's something of. So when it get around for a few issues.
Right.
And then, you know, as often happens, they probably will adjust it over the years and keep fine tuning it until I'm guessing this one's probably not gonna see a lot of reprint
anymore outside of, like, the the collections that they do. But it but it is worth noting right, that these attitudes
even though we're not gonna justify them they were totally in keeping with the time. Right? I don't know if you've read any other
comics from this era. I was actually exposed to one just not to... Recently, I got from a library called
involving a
superhero comic called the green turtle about a chinese.
American
superhero
that I found very interesting and was very
kind of been compelling. So I thought that was Al interesting contrast to what reading this one as well.
And did that one... I mean, I'm I'm sure it had problems. Was it Oh, oh. Absolutely. What it what I read was it was a a new walker, a new asian American macarthur who had written and he brought it,
the the shadow zero, and so he created this backstory
to this Asian American hero that's featured in the in the forties and wrote about the Chinese American who had created the zero, but at the time could not
portray him as a chinese hero And so this hero, you never saw his face in the comic. It was always his back or you always saw it was always hiding in face because couldn't show that he was in Chinese American
fighting, Japanese
enrolled in China world or two of the japanese were just horribly stereotype your tight. Know that Al as they were back then. So many were back then. Yeah. Having read that and now reading this one. Yeah. It's it's been an interesting
week and and a half for me reading those. Al all that. Yeah. To me the ones that come to mind,
you know, the ones that I'm most familiar with are, like the Asterisk
stories. And
ten ten or ten ten and those have kind of the same... Those are like almost the exact same era and are incredibly famous, well comics have some of these same stereotypes.
Again, we're not ex it, but we're like,
understanding. This wasn't unique to Carl Barks. This really was
just kind of the way you depicted savages at the time. So... And and we'll we'll see a little bit of growth from him
moving forward we'll also see some other problematic stories, but, you know, as always, I don't wanna be labor it too much, but, you know, we do have to recognize it no. I'll share
on the Facebook page, some of the panels
that we can look at to compare some of the changes that they've made. You know, some other interesting background for this one, I think is apart from, like, the racial stereotypes.
This one, it's almost like he went out of his way to make it awkward to reprint it because it has some like, some pretty brutal treatment of animals
in this one and and then that old, like saw of the the old trope of the comedic attempted
suicide at the end. Right? So there's there's some content here. And just times have changed. Yes. Yes. They.
And and before we talk a little bit more about the historical backgrounds,
one of our newer features is trying to wrap our mouths around some of the titles
from
publication from around the world. So we've got we've got four of them today. Eric, I think you're gonna do
Spain and Italy. Right, which leaves me France in Germany. Alright. So
in French, the title is
Lars
o c, x stan,
which I'm thinking must be the chase of the almost as extinct quest or quasi extinct
I I'm going out on Limb. I didn't even look that one up. Go for go for Spain. In Spain
in at,
the Africa.
The heart of Africa.
Right.
And in Germany, we've got
d le
mori
and that's the last more bun. I think we're we're thinking that more must be the name of the almost six distinct in germany. And then go for Italy.
Sum Chase of the
pre purchased sixteen
which is part the name of the butterfly. Right. I think it's just Donald and the extinct. Oh, it's how
Patrick. Yeah. Yeah. Oh, okay. That makes more sense. Like, the should be and. Right. I think it's just Donald and the extinct Cl. Yeah. So none of those titles really match English one, which is pretty interesting. Eric, do you know kind of switching to the historical context here? Do you know anything about the term Darkest Africa?
Only what I've seen in media where they would often call to remember this what's his name that famous
hunter
excuse me. He was played by Sean Conner in the movie
league of.
Oh, Al Quadrant, Is allen in quarter. Yes. They prefer going after Al the dark consonants. Yeah. Yeah. That's the other term. Right? It start this Africa where the dark content. Yeah. So I actually
just happened to learn about this a couple months ago in a podcast
about atrocities in the Belgian congo. It was
What's his name Ward
not Lord. It was Stanley.
Henry Stanley, you know, famous
Explorer, the guy who said
supposedly said doctor Livingston
he he popularized that term in his
in one of his books. And you know, it... It's just what you think it's meant to, like, refer to Africa's
a very savage and mysterious place. So that's that's where we get that title. It's not really...
Yeah. Certainly, it's certainly not not a good term. To use for Africa these days. I I also found interesting that this story has a lot of examples of what what I learned is called dog Latin. Right? So there's pig latin.
Sure and there's dog Latin. And Dog Latin,
Dog Latin is when you take
a word and you like fake latin. Right? So the almost
extinct is just the almost
that actually... There's there's a there's a term for that practice.
Okay. Yeah. So I like...
I like learning that. And then
just out of curiosity, I googled.
I think I Googled like, Cut throat and butterfly collector or or butterfly collector and murder just to see if anything came up. And it came up with an Npr story from about
thirteen years ago about a dude I mean, the story was more about the fish and wildlife guy, But who he went undercover to trap an international
butterfly thief.
From japan. Yes. And the guy touted himself as the world's most wanted
butterfly smuggle. So. They can't leave his large competition, but should go for it. Yeah. Absolutely.
That sounds so we has a Barks side cartoon. Yep.
Let's see. I I kinda skipped over the value range for this one. For whatever reason I had trouble finding
the, like, top top value, but I found that there was an eight point o that sold for twenty one hundred dollars. So,
you know, expensive, but maybe not Al a range for some people. And
let's see notable appearances. We we have professor Mc.
I don't even remember the name of the the random ben manufacturer. I don't know if he's even named, but But no one in this one is ever going to really appear again. And then I like to talk about which version of the characters we get in here. And I would say this is a good example of our our very stubborn
version of Donald. He's also very resourceful on this one now. And, you know, he's he's not quite a villain in this one, but he's definitely like, willing to kind of meet
professor Mc at his level I guess you could say. So and I I just I would get up and there's ben is sir that monthly. Oh, yes. Thank you. Because he does have a great Barks cnn name. Yes. Awesome son. Alright. I think
we are ready to dive into the story itself. Eric, you let me know if you have any reflections
after
talking about some of these pages. Sure time. Alright. So
darkest Africa you mentioned opens with the Ducktales
catching
butterflies, Donald is helping the nephews out with Al class project of theirs. And, you know, they're all they're all really into it. They seem to be having
some good clean fun.
I'm not sure about the fact that they're just kind of like tossing a bunch of butterflies loose into a big jumble in a cigar box, but, you know, it's a school project.
Donald seems pretty knowledgeable too about butterflies. Right? He
identifies the f fa from the tropics at the very beginning. And by the end of the page,
he is pursuing a new kind of butterfly that they've never seen
and he his net crosses with another net from an unidentified collector simultaneously.
That's gonna be interesting that these boys just have randomly i put place in the park and the funny clear ones and they just have across some... Like, there's some kind of butterfly magnet in this part, that which Al these heard better butterflies so those other collectors there. Yeah. Funny so. Popcorn. It's Duck berg butterfly district.
Here go. Alright. So
Donald and this this new collector get an argument
over this butterfly and the collector indicates that it's a very rare Pip
from Brazil and, you know, he's very determined to have him first his collection.
So they get in in a sc
And Donald kinda gets we see him get a bright idea. He
removes his nets suddenly and
smash is the net over the head of the other collector grabs the collector's net and is able to scoop up the butterfly himself. And in the background, we see a very well dressed gentleman kind of taking in this seam. This is interesting because very rarely
Donald being more than somebody else. He normally...
Mean, he he did go to anger, but he actually
outside the guy to get ahead of him get you money, which
looking at and now nice you get a little bit of foreshadowing of what's gonna happen later on in the story, at least you guys going at it. Yeah. That's true. It's it's necessary in this story, I think for Donald to be more strategic than he usually would be. Yeah Alright. So on the next page, you know, donald is triumphant, the other collector
is fuming
and the
well dressed gentleman approaches him. And I like, I like his line. He just says young man, I like the way you did that dirty trick. You know, no one is no one is being shy about how under handed they're being. And this guy introduces is... As you said, he's got a great Barks name Sir
Mo, the famous butterfly collector. He wants to recruit Donald to help him complete his collect And specifically, he'd like to have him go to Africa
to bring back the butterfly that we're gonna know so much about by the end of the almost
six stink.
Donald,
upon learning that it's in Africa blanche, because that's very far away. And he's like, why why would you need me? And he indicates that, you know, Donald has just bamboo b one of the most cut throat butterfly collectors there is.
Professor argus Mc fe. And so, you know, he's probably gonna have another run with him if he chooses to go to Africa.
I like that he's a butterfly collector.
But he has no net, like, he just came towards their butterflies.
Yes. Yeah. That's true. He he came to
scout for another butterfly collector to do his dirty work, I guess. But, you know, that's what you find in the butterfly district. Absolutely.
So on the next page the f user
are kinda saying now, it would be pretty neat to go to Africa.
You know, Donald is right right fully talking about what a pain in the butt it would be all the things that he'd need to arrange while he's gone. And,
you know, they kinda give it up the nephews
say that they might as well take the butterflies to their teacher, and they walk past professor Mc hiding behind a tree and he just snatch the whole collection and catches the taxi and runs off. I've gotta to say I like the the the evil sn that is plastered across Mc mackenzie face in, like, ninety percent of his appearance.
Yeah. Absolutely.
But I mean, how evil can you be when you stealing butterflies with kids?
I mean, it's just that's his name. What Al load levels of hell right there. Yeah. That's almost grinch. Right? Yeah absolutely.
So
Donald learns from a random farmer who heard him take the taxi that he's on his way to Africa.
So that's that's all it takes. Donald is driven by his need to get
revenge.
He's gonna take that job and just midway through this page we transition
to Africa.
It's right. No transition per store for traveling, no adventures there, no t monsters,
or pirates just right africa?
Right. And,
you know, we even transition
immediately to the butterfly, which
has a helpful arrow
pointing to where it is. It's a really a lovely scene of, like
lagoon with a lot of cool wild but really, really great panel. So nice depth to it too. We see a native an African native who spotted it and it starts kind of a
a drumming
transmission of of the message.
And go ahead and comment whatever you'd like, Eric. I'm gonna take a moment to share the original panels here with you for some of these.
Well, I just looking at that
native and just... Yeah. That's really request.
And if that's been changed,
Yeah. Those are those are red drives. Right? So We're we're looking out at the original art. And and like to be fair, these these depictions are again totally within the standard of of the time. They have the kind of like,
oversized
lips. That we're we're drawn for many black characters.
But it it's gonna get a little bit worse for some of these. Yeah. That's that's this that the disturbing to say. Gladstone redid did them. Yeah. I I agree. It was it was the right call. You know, in the panel that we see, there is some
sort of pigeon talk to communicate the transmission but in the original
panel,
you know, I don't have that part. I actually don't know if they just retained that or not. I I am glad to see that they at least like... Oh, it's not pigeon. I'm glad that
you know, making a made up language is, I guess, arguably, not as offensive as using, like a pigeon speak that you sometimes see. Yeah.
That's there.
So on the next page, we see the rest of this transmission
and
donald,
you know, it gets back to Donald who's you know, at a camp. And in this panel that we see, he asks know you the voice of the drums, Moo
is the name of the native that he's talking too. And then in the original one, he's actually referred to as fuzzy Wu, which which is both offensive and and confusing to me. So... Yeah. But the the native says that the
butterfly has been spotted on the upper w Busy river.
And B is the... You hear that a lot in, you know, this kind of media. That apparently is sw Huey, for for, like, master
loss. Okay. And so the the du break for their camp and they launch a boat to be on their way. And as they as they lead their boat off,
it's clear that
holes have been drilled in their boat
and
about sinks
and they see a note floating on the water that says, welcome to Africa,
professor Mc.
Yes. Did you wanna mention what you had found about
Lamb be z? Yes. I did some research on the Web Busy just thinking i don't think it's real, but let's look it up and what I misspelled it because in this one, it's spelled w h a m. When I was going after by memory I still did w m and it popped as a reference
to the old serial comic... The phantom, which
involved heavily of the advent in the Ducktales. If you know anything about the phantom.
From what I could find, the reference was some created in the eighties. So I don't know if writers were pulling from other stuff or older stuff because the phantom has been around
forever, and they had been lost the continuity excuse with the van. Was in Southeast asia was in Africa. But doing... Don't know it's coincidence. Don't know if it's i mind or if it's something maybe Barks heard when Huey, was when, you know, you mentioned in the original phantom of comments back back the day. But I just thought it was very interesting to have that very similar name in a similar site type of adventure comic that is the phantom. That's all about the the daring dew and the rescuing and fighting of pirates and evil treasure collected collectors I don't know Can... I fan everyone after butter butterfly collectors
who knows. I I think that's a good catch. I would I wouldn't be surprised, You know, the the phantom was a super famous
serial
strip. Right? And so I I would be shocked if Barks wasn't familiar with it. So I think that's a cool catch. So on the x page, the du power are patching up their boat, they agree that Mc
has one
round one of their sperm here. And
they managed to get the boat going again. Eventually, Donald is really thirsty, so he takes a big drink from his canteen.
And finds out that it has mud in it. The water has been doctor. And so they decide they need to check out their rations. So Tunnel throws a piece of hard attack to one of the crocodile dials that's near the boat. Eric do you wanna tell us
what happens to that crocodile
Oh
look rapport to say crocodile just wanted have a snack and then he ended dying.
Yeah. He open dies pretty thoroughly. So
butterfly collecting is serious business
cut throat. So i and, you know, I like that that pan. I don't... It's a little bit off putting the fact that, you know, they're just killing crocodile in this episode in this comic, but I like the
crocodile, death throws in those two panels. That spreads it's pretty funny and pretty neat art.
So the Ducktales
journey down the river, they, you know, figure they have to live off the land. They get their water by mocking
a monkey and getting it to throw coconut that's at them. A nice lever touch. Yeah. And we transition to nightfall. There's really awesome
couple of silhouette panels of the ducks in their boat. One of these was adapted into the the cover
for the the issue, the reprint that I first read this one in which I think it's just a... Yeah. Really cool cover. I'll certainly have that up on the Facebook page, but they approach a fire. And when they get close, they see the silhouette of professor fe. And, you know, he's already
sabotage them. So I guess it turned about is fair play, and they thoroughly
wreck his campsite while he's sleeping, but as they're leaving donald trips,
waking
the figure,
And as he gets up, it is revealed that it is not,
but it is
an unpleasant looking man with a German accent.
Who claims to be a professor von
from their university of Rotterdam.
So professor Von tulip is looking at his reps boat and supplies a gas and the duck Scrooge just feeling incredibly guilty.
And, you know, Donald points out, you know you're here's your gun. It isn't her hurt. This is a bad idea because the professor
turns the gun on them and command years their supplies. And
Eric, you wanna tell us what the ducks find out as he paddle off. It was a mask. It was professor Mc Al along.
Yeah. Professor Mc is
pretty prepared. He seems to have really thought about his nefarious.
So
the Ducktales have lost round two and they... In in the morning they figure out there there's a couple of bad things. Right? They can't patch the boat. And they're not on a sand like they thought they were it's a it's a little island that is surrounded entirely by crocodile.
So they they kinda brainstorm
what are their options
and
they land on another plan that involves killing another crocodile.
You know, you go with what you Al and what they have is in the tons of crocodile. It's true. They've got poisoned heart attack and they've got crocodile. So So they feed another crocodile and they use its skin to disguise themselves to get away from the rest of them. And you know, Eric, you didn't get to
join us in the mystery of the swamp episode, but I think you read that story.
This this whole page, you know, the du disco is d
as the crocodile and the the sand Barks this this I felt like it was kind of a callback to history of the swamp. Sure. So on the next page the Ducktales,
you know, they see that they've got some easy grass land walking coming up ahead until they come to a very deep gu
and it's necessary to cross on a suspicious looking boulder. You wanna tell us about the boulder the boulder
is
elephant not done.
Yes. So
they start an elephant,
and this actually works out pretty well for them because the elephant
t off in the direction that they need to go. So they make some really great time. Well me think about they like, oh, look Al frequently that. That's not that's normal. Let's keep going. That's true. I didn't think about that.
You know, these are... I I like these panels with the elephant.
Startled and running away. The backgrounds look really cool. Al elephant itself looks neat. I like them Al lot. Yeah. And then on the next page, I think are some of the the very pretty panels with the elephant crossing the river with the Ducktales still on their back,
the Ducktales grabbing, some bananas
to subs off of
and eventually coming to
near the W b River. I
that clark really enjoyed the
making him a key part in two parts of the story. And really just like maybe that's every turns of going, you know, writing on the back of Al office is... Hopefully, we're so than getting it crocodile out sure.
But, you know, include that in the story so make it that's like, oh, that's, you know,
right hell this. Yeah. It does look like he had fun
depicting the elephants.
It's a good thing because by the end of it, he's gonna have to draw a lot of elephants.
Just give us back that's what it was. Yeah. So still on this page, we
transitioned back to professor Mc
who almost immediately
spots the almost as ex extinct
and as he's about to capture him, Donald pops up and trips him and intending to take his net.
And on the next page, of course, Mc is shocked to see him this is a a fun exchange. You know, He asks
how did you get here? Donald tells him I took the bus, and he says, well, you'll take the hears back pulling out a gun.
Fortunately, the nephew has a nice
late forties
slingshot every every kid needs to have a slingshot
and
peg him right in the eye winning round three as he says, So they managed to run off professor Mc
who, you know, needs to plot and scheme and he ponder.
So in the version,
Eric that we're reading, he says, he thinks to himself.
There must be a native village around here where I can hire some assistance.
Al least see Donald about to catch the butterfly.
Eric, can I share with you my screen again so you can see what that looks like on the original printing? I'm almost scared see. Yeah. This one's not great.
Yeah. Yeah.
So again, we've got... We've got the kind of African
savage
care share, but...
But even more so unfortunately.
Yeah. Alright. So on the next page, we see him
having
encountered
the the narrator box says that Mc fe makes a deal with some very rough
savages. That's the term that he uses.
And he says in in the version you and I read, it's he says now you
understand for two false teeth. Oh, no. In the version you and I read, he says you
understand for two confederate dollars here to capture these little boys and hold them until I tell you to let them go. And and in the original, he said for two false teeth here to capture these fat juicy little boys and hold them until I tell you to let them go. And
I'm not gonna read what they say, but it's implied that there just cited it, the prospect of eating them as cannibal.
And and if you look, if you compare Eric, it looks like there was some artwork
slipped in to kinda stretch this panel out. Yes and totally excise that panel referencing
cannibalism.
Yes. So the stakes are really high on this page. And we see we transition back to the Nephews use who have...
Donald is pursuing the butterfly,
they've gathered a big jar of caterpillars
that wanted an nephews
would like to take home to their nature teacher.
While they're pondering how much they're looking forward to getting home we see them captured
with spears point to at them. This is parallel. That's a kinda standard...
Yeah. Although though usually, they're the ones kinda getting out of it. And you know, in this one, Barks hasn't really turned them into the junior wood ups that he would later. Right? That would that would
look up information about the place they're traveling to and probably would not harm any of the the local wildlife.
No.
So meanwhile, Donald
has been in pursuit of the butterfly for quite some time. This is a pretty cool series.
How he gets the butterfly. The butterfly flies nearly off a cliff, but it gets... It gets puff backwards
by an elephant Trunk right into Donald neck.
So he when he looks down, oh, I like the line that he says, and elephant blew him back to me. That's two favors, I owe them. And then he's shocked twenty season in this goalie. There's like a gathering of thousands of elephants.
So Donald just journeys back to his to his camp. And I don't think elephants really do this. I don't think they gather on these numbers, but
it's a it's a pretty cool image. Yeah. That's a wonderful plot device. Yeah. So Donald gets back and he doesn't see the kids and he realized to his horror that Mick fe must have them. So he goes to his camp and mc fe he's sure enough gloves that he'll trouble him for that
butterfly and he points out that they are over at that native village where there's some ominous drums in the background.
And so he explains that he's gonna trade the nephews
for that butterfly. So in the version,
we
see it references
their heads being shrunk, because I guess voodoo head shrinking is considered a little less offensive.
Well, cannibalism.
I think little the more when see there's the head you could interpret that head out of the village.
For Pet. I think you can let that's that that's a little more... I'm not justifying it. But I'm saying it's word I
as opposed to. Right. I do think where they are in a.
Yeah. Yep. There's the stew.
So anyway, Donald has no choice but to give him the butterfly and he gets the nephews used back and I agree that the professor wins round four, and they're kinda doing
just angrily, fortunately not literally. And they're they're noting that the professor is gonna beat them to the coast, and then
Donald has a realization after one of the nephews make a joke about catching the ride on another elephant,
because that
reminds him of that convention of elephants. And on the next page,
he shows them where the river bends bends deeply where there's the opening of that pass. So he tells the Nephews
to light a bunch of fires
which
deeply alarms the smoke from the fires deeply alarms the elephants
who
stampede and terror towards the gap where the river meets that big gu. And the way to repair your favorite.
Yeah. Exactly. This is this is
another kind of example of the casual animal cruelty in this one because, like, they're not directly hurting these elephants, but I'm sure a bunch of them are
worse for the wear after the stampede.
But
I can't argue with the fact that on the next page, we get one of the coolest panels that Barks has gotten to do so far. Oh, yeah.
As the stampede of thunder elephants
crashes into professor and Mc.
Panel is boat across. It's a it's a great half page panel very detailed. Donald in the distance saying all that for a butterfly.
And,
you know, Mc gets patched up. The ducks patch him up at least. They rescue they rec come near the butterfly from him and head back with the butterfly and the jar of caterpillars.
Any other thoughts on on that one that's just that's such a cool panel. That that... you know, you guys spoke pivot a panel. I'm like, that's
anybody reads that's gonna be the paper panel that Al.
I I sometimes wonder what I see our like comics is it's someone gonna draw that picture and then had to come up with the story to go around that picture. So just for an excuse to draw that picture because it's done with such detail and such such appreciation. That's really the shows stopper. Yeah. I agree. I I had the same thought. And this is a pretty low resolution one that I'm showing you, but you can see the when he's gonna go back to this well and show a dinosaur stampede.
It's a pretty cool panel. It's not quite as need is the elephant one I think. No. There's... Well, we're actually got the up one, but it's good. Yeah. Yeah.
And, again, that's for Forbidden Valley. And this is that's like, ten years later, so we won't we won't do that for a pretty good span. But, anyway, we
transitioned to the boat to to the Ducktales
on a return ship to the Us and the docs seemed to have reached a bit of a deterrent with Professor Mc because he's still sc at them, but they're not, like, actively trying to murder each other at least. But professor mc fe is just like, despair that his life's purpose. Is
done. He lost the butterfly that he was dreaming of finding and is is really down in the dumps. So Donald tells the kids to go off and play and he's gonna keep an eye on the old guy in case he tries something funny. And on the next page, this is where we get that like, suicide for
comedic purpose where
he says that he has nothing to live for, so he plans to jump into the ocean.
But Al he about to jump in, He sees an almost
and then looking around, he sees even more and more and he and Donald point out that, wow, Now that butterfly is
basically worthless.
And they wonder where it's coming from and then the nephews around the corner and reveal that their jar of butterflies turns out to have been a whole brood of almost this ex extinct
and
how disappointed their teachers going to be. And that's the end of darkest Africa.
Yeah. Not not the longest of stories.
You know, this one, I
I only had this one issue of it. So i I didn't I don't think I read this one too much as a kid. But I definitely
remember enjoying this one more than I do
today. That's fair. And it's it's a good standard.
Or story, you know, they get put over by there like couple times times, and then they have to use their resources and like, all good adventure stories. You live by using a stampede.
You know? That the and end the putting he been and end it does become... you know, they're not the shiny heroes. It's like, oh, well, i victory
more of a moral one because we didn't give what we wanted it. But the bad guy undefeated. Right. Yeah. So so you enjoyed this one? I enjoy aspects of it. Thought I I I... The eventually part of it dude was the elephants for good, but Mean, yeah, the lot of the depictions.
Even in the booth first, you know you a that version.
Still questionable and
for that reason, i'm like, yeah, I'm not heard this one Al lot.
Yeah. But I did like I thought that the title was good because it's kind of dark story. It's all about revenge.
And and every it's all about revenge and it is called Barks africa, you know, revenge. This come from with our card you could think about it. Yeah. That's true. It ends up being a very fitting title. Yeah. I mean, I'm torn on this one because, like, Al lot of a lot of that doesn't sit well with me, obviously, but there's there is a lot to enjoy about this one. There's some neat adventure.
I do think some of the transitions in this one are a little bit jarring. Right? I think maybe it could have stood to have been like, two to four pages longer or something because, like, it's not just the fact that they get where they're going very quickly. It's just that things happen almost too quickly in this one. But
there's there's certainly some neat artwork work in this one It it didn't I wasn't as bothered
by
some of the, like, racial stereotypes
as I was in like Volcano Valley where.
That's fair. Yeah. Where I think it was like, more
important to the story. That's not to excuse these, you know. They don't no. But yeah the though those characters being the... The native characters were very much a background of the story. Right. To a degree, not like,
kind of valley where it was like, no their whole stereotype is the the stereotype of was pushing the story along. No. Right. You could have, like, taken them out of the story and just kind of changed it a little bit without really affecting it that much.
Because, like, most of the danger came from, like, African wildlife and and the Ducktales fighting against Mc fin in this. So, you know, again, that's not to excuse it at all.
But but at least it wasn't like, the stereotypes were not fundamental to story.
Yeah. So so this one this one's alright. This is kind of to me a middle Barks story. The the general consensus you know, we like to look on the index page to see where the community has rated this one. And I'm finding Eric that a lot of these stories
where there are these stereotypes that I might think would kind of pull down the rating, it isn't really pulled down. And I I
fact that that's because index is pretty ancient as far as the Internet goes. Mh you. So I... I'm pretty sure it's been around for I think since the nineties.
That's the original
there. Yeah. So like, many of the votes are
from long enough ago that many people
maybe are not taking these things into account. Or maybe they just don't care about it, and they're just enjoying the story the way they enjoyed it as a kid, and that's that's fine.
Maybe they were going up for printing and not the original printing. Yeah. That's true. Again, I I think it's hard to avoid some of the bones of this story. But... But yeah. So so for index, this one has a seven point seven out of ten, which is good enough for one hundred and fifty second.
Out of all about forty one thousand
Disney comics,
placing it pretty high in the ninety nine percentile. As far as like relative to the other
stories we've read, that definitely places it in the upper half. Time tied with stories like
terror of the river and Raja Donald. You know, I think this one is, I guess well regarded by fans. It does have some pretty cool adventure and some pretty
memorable
panels.
I would say that these these this version of the docs they're a little less developed. Right? I think Huey, doing and Louie are gonna evolve a little bit as we go along. Yeah. I can turn that one. We've we've already
talked about what's dated or archaic in this one
and what's retro grade? What's problematic? Obviously, the the kind of overall view of Africans as as savages and just the term darkest Africa.
So this one doesn't doesn't hold up.
That well,
but,
you know, has some has some fun pool elements.
Unfortunately I don't feel like there's a ton of educational value either in this one. No. There there could have been an opportunity to learn a little bit about butterflies. Only one of them was even a real one. You know, the the dog Latin is is kind of fun. But
but, you know, I I do really like it when I learned something cool from one of these Barks stories.
We both... We kind of acknowledge that the elephant stampede is the clear winner for panels in this one. Where were there any other panels that came to mind for you? Oh like I like... I you pointed out the one with the where
see the butterfly originally put the arrow in it. Pointing it out. That was a really neat just background front panel. And, of course, Barks is really well with anything with silhouette spots to do some contrast with the color and the cover was just very impressive to me. Yeah. And that was a rei imagining that he didn't do the cover that I showed to you, but it did... It did re... It was repurposed from his panels. So... Okay. Yeah. Because the original March of Comment had, like Al totally un unrelated cover. But I agree those silhouette ones are really cool. And you know, look kinda randomly, I really liked the sequence where Donald is pursuing the
butterfly and that elephants
trunk pops it into his net. It was kinda weird that it was neat. Yeah. Any...
Oh as as far as appearances, I don't wanna leave that out,
not really any appearances and any... He didn't use this one as inspiration for an oil painting. Or lit
And as far as I know, this didn't really inspire any of the Duck tales episodes in either of the two series. Any any closing thoughts, any final thoughts for this one?
No. I mean, it was it was a good standard adventure story. A flu different for me to donald or, you know, he's out for money or he's gets wrapped into something by accident or he yeah I was greed or his anger gets carried away. This one's is just about revenge
down
don't kinda hero this one, which is i again, a little bit different than a lot of the comics where donald is the one who comes up with the plan, even if he doesn't find a better front better her butterfly the end, for me, he he had done on top the building. His own his own thinking. And amazon planning not by accident or the nip is pulling his standing on the fire. And you know, I had characterized
him Al being kinda ro in the beginning. And he definitely... He definitely was, but you're right. He's he he is the resourceful one. Too much of this one. And he does end up being very heroic by the end, you know, saving nephews and even taking care of Mc
you know, patching them and trying to stop him from killing himself. Yeah. So
that's at least some somewhat of an arc for him. Excellent. Well, Eric, I really appreciate you
joining us again coming back. Yeah. No problem. I hope
everyone will join us next time when we get to talk about a very famous and very well regarded
story, the old castle secret.
Yeah. Should be a good one. This is...
I I like to say Eric that this is the true origin story.
Frustration.
Yeah. If anyone would like to reach out, we have our Facebook page for Barks remarks as well as
an email
Barks at g dot com. So until next time.