Hello, and welcome to Barks remark. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks, creator of sc Mc and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comics of all time. Join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological publishing or We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Hello, and welcome back to Barks remarks. I'm Mark Sever. This time podcasting
from inside a tiny closet hopefully,
I get some good quality sound out of that. I have a returning guest host with me today. If you can introduce yourself, Hi. I'm Sarah Santiago.
I'm currently
broadcasting
from my bedroom in
Thunder Scotland.
Yeah sla, which is
perfect for the story that we're gonna be talking about today. We get to talk about
fan favorite, the old castle secret. I'm very excited for this one. This is pretty landmark
story, and I'm glad to get you back to do this one because neither
neither of us enjoyed the first one that you were on which was.
I mean, it was kind of Al love to hate, and enjoy. But, yeah. This one was
enjoyment for pure enjoyment. Good. I'm glad to hear that because this one is like I said a fan favorite.
And it it's a pretty long one. So there's... And I think there's gonna be a lot to talk about So on when let we get right into it.
Again, we are talking about the old castle secret which was published in June of nineteen forty eight
in the old comic four color, number one hundred and eighty nine
Sarah, I started to look and
Al reprint and how many times something has been reprinted in the United States, which kinda gives us an idea of that popularity.
This one's been reprinted eight times, which is a pretty good number. As mentioned, it's a longer one. It's thirty two pages in length. And this is a very significant one
that I would I would call this
kind of the true origin
of sc doc. Right? Because the last episode that we put out
saw his
technical origin in the story Christmas on Bear Mountain.
That's kind of a kind of a goofy story
It's a lot of fun. I really like that, but, you know, it it doesn't really establish the character
too much.
I had sent that one to you as well to go along with this one just just for some background. Did you get to read that? I I did.
It was
It was interesting and that he was kind of one dimensional. He was kind of
a my league grumpy
happy eager to see them fail kind of character and he I enjoyed the development
away from that in this episode.
Right. And and I think you can really see that sort of pivot that Barks made from having him be that one off one dimensional character
to kind of, hey, This is this is someone that I'd really like to flesh out.
I'd like to establish him
as a major character
in the Ducktales.
Universe in their lives.
And so I'll I'll go back to the well, and I'm gonna give him this background
this very identifiable background and a lot of
a lot of characteristics
that he would, you know, keep throughout throughout the comics.
And
that
identifiable in that all of us are dis descended from scottish royalty and have ancestral acids. Right?
Yes. Exactly.
Or rather
or rather
identifiable in that this is the sc. This is, like, eighty five percent of the sc that we know and love today. Right? It's still it's obviously a very early version of him.
But there's there's a lot of, you know, what would make him a fan favorite going forward. And I think it'll be interesting as we talk about the story to kinda recognize what feels,
vary,
you know, classic sc and then what is something that indicates so, you know, this is a character that Barks is really still developing here. And this is not very typical.
So just just a very brief synopsis for this one. This is gonna be, as you said kind of about
sc
ancestral Scotland.
He is going to recruit the other Ducktales to help him find a treasure
hidden within its walls,
and they're gonna
run into what seems to be a supernatural mystery
regarding
regarding the treasure and who owns it, and who should keep it. And this one has some fun twists in turns. So I think we'll leave the synopsis at that and
get further into it in the story.
I do enjoy talking about backgrounds
trivia
regarding the story and its development and its creation.
And I also really like talking about background relating to the kind of history and culture
I'm gonna talk mostly about the stories background and I'm gonna kinda leave it to you to talk about the history and culture because I I think you had some fun looking into this.
Yeah. I'm ready. Awesome. So like I said, I would consider this
sc
true origin story because we see so much of what makes him a recognizable character. You know? We've got his
scottish background,
we've got the fact that he does come from this very long line
of of, you know, an old clan, a Scottish clan. And nobles at that. Yeah. Exactly. If you've got
if if your clan has a castle
named after itself, then then clearly you've got nobility
in your line.
We have the fact that he is rich. Although we don't really have the fact that he is super rich. Yeah. He's just I think garden variety rich in this one.
This might be what set them apart. Yes. Where he makes his extra billions.
Right.
And and
marx didn't really
go for much continuity
in these stories. So there's there are some kind of like
explanations here and there for how he acquired his wealth, but
it really came about later
through some of our and then what a lot of other creators do like Don Rosa to kind of establish some of the facts of it. So
This ends up being a very important story
that creators like Don rose are gonna draw from.
But again, this is this is a very famous one.
So there are some...
I was able to find a few interviews where Barks talked about making this one. There was a nineteen sixty two interview
that in which someone asked if you know, he went back to the well if he
went back to... And had sc come back because he had gotten, you know, favorable comments or anything like that. And he said not a word, but I kind of liked old Scrooge and he filled a gap. We needed somebody to help donald Al out.
So, you know, this wasn't like he wasn't like the fan favorite as far as Barks new. This was really something personal him. He liked
he liked what he had created.
And so he wrote the story to explain where the character came from. And then he also talked about a little bit about how dark this story is. Right? Because this one is really notable in that it allude two skeletons,
it it's going to show what we believe to be a dead body
So you know, he talked about there being a little bit of horror story in this one, mentioning the skeleton world up in an old castle. And he described it as almost being like the Ec comics tradition.
And and he said that he managed to put it over without getting too morbid of it. Do you know the old Ec
horror comics? That's like a classic famous horror comet? Line. I definitely
I don't know Sarah, if you happen to look into any of the real castles that inspired
clan Castle?
I...
It's...
Since they don't really say
when
the
castle was
built...
It was hard to kind of pinpoint Barks architectural style. It looked... It actually looked more continental
to me with the, like, cons turret.
Cons turns. And
and it not at all in the dials of
scottish castles that I've seen. Castles in Scotland are a dime dozen. And they are so much fun to visit. I highly recommend
visiting all the castles you can, but they're generally more angular
and and square.
They're more fortresses
rather than palaces. And this one appeared more
more like the
In Germany, like the that inspired the Disney castle. With just the rounded
of everything.
Yeah. So that that's a good instinct because you're right, it's not modeled after a scottish castle,
but it is
it is model largely after one in wiggle
if let's see. I'm gonna go ahead and share this image with you. So this is
har
castle.
According to what I read. And again, you know, this one's a very famous story. So I think people had asked him a lot about
where he was inspired.
This one's supposed to be an ama of
har cat castle is like the main structure of it, but he added some turret and battle from Al
and a tower of cow
which are true Scottish castles
that are ones that figure in the legend of Mc bath. Many use Oh. Yeah. Have have you been to any of
I don't know if those sound familiar. It sounds like you visited a few around there.
There,
I I I could be wrong, but I believe that the one that you're saying is called Glam is actually pronounced
Gladstone
I know this
because There is an episode of one of my favorite podcast podcasts,
Steph,
and there is
a a legend of the monster of guam and it's this, you know, supposedly the this monster.
Yeah. It's... I bet you're right. I bet that's the castle.
That it's talking about. I'm often surprised Al how things
are really supposed to be pronounced.
Oh, Scotland has... It's a it's a thing on Tiktok where,
you know, the on tip tiktok they have the pronounce this challenge just to see what different accents,
how they say different things. So
everywhere has
their
idiosyncratic
pronunciation. Right on. So, yeah, we've got we've got some pretty cool historical
castle
imagery in here.
And Barks famously like to use national geographic as a model. So I I think that you can tell. Right? Because it looks to me like there was some care taken and drawing both the exterior and the interior of this castle.
Just from the backgrounds I can tell when we're in the dungeon versus when we're in, like, you know, a main part of the castle. So
I I think that's probably part of why this story is very well. Like. And then
cup a new thing that I've been doing for a couple episodes now is
just thinking about how global the fan base is for these these stories, I've been having some fun looking at some of the printing from around the world. And
trying to say some of the titles in their native languages.
And just paying attention to the different titles that get chosen. So
I picked six of them. I think I'm gonna butcher the first one pretty badly, which is the finnish title is is.
Van
Sal,
which translates to secret to the old castle pretty close. Okay. Yeah.
And then the French title is Lu,
which translates to the Scottish ghost. So they're really... Yeah, They're really playing into the the Scott's part of the title with this one.
Germany, this one is
s
dispensed, which is uncle Sc and the castle ghost, and then in Mexico.
You know the secret to old castle.
Here's another one that i'll butcher shirts in Swedish,
then
Ga Bo
ham
secret of the old castle. And then in the Uk for whatever reason it was at one point called capsule of fear. Oh out Yeah, some fun titles from around the world. And I I do think that it's notable how scary this one is. Right? I read this one to my kid.
And I'd say this one that's another kind of interesting background thing. This is scarier than the average Barks story.
And not preoccupied with, like, death and
violence. I got that impression too.
One in my notes, I wrote
spooky
with before with four o's. It was obviously
a cartoon.
So, you know, there wasn't an
skeleton and it wasn't even an actual skeleton. It was a shadow of a skeleton.
But they mentioned other skeletons.
They
came upon, you know, as you said, a supposedly
a dead body spoiler luckily it wasn't.
How how often
did the
donald Ducktales comics get
spooky. That's an awesome question. I offhand, I would say this isn't probably the, like, five or six
scariest of the stories. You know?
They were frequently
creepy, but
this one's pretty notable in being creep than the average by a lot. Yeah. I can imagine putting myself back at, you know, single digit age. That it it might have been kind of scary in the same way that, like, the garfield
Halloween special back when we were single digit age,
was sometimes too scary to watch even on, like, the tenth three watch. How... That was that was a randomly
incredibly scary piece of
animation or or I I remember that one too. That's a weird aside, but you're absolutely right. Though terrifying.
It was.
How often
did
they... See it felt very scooby do es in that oh hears this creepy seeing and we've un it and it turns out it's just a regular
but nefarious person. Right. How often did that happen in these spooky stories?
I would say that this one is kind of unique, you know, in and having that sort of sp doo feel. There's definitely, like, i I guess I can think of a couple stories where someone is trying to scare people and they do get on mass So there's probably Al a handful of them. There be like plots to scare people off Al valuable property going in the future, but this one does feel kinda unique. I'm trying to think about how much it must pre scooby doo dubai. I think. I think Scooby doo came around in the like early sixties or so. Yeah. It's a good decade or a decade and a half. Right. But... Yeah. It's definitely
definitely creep than the average Barks story. Was there an actual
did any of the more spooky stories
turn out to be
real ghosts real monsters, anything like that. Yeah. I mean, the duck are gonna definitely encounter, like, real monsters and real creatures of legend, but he doesn't usually
combine like the creep with an actual
monster. It's usually, like, either creepy
or monstrous.
But, you know, there there are... He he wrote like five hundred some of these stories about a hundred of which are the the like adventure length ones. So I'm sure I can't think off the top of my head. I I remember there's a later one that has Al legend of werewolf where I believe it turns out to be similar to this. There's there are a lot of similar ones. There are a few similar ones to this. But I I'd say this one's pretty singular
in its creeping I don't think that there are as many that are as
preoccupied with, like death as this one. You don't really see a lot of death in these stories.
Yeah. Okay.
So this one, I was Al little surprised at the value range I expected it to be
more valuable. But what I found was that a very good copy of it a nine nine point zero rated copy sold for four thousand eight hundred. Which, you know, is obviously a pretty penny. But
compared to, like, last issue where we had the technical origin story that one was like, extremely valuable, I think went up to a hundred thousand.
That's that's what I've got for the sort of background of the story So as far as notable appearances in this one, we don't really have many characters at all because this one's so self contained. The only
apart from the Ducktales family now including Scrooge du, we just have the character of Scott, and this is a weird one. Right? Because you know, again spoiler, he's gonna turn out to be an impostor. So we never really meet this this scott up until
up until Don Rosa is gonna use him as a character in his flashback story. And then of course, I've been talking about which version of the characters we get in this one. I find it notable that
Barks still seems really interested in bravery and coward in this one. Right? Because we have this very, like,
coward
blow hard version of Donald
and and even Scrooge to a certain extent. Yeah. It was a nice contrast
with the sc from
Christmas on the mountain kind of taking Al in Donald coward And then in this one, he was just as frightened
if not coward as donald. Right. And a couple of good, like, comedic moments. Of
of fear in this one. And as you have pointed out to me before, the kids are super brave they're not bothered by anything.
They're they're the problem solve and they're are the ones who save the day. Yeah. Exactly right. And and this one even more so than many of them. Right? This is, like really the kids story in in a lot of ways. Yeah. Alright. So, I think I'm ready to dive into
the actual meat of this story. Are you ready for it, Sarah? I'm ready. Alright. Let's do it. So
The old Castle secret opens with Donald
receiving a phone call from his rich uncle sc,
asking
him to pay a visit for some
mysterious purpose. And so the Ducktales
they meet him at his mansion.
This this might be one of the last times that we'll see Scrooge having a butler. And he's not usually depicted going forward Al as
spending his money on something as frivolous as a butler. Sc reveals that the Mc fortunate is in bad shape and tells them that he needs to raise millions of dollars. Quick and we get a nice
sweet offer from the Nephews who offer him his their piggy Barks money. But Sc tells them that they've already got... He's already got access to the money he just doesn't know where it's hidden
referring to millions in ancient treasure comments on this page? I mean, these children shouldn't be giving their money to Rich uncle. He should be taxed and blah blah blah.
I I choose interpret
Al wanting to highlight their generous nature. But yes. So yeah. Yeah. Yeah. So on the next page, Scrooge
starts to tell them about
a family secret Al legacy of treasure that's been in his
family for nine hundred years.
And he tells them that the treasures in Scotland
in his family castle in the huge old castle of dismal downs.
He he indicates we get some nice
character building that he owns the castle as the last of the clan Du. So he wants to bring the
Donald and the nephews over to help him find it. And
he warns them the castle
is guarded by ghosts
of the clan, particularly the ghost old lacked Claimant mc doc who hid the treasure way back in the eleventh century.
But he tells them, you know, it's not that easy generations of Mc. Search. For it. But then he reveals with a flourish that he's got Al aes his sleeve. He's got a... What must have looked like a very fancy new x ray machine at the time that he's gonna use to look right through the walls of the castle. That part made me laugh because obviously, we have our twenty first century, even late twentieth century sen
of... Oh, my goodness, x rays are dangerous we need to protect everybody from the radiation. It should only be used in small doses,
especially children need to be kept away from it. But They didn't understand that in the time period that this came out. X rays were such a part of everyday life that they had flo
in shoe stores as a kind of marketing gimmick to take an x rate of your foot within a shoe to make sure it was fit properly and that lasted that started in about the nineteen twenties and and lasted up into the sixties.
So Sure. This rich guy has an x machine and he's going to let the children use it. Right. I know it's it's amazing to look at like when something is new technology,
all the ways that people might of try and apply it. And
i I imagine,
you know, x rays, I I saw that they've been
discovered in the late
eighteen nineties, but I'm sure it wasn't mainstream for a bit. And then when it was, as you say, they're using it for just just about everything.
But this does seem like a clever way of
kind putting this twist on why the last of the clan. Could be the one to find it. Right? Because he's got he's the one with modern technology.
Yeah. And I I looked up apparently
apparently industrial
radio
really is a thing. Right? Using x rays on buildings, but they're they're generally using it to, like, check the quality of welding.
And and things like that. Alright. So on the next page, you know, the Ducktales
are excited. They're they think that Uncle Sc just got a great plan.
The only problem
that he sees it is his concern is what happens when he does find. He's very read about ci
ghost
coming after him. The Nephews
aren't concerned he do in Louie. They're like ghosts can't hurt you. But this is where we start to see donald. The the two adults are gonna start to get nerves
and
they have to really puff themselves up. We get a cute little site gag where one of the Nephews start them from behind the door just after they've have both puff themselves up to show how brave they are. And they faint. And so the nephews used to despair over how how fearless they aren't.
And this is an interesting depiction of sc, you know, going forward or he is... He is not gonna be shown to kind of like, be open to supernatural stuff like this. I would say this is out of character for him based on, you know, when he gets really established. And so on the next page, we transitioned to the Ducktales arriving at dismal downs. It's a it's a really neat picture to me of them approaching the castle on Barks calls the Misty moore of Scotland.
What do you think really quickly Sarah of how they're depicting Scotland as as a local? So I looked up
the wikipedia entry
for
this
episode and there was a wikipedia entry just for dismal down. And so I read that.
Geographically,
downs are a
geographic feature that appear
down further south in great britain. Like, down on the like Southern coast of Apparently,
the castle is set technically situated in Ran moore, which is up in the kind of northern
part of Scotland far north, not super low the very tippy top. But very far north, which is a really baggy area. It's it's very desolate
it's very isolated.
And I do appreciate the
of this depiction of it. Okay. I did wanna talk about clans. Yeah. Go for it. There there's no actual plan Mc.
And Yes I'm sure most people.
Know. But you may be disappointed to find out the closest names I found were in the, you know, alphabetically where Mc or Mcdowell. There's also
several branches of clan mcdonald's. Right. But there's there's no
clan.
That they have that they have found evidence for. I'm sure it's out there somewhere. I mean
Sure.
Mac is the Al basically means son up. Mh.
This is the son of Ducktales.
Right. Excellent.
So when they... When the last of the clan does arrive at the castle, their the family of Ducktales are greeted by
his caretaker,
Scott, I think Scott terrier
and, you know, he's got much more of a pronounced
accents
Scrooge screwed shows in this. We see him
using a lot of, like, very old fashioned
to to my Barks, like using the word Jan, which I don't know how often gets used in in modern Scott's. I would guess not. You know, I haven't heard it. I've heard kind of quite a bit of Scott, but that is
more of an old fashioned word. What the other... Accent here Is is it a pretty good depiction? So what I've noticed is that they... When the great vowel shift occurred, Scotland just kind of ignored it Right. So
if you were to spell
scott's phonetic
in order to indicate an accent,
it would be rather difficult to read. But they did pepper in some Scott's words, you know, Huey,
instead of have
whatever what else there was a couple of other ones. Yee instead of you or... Yeah. Yeah. So that's an interesting one. In...
In Scott's, they say use. Mh. Meaning more than one use. But it's for
American readers it's not a... It's not a bad depiction of the Scott's language.
You know, there are some Scott words pepper in, but it's not... Obviously, it's not accurate.
Because and it's
it can be ins
to American.
Of course. So, yeah, not not a bad depiction I'm guessing for someone who didn't have access to, like, the wikipedia guide. Yeah. I was so impressed with some of this because he he... It's not like he could just call somebody in Scotland or, you know, facetime time with them and and look up the dictionary dictionaries Scott's language, like I was able to. Right. Excellent.
So
Scott does greet the Ducktales and,
you know, they kinda... He kinda gives them an update. The treasure is still not found.
Scott also believes in the ghost of ser
and, you know, warns them
that he bash the heads of pro that are searching for the treasure, but he wouldn't he wouldn't bash
the head of a clan mc Ducktales
and
he would only bash those that, you know, might be finding the treasure, which gives him a pretty good setup for later.
So on the next page,
the ducks are just having some conversation with Scott and wandering
through the the castle. You got some really cool panels I think here of the various suits of armor throughout the castle.
We see Donald becoming
more and more scared as they walk through talking about some of the history of the castle of the ancestors.
We get a really great site gag where they look at
large suit of armor that says that it's from twelve o five and it's sir roast Mc who died from over eating after robbing the kings pantry. It's it's kind of a silly, like fat suit of armor
that... It's kind of a taste joke, but it's It's pretty funny. It's a good side. Yeah. So I went to look up armor.
The history story of armor. And
plate armor
such as is depicted here. Was not really a thing until about the fifteen sixteen hundreds. And and so it's sir elder Mc Ducktales. That was killed by station
Saxons in nine forty six might probably have only been wearing leather. Work.
Roast up So while using the the armor as a site gag,
it's technically
not
accurate historically
So they might have been they might have been using scale mail, then definitely not plate armor at that point. Did you
consider the fact that most of these suits of armor are way too tall for ducks like Donald and sc. Did that ran across your mind at all?
Oh my goodness.
Used to blew my mind, Mark.
Well, I don't know that I would have thought of it either. But... But Don Rosa addresses this later. He has a pretty good gag in his life and times of sc Mc
where he allude to how fearsome
warriors, the the clan Ducktales.
Because they would only wear the top half of the armor and their enemies couldn't see out of the,
you know, out of the eye, the ice.
To to fight the clan Who would be able to hack them at the at the legs and stuff. Excellent. So I like that I like the Don Rosa thought about that.
But I think, you know, Bart just wanted to show a regular
suit of armor obviously.
So
the docs are talking about, you know,
they they note the fact that
you won't find ci
armor
in here because he disappeared, including his armor during the siege of ten fifty seven, and Sc mentions that the legend is that he sealed himself in the walls of the castle along with his treasure. You know what's going on in Scotland and ten fifty seven? Oh jeez. What... Is this like Had wall? No. That's like a thousand years before
Alright. What what's going on? I have
educate me Scott's history wise. Oh, out damned spot N
yes. Of course. That's Al. Next stuff was killed by Malcolm on the third in ten fifty seven. Wow. Look at that. Yeah. So oh, I'm getting goosebumps well done Carl Barks using
an actual bit of Scottish history
as
you know, he doesn't say like, oh, he probably helped. Knock on the third to kill Mc, and then he got some spoils from this. But if you know history, then you know where he got his spoils. Well, that is a fun fact. And knowing that the castle was partly
modeled after
after that is is great. Awesome. So on the next page, we see the Ducktales get around and to setting up the x ray machine. And they start to look through the walls of the castle, and it shows the passage of a couple of hours.
And then Donald brings the x machine to us to suspicious looking bulge in the walls. And when he looks through the port, he gives that classic donald whack cry and he kills over fainted.
Obviously he's found something very frightening. One of the nephews looks in and he sees the armor and bones of what must be the remains of ci.
So they figure that the treasure must be nearby and they get very excited to keep look And so on the next page,
they they look for a little bit longer until they find what appears to be a chest in the walls,
a box in the walls and when Sc looks in, he identifies it as an old Roman jewel case and gets excited that it must be the treasure so they pry the wall open, and
they do find that box. It's very heavy. Scott helps them set it on the table. And, Sarah, I like that they find the treasure really quickly in this, Right? I think that's kind of a nice change of pace. Usually, the treasure comes at the end of a story. Okay. Any any other thoughts on this? What about the fact that it's a roman jewel case? So as you as you mentioned earlier,
He wall and nine wall Those were all...
Those are part of the exploits of the Romans.
So there there there was a roman history in Scotland.
They're the ones who built Had wall and then the anton
built the Anti nine wall and then Sep sever
was like, no. That's a little bit too far. Let's go back. Basically,
they couldn't get this
tele
as they called them. Under control, so they just kind of retreated and left them alone.
There were... They did go a little bit further
into Scotland
not as far as Ran moore,
that that doesn't mean that you know, they couldn't have had somebody had access in Scotland to
Roman jewel case, etcetera, etcetera. Right. Jewel cases get around clearly. Yes.
Alright. So
when they open the when they open the the chest, they do find millions in gold and gems. They found the Mc dot hoard.
Sc identifies that there are old viking clasp in it, norman
Norman rings, coins from the midst of Realms,
He greed looks at it and says that it's worth billion. I like this touch. I liked that he mentions some of the different sources of where this wealth comes from. It's not just like an anonymous
pile of treasure like these things often or. Yeah. And it it speaks again to kind of the accuracy
of the the history,
Scotland has a long history of
viking
interaction
shall we say. Yeah. It's a nice general way of putting it.
And and so there there's quite a bit of viking and... There's quite a bit of viking influence
within Scotland
and then the Normans
mentioning the... Just across the channel of of Southern
England. In ten fifty seven, they had quite invaded England yet. But there was still quite a bit of interaction as they were only a shifts right away.
And, yeah, Romans, vikings,
Normans, that's all period accurate and Al excellent touch Yeah. We know the Romans got around.
And, you know it's interesting to me because I don't think that a lot of American readers might have
imagine they're being as much like cultural
interchange in Scotland a thousand years ago. But as you say that is pretty periodic.
So the Ducktales have found the jewels and Scott
warns them, you know, they gotta get the treasure out of there quickly before.
Finds them. So Donald who's just woken up gets assigned to
take the Barks out. And as he's running, he seems to get bash in the head by some kind of invisible force,
which Uncle Sc, you know, quickly
identifies as the ghost of ci plaque So on the next page, we get a pretty cool visual
of the box rising
and floating in the air. As though it's being carried away by a ghost. And
the nephews use, they're they're pretty brave. They're pursuing
whatever is carrying the box. And as they round the corner, they and fear. They give that classic whack as they see
the silhouette or the shadow of a skeleton, which they identify as the bones of ci plaque, So now they do believe in the ghost story, but they're not deter. They're gonna keep following it. And so Donald wakes up after being knocked out.
And he sees the ghost of ci
his shadow as well. But he has a different reaction. He runs out in terror
before checking in. He calls out from the courtyard to find out if everyone safe.
And I'm just gonna read this because it's a it's a pretty good a good exchange. He says hello in there is everybody's safe? And from behind him and a rain barrel, uncle Sc,
emerges and says, I am. I found that I have asthma too, which is something that Donald had mentioned in a blessed way that he he had.
I thought that was pretty funny there. Yeah. I wasn't expecting to see
uncle sc there,
and it it was a nice way to put the kids up on the forefront
and and kind of equal legalize
Donald and uncle sc,
especially in contrast
to the
Christmas on the Mountain
comm issue.
Right. Alright. So we get a a nice sequence of the kids chasing
the ghosts.
They have to break through a door that's been been locked. And when they get beyond it, they find Scott who seems to have been knocked out. He explains to the ghost or something hit him. And they check with him on on where the ghost might have gone,
and he says, you know, really the ghost could be anywhere. They pointed out a door that's been brick up and he explains that that goes down to the dungeons, but it was sealed up by search swamp pole back in twelve twenty and that there's no other known entrance
to the dungeons.
So they they figured that ci
must be in the main castle. Dig get. You go ahead. Do you want know what was going on in Scotland in twelve twenty? I do. Nothing.
It's it's it's
it was such a a kind of dry period that I completely
understand how
Swamp
decided that the dungeons should just be for
up. Yeah. The darkest to the dark ages, I guess. So the nephews are creeped out as they think about ci athletes go being in there. And then they hear the clan of a suit of armor and
the audience can pretty quickly identify that it's Donald, wearing the top half of a suit of armor, but they ambush him. On the next page they they learned that it is Donald, who has come in there to track them down. So I like that, you know, even though he is very terrified of the ghost, he was concerned enough with an nephews used to to armor up and and come come get them. But the Nephews are really determined. They run off and they tell donald, You know, you're gonna have to catch us to get to stop us from pursuing the treasure.
He demonstrates with Scott, who says that he he's also freaked down. He's gonna get out of there too. And, you know, I'm I'm reminded of the fact that Bravery is not the quality of never feeling fear. Right? Bravery is when you
overcome fear. So I like that. Yeah. I mean, it is a it's a good comment because
the the children exe that when they first see that ghost. Right? They're like, I'm gonna believe every ghost story from now on.
This is real ghosts are scary
let's go get it. Right. And and even Donald, who is coward
throughout this also displays Bravery right as he works to overcome it because he needs to get his nephews out.
Yeah. So. So when he's left by himself, he
he looks for a helmet. To wear. And
this is another cool visual where we see the ghost or something lifting the helmet off his head and trying to knock him out again. But Donald been very clever. He has put on a second helmet,
but not clever enough not to not to kind of mock the ghosts.
Because the ghost
kicks him right out the window and he lands back in the courtyard where sc is still hiding. I liked those that succession of panels
because you have the the joke of.
I was wearing two helmet
and then
the ghosts and and then you're like, okay. Good job. Donald, but then the goes one up upstairs. And you can see the footprint
straight Donald be behind. That's right. He gets kicked out the window. Yeah. It is a nice sight bag. Alright. So on the next page, we flash back to the Nephews who are still searching.
And they they seem to come to a hall where there are a lot of suits of armor and they're
looking
sequentially in each suit of armor. And when they get to the last one in the row,
the one of the nephews is
shocked to see that there's a skeleton
in that one. And it's a pretty big contrast right because when Donald saw skeleton he he fainted a dead away. But this nephew keeps his senses and
just tells them, you know, there's a skeleton in there. And so they're they're wondering why is this
why is this Mc du still in a suit armor? Why need buried like the rest of them? And so they look at the p or whatever where it says the and they find that it sir swamp whole, Mc.
And they
reflect on the fact. Scott had mentioned and that he's the one who sealed up. The dungeons. So this is,
you know, a big part of the mystery of the story, and it's some... I think some cool table setting. I like that they have found some helmets as well and that they're all slightly different from each other.
Yeah. Yeah. It's a good look. It's it makes for an interesting look to the story and it shows the that's being resourceful. So
the he doing Louie are pondering, you know, the mystery of the castle
and they're still looking around they hear a sound that they
expect to be ci.
They they think that they've got him cornered, but they find that he must have slipped through
door. So they get ready to jump in and ambush him on the other side of the door and when they quickly dive through the door, they find that it's not another room, but it's actually a castle battle.
So this is like a a really classic dead end And as soon as they're out the door, it slams closed and that you hear the lock click and they find that they've been tricked and they've been trapped out side on this battle. It's too far for them to jump because the shallow mode is a hundred feet down. So they're their stuck pretty good. And we flashback back to their uncles where sc is and treating Donald to go back and look. But Donald like, hey, It's your turn. I've been in there plenty and Donald like,
sir clap is not gonna hurt you you're the last of his skin folk. Even though I guess, technically Donald related, but I think he's not, you know, in in line the way Scrooge.
And Sarah, I really like the...
A lot of the story is gonna take place on this battle
specifically.
And it's an interesting
spot for me. I really feel when the ducks get trapped out there. It feels like it feels like good peril to me. It does it feels like a good dead end. Definitely there's peril from being trapped from from falling from a height and an inability to go back in and and site, which is what they wanna do.
Right. And and this
battle
specifically is gonna get used as a setting and some of those
life in times of sp mc redux stories that Don rose that does later. So that's probably part of why it stands out in my mind. So on the next page, we see sc nervous looking around himself
and he ultimately is gonna end up trapped out on the battle along with the kids. Right? They
they end up ambush him, but he's been tricked the same way.
So
that leaves all of the Ducktales except for donald
stuck in this position, this predicament.
Sc
despair, Donald not brave enough to come and help them. Scott is their only hope. And Donald, we flashback Barks to Donald who's pacing around and figures that, you know, enough time has past that something must have happened to sc,
which means that it's up to Donald.
And again, you know, I like the resolve that he shows here. He's he's afraid, but he has to go in and he knows that any does.
So he grabs a line of rope planning to drag the kids out if he has to, he helmets up again, and he
looks around. I did...
I just looked at my notes, and I was wrong about the... When late armor came in it came in in the fourteenth century.
Okay. So still still the timeline is is off. Yeah. Cool. I can probably move that around if you care, but we've corrected the record here.
Yeah i even remember what I said so I can't repeat it. Yeah. No worries.
So Donald is exploring. He's trying to figure out where they are. And he comes across Scott living quarters.
You know, he it's identifiable as Scott room because of the solitary picture
of Scott himself that
that he's got.
He doesn't see the man in there. And then when he turns, he is terrified
to see
Scott in the classic dead corpse posture.
On his bed. Covered all the way up by the sheets. Yep. And you know? If I were if I were in a creepy castle like that, don't think I would be in the right frame of mind to think about the logical fallacy of how could he have covered himself when he died. Right? I'm very sympathetic to donald there. Well, I mean, I I didn't give it as Second thought either until just now, but,
you know, that could have been just a very kind ghost
to kill
Scott and then cover him, you know, that right one of the tropes in in movies and Tv shows is that if if the body is covered, usually the murder was done by somebody who cared about them. That's right. That's baby very response
maybe with Scott being there so long, the ghost grew a little bit affectionate, but then, you know, realized he had to do what he had to do when he went after the jewels
so it it just... It just blocks over me. Yeah.
Swear up. So Donald runs of course in terror. And, you know, I I'm I'm looking closer at these two panels at the bottom. I I really like these two panels of him fleeing, especially the one on the right of him zag around some of the support pillars in the castle.
Because Donald is just terrified. He knows that he's gotta get the kids quickly because they're in grave danger. So on the next page, he is following some ghostly
footsteps
and he resolves to get a rope around around the ghost. He follows him through that same door onto the battle and he gets kicked out outside and locked locked out with the rest of the apps in the same manner. And so they're reunited and one of the Nephews explains that they're waiting for for Scott to come and rescue them and this is a pretty great Al well where Donald is kind of lying down resigned, and he says you're waiting for Scott.
This is a fine state of affairs. I like that a lot.
So we see we see the passage of time, you know, the docs are kind of figuring out what what are their options?
And one of the Nephews takes another look over the battle. And he realizes that there is a part of the mode that seems to be a little bit deeper.
So using the rope that Donald has brought up, they can get about, you know, part way down. And if they figure if they swing down that the nephew you may be able to survive the drop if he can get in just the right place. So this is a really nice tense moment.
This is another example, two where Barks draws a random bird in the foreground.
Which I really like as the nephews swings. You start a bird and he manages to land in the moat deep enough. He start a frog and he so he's made it safely and you know, it does seem like a lot of trouble to go to and then call for the other nephews to be drops down. But or does really tend to like to keep the nephews used together. Any thoughts Numbers. Yeah.
So this is the part of the comic where we really transition to it being kind of the kids show. Right? We've been focused on them before, but now we know that their
uncles are really trapped. And so they've got... They've got Al look around they're locked out of the hassle at this point, and they need to figure out another way to get in.
They they surmise that these castles always had secret entrances
which I imagine is probably true, sarah. A lot of them probably had ways to get in in in the event of a siege or or something like that. They're there were tunnels generally kind of
that went through sellers.
There were secret water tunnels so that if the castle were under siege, they could still get to a water source.
All kinds of stuff like that. Alright. So back to the tunnel, they figured that they need to be looking for a grove of trees for the end of the tunnel, but there there aren't any trees for miles so they
explore. And the only thing of note that they find
in the perimeter of the castle is the old Mc burial rounds. So they start to look through the graves. And they find graves for sur
Docs or stuff to.
And then one of the nephews
stumbles on something interesting, the grave for ser swamp pole mc.
And, you know, the other nephews don't catch on immediately it's so interesting to find sir swamp pulls marker.
But
this one points out, you know, the fact that that guy was never buried. Right? They found his body in the suit of armor. So they're puzzling over
why he would have a grave and
that nephew points out that ser swamp pull is the guy who had sealed off the dungeons. So there must be a connection to that and they surmise that, you know, this grave must be the location of the end of the tunnel. And after playing with the grave a little bit, they're able to get it to open up the slab of the grave opens up like the door
with steps leading down into an underground tunnel. So this is probably one of my favorite aspects of the story. Right? This seems like like, often when a story is built around there being a mystery, it's it's kind of... There's not really a neat little logical
thing to figure out in a kid's comment like this. But I I would really like this how, you know, you have to figure out well, we found this guy's body. Why does he also have a grave, this must mean something? I just think I just think that was really cool. Yeah. It was kind of Al una expected. The this whole story had some little inter woven
mysteries
within mysteries. Right? To the point where I even went back and looked at some panels to see if I had missed clues. And
yeah. It was really neat. These little mysteries is woven and Yeah. Alright. So the nephews
to descend into this tunnel and while they're going down, we got a nice line here. One of the nephew says ballots it's damp here in full of spiders and the other asks, what did you expect air conditioning?
That? It's called Air con here.
And almost nobody has it. Oh you and I are from the land of air conditioning, so that's gotta be tough. Oh, it makes the... like seventy two
degree f
ninety percent humidity days
miserable.
Yeah. Al bet. So while the nephews are going down the tunnel, we flash back to Donald and sc and they're pondering how hard it's gonna be for the nephews to get back in because they don't have a key. And we got a good gag here that
kinda just needs to be red to be appreciated.
Sc says, you know, how stupid of them? I could have learned them this gun and they could have shot the lock and he pulls out a revolver.
And Donald Chi him, he says you Scrooge all that gun will unlock this door and
sc
tells him, know, you're right. I'll i'll unlock it, but there's something I want you to do first nephew. Wind up both feet and give me a good swift kick. You know, I I thought that was a fun little moment of absent minded. It's totally out of character
going forward for sc Mc, you know, Barks really depict them like this for the most part in the future,
except in the story where he famously has some memory loss. But but I I thought it was very funny. I thought it was one of the funniest parts of the story. And so we transitioned back to the Nephews
who have approached a part of the tunnel where they have to do the torch because they've... It's lit ahead.
And they sure enough they have come into the dungeons
which seem to be empty. There's a very creepy panel where there's a a terrifying looking wrap watching them so that this has some really good to me creepy
atmosphere. And so they look around until they spy the jewel box.
So they... They're very excited. They dive at the jewel box. And this is a this is a terrifying panel for a kids comic. You know, they they see the silhouette or the shadow
of the ghost,
the skeleton ghost, rear back with a sword ready to strike. And then Yeah. Yeah. And then in the next panel, the the sword is floating in mid air. Yeah. It's a it's a very cool effect. Right? We see both the shadow of the skeleton and and the sword and then the sword like you say floating by itself. And
they're being pursued So they they have to hope that they can get out of the
walled up entrance.
They've they've found the secret entrance
it's in the pillar behind sir swamp pull.
They're running away from
what seems to be the ghost, which is just slashing at the air, and then we transition to their uncles who hear them in trouble.
The nephews round the corner crash right into Donald. And the ghost ends up pursuing them and, you know, tram Donald. And when sc sees
that the ghost is in pursuit. He fires his revolver
at the ghost
and we see the skeleton
kind of
flinch in a way that, you know, a ghost shouldn't really be afraid of bullets.
And Donald is celebrating that he doesn't like the bullets.
So the ghost
runs back right over him. Donald says a line that kinda puzzles me here. Sarah. He says blow your horn you invisible juggernaut or not.
I I figured that that must be a reference to something or Al align, you know, a quote
maybe a song lyric or something, but I couldn't find anything
about that. So I don't know. Maybe maybe a listener will have an idea. Yeah I don't suppose you recognize that. I just just assumed it was a a nineteen
forties
comics
for f u a whole.
Right. So, the nephews
pursue him to see where he goes, but he slams himself shut down down towards the dungeons.
And they can't figure out the catch for that secret door. So Donald decides he's gonna see if there's a crow bar in Scott room. And when he gets to Scott room, he finds that Scott has vanished.
He suppose that the ghost must have taken him away because you know, he was... He was his corpse was just there. And he gets off a good line. He says he was colder than a macro and then the nephew, one of the nephew says, speaking of macro, don't you smell something fishy about this disappearance
and the other nephew says that it reap of red herring
Did you also like this? That was just delightful fall well done. Well done, sir.
Yeah. That's a that's a great sequence of lines.
A red herring, of course being something that's meant to distract to you in in a story.
Mister direct you? Yes. Yes. Exactly. And so the nephews look around the room to investigate and they find what one of the nephews
thinks
might be fly spray. When they spray it at the curtain, we see that it has some kind of weird looking effect on the curtain. I don't know about you to me. It's not immediately obvious that it's supposed to look transparent.
But we can tell that something weird is going on with that spray. So the nephews user saying they know how the ghosts are made. They obviously can tell that you know, this is a trade a spray that makes things transparent.
So they go back to figure out how to pursue the ghost and they do figure out how to
release the latch behind ce swamp Armor.
They run down the tunnel where they can feel blowing and that indicates that, you know, he must be too far away. And so the ducks
pursue the ghost until they're out onto the moo.
They emerge from the tunnel and the grave and they look around. Donald is able to see the box being carried by the ghost.
Out there going over a ridge. So the Nephews
encourage everyone to corner him and force him to go through a mud hole. And so you you can see, this is some cool art that shows the invisible ghost or whatever the entity is.
Going through this muddy
pond or whatever.
While they're passing through the nephews speculating, you know what it truly is, And when he emerges Donald says, it's a mud man with no head. Because you can see a lot of mud covering a body.
So one of the nephews use tackle this thing, bringing it down and sc holds it at Bay with the gun. And the Nephews
say, you know, just wait a moment. We'll see who it is.
And
we we do see that this is Scott becoming gradually visible.
So sc says, sky, my old faithful servant. You tried to steal my treasure And this is where we learned that we have not been... We haven't even met Scott at all. This character reveals that he is actually diamond dipped, the jewel thief. He explains that Scott had died months ago and that Diamond Dick has been handing to be him so that he could get a chance
at the horde.
He further explains that he knew about the treasure because his third wife was like a distant Mc Ducktales On her a great Grandfather side. And you know, this is the time where we get all the explanations. Right? He explains
that he's been making himself invisible using a chemical
spray that he stole from a foreign spy during the war. And this whole time Donald been blessed about, you know, oh i I knew your Scotch accent was phony. I knew that it was a chemical
on
The
the preferred term is
scottish.
Yeah. For scott.
Scratch is a drink.
Yes. I figured that was the case. I want... Not even called Scotch here. It's just whiskey. It's just whiskey. Yeah. I figured.
Alright. So,
you know, this this page really is all about the explanation and it's all about Mcdonald's blu.
You know, the the ducks have him explain, oh, he had pretended to be knocked out pretended to be dead he was just trying to throw them off the trail.
He he allude to just making one
mistake. Right? He thought that he had enough time to escape when he locked him out on the battle, but, you know, he says that he should known that the kids would free themselves. In a hurry. And to me, the sub there is that he regrets not killing them, but I suspect that Barks
didn't want to be explicit about that, you know? Yeah. Yeah. And then and then we get this nice moment where they not how clever the Nephews used were. Right? Then one of the nephew says, you know, that wouldn't have helped
referring to, you know, locking them out further or doing something. It wouldn't have helped if they hadn't found the way into the secret tunnel and Diamond Dick says, yes.
It took me six months to find that mo hole and new kids found it in six minutes. And Donald further blu that, you know, he wasn't around. That's why it took them so long.
And
and the little cap of the story is that the the Nephews
send up their uncle Donald.
By offering him some of the fly spray and and in his very blessed array mode. He doesn't realize that it's the chemical formula.
And they closed by saying why i'm donald. We thought you knew all the time it wasn't fly spray. And that's a pretty funny image of just his lower half walking along saying. Oh shut up. That is invisible.
Leaving his
Barks button legs. I love how it's his
cloth half that goes invisible leaving only his Barks button legs visible.
There is a lot of a lot of people joke about how, you know, winnie the poo doesn't wear pants, Donald duck doesn't wear pants. And there's
donald ducks bear, but... That's true. I haven't even
like, picked up on that. You know, it's just a funny image, but it is funny when you think of it's it's the part of his body that everyone jokes about. So... Yeah. So, yeah. This is a nice a nice goofy ending to
what again was a pretty creepy story. I I did wanna make a comment on the fly spray.
Up in the highlands
there are these little flying biting insects called mid images. Mh.
And they
swarm, like you wouldn't not believe.
I mean, it's totally plausible that maybe not a fly straight, but
some
helen So so tell me, Sarah,
before I talk about the critical consensus, you know, I I was very eager to have you come back for this one specifically because you do live in Scotland, but also because this is a very well regarded one and the one that we read previous to this, you know, we didn't really care for it. So
would you say Barks has redeemed himself in your eyes? Or
what did you think? You know I would I would have never
imagined that he would write something
like Volcano Valley if I had only read this one because this is a great depiction
of a culture. It's it's not
stereo
as much as even even the guy who is impersonating a scott is, you know, not overdo doing it or exhibiting the, like, negative traits or or
It's not like car.
It's not. And it's it it seems rather respectful to me. And I I did quite enjoy it. Had...
What what level of development were, like cartoons at that point. So at this point, you know, the
the mickey and Donald cartoons
have been huge that they were hugely popular. The ones in the early forties, you know, Barks have actually gotten his start working on it. The donald duck cartoons. That's how he got to do this. So I I think that Donald Duck has recently
at this point,
surpassed Mickey mouse. In terms of, like popularity,
global popularity.
He is probably the most popular cartoon character in the world at this point. And so these these comics are becoming
very big on the tail of those. It felt
not cinematic and that it was, like, grand and ethically scaled, but in that if I were to imagine this as an episode of a Duck Al part june. It wasn't the stretch that it would have been with volcano Valley. And I think it's because I've seen enough dovetail hills and I've seen enough scooby doo that I could piece together, you know, between the panels,
what action was going on. But it it slowed
very well. The story was engaging.
It was creepy and kind of a way that I enjoyed even though,
obviously,
I'm Al skeptic by nature.
I I did think
a
a spray that makes you invisible except your skeleton
shadow,
that sounds dubious
and that's taking me out of the moment, but I could still at least shell that in a way that I couldn't show a lot of my
disbelief Al
what was going on in Volcano Valley because it was it wasn't just absurd. It was bad
Right. Yeah. As far as Mac go, you know, it's definitely like, it's a bit of a stretch as I I think that it was one of my criticisms of the story was that I felt like I wanted a better explanation for why he looked like a ghost. Right? But there really wasn't. You know, there was no way around it. So as far as making up a reason and having it just be attributed to, like espionage
and research during the war, which of course would have been, you know, World war two is very very fresh at this point.
Right. I I think
think there were a lot of stories that used the war as like one of their justification. So...
Even then Fa volcano Valley, they got a surplus playing from the war. Yeah. Isn't it crazy? How much of a culture
couldn't get away from the aftermath the world war two at this point. Right? Like, it's over, but but it casts such a long shadow. Absolutely.
Under understandably.
Yeah. Yeah. For sure. I'm glad to hear you enjoyed this one. I I agree I think there's some, you know, really nice
development that the story is very well plotted and the mystery is for a comic, it's very well developed. You know, I when I first read this one, I kind of read it under
circumstances that weren't ideal
because I had missed this one for a long time and I had read most of mark's other stories
I knew that this is one of the few remaining stories that I hadn't gotten to read yet because I was trying to seek them all out. It was probably in the last
last ten or so of the adventure ones. And and so I was initially a little disappointed because I didn't really care for this, like Pro version of sc.
And I I had trouble getting past that for a long time. And it's only been as I've gone back to this one to read it more without that kind of baggage that I've been able to appreciate more, you know, how creepy it is, how
tightly plotted. It is in many ways.
How what a good job it does of integrating some of these like, it's this neat little tour of a pretty cool version of Scotland. I'm sure there are lots of inaccuracies.
But as far as Barks was you know, as far as he knew, writing from thousands of miles away using National Geographic Al a reference. I think this is a pretty neat representation. So this one I've really grown to appreciate it a lot more over the years. And we always like to look at the general consensus as well.
This one is
extremely well regarded. Now if you look on the Index website that crowds sources
ratings, this one has an average
rating of eight point four out of ten, which is good for a thirteenth
out of every Disney comic story, almost forty one thousand of them. So that places us in the very, very high, like, you know, ninety nine point nine nine per percentile of of all stories or point zero zero one, I guess percentile. I do have to say to me, this one is not that great. Like it is a classic, but I wouldn't put it in that verified air. I think that it gets a little bit of kind of inflation
from the community just because it is kind of the real origin of sc, you know, and it sets up all of this... All of these aspects of what we come to know and love about Scrooge doc.
I do think that there is a lot to really appreciate. But I I have to imagine if this if it didn't have that kind of historical position amongst Barks stories wouldn't be rated that highly. Well, out of the two that I have read, it is number one.
Excellent.
Yeah. I... This would probably be
the third or fourth favorite of mine out of the ones that I've done for this series. So that this is a very strong one. My my one criticism
is that there's some some kind of abrupt, you know, explanation. Oh, it was diamond dick all along. Oh, it was this invisible spray. It's almost like, he he couldn't quite stick the landing for me on
some of the resolution aspect, but there's just so many cool visuals and so much cool plotting along the way that i'll forgive some of that stuff. And you know I I'm just always a fan of anything set in scotland. I love castles.
I love creepy things, You know, the fact that there are no trees in that area is accurate. It's it it really feels
like Britain. And and it... And then. If
reflects back a lot of the things I love about Scotland. That's awesome. I'm I'm glad to hear that. A few more reflections on this one and some of the other appearances
I like to talk about what what seems dated or archaic.
You know, we did talk about, like some of that post worst stuff. Obviously, that's its own position and has history.
Also that x ray machine, I pointed out that that must have looked very modern at the time, but now it looks like an antique. But I I think really actually holds up very well. You know, like you were saying, this one is not a carrot shirt. There's not really a lot that's problematic
about this.
You know, uncle Scrooge wield have gun
for part of the story and that's something that gets depicted a lot less
in in modern stories, Disney is certainly shi away from that. But but in general,
I think this actually holds up very well. And yeah. I have obviously, I have mixed feelings about guns as as
American
living abroad in the twenty first century. The gun used in this story
is it doesn't seem glorified
or
it's just... It's just another tool that Huey, using rather than high
I have the the right that that makes that's stuff American. Well, you know, he's got... I I would agree with you, you know, I I feel I have similar feelings regarding guns to, but this feels like this feels like one of those natural times where someone might have might have brought a gun to an abandoned you know, desolate
castle. So... And I agree it's it's kind of a... It's a tool. It's not glorified here. It doesn't seem. It is a little bit striking to me to see guns depicted in the Disney comics, but it is from an era where they were. They were used in a way that never really struck me as glorified. Right. And so
appearances and other media, you know, this is one where this is a segment where I don't usually get to say too much, but
honestly, you could you could fill a podcast
episode talking about appearances
in other media because marx
has done. He's gone back to this story for three very different oil painting.
All of which are very, very cool. One of them is called the old castle rooms Al the same title as story. And one of them has just the best title. It's called dubious doing at dismal
downs.
And
why don't you take... If if you can take a moment to look that up. It's a... I I like that oil painting a lot. It's one of my favorites that he's done. And then this, like I already alluded, Don Rose used a lot of the characters,
the historical characters that were mentioned this one
in his future stories to develop kind of that biography that he did have unscrew the twelve part biography called the life in times of sc Mc.
He had some pretty key story moments set in different parts of this castle. So he references
story a lot. Huey, did a chapter,
a story that was called the old Castle other secret that, you know, is kind of a direct sequel a referencing this one. Oh nice. Yeah. That's a it's a pretty cool what we'll, of course have the different oil paintings shown on the on the Facebook page. Did you get to see that one dubious doing decimal downs? I do. I see it right now. Oh, and there's some heather down in the corner. The heather is kind of a the signature plant of ran moore. Heather is this
shrub
brown plant that just Al. It... It's far as you can see. Very. No. No trees up in Rad more. And then in the late summer, it blooms
purple.
That's a great painting.
Oh, yeah. Barks did some really cool paintings.
I... This is just something that fans, you know, know of, but
Volcano Valley didn't have one associated with it. Barks had like a second career where he went back and did these oil paintings.
That became, you know, hugely well regarded valuable
collector's items. Very well liked. I mean, it was he's almost as famous
for his oils.
And lit the graphs of them as he is for these stories. It's it's it's so vibrant
and
and detailed
color wise, it's kind of it's such a contrast to the simple almost primary colors in the comics.
Yeah. Agreed. Oh,
Ducktales has definitely referenced
some of this, like as source material. I don't think they ever did Al episodes. Specifically on this one, but, you know, I think both runs of the show have have alluded to this comic And then as far as the educational
value
you know, you you've given us some awesome
specifics regarding some of the, you know true dates and some of the cultures. So I definitely think there's some educational value and kind of an idea of that, like inner interchange between Scotland and other cultures and just some of what what North Scotland
looks like or feels like this is this is where I learned what the word battle
meant.
So that's that's not quite a battle. That it's more like an oreo balcony.
The battle are generally on the roof. You generally... If you're going to go, you know, protect yourself from lower down, you just have these little slit You don't have a whole balcony.
Let's I think are called murder holes. But the the ones on top are correlations and then the ones in the side murder. Ventilation are the the little up and down things. Well, that's fair. But...
But yeah. It's least soon use of the term? Yeah. Yeah. That's a word that you learned.
Exactly.
As far as favorite panel, you know, you and I have been talking about we've we've highlighted a few panels in here already. So, you know, some of those like that depict the skeleton
and and the castle itself look really cool. But on on this
go through, I really liked the
the panel that shows the Ducktales kind of hurting
what they think ci
ghost
to be through the through the bog and seeing that chest floating above the bot. I thought that one was pretty cool. Do you like the scare ones? Mh. I liked the ones where the kids were creeping through the the dungeons. They they sell very, you know, enclosed. You you you see the little rat that they don't see. The lighting was great. It felt properly spooky. And then
another one that stood out for me was one that I pointed out where the skeleton is chasing them with the the sword in mid air. If I were a
younger
child, I think that would have really
scared me because
one skeleton scary. You know, like, there's just... We just have this primal fear of skeletons. Right And then the fact that it's facing you and you can see it, but you also
can't see it and it can wield weapons.
That is
truly threatening.
Yeah. I agree. I just... I left that. Yeah. I think you're right on. Some of those scary panels are very striking. They really they can really stay with you. Those are cool. I I also like the story of dawn the panel of Donald kind of running towards the quote camera.
When he's got his like, rope in a la. It's just a really cool pose.
That one I noted this time. So that's a neat one. Let's see. I'm trying to think if there is anything else that I really wanted to mention. Is there anything
in your notes there that you really wanted to make sure to highlight before we wrap things up. It looks like I did already.
Excellent so much. Well, I will note really quickly that this out of the episodes that we've done on the podcast so far on index, this one is the second highest rated by the community.
Only Al venture down under
rated higher. But this one is very strong. This is a this is a classic, and I think it definitely deserves to be remembered. Sarah, I really appreciate you joining us again.
Hope to have you back for another. I'll have to figure out another one that
we could have some fun with this point. They're so easy for me to read that as long as it's, you know, not gonna make me hate to love it or love to hate it. I'm down for anything.
That's great to hear. Good.
Well, I hope that
everyone enjoyed the episode. And as always, if you do have a comment, you know, you can reach us on the Facebook page.
Email is burke Barks at g dot com. I hope to have people back for Al really another really long story. Next time. And and one that is very memorable to me next episode is gonna be the sheriff of bullet Al. So hope see you then.