Hello, and welcome to Barks remark. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks, creator of sc Mc and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comics of all time. Join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological publishing or We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Welcome back to Barks remarks. I'm Mark Sever, a devoted Ducktales comics span. I am here with the returning guest.
And
please introduce yourself returning guests.
Hi. My name is Sara Santiago.
So once Sarah, thank you for
coming back after a pretty epic
adventure story and the old Castle secret. We have
a a story that is a little bit less epic
today, I think. Right. But we should have some fun talking about it.
Yeah. Thanks for having me back. Yeah. Absolutely.
We are gonna be talking today about the Golden Christmas tree, a pretty unusual
Barks adventure story.
You know, I think you mentioned to me that you
have a little bit of experience with Christmas tree sales.
Right?
I do. I am your resident Christmas three
sale
apparently.
So you you said you worked on Christmas tree lot for a while?
I did for a couple of seasons. I think at least
two, maybe three.
In high school, I worked at a Christmas tree lot in
Tempe, Arizona,
selling Christmas trees.
And that it was kind of one of my favorite jobs. I I actually miss it. That's awesome. Yeah. I I never expected that you would have any kind of personal connection to this one when I ask you to do it. But
Well, I'm sure I'd get a little bit of good conversation in
about
Christmas trees of many colors.
But
But especially gold because again, we're talking about Golden Christmas tree.
And this story was published in october of nineteen
forty eight
in four color number two hundred and three.
Looking at how many times it's been reprinted,
including the original. There are seven different publications, a pretty average number of them. And this is one of our shorter
adventure length stories. This one
clocks in it only a scant twenty pages.
And
basically,
this one involves Donald And an Nephews facing off
against a Christmas tree hating witch
who may or may not be the witch from Snow items and seventh warp.
In an epic example of stunt casting,
Yeah. They've
they've
commissioned this little tiny comic just for her.
Right. I don't know if this one... So screamed editorial
interference to you,
but that is definitely the case.
This. Really.
Yeah. This is one where
Barks
indicated that he had an editor
suggestion. I think he even received a script. For this one when he was... Oh yeah. And so if if it doesn't seem, you know, you've only read a few of these this points so you may not have enough experience to be able to say that there are parts of it that don't seem very
Barks.
But
I think to a lot of readers, it might not feel very Barks
apart from the fact that it's a little bit jarring that the the wicked witch. Appears in this one. It did feel different to me. Not just the the... you know, this
what I kept calling casting.
But it it seemed like the boys were in parallel and Donald had to save them, which is
the opposite of
every other example that I've seen so far. Yeah. That's right. It's it's very out of character.
For the boys. You know, I I read a few a bit of commentary on this and a lot of people point out that Barks has to kind of make the nephews much more juvenile
in this one because the way they're usually characterized, they wouldn't really fall into this kind of track and they wouldn't really act this way. That was another question I had. Was the... It... It... So it starts off with them fighting over what color Christmas Tree they want. And I haven't seen them fight in
handful of comics that I've read with you. Is that something that they do often?
I would say it's a little bit out of character.
I think that you see that kind of characterization much more in the short gag comics, you know, the ten pager that I've
alluded to a few times.
But but really, Barks is just gonna do what he wants to do with these characters.
Sometimes if he needs them to act more juvenile,
they will. But but, yeah, it it is a little bit out of character.
They will sq
in in many of the stories.
I like that fight, you know, in the beginning. It's it's a little bit off putting, but I think if you have brothers Al
it probably seems familiar to
a lot of listeners.
But, yeah, we're we're we already have a lot to say here. So let me let me just go into a little bit. More background Trivia will launch into that story.
I I mentioned that, you know, he is known to have been... He he had a little bit of sour attitude about having to do this one because it was a little bit fo on Barks,
I don't know explicitly if they told him oh you need to use the wicked witch from snow white.
But
that is not something that he regularly
does. You know, he doesn't
pluck characters
from other Disney properties
very often.
It's it's very unusual. Like, there's one story where it uses more and fe who are Mickey Nephews.
There's one single mickey mouse comic that he did that was not a Ducktales, but there was no, like, crossover
between the ducks and Mickey.
That was that was very unusual
to have him do that.
He also commented in a letter that he wrote to a fan that he had to make a lot of changes to this one to suit the editor needs and that they even wrote rewrote some of his dialogue
near the end of the story, they made it. What he considered very preach and very sap
because this one does have a very, like, moral
sac Gladstone that's kind of out of character for for Barks himself. So we can we can take a look at those panels where we get there. I did wanna to mention a few of the titles from around the world. I've been having fun doing these.
So I'll just share
three or four of these. So in in
most of the languages, this has been just translated directly it's generally just called the Golden Christmas tree. So in France, it was
and noel
in Germany, was their golden
bomb,
In Mexico is.
I don't usually
see a listing for Mongolia.
For whatever reason, this one was published in Mongolia. So I have to say it's called A
Got sewer.
Golden Christmas tree and Mongolia.
Nice.
Yeah. Oh and then it was published in yu yugoslavia.
The dearly departed
Yugoslavia.
And I think I think the language would be Serbian
and it was called z
Nova.
So there are some of your versions of the Golden Christmas tree from around the world, the value range. You know, we've been talking about I've been mentioning the value of these comics, it's
decreasing
steadily as we get further out of the golden age of comics. So at some point I'll probably stop. But this is still fairly valuable and a nine point two edition
is two thousand two hundred and fifty dollars.
Well. And
Sarah, did you
have any kind of historical
our cultural context that you wanted to talk about
outside of, you know, the story itself before we get into it.
So I'll just mention that,
you know, the Christmas tree tradition
is
I think it goes back to something like the sixteenth
century
and is generally agreed to started in Germany.
And
I will mention
to give some context to the wicked witch appearing that snow white.
Was just a colossal hit for for Disney. Right? It kinda rescued the studio.
And at at this point,
it's only eleven years old, and they had
their first re release ever of the film, which would have been a big event, you know, in another itself was just four years before this story was published
in nineteen forty four.
And so the wicked could witch is gonna actually show up in a lot of other Disney media. Gonna karen a lot of other Disney comics,
not Carl Barks comics that I'm aware of, but you know, she kind of pops up and, like, burr rabbit tails
and little bad wolf from some of the other like big cast of characters from walt Disney's comics and stories.
And and I did find that Barks
himself actually submitted some gag
for the production of snow white,
hoping that he could work on it, but he didn't ultimately get to work on that one.
Let's see what? What do you think is our version of Donald? How do you think we should characterize him in this? Because as you mentioned,
the Nephews are a much more, like juvenile version of themselves.
Yeah. He seemed
put together and determined
Right.
And and and,
you know, not kind of his disorganized self. Yeah. He's pretty level heading this one. And and I mean, he's usually very determined, but it's usually like a much more
branch. Hot headed determination. Exactly.
Alright. So I I'm ready to get into it. I look forward to your comments.
Ready to talk about the Golden Christmas tree? Red axles.
So it opens with the net fuse having kind of a violent brother's arguments
while Donald is reading the newspaper
They are coming to blows over what color a Christmas tree they'd like to get.
And meanwhile Donald is reading in the news
about a witch that's been spotted in the area and is
destroying Christmas tree. She is explicitly
identified as resembling the one that poisoned snow white, which kind of points to some
interesting universe
implications for the story.
Donald dismiss the story is laughable.
And the nephews gradually stop arguing and tell donald, but they have agreed on which color of tree they'd like to get. So we had talked about previously
in our messaging about this that it seemed odd.
That there were all of these
choices of colors that they wanted a blue one that they wanted a a a purple one. And and they you know, and
none of them were either even consistent on the one that they wanted. So it just cycled through several colors
basically the entire rainbow, and and Donald says, oh, does it need to be painted Al like a rainbow.
And
that was kind of confusing for both of us, because we've never heard of
colored
christmas trees.
Right. And and this guy comes up as you researched the story that lot of people kind of bog at the fact that it's kind of presented as just in every day. Oh, this is one of the choices you make when you go to the Christmas tree lot. Did did your lot have any color choices, Sarah?
No. We had
christmas tree color.
I have heard of
some
lots that will...
What's called flock, the Christmas tree, which is, like spray, kind of a a white ish foam on it to make it look like there's snow on it. And they'll do that for you at the lot. You know, that if that's a thing that you you choose or, you know, if you get a fake tree that it'll come that way.
So it it was at least interesting that that was a thing... A decision you made at the lot and then you picked out a tree and and in the comic you they seemed to just... Oh, okay. We'll we'll paint it purple now. Right. But
Christmas trees only came in and they're not cheryl green color.
Try. Vanilla
as it what?
Vanilla color.
Yeah. I I always... Even as a kid, I thought this was weird,
the way it presented it, because you know, as a kid you you do think about Christmas trees a lot. And I remember being super excited every year.
And from what I can tell, I think there have been times where you could buy Christmas trees of different colors, but I don't think in my race research, at least. It doesn't look like there was ever an era in America
where it was like routine. You know, I think it's a special order thing or you paint it yourself
I know that famously,
our former first lady in the states decorated with red Christmas trees a couple years.
In which which many people found very off putting. But
that's the only time I've ever seen a reference to another color besides this. And it would be with the way that natural things are shaped, especially
fur and pine trees. It seems like it would be difficult to get it
completely
to the color.
Yeah. Yeah. I I don't imagine it coming out very nice unless you, like, totally dip and something that's
gotta be
not very good for your health.
So I guess, you know, this is really of those situations where this is meant to be about a golden Christmas tree and so this universe has got it needs to have this as an option. And so it does. And, you know, to its credit
by by a few pages in, I'm... I'm I'm into it and i'm buying it. Yeah. It it was funny that I was...
I could suspend my disbelief for a golden Christmas tree mh but not for a purple one.
Right. Right. Yeah.
Alright. So
when they come to Donald, they inform him that as you said, they would like a golden Christmas tree and Donald kind of branches and he counts as his pocket change, hoping that it's not gonna be too expensive.
And on their way, they're passing stores
with the the kind of the old trope. I love seeing this old trope. Right? You you need to hear some news so you walk by the store that sells Tv
or radios and they're broadcasting,
some setup. And
in this case, it's broadcasting stories of the witch terror the town.
And Donald kind of sm
you know, dismissing the possibility.
And when the Nephew asked about it, he stops that this is just a racket to get people to buy more christmas trees.
And so they they get to the tree lot and sure enough they encounter trees in all colors and Donald
immediately gets a bad case of sticker shock.
So from my experience in the late nineties working at a Christmas very lot. I would actually say those are pretty accurate prices, you know, the the blue ones are fifteen forty eight red ones are twenty ninety eight. And then they have old rows, which I thought was really funny given how popular
rose gold is.
Right now. And and then strawberry pink. Those are twenty six fifty.
And those seems like totally normal Christmas tree prices for what I'm used to, obviously, in the late nineties,
you know, our our bottom of the line
I think it was either Douglas for Western ba where we started about sixteen, if you got one that was like four to five feet,
And then I looked up the
inflation calculator
and those
fifteen ninety eight or fifteen
those fifteen forty eight ones would be about today's equivalent of a hundred and sixty
two dollars.
And I tried a couple of different inflation calculators because that just seemed
way too off. Way just wild.
And
Yeah. One fifty eight to one sixty two was was the range I got. So we definitely
understand why Donald was blanc.
And, yeah, I remember vividly in the late nineties,
slapping a tree home just a couple days
before Christmas that I got for, like, fifteen dollars.
Because it was so close to Christmas. So so, yeah, these prices are are pretty high. And and so on the next page,
Donald
gets off. We get we get a gag about needing smelling salts.
He
he gets off that good line about... you know, do you have smelling salts for when I hear the price for a gold tree.
And we do see a can in the background
behind him of the spray paint that must be coating these trees. And so
the Ducktales
we cut to the Ducktales
walking home with a very sad green
tree and Donald is
despair at the cost of a golden one. And the kids
they sit on the curb to have a good cry. Oh, I think it was forty. Right?
It was forty dollars which in today's money would be about four hundred thirty two. Wow. Yeah. So I I understand why Donald
couldn't lead with that.
So the kids sit on the curb to have a good cry. And from behind fence, we can
spot that the witch. Is spying on them because we
we get her thought balloon which states that she needs their tears for her potion.
And when she comes over the fence,
she appears as a kindly old lady who consoles them and tells them that she can direct them to a genuine golden tree. I think I I think my
calculations were for the nineties.
Back to when I was working there. Let me... Yeah. That makes sense. Calculate.
Yeah. Close enough. The twenty twenty one would be the
fifteen dollars
would be
one seventy right now, so I did do it for the nineteen nineties.
Right.
But that gives us a pretty good idea. Yeah. Okay. So a quick correction that I wanna make. Mh. Is that the
inflationary figures that I gave for nineteen forties Christmas tree,
and then what it would be in today's money was actually, I did a calculation based on when I would have been selling such a christmas tree in the nineteen nineties.
They would obviously be
quite a bit more today.
Right. Yeah. No worries. Cumulative of inflation apparently from nineteen forty eight to today is one thousand thirty five point one percent Yeah. So yikes. Absolutely.
Alright.
So on the next page,
the lady indicates that the genuine Golden tree grows on the highest crowd of mount demon tooth.
This is the first time that Barks is gonna reference that. That's Al landmark and Ducktales that he's gonna use a few times.
And and the boys cheer up and they head immediately towards the mountain as you pointed out, you know, they're being very cr.
And unlike their usual
characterization here. And then
the the lady immediately
turns very creepy looking.
And transforms into the witch.
She grabs her broom and races ahead of an nephews u's.
And on the mountain, the boys encounter Barks for trail and then they do a double take on seeing a sign that indicates the tree is on the right word path. So I'm
not ex knowing what to expect.
Was actually kind of like, oh, that which is really adorable. It's just an old lady Mh. And she's
got cute little glasses.
And
she just looks like she's a very sweet one. It didn't occur to me that, like, her being
you know, humanoid, human
might be a giveaway.
It didn't occur to me that she would transform into
the wicked witch but she did.
How often humans...
Like, human humans is used. So I think I think she's
drawn as one of the human like cakes, actually.
Okay. Because that nose I read it as, like, the the Barks sort of p,
And and Barb has kind of a well that he goes to. Right? Most of the human like characters
are done as dogs in these stories.
With kind of like, pigs and and various birds,
ducks and
gander and other birds being the next most common.
So
I think she's supposed to look like one of the pigs not a true human. The the pink... In that
one where she's kind of transforming back to her normal self. I can see I can see pig resemblance, but Yeah. She just looked like i a typical cute cra.
Yeah. I could see for that. I could see why you thought she looked human like. And isn't isn't that a little transitional
panel where she's
got the witches kind of expressive, but she still looks like the the kindly lady is not very unsettling.
Yeah.
Yeah. It is.
Alright. And and I remember reading this for the first time being like, wow, this is so weird that the witch is here, because that's clearly the witch from Snow white.
Right. And and on the next page, that witch from Snow white it is transforming
back
from the sign that she has turned into.
And
Donald meanwhile realizes that the boys aren't home yet. So he goes off to search and he encounters their footprint and follows those and then he sees some point to chew footprints
such as might be worn by a witch
not that he believes in witches.
And
then when Donald sees that the footprints seemed to include Barks where a broom has taken off he panic and
and then he calls out the police who immediately cast a very wide net.
Donald takes a moment to stop and consider what which is likely destination would be, and he thinks about mountain Demon too, so he sets off.
Meanwhile, on mountain demon tooth, the Nephews encounter a chasm them, and they again do a double take as they see a log that's bridging the span that wasn't there before. And on the next page,
the nephews used crossed the log and they advance to the summit of the mountain where they instantly find the golden Christmas tree right next to a cabin.
This is one of those moments where it should probably seem like they got to it too easily. Right? But the tree poof out of it existence
just as they approach
and the which is behind them
testing
and looking on. Yeah. And she's she's there her in her normal self instead of in the cute granny lady
self.
Right. So I I wonder if they're starting to get suspicious at that point. Yeah. We don't even see, like, her take a Al triumphant moment to Tackle that she fooled them or or anything like that. That's not what. Yeah. Dory is interested in.
I I... It's not interested in in in kind of
falls and and Barks and and
failing a few times before they get to their goal.
Yeah. Because the journey of mount demon to, seems like it should be much more fraught but, you know, the witch is kind of just advanced to the long.
I think that the energy of the story is really working towards
Donald kind of siege of the cabin that's coming up.
Mh.
Alright. So on the next page, we transition back to Donald, who is In hot pursuit
but he gets stalled at that chasm.
Meanwhile, in which is cabin cottage or whatever, she is cage. He be doing Lily. And encouraging them to work up a good cry as she grabs
an array of witches
ingredients to mix up a potion.
Kind of a fun little
panel showing some of the the neat little ingredients. Do you mind telling us what some of those fun ingredients are, Sarah? So I thought the ingredients were really cute.
There's some gould rule Mh
of tears.
Hate.
That one I had a question about, is there, like, love min? Or is there some some kind of cultural reference that I'm missing or just like, oh, these mint are for hate or hate. Yeah. I don't I don't know. Because it does sound like it should be referencing something, but
no. It's just pretty stark hate. And she has the typical witch is called ran over a fire
and a a skull that seems to be a container of some sort.
Right.
Although with eye holes, I don't know how great of a container
is.
I bet it's for measuring. Mh. Mh. Alright. And so on the next page, we learn...
On the next page, we learn that the witches evil plan is to destroy all the Christmas trees on Earth
thus apparently destroying happiness.
And back at the chasm, Donald uses the old snowball trick. He rolls the snowball down to span the gap and he he goes onward.
And the witch is just in the process of getting tears from the boys. I did like the little demons
that didn't look like they were part of the
of her
con in the cauldron. They just looked like they were having a leisure swim. This is what we do.
We're helping stir this how relaxing
Yeah. I I agree i like that pan Al lot. And
so the witch gets startled by a knock on the door and she spies Donald through the people.
She thinks fast and she turns into a bombshell
female duck. One of the writings I read about this suggested that she might be intended to look like the pin up girl,
Betty Gray.
But Donald is not distracted by her. I I I liked that. Right? It's a cliche
to have the hero get distracted by by a beauty and
she tells him that she can point him in the direction of the witch, but he has to help her with her knit. And so she spins Ducktales of knowing where the witch is by the smell of her terrible potion,
at which point Donald sniff the air in the cottage.
I thought that was a clever
ru
to
kind of
hap bind his hands right. He's gotta hold his hands together, so she can
unwind this skiing and
wrap it around his hands. That's kind of a normal
thing that you do with yarn
when you're working with it, and and it kind of... It mobilize his hands
to
make him less of a threat. I thought that was really clever. Yeah. I agree. That that was a neat little sequence, and I feel like this would have looked probably a lot more natural,
you know, back in the late forties
that this is kind of one of the ideas of femininity is that you're always doing the knit And and, you know, i I think
this wouldn't maybe play the same way today. Right? Mh. It's it's... The knit is not as common.
The those of us that work with
craft would know. But knit and crochet and such are not as common as they
used to be. Right. And so Donald realizes that this
bombshell
duck has a foul smelling cauldron her south. But it's too late. She has his wrists bound in that yarn, and she transforms back into the witch.
But donald is too quick.
He freaks out he escapes,
but then he kinda stops himself. He realizes that even if he's a afraid, you can abandon on this nephews and he asked go back. And so on the next page, we get a sequence of Donald trying to break in and the witch
defending.
It's it's very imaginative. You know, he uses a log as a battering ram. She transforms into a wood grinding machine I like the the little side gag of her
turning the pulp of the wood into a a newspaper that says which foil house breaker that's that's probably my favorite sequence in this.
Yeah. It you know, it threw me back to
the twenty eleven
green lantern movie that was
so disappointing. U. You know, the green lantern
power was that he could
turn into anything,
right? And
problem solve
that way. And
this little twenty one page comic,
the problem solving that the... Which floyd turning into
a log to cross a chasm
a a wood grinder with a newspaper printer at the end. And then on the next page, a little machine that has three little gravity arms to grab each of the voice that was just infinitely more impressive than
full budget, Hollywood blockbuster
from ten years ago.
That's awesome.
Yeah. I would agree. I I think to me that this is kind of the strongest part of this.
You know, otherwise, not too remarkable story is these, like transformation sequences. They're the most entertaining thing in it. They're and they're so creative and so clever. Yeah. Definitely.
Alright. So on the next page,
the witch turns her attention back to an Nephews
only to realize that they have escaped and they're in the process of being about to tip her potion as she angrily turns into that duck catching machine
that you commented on. And I like that it basically seems to have exactly one purpose.
Right? Because if you can transform into anything,
why why limit yourself to anything, but exactly the thing that you need. Yeah. And
so Donald
despair that the cabin is all shutter up, and she's, you know, hadn't advantage right now. And so on the next page,
the witch attempts again to get the nephews used to cry into the cauldron.
But she gets battered with her own broom by Donald who explains that he came down the Chimney just like Santa Claus.
And the witch intends to change into a cat amount to attack them, but she finds that she can't transform.
Mark, do you know what a cat amount is? I think it's just a wildcat cat. Isn't that? Let's see what Google says. Yeah. You don't you don't really see the term cat amount.
A wow. Yeah. Google says it's a Cougar. Yeah. So I don't know if that's just a a saying that's out of style. I know I've heard it. A little bit before, but but but it it definitely stands out. Right? And so on the next page, she realizes that the reason she can't transform is because Donald is holding her magic broom.
He directs her at room point
and the Nephews
explain what the potion for. Rather than tipping it Donald decides to
set the cabin on fire
and
the anguish witch
claims that it contains her life's work.
Three thousand years worth of it. You know,
had she been trying to get rid of Christmas trees for three thousand years or just was it like other work?
Because...
There's some acronyms
with
Christmas
in general.
Yeah. I guess, some of her other evil schemes are going up in smoke. And, you know, there's there's part of me that's like, is this
proportionate, but she did kid kidnapped his nephews.
So, you know, I guess, house bla.
Alright. And so on the next page,
the witch is scheming.
And she determines to act like something is stuck in between her teeth and is able to Donald out of one of the straws of her broom. And that's just enough for her to be able to transform and do a fire ex
to try to put out the blaze.
And at this point, Huey, dewey and Louie can redeem themselves. Right? They get a little smarter. They figure out how she's doing her transformation and they encourage donald.
To use the broom to make a wish to stop her.
And instantly the boys roar out of control as he has turned her into a gas camp. And
now he becomes kinda drunk with power.
This is a pretty entertaining page, I think. Yeah. Yeah. Again, with the excellent problem solving with trends
transformation. Right? Yeah. I just love it. It really escalate pretty well. And I like Mcdonald's expression when you realizes he's a witch now himself.
Alright. And so with his newfound power, he transforms himself into a handsome and tall Ducktales,
you know, intriguing looks a lot like glad stone gander, I think. And and Gladstone is a new character at this point, but he he appeared for the first time just a few months before this.
He intends to make some more wishes, but one of the nephews snags the broom and he wishes for that sought after Golden Christmas tree, which poof into existence
immediately and is suddenly talking and thanking them for sub doing the evil witch.
I had a question about this this the fashion choices for handsome donald. U.
Kind of... Yeah. Definitely it... It reminded me of Cla. It did remind me of Gladstone Gander.
Who made me think of nineteen
twenties and thirties era fashion.
Would you would you say that's accurate.
You know to me it reminds me is it... I'm trying to think of which old hollywood actor, probably from the late thirties.
Forties has that kind of like, wavy hair.
Not bog art, but
someone from that era, It's definitely
an interesting
version of masculinity
that he's imagining. Right? Yeah.
It it the slick hair. It just it reminds me of the song putting on the r. Right? Yes. Yes. Absolutely.
Right. It's very r. There's a story, another Barks story where he wants to Gladstone
is a member of a club called the idle Dandy
and then that's what he looks like to me. Looks dandy
in this. Yeah. That one with his eyes closed, it's it's kind of a feminine looking and
contrast to, I think you know, there's a lot of anxiety over masculinity
in these. So it is interesting, which
kind of pictures for himself in this little throw away sequence. Yeah.
Especially if it's kind of dated fashion for that type. If I'm correct on my fashion history. Right. Yeah. I'm not sure. But...
But it's definitely...
It definitely stands out now. And so on the next page, the tree explains that it is the spirit of Christmas. Donald feeling very ashamed of his selfish wish and when he learns this. So he re the broom thinking, you know, at least I've got my my hands some good luck, not realizing that he's gonna trans... He's gonna revert. And and so that this makes him so upset when he changes back he kicks the gas cam and the witch ends up falling to her doom. And the Golden Christmas
explains that Donald has now saved Christmas and ben promptly leaves. And and those
These pages, these panels
feel very rushed. Right? And these are some of these Barks some of those panels that were either redone for him or that Barks was asked to redo because it all feels very.
Right? And very, like, oh, let's make up the fact that he's a selfless
hero now. Yeah. And then so
I just was wondering who
who delivers Christmas trees at night. Yeah. Is they're like, an Uber Christmas tree, Yeah. And your Uber eats. To the last the the the fun gag. I do like this gag at the end where
we see the town's folk kind of pondering, you know, what the the the hero of the du.
And so as we transition to Christmas morning,
Donald is exhausted because he's been up signing
delivery receipts all night and shows an Nephews
outside eighteen thousand seven hundred and sixty six golden Christmas trees. And as you say, that's
that is a very efficient
delivery company in Duck.
Anyone who can get that done overnight can do pretty much. On Christmas eve night, no less.
Right. On Christmas.
I think any one of those is probably a couple hours of effort between the delivery and the painting and and ever. Right. But I have no problem accepting that there's a trade talks that is the embodiment of the spirit of Christmas.
Right.
And and that was battling against the nemesis of the Fairy tale Princess,
snow white before
relocating to Mountain D two. That's side of Duck. Right. Right. Yeah. So this this one is a pretty unusual one.
What what did you think about it overall, Sarah? I I felt like it was a little bit more simple, a little bit more streamlined
I I do kind of like when they can get from a to b without a lot of the
falls and failures.
That's just kind of my preference.
I like to see people succeed even if it's
succeeding in getting up a mountain so that a wicked and which can capture you. Right. Yeah. The the pacing on this one is is weird. And to me, this one, it feels like what it is. Right? Because Barks had these, like, adventure stories and he had many, many more of those ten page storage. And it feels like something in between and it definitely feels like someone was like, it's the Christmas
season. Where you've gotta you gotta do a Christmas story
and it feels like something that he had voiced upon him. But but you know what? Later on, he's gonna have another
holiday story with a witch
voiced upon him.
But
that one, it's trick treat is what I'm thinking of. He
really like, enjoys is doing that one and and has a blast doing doing that one. Oh, I'll I'll have to bring you back for that one I think you'll
huge think out of that Halloween story. But you know, this one feels like he's going through the motions a little bit. I do really like the, like, invasion of the cabin sequence
overall. That one was fun. You know, this is definitely like a lower tier. Barks story for me. But but I I didn't. I didn't dislike. And it's just not one that I remember very fondly.
Yeah. It seems
it seems kind of
forget in its simplicity but not bad. Yeah. And and I wonder if it had had, like it's a twenty pager I think.
A lot of his best regarded ones are kinda span more like twenty four to thirty two pages.
I wonder if it had a few more pages to develop.
I I don't know if it really could have improved on itself that much. It's just so weird, the witch feels so shoot to me and that weird... As I think Barks was correct that the ending is is very moral.
We don't really know how he was going to ended it originally, but apparently, it was a bit more of a cynical ending, and I think the witch met more of a graphic
demise.
Well, you know how Disney villains can never actually
do anything
worse than fall to their death. Right? Like, they don't ever get stabbed. They don't ever get beat up or shot or anything. They just fall off of cliffs or roofs or... Yeah. They're very good at Mountains
Yeah.
So it seems, you know, it's it's more passive and kind of off screen. Right? Yeah. It clearly has editor or reminded you know, This is Disney, that's we do. So the community feels about the same. You know, they're fairly indifferent to this one. It has a a seven point rating, which is like average. It's good for the six and six
best story. Out of the forty two thousand or so that have been voted upon. So, yeah. Kind of a weird little story. Some of the elements
do pull me out of it, but... But it's still a fun read.
As far as, you know, what's dated, what's our k, you know, I had fun talking about some of those old tropes of walking past the the broadcasts.
It feels like some of the gender added tubes are a little bit retro grade,
you know, but but nothing is like overt.
I guess nothing nothing made me cringe in this one. Yeah. You know, I it was it was very
trope,
but it wasn't
necessarily
as cliche shade as others have been or Al dated or as
offensive as some stories from that time period could be? Right. Yeah. So way a go.
It was just very average.
And and as far as I'm aware, this is not one that gets referenced
anywhere else. Sparks didn't do an oil painting that I'm aware of. But in search I did find another painter who did one in the bark style that I thought was really cool. Guy named John Ga. So that's worth checking out. And this was never used as, like, the inspiration of a Ducktales
episode or anything like that. And and I wouldn't say that there's really any educational value
of notes to this did
did you have a favorite panel that's stuck out to you Sarah, a favorite page or panel, I guess? You know, it wasn't
necessarily
a visual
thing that stuck out to me, but I really
enjoyed
how the cabin up on the top of the mountain was referred to as a sinister s. Yeah. Yeah. That is fun. And I do like that.
I had mentioned that I enjoyed the, you know, the machinery that she turned into as well as the
creepy ingredients.
The pile of Christmas trees at the end was definitely fun. That's certainly meant to be the show list of the panels. But I also really liked how even though she's just like a formed gas cam. There's there's one page where you can really kinda see the witch the which is
despair. As a can of gas. And I I know It's that's some skill to to portray emotions through a gas.
Right. It's that second last page, the fourth panel on that one. I thought that was that was funny. Alright. So any any closing thoughts about the Golden Christmas tree? Nope. I did have a question about this this reprint that you sent to me. Yeah. It on that first page, it said published by So and so, blah blah blah in
subsidiary of walt, Disney company,
Bob Blah Bank. Mh. Blah blah blah. Blah blah blah.
Do you have any address changes,
send them to this post office box in Prescott, Arizona.
Do you know when that's about being as how both of us have lived in Arizona
and probably been... You've been a press get right Those definitely.
Yeah. So glad stone or another rainbow or one of the publishers. You know, the this at this point walt Disney themselves have taken Al license back for the publishing,
but the company before and the company after is called Gladstone
not to be confused with Gladstone gander. And they were ahead headquartered and and what I thought of at the time as prescott Arizona.
And
I would tell my parents, you know, can we go to prescott Arizona someday. I wanna see where my favorite comic book are published. And and I subscribed or bought some back issues at one point. So one of the very first letters that I ever wrote was a dress. To to prescott it Arizona as it's properly called. Yeah. I'm sure it's some non office building there. But
in my eight year old mind, Prescott Arizona is the magical place that Disney comics came from. Alright.
Thank you very much, Sarah for joining me. And I will see you back next time I think when we get to talk about race to the south seas.
If any listeners
have any
comments that they'd like to pass on, you can reach us on Facebook, rx remarks.
Barks remarks at gmail mail dot com is our email address. And, you know, we have gotten a you a few nice comments recently. So I definitely appreciate when folks chime in. When we get to, you know, a couple, I can share some of those the and one of the ups. Episodes
And thanks again. See you next time.