Hello, and welcome to Barks remark. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks, creator of sc Mc and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comics of all time. Join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological publishing or We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Hello again, and welcome back to Barks remarks, the podcast where we talk about Carl Barks Stories.
I am Mark Sever marino, Al longtime comic fan.
And I'm gonna ask my guests to introduce herself and tell me the last time she was on a boat
I'm Sarah Santiago
and the last time I was in a boat was about a month ago.
We have this
this paddle steam,
which is quite rare for Scotland. Right? There's something that you normally consider like, a mississippi delta kind of boat. And there was one that's been in Glasgow for a long time. It was recently
restored and now it makes little day trips out to like, the isle of butte and back to glass. So it i have to go do one of those. It was really neat. Does sound neat. That sounds like some peaceful fun. It sounds more relaxing than the kind of long ocean voyage that the ducks are gonna take because we're gonna be talking about race to the south seas today. So this is a story where Donald and the boys are gonna be in a race against their cousin Gladstone
to see who can be the first to locate their missing uncle sc Du. So we've kinda got the dynamics of the Ducktales family taking shape, you know, Glad gander and sc duck are both very new characters at this point. Both characters that were created by Carl Barks
you got to you got to read the first couple of sc stories,
but you haven't... This is your first experience with Glad
Gander.
This is my first experience with Gladstone. Yes.
Yeah. I'll have to share with you his
original
appearance.
He is not in too many of these adventure length ones. I I can think of probably about half dozen of them. But I think this is roughly his third or fourth appearance. It's just the first time he's been in one of these long ones.
This is one of the very first ones, though where he's had his very characteristic
luck.
So to me, he's a really interesting
carrot who makes for some very entertaining stories. Can I ask Sarah, what is your impression of Glad gander?
I mean, he's His his luck is annoying. I have on my notes.
Wow, Gladstone
look is really annoying. Mh.
Yeah. And I can see how
how it can
look to Donald whose luck is typically bad. But I also feel like
glad stone is
the beneficiary of of so much privilege
that he was cultured and nurtured and raised in in these ways where Donald wasn't.
And so he knows how to cultivate
relationships
where Donald, I think only has
friends because his nephews have no choice. Right? Donald not really
pleasant
in a lot of ways. Whereas,
I specifically wrote down. I'm pretty sure that Gladstone has read how to win friends and influence people. Almost certainly,
if it if it existed, I don't know when that was published. It did. It was was first published in the thirties. So it it had been
widely
read by that point...
I'm not sure though that he would, because that sounds too much like work.
I mean what's stone above all is a professional idol.
That's fair. I... Maybe his
father had read it and
instilled
some of that kind of passively and so he's absorbed some of it by osmosis If he hadn't read it. So... I mean, you're going off your your first impressions. Right? I've read dozens of stories with them. So I think I think you're totally on base. Right? Because he he really is like that dis.
The... He is the essence of privilege.
Because he gets everything
that he wants. It just comes to him without having... You know he he's playing on easy mode. Right? And he's always meant to be a contrast with Donald. You know,
sc, of course is gonna get to appear in his own stories very soon. Gladstone never appears in like stories by himself. He's always a foil for Donald. And I think it's interesting because you can tell that Barks
himself hates glad.
Right? Like, he is... I think he's amusing and his luck creates for some really
interesting
situations and scenarios, but Barks does not like him. Barks
is almost to a false he is about that sort of idea of the self reliant man who pulls himself up by his own bootstrap.
And so Glad is kind of meant to
embody
those who are not willing to work and just wait for
you know, good things to come to them. Yeah. I had
I had wondered
what is this guy? What does this supposed to mean? What is this supposed to represent
these... I find these
comics to be Al interesting
anthropology lesson right on
on this era of American history and and cultural
ideas
And obviously,
America... The rugged individual has been kind of pervasive since the beginning and it takes us on different shapes and different flavors with different generations. And
I I just wondered it just felt weird
that
Here was this character
that failed up in such a in such a way that it was
not celebrated.
Right? Because we we have people in our culture, you know, now that sail
and they have, you know, a whole half of the United States that want to see them fail upward even more. Yeah. And and
So I could see that there was a commentary
on
hard work and kind of the p work ethic. But it was it was a confusing mesh message
because
we see
success on in the hands of this lazy character
and
failure
on on Donald, Who's our protagonist and who is working hard. He's just not necessarily
working
smartly.
Right. And I think you really have to read it as being all about Donald. Right? None of the commentary is specifically about glad. He really only works as a foil. I think you're right on about, you know, the the p and work ethic
that's very much in character
for Barks.
Stalling the virtue of hard work.
And and a lot of these stories
are gonna end like this, the stories that feature glad stone where even though he is lucky,
Donald will still come out on top in some of them. But but again, because this is Barks and he's not consistent, there are gonna be times where Glad does come out ahead.
So, I mean, as far as high concepts,
glad s
supernatural luck is something that a lot of comic book writers are gonna have a lot of fun. It's a it's a really interesting character feature.
So I'm I'm excited that he has kinda joined the fray. Well, we'll get to do a few more of these. I found it interesting
that
it it wasn't just luck that
he represented, but
wealth
because I look at at now, right, where where wealth is v.
And... Oh, you know, if you're if you're rich, you can get away with anything. If you're rich, you can
buy your way out of any situation
And
we we really elevate people who are wealthy
in our culture. And so it was interesting to see there was a time when that wealth
without hard work
was... It was very clear that Barks was taking a stand against
wealth without work. Whereas in our culture now, we have
people famous just for being famous and and that's just kind of the opposite.
Yeah. Keep... Keep that in mind going forward. Right? Because that's gonna become just a huge part of the underpinning. So ami subs
deck and so forth. So let's let's get into the comic itself. This is our oh, I think this might be the last one that appeared in
March of comments, the one of the giveaway comics, number forty one.
I think I said that this didn't. This is published in nineteen forty nine because it was one of the march of comic stories. I don't have the exact publishing dates. This has been reprinted
seven times including the original and it's again a fairly shorter one like the last episode. This one only twenty two pages.
And
there's some moderately interesting background trivia. So some parts of this story were
lost for a long time or at least the original art that was easier to reprint.
So when it was reprinted in
In the Netherlands,
one of the local artists
redid many of the panels
and
So the reprint over the years have been kind of a mash of Barks and
either
Don
or dick v, I think is his name. And and some of the re reprint they've kinda left some of the Dutch writing in intact. I think you can see it in the one that we're re reprint or the re reprint that we're
that we've read where in the on the second page. I'll point it out. It has the Dutch name for uncle Sc, which is Dogg barrett on the document that the lawyer has. And then
the that lawyer that I mentioned, his name is Sylvester Sc,
and that's kind of a random
maybe an accidental reference, maybe a deliberate reference to a character from the old Mickey mouse comic strip from a decade earlier.
That floyd Gottfredson
created. He was a pretty notable villain that worked with them with Peg leg Pete.
I mentioned that this is the first full length or adventure length story that Glad Gander
has appeared in. He was recently introduced in one of Barks
best ten pager in my opinion called wintertime Wage, but he didn't have his luck at that point. And this is, I think the fourth appearance by now of uncle sc,
and this is gonna to be the first time he appears with his top hat. So that's a excellent.
What what was the name of the character? Was it also sylvester shi?
It was. The the same name, so sylvester s and and it could have been coincidence
because, you know, it's very common to call boy characters sc
and, you know,
sylvester
with that nicely. But I i I assume that Barks read those those mickey mouse he was so involved with the company. And they were very popular.
I did think that the name... I did think that the name Shy was interesting. I remember my and father, you know, anybody that he thought was crooked. He called it shi.
So I I found it interesting that His name was Sc spelled s h y s t e r.
Because I thought that that kind of word which my grandfather always used you know, and and as some, you know, to describe something crooked was
a reference to the German word that is, you know, a swear word. And here I find it that it's it's
completely
different spelling. So I've I've always wondered where do you know the the origin of that word? I I think it... I think it's origin is exactly what you just said actually.
I think okay. Is an an s head is
kind of where it comes from. K? I I did I did see some people
suggest
some people have the impression that it's anti semitic,
because I think it sounds like Shy lock, right, which is
Al slur that people use against lawyers
to typically Jewish lawyers and comes from
Ot fellow. Right? But
or oh, no merchant events. I'm sorry.
But a different different word. Right? S stir versus Shy.
But but... yeah, it's it's... I've heard that too, and I think people from that era used use Chi a lot in a way that they don't really anymore Yeah. So i mean, let me say a couple of the titles from around the world.
This was... I like this one because it had a publication in Indonesia. I haven't gotten to do that before.
The direct translation was Lo K
Ce
race to the South seas.
That was the most south sea adjacent country I could find that it was published in. And
let's see and Spain, it was Colorado and los modest and sur and
in
Greece, it was translated as
confrontation in the south pacific.
Anna a med three c.
I'm sure that was
not even clubs. But anyway, I
Alright. A little bit of geographical context, of course, the south seas is the term for the southern
Pacific ocean.
What we would call Ocean,
which I don't know if that's even used that much.
It's not Ocean.
i've I I may be pronouncing wrong. And then and then I know that culturally,
it is true that many of the islands of the South Pacific were known to have kind of a tradition of
hospitality and gift giving
in the way that Gladstone is gonna take advantage of in this story. I don't I don't think it's quite as not as characterized in this, but I think that is
somewhat a part of
culture, some parts. And and you know, we get kind of the trope of of cannibal outages at the end of this one.
It's not like a
huge part of the story fortunately,
but
you know, it's a it's a tough thing to talk about these days because it's like such a taboo, but I do think it is worth kind of commenting that, you know, cannibalism is one of those things that's been practiced by societies all around the world in varying forms
it
was practiced in fiji
and in neighboring areas,
but it had basically
gone away as of like the eighteen sixties.
So this is something that you know, appears in adventure stories well into the sixties,
but that's not really
reflective of modern poly.
At all.
I think it's... It's largely disappeared even by then except in some very remote areas.
Alright. Any comments
before we get into the plot of the story itself. Nope. Awesome. Oh, you know,
what do you think is our version of Donald here? Any thoughts on that?
I I I feel like he's gone back to his
ruled by big, disorganized emotions
and the kids end up having to
and problem solve, which is based on the comics that I've read so far, that's very typical for you. Yeah. I think that's exactly right. Awesome.
So
oh and of course, our notable appearance is Gladstone
Gander.
And we'll see a lot more of him.
So this story opens with Donald and his cousin glad stone fishing and having an argument over whose side of the family is better. You know, the way family members do.
Donald brag about the great workers
that there are on his side.
Especially as rich uncle Scrooge,
while glad stone brag about how the gander never had work. And they get to arguing over who Scrooge just favor relative and by extension, who is going to inherit his wealth?
And eventually a lawyer encounters the Ducktales and reveals that mister Mc has given Gladstone a wonderful
present.
Alright. So on the next page.
The cousins are shocked to learn that the gift is a sailboat boat anchored nearby. The man introduces himself as Lawyer, and he reads the very sarcastic letter of gift getting. Donald is disgusted by what glad tones getting, but then he stops when he realizes the lawyer has good news for him as well.
I thought that was pretty funny. Whereas
The gander is so full of when he can sail boat on a still day. I am presenting him this twenty foot sale craft. I liked that. That was pretty funny. And so he reads a similarly
sarcastic message
that gifts her boat to Donald as well.
And both cousins now are very sm and they evolved deeper into argument over who is Ru favorite.
And the nephews
resolve that they're gonna have their uncle settle the question. Does it feel like
Donald
sailboat gift is not as nice as glad stones.
Yeah.
I mean,
the the gander one, I don't know. I can't I can't really tell sailboat apart. But i I do think it's interesting that Donald doesn't seem to react to sc just like insults.
There. He's just standing there so proud. Any attention is good attention sometimes.
Yeah. And this is pretty common this this, like, these don and glad stories, they often open with this kind of arguing this kind of bi.
So on the next page, the Nephews arrive at Sc his office and learned that he has recently flown to Australia.
To count his billion his eight billion sheep. He's not gonna be back till tomorrow
and
d
the head back and encounter a headline from a newspaper boy.
They share the news with Donald when they get back that sc is missing. He is feared,
cast away on some lonely island.
I thought it was interesting that he was gonna make a
round trip to Australia in
one
day.
Yeah. If they been paying attention, maybe they have realized his story didn't didn't hold up. So glad muscles in on Don news reading and they both learned that small boats are needed to comb the remote lagoon and shallow
glad gets the idea that sc is going to be mighty grateful to whoever rescues him.
And
the two cousins go to each other into a race to be that rescue.
The nephews
sen separate to go get provisions to together for the voyage.
Yeah. They're the ones, of course who have to do all the problems solving, getting maps and
supplies and such.
Right. It's easy to picture Dom glad
arguing
for hours yeah. And so on the next page, we see the docs very thoroughly and sen
preparing for the voyage.
Gladstone is just talking big and sailing around the bay.
Donald cancels the Nephews that they need to call him sir on the voyage. And the nephews think they're gonna have the vantage
because of Gladstone behavior. But Donald reminds him about their...
Gladstone is born lucky.
And that night, they get awakened buy a commotion at the docks.
And that commotion turns out to be a bunch of people
loading
supplies
well wish that are provisioning glad boat for him. So his boast full talk has gotten everyone attention,
and he gets provisioned for free and at no effort to himself, leaving Donald to silk.
And I don't know about you, Sarah, but this this does feel fairly timely
this kind of
attention seeking
Yeah. I mean, given the... What we know today about how to court the media,
right? That this is where I wrote. I bet glad stone has read how to win friends and influence people.
Because
he is cultivating
relationships,
so he's not not working in this case. He's just cultivating relationships.
And
winning people's,
affection
and well wishes and kind of exploiting them, definitely exploiting them to get all of this provisioning and preparation done, You know, all he has to do is butter people up. Yeah. And And
to me, this this feels very realistic. Right? Like lots of his luck is supernatural and very fan, but
This is easy to picture.
You know, people like to be involved
and they like this kind of big talk sometimes. So this kinda trying hit a little realistic to me. Alright. And on the next page, at daybreak break, the docs set sail while Glad tone sleeps in and Donald
immediately proves that he is not up to the challenge of sailing.
He's piloting the boat very radically by while he's spout nonsensical
maritime lingo that doesn't mean anything. And this this really feels like Donald is kind of coast on his own... He's he's very much assuming that this is just gonna work out Oh, yeah.
Donald is
completely oblivious
to what he doesn't know. He's...
Well if if Gladstone is the embody of luck and privilege.
Donald is the
embodiment of Dun Scrooge. Yes. He's he's very over confident, but he's at least gonna be able to reach calibrate.
Yeah. And he has the kids to with that. That that is his his true strength. So Donald, on the next page, he keeps running his mouth and con comp himself and eventually runs them ground on a sand.
As he despair Gladstone getting an early lead, the Nephews rum something from beneath the charts in the hold, which is revealed to be an instructional book called how to sail about. And I really like this gag. I thought this was great. Kids to the rescue as always.
Yeah. So the ducks are able to set sail and get underway. And eventually, they come across Glad,
who has fur his sales to stop and fish.
And he brag that he could fish for a week and still beat them. And he's basically proven a riot when he hooks a huge
sail or Marlin,
traveling west by Southwest at fifty knots exactly where he needs to go. Yeah. That's some luck. Yeah. More of a supernatural variety. Yeah. I'm sure that
making the Marlin
feel you know, warmth and love and and and seen is not the
strategy he used from
for this one. Right.
And then on the next page, Donald luck proves as bad as Gladstone is good. As the typhoon forms around them. The Ducktales take shelter and they hear the storm smashed their mask and red and steering post. And Donald despair that they've basically lost the race. But the boys point out that Gladstone is nearby and he's getting just as bummed up.
And when the storm passes the Ducktales get to work and they use ore to paddle, they caution Gladstone that he needs to get rowing. But he explains that he'll just wait for a lift rather than resort to manual labor. And sure enough, we got a pretty cool scene of a whale
emerging
underneath his boat and carrying him towards ta tahiti. As as you do, you know, Yep. That's that's what he counts on. And so Donald is Al
from anger, but he does quickly come to his senses and he tells the nephew that they need to ration their supplies carefully as they are fifteen hundred miles to the nearest island. So the Ducktales we row onward for days and days and they get to listen to radio news about glad,
breaking all records for fast ocean crossings.
They learned that he has arrived at one of the islands and he's basking in the sun, while helpful Islanders
repair his boat.
And I guess, is the fun gag where Donald gets
upset with the radio news and throws the
the radio in the ocean as the four cats come on singing how deep is the ocean?
And eventually the Ducktales land on what they identify as Coca ebola Island
where Gladstone landed long ago. But we learned that Glad is still there. He's just been living off the natives
generosity and goodwill and and en them with his glut knee because they're
you know, their traditions basically
for treating guests appear not to let them say no.
The island's mayor approaches Glad to make the case that he should leave.
And and you know this to me, Sarah is pretty notable because
this depiction of the islanders is probably one of the more
it's one of the best depictions that
that Barks has made of a person from the global south
a group from the global south. I I wouldn't say it's like sensitive.
But, you know, they're not speaking and, like, pigeon speak
the way the cannibal
will and couple of pages.
They
they're drawn relatively
respectfully.
They have
what Barks seems to be depicting Al like a very
a more positive culture than then we'll often see some of these, like, very colonial
tropes. Represent.
Yeah. And it's clear that he's exploiting them. Right? Where
he... He he obviously feels entitled
to
what these people have and
the message overall of this page is that he is exploiting them and overs staying his welcome
and putting them in a dangerous position. Absolutely.
And and on the next page. There's even more that you can read into it. You know, the mayor
explains to him that they're almost out of food. They have nothing but coconut left.
So glad stone decides to leave with everything left in their kitchens.
The natives celebrate his leaving,
and he's basically poisoned the well, right? Because they they resolved to stop being so generous.
Right as the starving Ducktales
arrive. And I I read an essay
in one of my re reprint that you know, kind pos that this is Barks talking about
colonialism or
globalization
basically,
you know, ruining
some of these indigenous cultures. And it might have been a generous reading,
but but I think it's at least a legitimate way to to frame that. Right? Because that that you could argue that Glad stone
is representative of that kind of
exploit of colonialism.
Yeah. And they are really smart to say,
okay. This is this ended badly for us. So
Yeah. We're not gonna do this again. I think the menace in that second to last panel
is kind of problematic.
Yeah.
The the facial expression and the kind of threat of violence with him holding the club. But otherwise,
I mean, yeah, that
just... No. You don't deserve to be exploited, and you don't have to put up with it. Definitely. And and, you know, you're right. That's a very men thing look picture. But by by the next page when they get the chance to, you know, interact with the Ducktales they
basically,
they they still treat them as well as they need to. They just make them pay for everything.
And they may... Absolutely. Very well. And so it puts them on a more, I guess even footing with them. Yeah.
And
on that page, we also get to see the archipelago of
y
which is very lovingly drawn and and I think that that's probably parody a real place name, although I don't. I don't know which. But it's a cool panel of the Ducktales arrival. And Donald is just looking around with a spy to see if he can spot sc anywhere. And then on the next page, the Ducktales are stopped by an imp reef that protects all the best islands in the lagoon. And suddenly Gladstone shows up and his luck delivers him a tidal wave that lifts him gently over the reef. And this one, I found reminiscent of an earlier story that I don't think you got to read where the ducks
are
trying to get access to a a lagoon in the ghost of the g. Very fun.
Share that with you. And so the Ducktales decide that, you know, if they wanna keep up with Glad, they're gonna have to blast their way through with dynamite.
And they do and are back in the race.
And soon Donald is scanning the islands with his spy Gladstone, and he suddenly spies uncle Scrooge.
Who is sitting calmly under a tree sipping with Coconut
and so the that's fell sure. And as soon as they dis,
They are greeted by a throne spear and they are shocked to see what they believe to be cannibal.
Donald starts to stem about being only there to rescue you his uncle, but the Nephews wisely told him to shut up and run when they make it back to the boat, the Nephew point out that
those
inhabitants
might not know about uncle sp and they need to keep the element of surprise. So again, we've got the nephews, you know, really taking the lead here and and being
the clever ones. And so Donald at this point proposes to use glad luck to their advantage,
He uses
reverse psychology to convince glad to get on the island and intending to use him as a distraction.
Glad gets confronted by a similar spear and Donald tells him he'd better start on it. But
instead of chasing him, the islanders
point at glad
spat, and they pros them themselves before him and bear him in a litter chair, like a king. I didn't know that term literature chair before reading this comic.
And the depths aren't are annoyed, but they see that at least the distraction has worked in a way.
And so they go ashore. And when they come across uncle sc,
they don't reveal themselves right away, but they see him basking with a mobile business office,
and they observe as sc talks calmly to one of those islanders.
Who speaks in pigeon,
telling him about op fellow with white feet like Scrooge
spat. Any thoughts here on Scrooge
pretty luxurious island setup. I do wanna talk about it once he reveals what it is.
Sure. I did wanna comment on the spat. I
looked up kind of when spat were popular, and it seems that they kind of went out of fashion
at least in the Us in
quite a bit of time before these comments were made. And so... Right.
Is sometime in the, like, nineteen thirties.
So I've I've been finding it interesting that
spat are used as a trope
to identify kind of wealthy people or attractive people. Like in
in the golden Christmas tree comic. Where
Donald wishes himself to be
attractive.
Right. Yeah. It's an interesting sign fire. And and like you say they're so out of fashion that it doesn't really seem relevant at all these days, but it's just such a part of Sc character.
And yeah, as mentioned, this is know, our first time seeing that other fire of sc Al well his top hat. Oh he's got one of those old stock ticker next to them. Yeah. My my favorite little bits of of archaic, whatever. I love those things. I've never seen one in a real life. Alright. So
a lot going on on the very last page. The docs
realize that the the so called cannibal
have been hired by sc. They're called his s,
and they watch
Glad
kind of bs s about his rescue
operation.
He lies about Donald not caring enough to come to the rescue.
He paints himself into the corner into a corner here because he's surprised to learn that sc doesn't want to be rescued.
He has
staged this whole plane crash so that he could get some work done without pest relatives around, and he's grateful to Donald for minding his business
and tells Glad tone that he's gonna cut him out of his will and favor of Donald. And so the the story ends with the Ducks heading home with Donald, you know, donald that advantage and glad now su. And and, of course, this is all gonna be etch sketched away because there's gonna be other stories later about
figuring out who sp real hair is.
But
what were your your other thoughts about Scrooge setup and the conclusion?
So I I talk a lot in my real life and,
especially about, like, fictional media that I consume that I wish people would just use their words. U.
It's a thing that we, you know, try to teach children is they're developing language and learning to understand their feelings, but I feel like there are so many adults that I wish would just use their words.
And, like, why can't sc just like set a healthy boundary. Just like, hey, guys, don't bother me. I need to be working.
Instead he goes through this whole thing where he makes everybody think that he's lost sea or dead or a cast away on a lonely island
he wastes navy
resources.
We don't know what the what the agreement is with him in the locals, but, like, is he exploiting them. Right. I don't know.
And and so that seems kind of like one of the worst defenses kind of more offensive than some of glad antique.
It's definitely the nuclear option. Right? Yeah. It's it's pretty over the top here. Yeah.
I did also wanna comment on how
good the kids are as far as, like, being
being the more
mature out of the most mature out of this whole group. Oh, daphne. They they obviously
don't like. Glad.
But they don't
participate in the rivalry
or the, like, fighting.
Right. The.
Yeah.
Yeah. So good for them.
So
what do you think about this story? What what what were your thoughts on it? Did you enjoy this one?
You know, this one
made me
uncomfortable. The narrative made me uncomfortable.
And as well as the kind of
exploitation of indigenous peoples made me uncomfortable and
The cliches
about indigenous peoples made me uncomfortable.
But
I did also find it a really interesting study
of the values of the time. You know? Like I was saying to wealth without work was was not seen
as
the
esteem
societal
thing that it is
today. Yeah. We hadn't
moved away from that, like, v generation of work ethic. Maybe an over,
but at least, I feel like it was a consistent
value. I don't know. I don't I don't wanna sound like Al old Fur.
I started reading these when I was
seven or eight, and my my appreciation of them is definitely changed over time because like you I find this one very
discomfort,
discomfort.
Because you do have some of these old, like, colonial
tropes, you know, this there are certain parts of this that feel very nineteenth century.
Mh.
And that is the case with a few of the, like, very first appearances
of uncle Scrooge.
I hope to have you back for a a deeply uncomfortable story that's coming up in just a couple
called Voodoo Who do. Oh, god. Which Okay.
Is is the singular story that I've been dread the most
but but it is also an excellent piece of storytelling, and I don't wanna to dive too much into that right now, but
it
it was probably the first six to eight stories that featured
sc that didn't have him Al as the, like, modern capitalist
that I think he became and still had some of these more nineteenth century
like Robber Barks,
very colonial era,
money making tropes.
And
it is very uncomfortable.
It is entertaining. I'm I'm always entertained seeing Donald Gladstone.
Face off against each other. So I do like that aspect of it.
Glad tones luck and some of the slaps stick around that. I find that endlessly entertaining, so I do like that. That aspect of the story. I also... It was really creative. It the the ways that his look
manifested. We're quite creative.
Yeah. It's it's
definitely worth reading a few other Gladstone.
Including some of the short ones that have some really fun stuff. And
Donald rivalry with Gladstone is gonna end up being very multi facet, right? Because you probably won't be surprised to learn that he becomes rival
for Daisy affection with Oh goodness.
So
there are a lot of
Donald versus glad with Daisy as the prize story.
Course, because doesn't have grown agency does she.
Right. And and it's
it's definitely
interesting to read Barks
take on Daisy because he's not you... He's not very interested in female characters,
which
shows a lot. And he he kinda got stuck writing a lot of Daisy Ducktales stories for reasons that escaped me right now but he wrote, he wrote this series called Daisy Ducktales diary.
As far as, like a great example of men's idea of women's inner monologue
in the nineteen
is is a is a pretty great thing to read. But anyway, I'm I'm digress. I do like these Donald versus glad stories.
This one you know, this a this is a pretty enjoyable one.
I consider it kind of a middle story as far as the ones that we've read. I was a little surprised to check it out on ducks and see that, you know, this is actually one that people...
I guess it holds up very well for a lot of people because it's pretty highly rated. It has a seven point seven out of ten, which is good for one hundred and sixty four out of the forty one or so thousand stories that are rated. So like, not not the highest
tiered comic. But,
you know, Barks wrote about five to six hundred stories
and so anything that's in the top two hundred
is probably like, in the top twenty five percent, you know, his of his specific story. So people like this one. And I can see why it's it's got a nice mix of
adventure
and
comedy and it doesn't really overstate it's welcome.
But
I can see why... It's also
been difficult to reprint because of some of these dated
depictions.
I I don't wanna overlook the fact that I think I didn't mention as i did the read through. But the scene where Donald is, like, blistering his way and and kind of spout nautical
nonsense.
I I think that's one of the funniest
sequences that I've gotten to read in any of these adventure lengths. Stories. I I thought that was hilarious. So... I thought that they were pretty funny too. I almost
tried the crowds source to see if I knew anybody with sailing knowledge to see if there was any any any any basis in reality to any of the phrases he was using, but I decided nah I'm sure there's not.
Yeah. I'm gonna just read a couple of the lines really quickly because they are that funny. It's
left the gym sail,
delay the Merlin spikes. I'm porting to the Fox to Starboard board. Okay. So that's... I think that means what I'm I'm left to the rear to the right or something.
That's pretty awesome.
So it's got some some inspired gag here.
Do you have any panels that stuck out for you? I do think there's some some really lovely
maritime and South Pacific.
Art in this one. Yeah. I thought that the...
Just kind of the arch of Palazzo of y,
drawings were really
pretty
just all the little sand bars and little islands and such. I thought that was really pretty Yeah. I agree. And
I it it looks to me like he was running from reference. You know, I don't think he drew like, generic
south sees archipelago and that or anything.
And it takes the whole... It takes up the whole width of the page. So it's this big panorama,
and then you can
see some big, fluffy
ocean
clouds off in the distance. And you just really get a good sense of scale from all of it. I really thought that that that from a technical perspective,
it was excellent. Yeah. Definitely.
I really liked a panel that
takes place.
The night that Glad tones boat is getting provisioned
there are two panels at the bottom of the page where Donald and silhouette and he's slumped over,
you know, despair
glad good fortune and his bad luck. And I thought that was really cool as well as the one right next to it. And he they do a good... He does a good job with the silhouette
still portraying the emotion. Yeah. Yeah. Definitely. I agree.
Barks is, you know, that one thing that doing this series has helped me realize. I didn't really understand how much he did this silhouette drawing, which looks very cool.
Mark when was last time that you were on a boat. Oh, yeah. That would been... I went to
Greece and Rome
about Yes, it's gotta be a good
six or seven years ago now. And
we took a little ferry boats to one of the Greek islands
in the.
That was that was pretty cool. Oh nice. I think that's the last time. I
I don't get don't get over to the coast as much as I'd like to these days. So, yeah, thanks for asking.
We talked a little bit about the david and archaic stuff.
To my knowledge,
there is not an oil painting or lit graph
of this one nor has it been made into a duck tales episode? Know, weirdly Glad Gander was used
only in a couple of episodes in both of the runs of Ducktales.
Which I think is a shame because I think he's a he has a lot of potential as an animated character. I did find this one fairly educational though. I thought that there were a lot of neat nautical terms,
many of them used correctly
that were very illuminati. And then there was a good sense of place of the South Pacific even if it had that kind of t
colonial
perspective. Yeah. Any
any final, any closing thoughts from you Sarah. Nope. Alright. Well, thank you very much for joining me and thank you to all of our listeners.
I'm grateful for everyone that listens.
And
you can get in touch with us at Barks remarks at g dot com or via the Facebook page. And oh, man, I am very excited for our next
episode This is a personal favorite of mine. We get to cover lost in the Andes
next time around. So That promise to be a great episode. Please come back and
I'm gonna do my best. To keep it under two hours, but no promises.
Awesome. Thank you again. I really appreciate it.