Hello, and welcome to Barks remark. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks, creator of sc Mc and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comics of all time. Join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological publishing or We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks. Welcome listeners You are about to listen to an episode of Mark's remarks that I hope is not plain awful. Before I get to the regularly
recorded episode, a couple of quick notes, First, I mistakenly said in the episode that this one is the highest rated non uncle Scrooge story but after recording, I realized that wasn't quite accurate.
Rather the golden helmet is rated slightly higher on index.
Also, I wish in hindsight that I had spoken a little bit more about the plane
Themselves. And some of the implications of their society being so quick to imitate outsiders. But I suppose I can always wait a couple of years and eventually cover Don Rose Sequel. So speaking of which I also learned after recording that Barks oil painting returned to plain awful,
apparently did proceed the Don Rosa story. Thus answering that chicken egg first question. I'm sure there will be a few more errors or emissions because it's impossible to cover absolutely everything about a great story like lost in the Andes, but please enjoy. Welcome back everyone to Barks remarks. And I'm Mark Sever, a Carl Barks fan on his eighteenth podcast who finally gets to talk about one of his all time favorite stories. We have a very full house
today to discuss landmark
story lost in the Andes.
And I've been super excited to get to this one. So I wanna jump right in with
introductions.
I have almost
every host returning for this one today.
Because I I couldn't bear to leave anyone out. So I I'm gonna have these guys introduce themselves
And then
after they say their name, I want them to tell us whether they think this one deserves
Its reputation has one of Barks most famous stories.
Eric.
I am Eric partly currently lost in Arizona.
Yes. This is a very much landmark
creative
completely out story that is fantastic and holds up Awesome. And and you've read this one in the past. I think you're the only other person here who'd read it before. Right? Yeah. And we this one. Awesome.
Ryan. I'm Ryan Bailey. I'm from yet another time zone. I think it's fitting that the most popular Ducktales comics podcast on the planet
should physically cover the entire planet. I do think this one is... It definitely stands out. It has a lot going on.
In a pretty
small package. I think other people probably would've have told this story over more issues,
but he's good at kind of condensing things and
there's a lot of originality to it, and it's just kind of a crazy
adventure. Awesome.
Alright. And ben. Yeah. My name is Ben. And yeah. In Arizona also. And...
Yeah. This is a good one. I I've
read very few of the issues,
but, yeah, the ones that I've read I was more... I was more of a fan of the the cartoon
and I've only recently kinda started reading some of these. So I'm I'm really enjoying it and. This is a good issue. Barks.
And, you know, I'm I'm excited. I feel like the theme song that I've picked for the podcast.
Really
really fits well our hail the games all here because we all go way back and,
you know, this honestly is kind of almost the fruition of my
villainous scheme here to finally get all my former roommates to to read this story that I love so much. So
you guys have fallen into my clutches.
And let's let's do it. Let's get into
lost in the Andes.
This is
a comic that was
first published in February of nineteen
forty nine, this was in four color two hundred and twenty three and there have been not as many reprint as I thought, including the original one, there's been eight of them. But
but again, this is kind of one of those signature stories where if you ask anyone
who who knows about Carl Barks. This is kind of the story that
everyone has been a name. At least of the Donald Duck ones. Right? I think that this is probably the most famous of his stories that doesn't include uncle sc in it. This is a long adventure story. This is thirty two pages.
You know, you mentioned Ryan that this might be told over more issues in a different
era and... That that could have been really fascinating to see.
At some point, It might have you read Don Rose Sequel because that adds a element to it as well. This is
the the famous
square egg story. It's kind of everyone's shorthand. For it. Right? Donald and the boys are gonna search for square eggs
hidden in a lost
civilization high in the peruvian andes.
And fitting fitting with Barks famous, most famous story, there's a lot of of kind of background trivia
that is associated with this one. So this is the podcast
highest rated story so far. And this is... I think part of the reputation is because this is one that Carl Barks
himself frequently mentioned as his favorite.
And he wasn't consistent about this. You know, he would mention other ones. But if you google it, this is the one that probably comes up the most often.
This is his second lost
civilization story
after mystery of the swamp
I know I had Ryan on for that episode.
Eric, you got to read that story as well. Ben, did I have you that odd ball one?
I don't know if you asked me too, but I do I did read that one that was. Yeah. I I think that his like lost
civilization one are kind of what he's best know yeah. And and I thought it was kind of unusual that both of them feature like, square dancing
randomly as no and.
And and so this was again, he wrote this at a time where his domestic life was really
sort of a mess.
I I found a quote that said his his second wife, Clara was
having some addiction challenges
and was quote coming part at the seams. And by his account, she was increasingly violent.
And,
you know, she she would go on to, like, they they divorced shortly after this period and she had some significant medical challenges. And
a lot of people have mentioned that that Barks kind of really threw himself into his work
around this time. And so this era of his stories are kinda considered his most fruitful,
most productive.
I don't know if I wanna buy too much into the like tortured artist escaping into it into into his work because, you know, that has a weird dynamic, but that's just something that kinda comes up. He was... He considered himself an armed chair Al explorer and national
geographic fan who
he he never left the country for the first time until very late in his life. And so he kind of would explore them and the the world through his material. And I don't know about you guys, but, like, I felt like this was a really good
window into and
civilization I think he tries to do it right, promising some of the key details, but not actually experienced it there. Right. And and to me, this one looked like he was using a reference.
This one, they they just seem like citizens of the people of the andes. Let's see Barks did have a brief stint early in his life as a chicken farmer. So I suspect that
that might have played into his
his decision to base this story around eggs.
And, yeah. He's quoted as saying my best story technically is probably the square a one. There there's a splash panel late into this
really spectacular one where they view the the civilization playing awful for the first time.
And
I love it, but he he is quoted as saying I botched up my perspective a little in drawing that. I should have laid out all these squares
down here by measuring points
instead of from the vanishing point. And he mentioned that a neighbor was talking to him and distracting him while he drew it. So that was just something that I learned, in know research jerk.
Yes.
And then this was really interesting to me. I I put out a call on the carl Barks
Facebook group that got shared on the Don Rosa group as well. Asking
about playing awful itself, the name of the civilization.
And I I I went down the the Rabbit hole I learned from
someone who shared this that there was a big
Norwegian controversy
with this story. And quote, the story gained a lot of attention when it was first published in the Norwegian language in nineteen sixty three, because the translator chosen Barks archaic and slightly garbled version
of
mean York
for the for the plain.
And that that was kind of widely viewed as an insult. Because it was kind of the back,
you know, the backwards
version of Norwegian. And in later additions, the language was altered
So that that story got a lot of attention in Norwegian
media.
And
this story is well loved
in norway especially. And here is how listener,
Y Abel
Characterized it. He said, I will not claimed that the country was set on fire in nineteen sixty three, but the country was set on fire.
Everybody got mad, especially the new
card miners in Nord my, an interest group for the advancement of the Knee Language.
Alright. So you guys, I I like to
talk about some of the different titles as well from around the world. So I've just picked a few. We might do a few more later. Eric, do you want to tell us the title you're gonna you're gonna wrap your mouth around.
In Italian,
it's e in studio betty
And the mystery of the inca. Excellent.
How yours Ryan? It is
from Spain, they said
this on this.
Walk where you may, but don't walk through the Andes.
Yeah. And that's a fun one. They get a a really good Spanish pun in there.
And how about you been? I wanna do the German one, but I haven't looked at it yet. So let's see. I'd luck.
In
ver
here. In the land of the square eggs,
nice sound. Excellent.
Alright. Thank you, guys. And then did you do Chile lane, Colombia? Oh, yeah. I was gonna say Chile Colombia. So in Chile and Colombia, it is just a straight up translation, pedro and.
Lost in the andes.
I mentioned that I had put out that question on Facebook,
what people what the translators
how they chose to translate plain awful because it's such a like specific idiom, I think in English. So
here are a few of them.
In most of the Spanish speaking countries, it was called Quad
which is just square land in
Danish in Denmark. I heard from
Gust
Johannes
he told me that it was
Raven,
which translates directly as like Shabby Raven corner
In finland,
on
Hun
said that it is called
Rot.
Which is literally the ultimate Rat hole.
Yeah. I like that. And I wanna get that. I wanna get that embroidered then hanging it over my couch.
Right as visitors walking in the door. Right? Yes. Exactly.
Nice the ultimate one at least. Yes. The ultimate Rat isn't that great. In French, it is
set horse, which just means it's awful. And then in German, it's E,
which is just
e and, which is just the name of a German city. Alright. And then we'll we'll do a few more of those when we get I think to plain awful.
Okay. And then here's a little bit of sort of cultural and geographical
context for this story. You know, I think I I read this at least at the beginning. This is clearly a satire of sort of hierarchy
and bureaucracy. Right? We have a lot of mocking
of
bureaucratic levels in this, which is a fun part of it. We mentioned that this one is set in in Peru peru in the And
area.
And I I felt like he he made a point of you know, using the clothing
and kind of depicting the people pretty accurately.
You know, I thought it was interesting that he didn't have the classic And
know, those classic And caps where it kinda goes down over your ears But yeah. But but apparently, the the song that he showed are also very typical. And they do use those like Au gallo blankets for carrying things. So I thought that was neat. I I could see him referencing Nash Geographic for some of this.
And then we got some of the awesome And
animals
at least referenced. If not shown. We got llama
shown and the v
mentioned.
And we've got some of those famous and
like rope bridges. That's shown at one point. And then we've got a reference to
Bet.
You guys...
I'm sure all of you know what that's referenced. Right?
He oh you guys really not not know anything None of us none of us have heard of that except you Mark. Oh I I don't.
So what don't... I... Eric seems to. Go on with the wind. Yeah. So it's like a a switched around version
of re butler. Right? So it's referencing the character from gone with the wind,
you know, classic southern film. In for our notable appearances, of course, and this one we have the plain awful,
the old Vic hunter. What what version of the characters?
Ryan, What what would you say is kind of the version? How would you characterize them in this one?
Yeah. They seem I feel like they're kind of back to their clever selves.
I think Donald probably a little mean,
than he has been in some other issues, but he's also not the villain
Right. Right. Yeah. I I have my notes. I was like, they're very resourceful in this one but Donald is also kind perpetually, like, put out. Right? He's always
annoyed in this one. You guys any any thoughts before we go into
the
content of the story itself? No. I don't think so. Alright. So
alright. We're gonna try to be organized about this. We have a lot of people
guessing on this one today. But if you have something to to say about a given page. I definitely wanna hear it. So lost in the Andes
opens
by
showing us Donald that one of his, like, yet another new job. He's working in a museum,
and he's clearly at the bottom of the hierarchy.
He is the fourth assistant jan or in the museum
and he gets tasked with polishing museum
stones.
He's really excited about this. He turns towards the museum collection of gems. But he he's told that he actually needs to clean a collection of rubble
from ancient inc inca ruins.
He gru about this and and he hands up living up to the third assistance nickname of butter fingers.
By dropping what seems to be a square stone only to discover that it cracks like an egg. Eric and comments I'm just wondering what a six year old eight would smell like even if it was and Al by
shell.
Yeah. And and I definitely wonder later on once when someone's gonna consume it. I think we can answer that question safely in sixty years. We're gonna gonna set one aside.
Yes. We'll be like, do you remember back in twenty twenty one?
Oh, yeah. I I already buried a couple in the yard.
Excellent.
Alright. So on the next page, he discovers that it is in fact a square egg. And he brings it to the attention of the museum leadership.
And and it's a discovery that start the scientific
world. And it creates a stir in in the scientific
the financial and the agricultural spheres.
And this excitement ends up resulting in an ex
being mounted.
Ryan, do do you mind kind commenting on those, like three different
sets of of groups that become interested in the eggs, the the museum people, the the business people and the agricultural
Yeah. Yeah.
First group, the
the kind of educated elites here,
they're all in suits and bow ties, but otherwise, they're kind of like the elite version of the aliens from the most isolated
In Star wars.
Like, there's one guy here whose head is just just a ball of fluff with two eyeballs in the middle And,
yeah, it's a good kind of mad scientist a little bit sort of collection or like the people who judge the nobel prize. And then second, we have
these kind of greedy fat cat kind of guys in a little bit different suits. He makes a point of illustrating how much their buttons shine on their shirts. Right.
And then in the third group, we have
some some yoke with big adam's apples and
odd facial hair and and straw hats
to show just kind of Al the all the different crowds of people who are just talking about what an interesting thing this is. Yeah. And and I love these panels that are showing, you know, what a stir arnold's accidental
discovery has created because I feel like there's so much, like, commentary
about these different groups packed into these individual
panels, you know, that you can you can pretty easily see Barks
perception of, like, the academic world right? This
the these like kind of kind of weirdo who are locked in their ivory tower
And then then the greed of big business
who is just looking to to exploit.
And then, you know, the the kind of plain folks of the the farmers.
Yeah anytime you have a new natural resource that's discovered, you know, it impacts all levels of society.
Yeah. Yeah. I couldn't I can imagine
what would happen in real life. Alright. So
on the next page, this is kind of all about the the x expedition itself.
And
we see the hierarchy
that we saw in the museum
kind of mirror Right? The the expedition is led by professor artifact archives.
Who is
craving and omelette.
And so he's gonna delegate the task to his assistant,
and it just keeps going down the chain of command to Donald who has gotten to become, you know, involved. I assume because of his accidental
discovery, they kinda threw him a bone,
and they're letting him come along. And
he delegates it to assistance four five and six,
who are, of course, who we doing in Louie.
Bus chewing bubble gum. And the bubble gum, of course is gonna to become very significant.
So they they go to cook the omelette, but they discover that the ship's galley has no eggs
and fateful, they decide to swipe a few of the museums
square x.
And any comments. I'm just kinda curious if
if the professor has a brother named
financial documents, mca archives, who works for the Irs or it's an content or something.
Perfect.
And are dentist the archives. Yeah. It's
like little plan words. And I love the grade a house
I don't I don't know what that is, but it's making hungry.
Great cow. That that would be milk. Right? This is
Barks kiss.
In more corn.
More car. Yeah. That's what was gonna comment on. He loves just little like identity and it quite sensitive them, you know, with the gray account corn more corn in the very first and the that museum has brought and then more rocks
Oh, yeah. And then here his and the last panel has spam
and
just the little things he does and the sides just makes it fact think he's having fun as well. And I think that's what I things it makes us enjoyable. So you can tell it's if something silly because he's been
very silly with her. Yeah. You're right. I was definitely
remiss and not mentioning the great labels on
the first page where the the stones are labeled A rock and another law too.
The this whole part part of what makes this such a classic is that it's just loaded with these awesome site gag. I think he was at the top of his side gag game here. And
aids, the eggs something to tackle about. Is just a fantastic and fantastic logo and
and tagline for the ai and consortium. Yeah... I just noticed the globe that the billionaires have there. Next to them is also egg shapes. I don't know. If not don't know they They always had an egg shaped globe or if they just got one because they're so excited about eggs now. Well, so on their heads.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, yeah. Every every panel in this one is just
So like, art
crafted to maximize
the the humor and the irony and the storytelling
this one really benefits
from multiple
readings. And and I highly recommend that you guys go back can read it a hundred twenty a hundred and thirty times the way that I have.
Alright. So on on page four,
The nephews
discover that the eggs really smell their age
and they they make the omelette and they pass it onto to Donald.
He again snaps at them to stop blowing bubble gum.
And then each of the assistance is subsequently gonna sneak a bite of the omelette kind of in their own
internal monologue. You know, they they kind of reconcile it in their own ways.
On the way up the chain of command. And each assistant finds the tastes questionable,
but none of them is really comfortable like,
stopping
the the disaster going up the chain of command and saying any Eric any thoughts. I yeah, I I looked for goofy chain of command on here where it's becoming assistant a second and Donald is so proud bring his nephews long. So he can have assistance to order around.
It's it's a great... Nope. I let's go up the latter higher than you. Absolutely.
Also,
none of them, like they don't have a good pretense
for saying, I think the sound is bad because they they would have to say, I I swiped a bite of as I was carrying it to your office boss.
Right. Just have to act like, they don't know how bad it is.
I know. I I love how this like hierarchy,
this this credit critique of hierarchy is that they've like,
been
insulated from both responsibility
and context
and and it's what kind of sets this disaster into motion.
Alright. So on to page five,
having gone all the way up the chain of command, the professor
ends up eating it and and both he and his immediate assistants are all stricken.
And we kind transition to this hilarious
diagnosis by this late forties parody of a doctor.
Yeah.
Let's see. Whose trying is, I think Ryan, you want you wanna tell us about the diagnosis.
So he has acute potomac patel of the Potomac.
And I think you probably...
I don't know if you read as a silent p or not. I think the only real word there is Home domain. I I don't know.
Know.
Tell tell us more.
It is an element in which the gastric Ducktales.
Tie themselves into square nuts.
If you if your stomach has been tied into a bow knot or a sheep shank that is completely different illness.
Potomac ketosis Al the square nuts.
So
so you can only trade it with castor oil, I guess. I've never used cast oil for anything.
I think I want to. Yeah. I I feel like it's a car thing.
So I mean,
you've seen
some of the, like, classic golden golden age cartoons, right, Old loo tunes and
This is like one of those cliche things that that little kids are always being given castor oil in those cartoons for what Al them. Feel like mary Happens maybe. Is giving the the Barks kids. Yeah. I think so. And I think it went out of style. I think it's actually potentially really bad for you. So, yeah. The rest of the page, we get them. We got some good
kind of jokes about their travels going through the horse latitude
there's a good pun where they're asked if they want anything to eat and they all respond May as they travel through there. Alright. And on page six,
by the time that they finally reach Peru,
the professor and his immediate systems have completely lost their interest and looking for eggs,
presumably because they've spent so long with with ag sickness.
And
Donald
tries to voice it off as well. But
as the only adult at the bottom of the chain of command, he is delegated with the task.
Ben any thoughts. Yeah. I just like the...
I mean, you can kinda see... Like, by this point, think I could tell the bubble down was gonna come in Al play later because they you know, i kept bringing up the bubbles popping and, you know, he's a good at, like
callbacks and things like that. So just... Yeah. So i I really noticed on this one is I'm like, okay. The bubble gums come up a few times now. And so then from then i'm like, how is that gonna play a part later?
Absolutely.
And in his reflection
He, you know, in an interview, he talked about being happy with his, like, gag riding in this one, how it's kind of builds up. I guess that was like an old rule when he was a Disney
cartoon
story border that they really tried to do with those callbacks
Yeah. I was just gonna say, I'm impressed that Donald did not get sick of the group of the people who eat me by the omelette
ones like that. So he obviously has a much shorter stomach.
Right. Or at least he recovered quicker.
I think I think Ducktales have a natural higher tolerance for eggs.
Right. Anything you've emerged from, you can handle eating, you know?
Gross. Yeah.
Gonna refrain for making the next three jokes.
Yeah. We appreciate that. Yeah. No problem. You're Barks.
Alright. So on page seven, we're kind of entering a different
phase of the story. You know, they've arrived in the Andes.
And I like how each of these pages is like a a kind of a self contained little mini episode, right, Leading up to it. So we transition to them high the Andes. They've hired Al llama.
They're they're going around making inquiries of the locals,
looking after the square eggs. But
each page, you know, is gonna see kind of a different
misunderstanding with them on the first page.
They get mistaken by a local for being dice. Eric?
Yeah. Great. I I love his animals. I love with llama. I mean, I know it is Al llama, but I can i'm just trying to figure out
dimensions in it. So... But how you figure how you talk people, but then he has this just goofy gucci Al lot
they just makes me smile every time I see is It's the happy one I've ever seen. Yeah. I I agree. I love the... Just looking at the llama that kinda cracks me up. I also I feel like comics as a medium have lost something by abandoning the dotted line showing what you're looking at. Right get on this page.
Show
what exactly the character is focused on? It's great. It's a great. It's a great mechanic. I agree. And you know, the the locals here, they're kind of a mix of of goofy
and
a little bit shady,
regular people. There... I don't feel like they're a car at all in this one. I feel like he
tried to depict them as kind of three dimensional
Right. So on page eight,
we get a a kind of a probably the goof encounter of the
story up until playing awful itself. He's gonna
encounter a very wacky man in the middle of one of those high and surges. And the guy is kind of that classic village idiot wearing wings
thinking that he can fly. But
upon learning that Donald is looking for square eggs, he appoint him the new goof guy in the andes.
What'd did you think of that Ryan? It was it was okay for a one off gag. Probably didn't merit an entire page for the one guy.
Also, we never see this guy again. So I assume he jumped off the bridge his death. With his fake fake wings on his arms.
Right. Yeah. I think this one is this is probably the page that works the least for me. This one takes me out of the the story a little bit.
I'm gonna I'm gonna disagree with both of you on that one. I would want... I would read an entire comic book series with this character as the main character.
And I would start a podcast
reviewing every single issue.
I... This this character
body everything that I'm all about and I i I... And I'm not being
sarcastic. I I genuinely like this character. Awesome. Yeah. I laundry concept
got looking to the weirdest guy keeps on trying to prove it, but keeps up finding people weird than him. I kinda want goofy to show up in one of his issues and goofy being. And I want give me to be like, dude you just kinda chill them man.
Yeah. And you know, he we don't learn
idiots name here, but
but he calls out to his friends,
Pablo Mon and Tu pack, and These are, like definitely,
you know, ke or or Inca names. Right? I know that one of the leaders of the Inca Empire was Mon to Barks, I think is his name, so I'm guessing Barks took took the names from that. I have a question. Two. So So there's four people there's... So who's Pablo Uncle quebec who here's the goofy guy. That was four. I think we don't see... Oh, of us. Right?
I'm gonna say that the guy
hosting
a
hundred
episode.
About duck com is probably the goofy sky.
So on page, page nine has the docs next encounter
and it's with a very, like sharp local
who
upon learning that the Ducktales are willing to pay fifty
pa a dozen.
He very cleverly alerts his village
using smoke signals. And when the Ducktales arrive, there are piles of square eggs conveniently waiting labeled fifty cent tablets a dozen. Now like is little work. He's like, okay. This guy. Got his number. And I'm... I'm I kinda wish they would have translated what he really sent in the smoke signal, like, incoming sucker
makes make make one thousand square eggs out of whatever you can find as fast as possible, you know. Right. And and I really like
I like this a lot. Right? Because it it gives them some agency,
You know, they've got... They've got this outsider. He's clearly
brandi money about. It kind of invert the whole, like,
exploitation
was going on around the world where and that continues too. They're they're gonna do a little bit of exploiting of of their own. It big signals. Where is that what's that was that a thing
and culture.
But I wondered about that. I I should checked in on that. If it makes sense to me. Right? That in the Andes
where you might be separated not that far as the... As the condo flies,
but that it might take, like, a day to go around a mountain you make sense. But... Yeah. I'll have to look that up. I'm gonna be ryan here and sadly really like, the exclamation point the Donald head walking into
the ability.
Seem just show surprise that excitement. Yeah. Sometimes my hat goes two feet above my head and I get really shocked too. You know what? I think I think I just came up with my halloween costume.
Yeah.
Al hat this two feet up and another two feet Gen exclamation mark. Yeah.
Spend by wires or something. Love.
Alright. So on page ten, you know, Donald runs in, he's cr looking to buy the whole lot of the eggs
the Nephews are a little bit
less
apt to be sucker. So they go to investigate. They don't they don't see any signs of chickens
but they eventually encounter the locals pouring cement in molds to pass them off as eggs
and they warn donald.
Of the scam. But yeah. I pressed the the nephews again solving the problem or, you know, realized that there's a scan going on. I'm also impressed by the fact that they have a electric
cement mixer this high the andes when they actually the
everything in by while. I don't want me to point while i that to bring that that thing up there. It's pretty convenient.
It... It's pretty convenient, but it... It makes for a great.
Oh, yeah. No. Though. It's a great day. Got just... And I'll mention too that, you know, that image of Donald brandi
w of cash was used, I think is the cover art for one of the collections of these stories that I got as a kid. So I... To me that picture there is very iconic.
And then I just... I feel like the dialogue is just so tight throughout this, but on on this page, you know, they
we've got a fun
little inversion of the name, you know, Montgomery Ward and Sears
Sears,
I think are kinda def, but it's call award and rob, cement mixer.
I didn't want us to pass by
Mcdonald's nickname for the llama
without pointing it out, but he he's telling his nephews to stop blowing that bubble and looks back at Llama, who is also now blowing Bubble gum and says, and that goes for you two, Shaggy Slacks
rides. And I i you're right. I I neglected to mention that in the summary. And that's a great part, but and and it's a throw a gag, but at the same time, it's this great sort of fore foreshadowing
of the fact that they've you know, they've taught this hap animal to to blow bubble them either it learned by osmosis, or they they taught it. But it... It's a hilarious image too. Alright. And on page eleven, they eventually reach the highest plateau and they seem to run out of people
to ask. And so the nephews come convince donald that he's gonna have to resort to breaking the eggs to just prove that it's real. And so he agrees to break one the next time they encounter a human.
And many miles later, they finally encounter
an old Vic hunter.
I appreciate
the the effort it takes. As an artist to gradually change the terrain in the background as they're traveling across the continent and they've gone from the gigantic
peaks
to
kind of some lower lower hills and now
here on this page, they're on some kind of high desert sort of thing with some big boulders and stuff and and they're definitely not up Al the, you know, machu picchu altitude anymore. There were a few pages ago.
Everything's
lot Al really different color now. And you can tell you get this sense of how far they're really traveling. Yeah. I definitely agree. I think you're right. He he does a really nice job of showing these transitions. Right? On page twelve, Donald
greet the man
He's very he's very old. He's very s.
And he breaks an egg right right in front of him. But he falls when the man shares that he hasn't been able to see a thing since breaking his glasses.
So the nephews used calm donald down, and they asked the old timer that And and I feel like they approach him, you know, in a very, like, conscious wear way, you know? To to feel the egg, And so the old man considers it very carefully. And he realizes that, in fact, he hasn't encountered them a very long time ago. Ben, any thoughts on this one? Just nothing really specific. I like it. I just noticed
in, you know,
comics like this and cartoons
you know, people faint Al lot from shock. And I I've never actually seen somebody
faint from seeing something that disturb them and I I hope before I die, then I just see somebody go. Oh, I'm just faint from seeing something that's too overwhelming for them. Someone just heavens to murder troy.
Just hope that I'm there to catch them and
you know Like is that something that happened more and now we're just so dis
because of the Internet that we just don't faint from anything we see. Yeah. I go to the furniture
and they barely have any any faint couches. Eighteen cat.
You I like the gag
to setting it up. Okay. We've before we got a few eggs. Right.
Cracking it up, and he's just... you know, just s like like a... Yeah see what.
Yeah. That was was good. Alright. So on page thirteen,
the old man, the the Vi hunter tells of when he was a little mu chat,
and he encountered a very adult
American on American
near the region of the mists
who had the stones
The man died after he came out of them, and the hunter father took the stones to the Pad and Cusco
before they must have ended up in the museum.
And so Donald asks him about this region of the mists.
And Eric, i need any thoughts on this one? It's a great
exposition. And getting the story of how the aids
got to the Museum and how come no heard of them since Yeah. I agree. This is some nice. This is really just an expo page, but it's done in this nice, like, remembrance.
Story. Yeah. And since it's well drawn,
showing you the shoulders just old the and hunter was.
Just well done I agree I find them very memorable. Alright. So on page fourteen,
the the Vic Hunter points out the mist which are not too far away. And he
sets up very nicely how it's this
hidden area where anything could be and shrouded within this deep fog. So the Ducktales. They they get very excited and they set out towards the mists
before the old man is able to warn them. But of course, have got the classic, no one who enters comes back to tell what they saw.
And when when the docs do get closer to the miss, they look very ominous
and their llama
very wisely
refuses to go any further.
Ryan, any comments. I think I've noticed also the art style,
the V hunter and then the mountains here are
drawn in a little bit of a different way. They don't have the kind of same
bright
colors
and everything they have more shading.
Yeah. They look a little more like paintings almost than the kind of cartoons
that were used to the kind of Disney look, you know. Right. They're very detailed. And
and this page has also taught me that when I'm on and unfamiliar continent and someone has told me where to go, and he says wait wait. I'm not going to rush off and just take my llama down to the
to to my doom. I think that's a good policy even if you're on.
Yeah. Yeah. And I'm gonna point out in the lower left panel where you can see the mists that some of them look very ominous
like yeah tend or clause reaching out. It looks
extremely threatening. My only my only criticism is probably a limitation. This would have been a great
you know, full page or half page panel. And I love the pushing the stubborn
llama forward. Right. So on page fifteen,
the Ducktales make camp, and by morning, the mists have rolled in and they're completely surrounded by fog.
They get separated briefly and in the process of finding each other. They end up losing sight of their camp. And they're they're quickly
completely lost. Got some of the kind of classic foggy art or the artist it's maybe a little bit of a break here. And any comments
Like, how we handle the the... you know, it's a unique challenge, You know, how do you handle that with Silhouette or I thought i handled the art... A style really well And I do feel like he does a good job of kind of conveying how
lost and frightened this must feel for them. Yeah. Yeah. Like, like said, I like the the silhouette with the kind of lines matching through it. Right. So on page sixteen, the docs wonder for for hours and they eventually bump into a mysterious wall that they say resembles, those, the ink is built.
They feel along it for an opening
and they come to a point where a block has fallen out. They crawl through expecting to emerge safely, but instead, they fall through empty space. Eric. Any you comments? I think it's great to expect, you know, we don't know where we're going. But this whole little bit of terror of
when go export I'll sudden shu. He's gone.
And man listen to somebody in the dark.
You get this sorted really fast enough and lose i've got minutes. That's creepy.
Yeah. Right. On page seventeen,
the Ducktales free fall for a little while, and then they land fairly safely on a grass
incline, which slopes
down. And they're
They're eventually stopped by another wall and they comment on how warm it's gotten.
Peer over the wall, they see a block lost world.
Beneath the fog.
And, you know, this is the panel that I was referencing
where he
he kinda criticized himself for his
perspective.
But...
But, you know, that's not something that I ever noticed reading it. And and this is one of those
very famous panels and I think is
does a great job of setting the the rest of this story up here.
Ryan any thoughts?
Yeah.
I like the top half of this page is four panels that are kind of cut out of one one rectangle into interesting shapes. Yeah. It gives
actually kind of a sense of the motion. You can see them falling in the
ink blackness on the top and then the panel below that there start to hit the
incline and slide down the down the grass.
Yeah. It feels kind of experimental.
Yeah, Al little bit. And then and then having them
arrive in my craft is also a little bit wrong.
Right. Any any kid reading this one today is gonna immediately think of minecraft and
when they see this.
Because it is one of the Nephews used comments,
sure is a block look place.
Which, you know, is gonna be very press and. Right. So on
page eighteen,
the Ducktales observe the place for a little while. And they note that there isn't anything round in the whole area.
Donald is convinced that this must be where square eggs come from for the boys caution him to be wary of the potentially savage
inhabitants.
And so Donald approaches a little more cautiously.
Then he gets surprised by the boys bubble gum popping again. We've got a little reminder of the the bubble gum going. Ben any comment.
Yeah. So when I saw... I mean, in addition to the Minecraft,
my first
thought when I started when they start getting into the
you know, how embedded the square of everything is into...
There's a rick and morty episode where they've the land on a corn kong planet.
And
they look like, oh, yeah. There's corn the cob. This is a perfect... Planet to stay on and they look in the mountains or shaped like corn com and everything, and then he he's like, oh, wait a minute. And he gets a microscope and he looks and everything
a corn cobb even at the atomic level and he just...
Let's get out of here. We Al. There's everything's scored go.
And like, when they get sick with the, you know, eating the egg, and it ties their stomach into squares and, you know, that's that's it's just like something in the Dna
of
vibration in the in the space. Just it just...
It seems like it's more than just
Oh, let's just shape this into the squares. There's... You like that that there's no real explanation for why everything. Yeah.
It's it's beyond just like, oh, architectural, we think it just makes sense to do things in squares. Like, there's there's something deeper that they never really get into, but
I've gotta assume it's coming out of those, like, volcanic events that are keeping.
Yeah.
So, you know, this page
feels weird to me a little bit because when I first read this story, I mentioned that it was in a collection of, like, it was a collection of ten Barks stories, and they excise a few parts of this one. To fit it in. And I'm sure they went for, you know, the parts that weren't totally critical to this story. But this page, most of the panels from this were just cut out.
So
it always feels a little bit out of place to me.
So by the next page,
the ducks send cautiously into the city and they hide behind the large Cubic rocks so that they can observe the situation and eventually one of the inhabitants approaches and he shocks the ducks by singing the very famous
southern Anthem
dixie.
And they're further shocked to see that the person
is
very block. He himself is sq
or Qb or whatever.
And Donald goes to approach him, at least knowing that they can speak the same language, at least the corn version.
Eric.
I have four children
and I was involved
in all four of their births
and the notion of a square headed person being born.
Right me for all the women in this society. Oh, yeah. I'm just putting that... I'll square rooms make it a little easier.
Sure. I can just... I'm just saying as we you know.
For all we know these guys also hatch from square.
This is true. We don't know.
Shaped like squares, I think they're fine. Just you don't... You just don't wanna have a
a a round in a square together.
It's right. Yeah. There's so much going on in this page. You know? Just... And and then this is one of those things that's very out of time. Right? Like,
Donald and the boys are definitely not southern,
but
I think Dixie was one of the most famous songs in the world. At this or in the country, excuse me. Sure. At this time.
And, you know, it's very controversial
for obvious reasons today, but there's there's none of that and here it's just... This is a song that you would have heard all over the place back then. You guys all know the song Dixie?
No it I think a little bit. I can I they had to to my head of bag don't ask me repeat it. That's fine. I'll I'll go ahead and put it in right here
At least snippet it. But this is you know, the expression West dixie.
Alright. So on the next page, the Ducks introduced themselves and the be
inhabit is shocked to learn that these queer looking folks are from America.
He alerts the rest
and and they excited yell about this being the first time they've had Americans for dinner since eighteen
sixty eight, and the only time.
And then the docs have, of course interpreted this to mean that they are to be the dinner. As they're nervous hustle into the main dining room. I I like... I liked
flipping
one of the oldest strokes of, you know, the aliens arrive and we would like to have you for dinner.
And like oh, yeah. That would be great. That sounds great. I would love to have dinner with you guys.
And they just are oblivious to what's going on and that these guys who are totally innocent and have never eaten anything in their lives besides square eggs.
Would like to invite their new guests, a new American guests to have some square eggs with them, but these guys are certain. These these weird alien cute people are going to are going to try to eat us. Right.
Right. You know. And they're obviously lee. They've they've wondered if they're savage.
And we're getting just this really quick
introduction to what we're about to learn is is playing awful. You know. We we learn very quickly that the inhabitants are these very cheerful
optimistic friendly people. I think it's it's really interesting. This is a big part of why the story stands out so much is that this is a very unusual
group for these like loss
civilization. Stories were most of the time they are hostile. And
yeah. And I just love the the brief passage
through their city, you know, and the the architecture that we see and the taste of it that we get. Alright. And on page twenty one,
the president of this place informs them
that they are just showing them some good old southern
hospitality.
That they don't need to worry about being eaten.
Well Donald asks them questions about their knowledge of America and how they know English, the Nephews focus on the banquet,
which the first course is poached eggs.
Then the president explains they learned English from their only other visitor, professor Rut Bet from the Bum
where Birmingham
school of English. And then we see the second course is scrambled eggs. Ben any comments I mean, technically, they are more southern than we are. So, I mean,
have to have it right. And and it's interesting that we never really, like, kind of acknowledge the fact that, you know, the ducks have these very round face. And so there's that
inconsistency. Right? You. But we just have to kind of... They accept
the American culture, you know, they they gave some allowances for it. Right. Ryan did you have something?
Yeah. I didn't catch on the first reading how Ironic it is that the only other guy, the guy who taught them to talk this way is a professor from the school of English and and
he he talks like he's getting some shrimp in the by you.
And I would guess that this is kind of supposed to be that very deep south. He's from Bum and. Right? So... Yep. So it's it's meant to be
Alabama, but you could read it as Georgia. We're we're really supposed to evo that, like, reconstruction era. What do you think, Eric?
I'd love... I I love this and I love the continued reference of the map having this extremely
extremely
very Al use spring
with wild rice dressing.
What
That's what they're initially hoping to get. Yeah. And like, in so of the comments, he used these Huey,,
these nephews just, like, well, what I'm hoping for mean, was it was last from watched third or something where we went to the bear.
Fair mountain. And they expect all this nice food they get like, i'll day. I I just love it so much. Eric, this this issue didn't remind you of the of the the way your mom used to cook spring between for you all the time when you were growing up. Okay. Sadly no. We had work the the the autumn, very definitely to meet in the different season of the year. That makes sense.
Alright. So on page twenty two, the conversation continues and I love this kind of parallel track with Donald getting information and the Nephews is just focusing
on the food.
And and they confirmed that the professor was in fact the Dying man who had encountered the vic hunter.
The third course, boiled eggs comes along with the
confirmation that the eggs are the national dish.
So after the banquet with the Ducktales look for an alternative meal, and they find a diner, but they are dismay to learn that there is nothing to eat, but eggs many, many ways. Yeah. I I just worry about the diet of these people with all their eating eggs. I mean, I really worry.
Yeah. And No Vegetables and fright. And I think Don rose kinda gonna touch on that in his sequel where he like very specifically calls the eggs out as being super mineral rich.
Etcetera. What do you think, Ryan?
I think this is the...
This is Disney's
predecessor to the Gladstone diet
Twelve thousand.
Until you're roughly the size of the march. That's right. And you know... But you know what, Ryan aren't most Barks kind of sq in shape.
Oh, man.
I'll all come together.
Yeah. I just love the pacing on this too. Just the the cut to the president saying well, to begin with, they is on national dish.
So on on page twenty three, you know, upon learning that it's only eggs to eat. The Ducktales are puzzling at this. Obviously wondering about the absence of of chicken.
But the cook has no idea what they are talking about. And and he reveals that the professor from Bum
had the same frustrating
exchange with them. And I I gotta stop in the middle of this page. The the exchange that Donald has with the
diner cook where he jumps up on the counter after the guy asks, what is chickens and he just yells chickens is the guys that lays these eggs. I think this is one of Barks funniest exchanges
ever, because he goes trying to say that's what the professor from Bum used to Al. Ain't nobody ever seen one. I love this moment so much. I noticed the ducks once again
that when he tells them nobody's ever seen a chicken, they all get the papers again. Al all backwards off there they're too.
Right. And just a pretty hard looking surface to land. It is. You have all the all the faint couches in country made out of square granite. So.
And and on the way out of the diner, you know, one of the villagers
innocently Barks if there's been any new songs
coming out in America since Dixie,
and Donald just very sn says, yes. Chico.
And I think that was a contemporary song that, like, was actually about a chicken. So that's appropriate. They live the chicken who would say.
All.
So that shit got sick and tired of just
jacob. So one morning he started to say
Again, I'll I'll probably put a moment Al link here. I I I could tell there was some kind of joke or something in that last
frame I wasn't getting
whether it was a song done loose making up or whether it's actually something that's popular in the Us at this time of the comic.
Or at least or at least in the last sixty years around long it's been since these guys are dixie.
Yeah. And I I think I'm not sure, but I think the joke is that it's kind of like us throw away of obnoxious,
you know, songs. Not like, it's not a serious song even apart from being about a chicken obviously.
So it's like us us saying, yes, Rebecca Black, Friday, this right. This is the new song that we're all into now, enjoy.
Old time Road. Yeah.
Alright. So on page twenty four, the Ducktales are pondering the situation. And then the next morning,
they ask a lady where
where the eggs that they're getting come from and she directs them to aid Valley through a pass in the distance. And there they see a bunch of square rocks but no signs of chickens.
Impressed by the dedication to square clothes these people have and just how Nope. It's gotta be square. Yeah put square test on. Yeah.
Where little hands.
I assume made entirely of eggs. Oh, or granite. That sometimes who the resource they had. It was half expecting to see a philosopher just saying, oh, the egg clearly came first.
Yeah. That does seem like a
a a missed opportunity for.
Alright. So on the next page twenty five,
Donald goes up to explore the cliffs while the nephew stay in this valley to investigate. And in the process of blowing their bubble gum and attaching around bubble,
Huey, dewey and Louis inadvertently discover that the rocks in the valley are actually the civilizations missing chickens all folded up. And the chickens are just
enraged by the bubble. Which really should be a clue, but the boys
some and uncle donald. Eric.
Just how much gum did these boys pack?
I mean I know they've got limited amounts of their the their hats and pockets, but, like,
so much.
I'm impressed. And the old days man, you could make... You could make one piece of gum last forever. You just chew that same piece of gum for a month Right.
Stick it under hat when you're not chewing it taking that later. Also,
I like that the chickens are apparently
has transformers.
Because they cracked like a an ordinary square block. But then all of a sudden they have, like, a red, you know, rooster comb and and
Ducktales
and everything they they completely.
Well now I wanna make a minecraft skin to re res the chickens to look like this.
Yes. Oh, yeah.
Yeah. And I love this page. I love this development in the story. This is such an audacious
like plot development.
I love the character designer the animal design as well on these chickens and rooster.
And so on page twenty six, we cut to a celebration. We transition to the Ducktales being herald for their discovery,
which makes them all time heroes of what they come to learn is called plain awful,
which is what the the professor from Bum
dubbed it.
And and they get made
the secretaries
of agriculture.
You know what? Before I forget, I do wanna take a quick moment to mention i'm stop the podcast dead and its tracks and and mention just a few more of those
global names for plain awful.
I I I love the name of the the civilization. It's one of the best gag to me.
So in Italy,
they named this one Tesla quad, which is something like square head. It was jam hao,
who shared that in norway,
it was called. So the name of the story was actually Ego miss dead,
so the egg mystery.
Okay. So in Norway, it was called Gu
so it's something like a cold place.
And this was shared to me by.
In greece, the city is called
Mono
or Mono from
nico
And then in Netherlands, they call it do Al, which means something like a dull misery from early
leaf.
And then in Indonesia,
listener Ari Factory.
Told me that it's negative U, which loosely translates to the country of villagers.
And then finally, valued listener Pierre Son tells us that in Swedish, it is called
Av viral.
And the literal meaning is world of disgust or disgusting world. And he lets us know that it's also a fun word play in Swedish. That means something like ab, to test or awful.
Alright. So
thank you listeners and hosts for ind me, but I was really interested. How they treated that around the world. Alright. So immediately after they get made the secretaries of agriculture, the nephews
demonstrate the bubble blowing feet that did flush out those chickens. And the plane
are a.
And,
you know, it turns out that they have violated plane awful
one and only law that says however produces a round object must spend the rest of his life in the dreaded stone q.
But the president
suspend their sentence for five days in consideration of their service.
Alright, Ryan, my second reading, this reminds me of and I can't remember which specific comics it is now. But this is the second or maybe third time that a strange lost civilization
has condemned them to be executed
or
imprisoned or come back to the death or something like that based on having broken end up your law. Right? What am I looking?
We had the measles in mystery of the swamp sentence.
Donald to that goofy game of theirs. And I think that's the only other lost civilization one we've had so far. And oh and I'm also thinking of when Donald was made like the the ruler of something,
but the... Oh, yeah. In the
Mah Donald. Yes. And they have that obscured. Yeah. They they
turn him into the the Tiger arena. Yeah. Yeah. That's that's probably what I'm thinking of. Right. It feels like it feels like even though it's a completely different event, it feels like the same kind of kind of a most a weird sentencing.
Yeah. Yeah. Of, you know, nobody could have expected this bizarre
you know, that any some random behavior would be fatal or in this case, you know, sentence to mind in the minds forever. Right.
I i the question too in the plain tony printing of this comic book, that they blur out those bubbles
No. That's a good guy they're all censored. It's pixel pixelated sense
big enough pixels, then it's all squared anyway.
On a on a side note, I was watching a Tv show called reservation dogs and there's a scene where there's, like, eyes and they they blur out the allies because in Native American culture apparently, there's some reason i thought it was kinda Al it's fascinating.
That's awesome that they they, you know, respected that. On page
twenty seven
Donald
asks what what they can do, what the kids can do to redeem themselves. The president dramatically reveals that on the day of judgment,
they must stand before the multitude on the grand alter stone of the succulent egg and glow
square bubbles.
And and the kids are dis dismay, of course they have five days to learn and,
you know, we we had to see their first couple of days.
It's not going well their efforts to learn to blow square bubbles.
And time and Bubble gum are in short supply. I I love the very dramatic flourish, you know, of their sentence. I I love the pacing on this page. Any thoughts, Eric?
I'd love the idea of having to blow where square bubbles and, like, they're unwilling everybody with these bubbles is finally come to get them in the end, even though it was because of the bubbles
they found the chickens. Right now, it's like, this is
a cartoon about blowing bubbles. Right. It it both it's gonna get them into and out of trouble.
And I guess there must be a little
me... Is that musical notation on the bottom right of this page. Is that like a a flat note? That is Al flat. Yes. Okay. Alright. Turns a fun gag if you because the no bread twists is the one you kind of that igloo blue one that's kinda flat also the pops and gives Al flat though. Right. So that's a clever gag for people who are more musically
inclined than I am. What else
I...
You know, it it occurred to me to wonder if it was possible to blow a square bubble, so I googled it, and
no one's done it with bubble gum that I'm aware of. But I saw one of those like, sort of mister wizard or, you know, there was the science kids science entertainer who built like this
special cubic frame with kind of suspended
suspended frame inside. And apparently using that is possible to blow a square bubble with soap sides. It's it's well worth taking a look on Youtube. It's probably a Youtuber that my kids watch frequently.
Right.
Alright. So on page twenty eight, we see the... Meanwhile. The citizens of playing awful will have gone chicken and crazy.
They're tending their newfound chickens. We get a a gag with one man bragging about his prospective regulators. All same cock doodle do. Again, it's a cute gag that's also gonna be a nice foreshadowing. And then the nephews are taking a little break. They find some newly hatched very cute chips.
But Donald snaps at them to get back to blowing. And let's see. Ryan, any thoughts?
I think we should point out the way they're trying to...
These people who have never encountered an animal lower on the food chain than them before and
So one guy has boiled this bird thirty six hours, and he's still telling.
Right. Yeah. I I love it. Everyone knows. You don't boil meat for more than twenty, twenty five hours management right. Right. I also imagine that the chickens, you know, are just based on the fact that they're very rock like, they're probably already really tough. That's probably true. Right? So on twenty nine,
we transition to their judgment day where the Nephews and the president who who... You know, he's really he's rooting for them. He's just... I think he feels like his hands are tied. They're both very anxious.
And then the the comic sort of camera
perspective rises above the fog line And then incredibly, when we see the nephews, they're doing it. They're blowing the square eggs. Everyone's excited and cheering. And then when the tunnel and shouting dies down, Donald
privately asked them how that they how they did it? And they reveal that they secretly
trained those baby chicks to blow bubbles from inside their shirts.
And and I I love the resolution here. I love how it's been set up so masterfully.
I love how clever it is. I I just... I love everything about this
page.
But
Maybe not everyone does. Ben? Yeah. I liked it, you know, the I his optimism how he's rooting for them to blow the squares also known as Square rooting.
Maybe that's where the origin of the work came from. I'm sure it is.
Right. The nature
term.
Kudos. Yeah. Yes. Yes. Well, well done then.
Alright. So
you know, we've we've gotten the big resolution
but on page thirty, you know, we still have a big problem kind of outstanding. They're they're saved, but the Ducktales still trapped and plain awful because they don't have any way to safely get through that fog with the load of chickens and eggs they anticipate having. And while Donald ponder the situation, the Nephews check inside a building that turns out to be the local museum.
And they they date their artifacts from
Bp b
before the professor from Bum
and and they encounter a magic Huey, gizmo on display made of brass given by the professor. And on closer examination, they're delighted to discover that it is a compass.
Eric. The throw comment
what do these guys have that's worth saving is
fantastic.
To
that's.
Like it's rocks and Barks, and aids. That's it. There's nothing here. Right. Because the only other thing they have to display that we see is, like an ancient egg.
Alright. So on page thirty one, the president
agrees that they will part with the compass if the Ducktales can teach the citizens something to improve their good spirit.
You know, which is just a nice little
illustration again of how how warm and positive if naive these the plain Al are.
So the Nephews cleverly volunteer to teach them square dancing.
Which is the last thing that we can hear the last trace of plane awful
as they journey from out of the valley. And then we transition to days later where the Ducktales finally make it through the fog and they stagger out into the sun. And there's a nice moment where they kinda sit and reflect on how the plane
have never even seen the sun,
but they receive warmth from those volcanoes that we see
and from their kind heart, which, you know, it's it's sac, but we we see it. So I feel like it's very organic and nice. And then the Ducktales take stock of what's left of their cargo, and it's just two chickens.
And so they celebrate the expedition
success Thanks to as Donald points out his brains and the Nephews used pipe pipe in a few lines of bubble gum. Ryan, and their backpacks are of course cube cuba.
Because they didn't have any stuff left. That all stuff was on the llama that wouldn't go down the into the fog. So they had to I guess pick up some backpacks from their new hosts here. Right. What else could it be? I'm surprised that they didn't bring more
stuff when they've discovered a lost civilization that's really hard to find. You know, I mean, one of the nephews carrying a backpack, why don't have why not have all three nephews that get Barks.
Right. It would've have fit nicely. It would stick nicely in their bag too everything exactly.
Square. Right. Yeah. Yeah. You just put in, you know, twenty five eggs five hundred and twenty five eggs. However they fit. Well, they do having to... They do reference having to eat all the eggs. Right? I I get the impression that their journey through the fog as is pretty long. And then and then we've seen from the museum, but there aren't really any other artifacts that they can bring from plain awful because they don't seem to have anything else.
That's true. You could bring some of those perfectly square loin cloth that everybody wears down there. Right.
And you know what for the first, like, six to eight years
of my reading this story and that original this is actually where the story ended on this kind of reflective
panel on the second to last page because the last page was one of the ones that this publication chose to to leave out. So don't was this very funny cap at the end. As on page thirty two, they get back to Duck.
And Donald delivers the chickens to the group of researchers that that examine them in amazement.
And they're they're very excited they're like, we can use this pair to breed a new race of super poultry. And just then one of the...
One of the chickens rev up to Crow, but to everyone's
Dismay, they both crow and they turn out to both be rooster.
And so the ducks leave Huey, humiliation
They go to a diner where the pork cook makes the mistake of offering them a choice of ham and eggs, a cheese omelette or roast chicken. And we get a nice comic sting. It's one of those calling all cars.
It informs us that an angry duck is wrecking a certain dining car. And that That is how plain awful
or the story lost in the Andes ends. Ben do you have any comments on that last
page there? I mean it's Disney, so they should just look for the presence of a pink bow on one of the one of the chickens. But right. Yeah. And I like that, you know, he establishes
earlier on that they all do seem to look the same. What did you think Ryan?
To ben's point, you could also look for longer eyelashes. Because anything that's female has long eyelashes.
Right. But I I do feel like this is also
like a wrap up of... I think three times, Donald says, if ex, then I going to start a war. And he he's just... He's just ready to blow up on somebody. He knows he's about to he never quite does until the end when the guy offers him some some eggs and
and he's like, you know what this is it. It's time for me to tear this place.
True. Yeah. It's an it's another of those great callbacks.
So we we've got all these nice layers of callback and gag and I just feel like they come to fruition
so nicely at the end of this one. So you know, I have already
kept my my hat that I just love this story. This is in, you know, the handful of my very favorite Barks stories.
I have read this just just so many times, and I could probably sit down and happily read it every month or so.
It's been a bedtime story
to my to my oldest kids. It's one of the few Barks stories that I've read to to both of them. Twice now and my youngest I'm sure I'll get to before too long.
So so I absolutely
love this one. And
I have maybe some very minor criticisms around the edge,
but I I think that this is as close to a perfect Barks story as it gets.
I'm gonna let's go in that same order.
Eric, I know that you mentioned you love it. You you told us a little bit about it. But any other reflections on
your thoughts? Where does this stack? Would you would you consider this one a favorite? Are there stories that you've enjoyed more? I think it's a favorite.
Absolutely.
Just to creativity Al all. Of Al lost civilization Andes. Who is bloodthirsty bursting or crazy? They're just nice simple,
and it's the advanced the advanced the know side the come in I think the place awful, but the news are happy content. Yeah. So it's it's the outsiders says say, let's sucks. Well, you know, that's that's your opinion. But they happy to them this is places great we love it. And the other notice is these square chickens are absolutely
adorable.
Yeah. I love the look of them so cartoony and so imaginative.
I think they're one of the creations I've seen know he has fun paying out of different... you know, with creatures here in there. They're absolutely or with their q.
Yeah. I love them post. Made mid crow, you know, at the same time on the last page. It's it's great. And and the check versions of them are really cute too. And that's a good point you made to, you know, the contrast, like at the beginning with the academic and the business people and the agricultural people. Everyone's like in this sort of rat race mindset.
You know? And and then the the plane off, they're very simple, but they're obvious Al. Just just exceedingly happy with their Al lot in life. I mean, who i under heard the freight tales of the lost Utopia me in the mountains. You and with me go plug over they're offline piece and i you know, be perfect and great. That's true. They found one, but it's great for those people
not for you. Yeah. You're
referring to the classic, like, S law of of lost horizon. And this is
the best example so far of them finding one up until
up until a story
several dozen issues from now, which will directly parody that. Another another all time great. That will we'll have Fun getting to. What about you, Ryan? What are your
thoughts on this one? It it sounds like this one wasn't
as much of a favorite for you, which which is fine, you know, different opinions
all around. How do you think it's stacked up to the other as you've read?
I think I think it is one of the best ones.
Right on. I
I like to ghost to the g more where their
they meet the the night and the sunken ship. Yeah. Everything.
I think that was a really tight story. And and
I like some
some
Alaskan survival. Was that frozen gold? Yeah. Yeah. Frozen gold. Yeah. Yeah.
But this is... I think this is up there. I'm I'm noticing now on the second reading.
If you look at the second page, there's... When they show the ship,
after we look at the professors and then the building billionaires on Wall Street and then the yoke on their farm talking about the chickens. The next frame is the the ship that they're leaving on. And in the foreground, you can see
it looks like a fish eat... I want to eat a smaller fish and then a seagull coming down to eat that fish. And then if you go to the very last page here, the very first frame is the ship returning to America and you see the fish eating the bird. It is
getting
revenge for the fish.
No.
That's phenomenal. I I never caught that in all those readings.
Partially because it's on that last page that I didn't read as many times. Yeah. I just gone. I was just looking at this page my eyes wondered and I was like, what the heck is going on right now?
Yeah. It's great. Great background, gag. Yeah. Awesome. What about you, ben? Yeah. This is definitely
out of the fuse that I've read definitely my favorite. You know, I I love how they just that have the absurdity of the main theme
round things versus
square things, and it's not just like you're stereotypical,
like, oh, they're going to find the golden near the, you know, the jade bracelet or, you know, they just... No. It's just... They're looking for
square egg. And so also just like the way it wrapped up in the end, you know. And they never quite... And I I know a lot of the, like, golden generic comics that I have red. It's
kinda wrapped up too nicely. And, you know, there's a lot of wish fulfillment of like, oh, the guy gets the girl, you know or again, and everything
has a happy ending and So I was kind of a surprised to see some of as old as some of these are, just like... You know, they always just
deflate the... Or, you know, they just undercut or be take
It's like
nope this.
It's kinda of this noble failure.
Right? Yeah. And it's it's pretty common nowadays, but, yeah
and maybe he's one of the people who kinda pioneered that concept of, you know, the, like, the... Joseph Campbell store circle where end up back at the... you know, the we can't end up with wells and riches at the end. You gotta end up right back where you restarted.
Right. But I and I and I just love the calling dog Barks and that like it's just a perfect way to end it. So... yeah. I definitely think it's
the my favorite that I've read so far. Good. I'm I'm glad to hear it. I i... Those are good points. I think even people who don't consider this when they're favorite. Like, there's no denying just how wildly
creative and invent it is. And it does such a good job of tying everything together. Yeah. I I it also really benefits from those reread, you know, as you
notice things more and more. And and many of his stories do, but this one in particular, I think.
And I've I've already characterized this as one of the community's favorites. Right? We... This is one of the the stories that you think of when you think of Carl Barks on index, the
community sourced
website where people rank these. This one is is an eight point six which is good for number six
out of all the forty one thousand some disney comic stories that are ranked. So this is just in the top tier.
It's basically tied for first. There are a handful of stories that are ranked higher. I need to double check, but I do think that this is the highest one that doesn't have uncle Scrooge in it. A question about that know the oil artwork these send. It does have sc inserted into there. Did they, like, re on this with sc later.
Yeah. That's a good question.
I
was gonna talk about that a little later, but this is as good time as any. So, you know, Barks famously did a lot of these oil paintings of his stories later on
in the end of his career is very long career. And for this one,
he did do a great oil painting.
A version of his cover that
Donald, you know, reaching
for a square egg, but I sent you guys an image of his return to plain awful oil painting.
I don't know. This is kind of a chicken and egg question. I don't know if he did the painting
first and Don Rosa
when on to
do a sequel to this one, called return to plain awful or, you know, if if they kinda did it in conjunction with each other. But
Don Rosa is is another artist who's kind of regarded by many, many people as the closest thing Barks has to an air.
He did a lot of sequels to these stories.
And he did a direct sequel
where the Ducktales returned
this time with their uncle sc,
and, you know, I I hope to do some
podcasts of some of those rosa stories Sunday. I just love return to plain awful. It gets it gets flint gl gold in there. And, you know, you it really almost writes itself
because you can easily imagine uncle Sc wanting to mount expedition.
For these eggs. But but as much as you imagine where that might go, he he really elevate the premise.
And it's just a wonderful story. I actually read it before I read the original. So going back and reading lost in the Andes or that kind of made a lot of that click for me. Eric, have you read his sequel to this story?
Yeah. I have a copy it. Awesome. Yeah. And and inside the comic, there is a little poster version of this.
Think I might have had that hanging up in the room that in one of the houses that we all live in.
So I've never been able to afford any of Barks oil paintings or lift graphs, but,
you know, I appreciate that at least once, they put out a little poster version of one of them. Let's see.
Some reflections.
We already talked about what's dated an archaic. And we kinda talked about the fact that there's really not too much problematic about this one. Nothing is too retro it. So that's a nice. It's nice to not have talk about that. We talked about those oil paintings just now. And then the only other time these characters have been used is in that don rose sequel return to plain awful,
which it doesn't get classified nearly as high as the swim. But it's also
very well regarded on index. It's like in the top two hundred stories. I do think it's a missed opportunity that neither of the Ducktales series. Ever tried to tackle this story because I think it could have been...
It could have been interesting. On the other hand, I'm sure it wouldn't have lived up to my ex expectations
of lost in the andes.
No. And then I do like to talk about educational value. You know, I feel like this one was actually very illuminati
life in the Andes,
at least some of the incidental...
What did you think Ryan?
I wanted to tell you that I have confirmed that in
used a swift message surface with smoke signals on the summit of the andes from Peru to Chile. Awesome. Thank you for checking that out. You know, My memory said that they did and it and it made sense that they do. Favorite panel is is really challenging for me because I I just love almost every panel of this one. A few of them just in brief that really stood out to me as the hilarious one with all the museum search, you know, Ryan described them just looking like a a ridiculous
collection of of
goof academic goof Barks. I I did mention that I really like that. To me it's iconic Donald clutch the money. That that first shot where we see the last civil is stands out to me. And then the x the the panel where they say, well, the expedition is success. It's that's in some pretty nice silhouette. But it... But if if impressed, I do think that I would have to go for that panel that made me laugh so hard the one where Donald is is yelling about how chickens is the guys that lays these eggs. A lot of the panels around the judgment day, though are are really cool as well. So sorry. I I I... I'm having a hard time limiting myself. Let's go on reverse order this time. Ben, do you have
Do you have a favorite panel that stood out to you? Well, not counting the one where either, there's got big wide shot of the
square city from above, but I but the one that stood out was... I like the reaction shot of Donald when he eats the egg in the beginning and and just that like yeah.
Disgusting. That's a a nice reaction shot. I agree. Donald is great, and and all of the
assistance have some great great reactions there all in very different ways. Yeah. What about you, Ryan? Any any favorite panels that come to mind? Another one that I think was just
done really well. Artistic, it's... I think about page fifteen here. It's the last frame before they go into the fog
they're just around their fire
as night is coming in, and we have Donald and lone nephew in the foreground Al silhouette except for their eyes and then more enough the background lit up by the fire
and you can see
kind of the texture of the around they're sitting on and you can see that deep blue of the night settling and around them. It's just
good colors good layout. It's
he's a good artist. Agreed. That that is an awesome one What about you Eric? I I I gotta stick with the chickens. I love them so much if when they find them, there's the chicken with the bubble on rear and it's head cracking up, You know, turn backwards and the boys like No. The roger.
And then the chicken's attacking them because of the bubbles. It's just it's it's it's great because it's also a U boot bubbles blowing public full time annoying everybody. Now you're getting the payback. Per not I think that then say stop bubbles. But the chicken i just... I love the chicken so much. Yeah.
More great choices.
Any additional thoughts
Alright. My question is square aids. It's just such a random idea and obviously, go like, look, Al way it's stack nicer. Sports earthquakes come from this whole yard this whole crazy venture since like it's spun the idea. Where would you get squarespace from? The score and then goes from there. It's a it's a great exercise of of of of story writing of this
extrapolate and they based on the whole thing and it's been fantastic. Personally, I aside from the perspective of Carl Barks was chewing gum and he he was trying to blow Al square bubble.
And then the eggs came off of that idea and then he's like... Yeah. Like man, I love blowing and bubble gum. I love doing all day long. I can't.
People keep shouting and me to stop blowing it, but I'm never gonna stop.
Yeah. I I I do like to think kind of ponder, you know, how the story being about. So that that is fun
also like to add them a little disappointed. If you were going to take sponsorships,
you should have gotten squarespace on this episode Yeah. Our square
payment processing,
you know, just... Wear soft the square
I guess, I guess are now
square en. Yes. That's right. This yeah square you. Yep. You know, a couple things that I
neglected to mention is just the fact that you know, we've got that slang for
square. Right? The plane off
Are literally square, but they're also kind of the slang term square.
And I associated out with the sixties, but when I looked it up, it it was coming into v
around this time. So I think that's intentional. You know, that we've also got the slang in America block heads and that was never like directly mentioned.
There, but, you know, there are simple people. So Eric, could you had another comment.
Yes. Real really quickly. The only other thing that I forgot to mention I I gloss over the value range.
This one's a little bit later, but it is a significant story. So I did find that a nine point four copy a nine point four copy was sold fairly recently for fifty five hundred dollars. So pretty good value. I'll go for it. Okay. Square,
square chickens, but yet,
circular goats.
Yeah.
So man.
Yeah. There's there's a few inconsistencies. Well and when, like the first tea when donald cox and falls open, it's a circular
would figured would be and more fun the square.
Right. And I have definitely buddy but he did crack it outside of
playing awful set nope you know, you could poke holes where holes into this. But
but that but I think on the whole it just works wonderful. Yeah. Just like we.
Us Round have square things in our world too. You know, There's a little over left. That's true. Yeah. Thank you, guys. I know that this one has been
very involved. We're we're clocking out at... Let's see two hours of raw recording here. We'll see we'll see what I can edit it too. After we and out all my swearing and be like quite a bit shorter.
Alright.
So
I am just gonna gonna say thank you guys again very much.
I do hope that people will come back for our next
episode. That is... I... you know, be be there or be square. Right? Mh.
We are stick around.
Yes
we're gonna be talking about Voodoo who...
Oh, yeah. Rx do you know that one? Yeah. Familiar. Yeah. That that one is gonna be a challenging one. Going from one that is remembered as one of the all time greats
to another one that's also remembered as a great, but with with a few glaring issues we'll set. Yeah. Please please come back
folks have been very kind to, you know, reach out to us here and there. We can be reached on Facebook, parked from Remarks Barks remarks at g dot com
we've had a handful of people click the review button
and leave us five star reviews, which I'm just incredibly grateful for for a, like small niche podcast like this that's super meaningful. So thank you all very much. And
and what's what's a good way to go out on this one guys. Someone square. It's hip to be square. What what do you got Ryan? I I was glad that Eric got one forth
Then. I you know, I got I got my square root one in. I don't think i'm gonna top that. So I went yeah. Alright.
Thanks again, guys. Have a good one.
Alright. And before we finish, I wanted to bring back my daughter Mia for the ask a kid segment.
She would never forgive me if I didn't let her talk about lost in the Andes.
So Mia remind us what grade are you in? Fifth grade. And what is your opinion of lost in the andes? I think it's a great one. It's it's probably my favorite one. That's awesome.
What did what did you enjoy about it? I just thought it was funny Did you like the square chickens and the square chicks? Yeah. Those are really funny. Excellent. Any other funny parts that you wanted to talk about? I like it when
the nephews
had to blur square bubbles and tricks
the people
and they use the chicks to the square bubble
Yeah. Awesome. That... That's a wonderful part. Alright. Well, thank you so much mia for joining us again.