Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of sc Mc and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge cl of all time, join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context, and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Just a brief content warning, nothing bad. Just My c host and I are going to be talking about the existence of a certain
man of Christmas.
So if you're listening with little kids and you wanna preserve certain childhood illusions, you might not wanna have them around.
Hello, and welcome back to Barks remarks. I'm Mark Sever marino, a grown man who enjoys donald dot com and
I am joined by my extremely patient and understanding wife today. Can you introduce yourself, please and tell us about your background and comics. Hi. I'm
missus Barks.
Also known as Susan suzanne. I do not really have a background in comics. I have a a degree in graphic arts, but I had actually never read a comic book before meeting mark. However, I am a huge modern art fan and
so I have kind of brought my
understanding of pop art, especially,
you know, most likely the works of Roy lie.
To bear on my feelings around what we're gonna discuss today. Awesome. Thank you. And and I was trying to remember
how many dates in we were before I
revealed that I was that they had a massive collection of classic Donald duck and uncle Sc con. Do you remember how quick how early in the relationship? It was relatively early. Yeah. I wanna say, like, maybe fourth or fifth that we hung out.
Right. So so I I I'd struck a balance
between
didn't wanna scare me away. I didn't wanna scare you away. And thankfully, it didn't. And I'm I'm super excited to have you join me
again. Thank you. This is
this is a great one I think to have you on as a guest. Right? Because this is... We we're gonna be talking about letter to santa. And this is one of the fan favorite Christmas stories that Carl Barks did. This is a pretty fluffy story. It's certainly not one of the adventure stories but but it is adventure length, which which are the the comics that I really like to cover and made it the podcast mission statement.
But it's a lot of fun. It's very memorable
and,
you know, in addition to getting to talk about some of that pop, we we can talk about one of your other lu. Which is construction equipment. Yes. So
Barks had me read this comic specifically
because I am an architect. And in the course of my my job, I spend a a great deal of time on construction sites. And I actually really
enjoyed that part of my job. I really enjoy construction equipment. So of course, I have read our children good night night construction site, just hundreds of times and you know, I love to point out you know, heavy equipment.
This was a a kind of a fun story for me to read. Awesome. Yeah. And and this one is definitely like a love letter to that. Childhood love of construction equipment that I know a lot of us had, you know, I I loved my big Ton truck, my big dump truck as a kid. Did you have anything like that who's? No. You know,
you and I are around the same age. We were both young children in the eighties. You know, it was not really
done so much at the time. There was not really the awareness of I think getting girls, the kind of toys that we're stereo
for boys. So I did not have things like ton trucks. Although I have purchased those for daughters.
Which is fun. I I think it's really important to expose young girls to all different kinds of toys and all different kinds of things. And and quite frankly, part of why I was kind of steered away from comic books while my male cousins had them is because it wasn't really considered to be appropriate for girls. You know, it's not necessarily my thing, but I think it's great that anybody can love what they want. Excellent. Well said. Yeah. I I had fun reading this. To to our middle kid too. She really loved that. And I think it's great for... I agree. It's great or little boys and little girls to enjoy their construction, equipment, their dolls, whatever they enjoy. And I will note that at the age of over forty, I still love construction equipment, and it is still so much fun. And I'm sorry. Anybody who says otherwise is lying. A hundred percent So let's do this. Let's... I'm gonna cover a little bit of the background about this story. Again, we're we're talking about letter to Santa.
This one was published
in October of nineteen forty nine. This is another of those special issues. This is the first issue of Christmas per parade, which is a title that would get to reprint over the years.
There been a decent number of reprint of this one, eight of them and including the original and it's one of the shorter of the full length stories. It's it's a twenty four pager And as far as the s synopsis goes, this one is about donald failing to get the kids letter to Santa nailed.
And resulting in him being responsible for getting the kids desired present, which we'll we'll get more into.
A little bit of background trivia,
I would say that this is arguably Barks first full length story where Christmas is the main focus rather than the background as it was in Christmas on Bear Mountain. If you look at the ratings on index where the community has voted
or how they feel about stories. This is Barks
second highest rated Christmas story.
This is one of a very select number of stories that has a full page splash panel. The other one that I can think of offhand is vacation time There may be more, but I I get the feeling that Barks really enjoyed doing these, but he didn't really have the latitude to do it very often. And I did find kind of a fun quote in which he was asked about the similarity
between this story and a story that was run in an old issue of Liberty magazine in nineteen twenty six. That showed a battle of of
similar machines, construction equipment on a on a construction site in New York and, you know, he he just said I had no idea that that the author
named Flag ever s to such slaps stick. I have never seen. I never seen his cartoon nor had I ever a red Liberty magazine
except in waiting rooms, and the idea of steam shovel fighting is another of those natural that anybody should be able to think up. I will know having spent my early childhood on long Island, being in New york city so often.
This was an aspect of the story. I really enjoyed because remember seeing tower cranes as a child and just being simultaneously
in awe and terrified of them. Oh, yeah. You know, this... Obviously the scale of construction in New York City is very few other places on Earth. Yeah. Absolutely.
Alright. Before we get into the story susan. I I enjoy checking in on some of the names for the story
when it's been published around the world. So I have a few of them here. And Why don't... Why don't we each pick a couple of them? Okay. Well, it looks like in Argentina,
they called this kart
or Christmas letter? Awesome. And and then in France, this was called la let
letter the father Christmas.
In Italy.
It was called
it three. I'm not sure how to pronounce that. That's part of the fun. I'm search.
But that translates to Donald and the digger, which is kind of different than in the other languages.
Yeah. And then let's see. I'll do... I'll do norway. Bit of it teal
letters santa claus. You should do Germany's though because German words are always so much fun. Oh, yeah. Yeah. We'll Al throw in We'll throw in Germany as well. So Germany, we've got Donald Duck, Un
Al.
Which translates to Donald Duck and the back home. Yes.
I will note that this is not a Barks home. Right. And and this is Google Translate giving me the results for s Bag yourself. Let's see.
I like to kind of think about cultural
geographical historical context for these stories
obviously, this one is a lot fluff than many, but... But, you know, there there are definitely some themes to note in here. I would say that, you know, part of this one to me, it seems to be about that sort of anxiety of gift giving that comes before Christmas, you know, especially if you're someone of humble means like Donald is in this story and and there's a couple references to, you know, the expenses of getting Christmas gift for everyone. We've obviously
got, you know, the steam shovel features prominently in this one.
What a cool piece of construction equipment that there's something to me about it that that seems cooler than it's like modern counterpart.
I I don't know about you, but there's something elemental out the boiler that's on it
and how it operates. Well, one thing that I... That I was immediately struck by with this is that I have literally never seen a steam shovel at work or a shovel of any type like that if you've ever been on a construction site, this one is portrayed doing
excavation.
And so an ex
is much more commonly used. And it looks somewhat similar, but I think the big difference is that the scoop goes the other way. This is definitely it's drawn more like a shovel with teeth. You know, more for moving dirt rather than ex, which is generally removing dirt. And your rate modern can russian equipment is not really done with with steam powered engines. But excavation if you've ever seen a really good
at work, they can operate the equipment with such with such skill that it almost looks like an extension of their hand. Another thing that really struck me about this story is that it felt... And I'm sure this is gonna be almost like heresy to to your listeners. It had... It felt very mad cap. And that seemed to be very much the tenor of this whole story. Yeah. I I'd say that's fair. You know, this one is definitely a slider story. It it's very fun, but but it's it's very za compared to a lot of these.
Another thing that I just really enjoyed about this was kind of that depiction of New York and
the construction kind of environment there you know, when this was drawn, that would have been the golden age of high rise construction in New York City. So it's interesting that you read this as New York. Because I don't remember any suggestion that it is, but, like, it it feels like because it's winter time because we're watching this big construction site, I could totally how you'd think that. But I think this is just supposed to be the Ducks, you know, hometown of Duck. Obviously, you haven't read hundreds and hundreds of so you'd have no way to know that?
This kind of panel is actually very reminiscent of the kind of visual composition rock a fellow center. Yeah. And since they're depicting Donald holding a Christmas tree, I think, you know, most of us have that iconic image of Rockefeller center in the Christmas tree right in the middle. So I did instantly interpret that New York. Yeah. And that's totally fair. I I think that Duck has definitely been, like, built up for the purpose of this story and and for the spectacular fight that's gonna happen
midway through, and, you know, you're you're referring to the splash panel. And, yeah, I can definitely see how you'd refer that. And there's something about, like construction sites and in large construction sites that just feels very new York. Before last thing before going into the story itself, did you ever read Mike Mel Mu and his Steam shovel? No. I did not. Alright. So that's a very famous kid's book. And that one would have been published
just ten years before this story came out. So I think you know, I think that kind of explains some of the genesis of this one and the popularity of steam shovel. We're very cute kids book about anti
construction equipment, very big in the United States around this time. Alright. Susan, are you ready to go through the story itself? Absolutely.
Awesome. So letter des Santa opens up with the Ducktales donald and his nephews all looking out over the construction site that you and I have been talking about. And as I mentioned, this is a full page splash panel. This is pretty special because Barks either didn't or was not allowed to do these very often, but it's a great visual the they they've just purchased a Christmas tree that has a price tag of fifty nine cents.
Do you you wanna tell us a little bit about kind of the scale of the
construction site and and just the look. Well, two thirds of the panel is shown Sub
and the angle
is drawn so that if there... The viewer is in a sub training pit, and it does look to be a very steep walled construction
excavation. So obviously doing some sort of foundation work, that's part of what gives this such a strong urban feel
because this is how we in urban areas.
Usually, if you ex in suburban or rural spaces, first of all, you don't have to go anywhere near that deep. Also, you wouldn't do that kind of of kind of sheer wall like that. It should also be noted that that isn't really how it's done.
This is obviously John for effect, but
if you had... If you were ever going to do an excavation like that with such a tight site, you would have a lot of s in there. There's snow on the ground in the front. So I can't imagine doing excavation in the snow.
That's usually not done. They'll just call that it They'll call that a weather day. Oh yeah. There you go. So it bears repeating too. This is such a great panel. You know, I feel like the focus is on the steam shovel, and it it does a great job of giving us the idea of the Nephews childhood
fascination with the steam shovel, and Donald is really appreciating it as well. He's got a big smile on his face. Al.
And a large kind of high rise building potentially even a skyscrapers is shown directly behind the construction site
so, you know, this is gonna be a very tightly packed kind of urban
location. Yeah. For sure. Alright. So the next page gives us it kinda sets up the the conflict of the story with the Nephews, both ad the steam shovel, you know, talking about their knowledge of how it works. And then they're they're asking for reassurance from uncle Donald that they mailed their letter to Santa,
and he reassure
him that of course, he did, and and they just they really wanna make certain
in in the way of kids.
You know, I thought the nephews looked adorable and they're matching snow hats. It's so interesting to me how
comic style art when, you know, we're trying to kind of convey a lot with us. Very with a little bit... And what I mean by that is you're you're trying to convey maybe a lot of information or storytelling
without providing a huge amount of detail in the art. The the artist, who I believe is named Carl Barks.
Well time.
You got something out of the podcast. Carl Barks has done such a great job of trying to convey how young they are
but also what time of year it is in the choices of their hat and also the kind of the different colors of their hats. And that makes these panels kind of graphically strong, you know, the the construction site is just kind of brown and white and and the the nephews
are also
you know, drawn and bright white, but they've these kind of brightly colored hats and scarves on and they look just just adorable. Mh. Excellent. And so on on the next page. On the third page, Donald is... We kinda go into his internal monologue. This one's entirely in thought balloon so set for one. And he's searching for his ear ups and while looking through his pockets, he realizes to his horror that he has in fact neglected to mail the kids a letter to Santa. And Susan, I I feel like his guilt is really Al. Bubble. Oh, and.
He's so stressed out. You can see, you know, he's sweating even though it's cold. Mh. There's little beads of sweat kind of flying off of him and a couple of these panels. One thing that just always makes me laugh about comics and especially
these, you know, kind of ant
animals is that, you know, he's wearing a coat, but no pants.
No shoes. Like
So
it's adorable. Yeah. And and there's
some interesting borders on these pages. You know. There's some on the previous page there's kinda some swoop lines. This is not very typical for Barks.
And and so by the end of this third page, you know, he's resolved that now he's he's gotta get them their presence, so he's gonna go ahead and open the left. So on the fourth page,
Donald
dives into their letter and he reads and and Susan, do you wanna just read verbatim the text of the letter? Sure. Dear Santa. All we want for Christmas is a steam shovel. Thanks. Hue, Louie and Dewey Ducktales
Donald says a steam shovel. Yeah. We got... We got a pretty great double tape there. Right? Well, he he takes a moment to process it. And
in order to process it, he has to run back to the construction site. And and look at it. And it kind clicks for him why the Nephews hughes were were so
intent on looking at the steam shovel. And so we kinda get donald in turmoil, you know, frustrated
and stressed out at this situation that he's got into with the knowledge that he's gotta get them a steam shovel. And and you know Susan after you read this, you you had come to me pretty quickly that you you thought it was silly that his brain went to a real steam shovel. Immediately.
I would say that, you know, maybe the stress of forgetting the letters is the thing that led him to being a little bit open to this. Yes.
I I guess we should say it's a spoiler alert. Right.
The nephews do not actually.
A true steam shovel they want a toy steam film.
And apparently,
the practicality of that, just didn't quite figure into Donald maybe. Right. So he's
this. And what do you think of this gag where he
approaches some random guy? Just holding an absolute mountain of gift skin asks him say mister, how much would you say a steam shuttle costs? And the the gentleman
says about as much as a wife and six kids k. This annoyed me. Yeah. Okay.
A very typical trope of this time was that the man made all the money and the woman spent all the money. Right. And, you know, complaining that your wife and your children cost you money. I think that's a a trope that hasn't aged really well. Just Yeah. I I agree. It's it's very much one of those, like, cat skills, comedian.
Take my wife, please, j.
However, I do love the visual part of it. The man just like absolutely
buried
underneath the pile of presence. I I think that it is It is pretty cute. Yeah. So
Donald figures out that the only person in the world who can help him out of this jam is his uncle sc mc doc the richest ty in the universe. Well, and the reason he instantly goes to uncle sc is because of course, he realizes that the steam shovel is spencer.
I can't even imagine how much steam shovel passed that's gotta be hundreds of thousands of dollars. Pro tip most construction equipment is rented.
Oh, yeah. There you go. So on the next page, we get to see this photo version of uncle Scrooge
And we've done... He's been about six or seven stories so far. I don't know the exact count. So Barks is still really honing in on his carrot and and there's parts of him here that, you know, our true sc Mc and there are parts that are still very much a work in progress. But, you know, we we come in on Donald having just asked him and sc his outrage
instead of letting him ring him for his unreasonable quest. Donald toss him a buck for a cup of coffee and a haircut. And sc responds, he says hit me with a dollar William. Does it feel to be hit with a million? And he toss as a sack of money at him. And, you know, I I liked that little exchange. The ducks are gonna get in this Pretty visually cool money fight is the only way to describe it. And the quote, real sc Mc Ducktales never gonna be so cavalier again. With his money and and getting in fights.
Or at least this would be very out of character, but it makes for a really fun visual and and he seems to actually be enjoying him awful a lot. And I see one thing about this page that stood out to me. Absolutely.
You know, as somebody who wasn't really familiar with the care of uncle sc until duck tales. One of the things I noticed is that Uncle sc is not wearing his hat. And so in a couple of these panels, it wasn't really clear to me who was sc and who was Donald and, you know, looking at the very kind of subtle ways that Barks
differentiates the two, you know, with a few more feathers kind of around the face and the feathers are a little bit rough and sc Scrooge.
Yeah. And and that's definitely not part of his character. He doesn't have the red
cloth that he usually wears. And I think he wears his top or later in this one, but it's true. He looks very different especially since his glasses fly on at the beginning of the fight. So, yeah, they they look very similar. Else seems like a jerk. Yeah. And sc his kind of normal character is definitely
greedy and mis
going forward but it's never a kind of this, like hard edged rough jerk or or very rarely. Yeah. I always thought even him more like you're a Tight wide grandpa? Yeah. Yeah. This is a weird
characterization for him. So once they work this through their system, Donald explains
And
again, very out of character, sc just like, well why didn't she say it was for Christmas?
And on the next page, again, super out of character,
key hands donald a lot of money,
says, go ahead get the steam shovel. And Donald
is great full and he let's slip that now he doesn't have to reveal that he forgot to nail their letter to Santa. And this outrage is sc you know, because he thinks it's awful that he's not gonna get the credit. I mean, reasonably so. I would say,
it's important to Donald to preserve the
santa.
Well and that's an interesting thing that I think we should talk about a little bit. In full disclosure, we have always told our children that Santa is not actually a guy who comes down the Chimney. We have tried to explain the concept that Santa is a metaphor.
Yeah. Where where those those parents.
There's a fairly
notorious story in my family about a kid finding out Santa was not real and it was very, very, very disturbing. And so we've tried to be as honest with them as possible about it. But our friends that do hold on to the Santa
story for their children. You know, that's always been the thing to negotiate.
Some of my friends
you know, will have they call it one santa present, and then the rest of the presence are from, you know, mom and dad or aunts
or grandma grandpa? Some just say that all of the presidents are from Santa. I know that's
especially once children get older and they see that, you know, some of their friends maybe
don't have families as prosperous.
The santa's story starts to be a little harder to hold on.
Anyway, I think it's interesting that sc is very concerned about the idea that the children would think that Santa claus brought their steam shovel and it wasn't him. Yeah. Sure. Yeah. Something something for families to figure out in their own way. I I like our balance of
haven't fun with the santa, just always acknowledging that it's a myth. So we're gonna find out more, of course about Santa. He spoiler is is real in this one. Going forward, we we see Donald arriving at a machinery company yard, and he has the very reasonable request that he wants a new steam shovel
tonight.
And you know, the the guy seems to have a pretty good response. You wanna tell us his response? He says listen bud you don't buy steam shovel like you do teaspoons. You Gottfredson
from the factory.
Obviously,
major construction equipment is not an off the shelf item. It's not a teaspoon.
No. So, you know, Donald rushes off to figure this out, because obviously, he doesn't have that time onto the next page And and we get this trope in just a moment where we flash to sc arriving to the same guy and, you know, we get to see that guys outrage perspective, he just think another crack pot. He Scrooge sc the same wise guy response that he gave to Donald, but sc just says, where's the factory? I'll buy the factory. I guess this is not the last time Scrooge we'll do something extravagant prove a point, but on the whole, he's not gonna throw money around like this. He does have his hat. Yeah. I guess, he's outside now. So So, you know kinda like this. We don't really cover how Donald does Fin
a steam shovel but we just kinda of flash forward to it. No. Let's just get to the fun part. I I think I think, you know, susan I think that Carl Marx for this story really wanted
to
draw and realize a steam shovel fight. Absolutely absolutely.
And I think he couldn't wait to get to it. And I think he made the story backwards from from this
very part because we we flash to Donald navigating the steam shovel through the city and he gets to the intersection on the way to his house and his path is blocked by, of course, Uncle Sc, in his own steam shovel. In the print we're reading,
Barks, of course, he wasn't his own color, but the original print has Donald and a green steam shovel Scrooge in yellow one. I like how they you know, contrast. They're very sharp. And Donald is outraged. He's like, what are you doing in in this steam shovel and sc immediately says, you no, i I'm gonna give this to them and I'm gonna get the credit from this and, you know, Donald is
absolutely
inflexible of all, he is willing to do anything to to to avoid revealing his thought.
And it escalate
until Soon would you like to describe what what happens with them? Well, they have a sword fight with their steam shovel and it is very hilarious. I think, you know, the steam shovel are are crashing into one another and their little action words w.
Chomp and these steam shovel are knocking into adjacent buildings and causing a lot of damage and it's very silly. Yeah. It it's very silly. And it's it's spectacular. I think a lot of fun. This this is the highlight of of the comic. I think this is why most people remember this one. Right? Because it... It's just wonderful
demolition. It's better than a demolition derby. Having
been on construction sites for so many hours though. I have to say the lack of safety.
Concerns is just
it's very upsetting. They don't even have their hard hats. No no Ppe.
No. They don't have anything.
But you probably don't usually drive steam shovel through the city streets on Christmas eve. Absolutely
not. Yeah. The the form gonna have something to say about donald sc here. You mean the super...
So while this is going on, you know, we get some neat background scenes of the panic citizenry.
We get a contemporary reference, a pretty contemporary reference
where a lady tells her husband to do something, and he cow behind the sofa phone and asks. Who do you think I am King Kong
We see the police racing towards the scene and
we transition to them being brought before a judge at Night court. And and this is
our first appearance of any adventure length stories. Is our first appearance of a background character that people have just called judge Owl. He'll appear a few times. But he threatens to throw the book at them and
Sc gives him some back
and onto the next page, he slaps them with a fine of one million dollars And we're talking nineteen forty nine
here. This is a fantastic
sum. Although it probably doesn't even cut
covering the damage they caused. And again, very out of character Scrooge cut toss them two million bucks and tells them to keep it in case they come back. If only skirts could pay my student loans.
So, you know, sc and Donald have kind of cooled down they're pondering what they're gonna do. We're kind of entering the second sequence, the second part of this story. Right? The first part is this spectacular steam shovel fight. And and I'll admit, it loses a little bit of
steam
in the second half. For me as we get into this part where sc tells Donald. He's gonna help him out of this jam. And,
you know, just to meet back. Essentially, the the conflict now is that the two steam shovel that Donald and sc
used to fight one another are now not
gift.
Right. As they are now to beat up, and that just seems like such a dude thing to do to ruin my kids Christmas presents. Yes. And and so now, you know, they've gotta to figure out they're scheming how to let them down easily. And we transition to the kids in Christmas eve mode, you know, they're waiting anxiously
for Santa
I love the poses that they're waiting in. And and I learned how he depicts that sort of little kid
completely
ent with that moment. You know of Christmas.
Yes. And so the Nephews
are back at home and they're trying to wait up for Santa. And they said thirty more minutes to wait.
Right. And and they even mentioned that they're worried about Santa, but one or they're worried about Donald, but one of them is like, I'm too, but Santa Claus is more important. And then they do hear some jingle bells. And we kind of flash to Donald Sc who have a a pretty cheap looking
imitation of a santa's Sleigh being pulled by a horse wearing
fake ant
and we're kinda getting the idea that the scheme here is to pretend to be santa.
And Sc says that you're gonna be santa to claus. I wanted to note on this page the nephews are all john the seam, and I can't tell them apart. Mh. So they're just drawing as three adorable little ducks. Also
just one nice little detail that I noticed in in this panel where
two of the nephews are looking at the window as there's this very traditional mantle clock shown over the fire and, you know, those were something I very much associate with my grandparents. Who you know, furnished their house around this time. So, you know, those nice little details, I think really give it such a sense of time and place. Yeah.
And that's an interesting thing to point out too about the Nephew being drawn the same because I would say that they're generally like one unitary carrot. They're never really meant to be distinguished. You know, sometimes one of them will become in peril and they'll have to save Dewey or something, but they're never. They're never really
identify as having different personalities.
So Donald and sc are kinda getting further into the scheme and Scrooge planes that Donald is going to dress up as Santa, and he's just gonna explain that he's all out of steam shovel this year. But that help provide one for next Christmas. And Donald thinks this is a great idea. I'm skeptical, but, you know, he approaches the house. And as he does, the nephews are hearing him, and they are very excited to let him come down the chimney. And Donald hears this.
And, you know, his heart sinks, because this is suddenly becoming a lot harder. Let's see. Donald got this kind of ridiculous putt knows I should mention. And so he he goes up the chimney and he tumble down
any lands coughing and sputtering,
And the nephews, you can just read the disappointment on their face. But but, you know, they kinda gather their wits and they start to make sand to feel at home and basically over the next couple of pages, we're gonna see the Nephews
trying to make him feel welcome and preventing Donald from getting out his very rehearsed story and also putting him in these like very uncomfortable and slaps dick's situations.
Yes. This is very much the whole classic
minimal
disguise.
Right. In fact it's so minimal. You wonder how the the nephews don't see through it. And
Donald is really trying to just say what he needs to say to get and and move along. Right. And and something that I usually talk about that I've forgotten about is just the kind of the version of the characters because Barks will kind switch them around to fit the kind of story he needs to tell. And and in this one, like a lot of the Christmas ones, it's necessary to kind of dumb the nephews down a little bit and make them a little bit more child like because they're usually much much sharper. They're they're usually depicted as smarter than Donald.
So, you know,
a few of the slaps stick things that happen over the next couple pages. His his putt nose gets flattened. They really want to weigh him because, you know, Santa's fat and you you want to weigh santa.
So, you know, while they're going to get a scale, sc tells him his idea,
to note that Donald is now wearing Santa's pants. So he actually does have Pants on. Oh oh, yeah. That's a good... That's a good catch. This is one of those incredible rare times, where Donald Duck is wearing pants. That must be part of why this one feet this part. Why this sequence feels a little off putting. But of course it's gonna be necessary for Gru idea here, which is to fill his suit with full of beans.
So he does, and it makes him convincing
heavy. The the grand total weight of a hundred and six pounds, I guess, for a Du version of Santa. Again, more mad cap scenes, they show off their Christmas tree, which, you know, this feels a little bit out so. It's got real lit candles on it. Absolutely.
That's another one of these small details that, you know, put this right around... When did you say nineteen fifty and then have forty nine And that totally feels spot on, you know, the idea that you would have these beautiful kind of glass glass or ornaments and yes, real candles on your Christmas tree. What could go wrong black. Just an amazing fire hazard thing. Thank goodness, we don't do that anymore, but I'm sure it was beautiful. So, you know, the predictable thing happens his suit lies lights on fire, the Nephews rush him into the shower, and we get this kind of weird mad cap little za scene of the beans having soaked up all the shower water, and donald realizing that he's got to get his
story out before the beam swell too much. And that's because he has to exit via the Chimney again And now with the beans also swollen enough, he won't fit out the chimney. Right. And so he he's
He's kind of telling them about the steam shovel about the letter, but he can't quite get it out, and so he he finds that he has to rush out the Chimney to keep up the illusion and of course, he gets stuck
just at the top of the Chimney as the beans have swelled. Too much. And so while the Nephews
are anguish Al how they blew their chance with with meeting Si,
Rouge is putting on his backup santa's suit. We should also know that these beans are apparently
swelling enough to cause structural damage. Should this is to the chimney water.
We're starting to see bricks shifting in the chimney and
I googled it. Apparently beans will swell. Most beans can expand two point five times when soaked.
Yeah. That this this the pretty silly part. But again, it's it's been result in this fun visual.
While
sc is posing as Santa.
And talking
himself up. Right? And the third person. He's he's having his version or Santa to tell the Nephews that what they really should have done. Was to ask their uncle
sc for that steam shovel. And and Donald is just listening to him being a blow hard from
within the Chimney.
And hoping that the beans will swell just just enough, I guess, to destroy his own chimney, which which happens. It's a very cool. Very cool little panel with some of the brick even
drawn. It is. This is apparently enough to cause explosive demolition. The.
Again, I'm skeptical. It just seems like the beans would just fallout out.
No I think you should... I think you should suggest that the next time you're on the construction site.
They need the demo a building.
Beans and beans in water.
This. So
one thing I just wanna point out here is that when they pick that the houses, you know, they're these very traditional medical middle American
gable roofs and they're drawn with snow on them and, you know, the trees look all kind of spider with snow. And and it's just this kind of almost courier and i ask.
Depiction of
of the neighborhood and it's just very charming. It's very wholesome. Awesome. Well set. So Donald has has been freed. He's still he's still in his santa's suit. Looked a lot more sc. He runs in the Scrooge sc right in his big santa butt, You know, calls him a liar he exposes him as their uncle sc into disguise, and he proves that he's the real santa claus by by flashing their letter. You know, he tries to get into his story about having run out of steam at the North pole, but when Sc kicks him in retaliation, the Nephews
note that the letter doesn't have a post Barks. Thus was never male and they're they're just so down
as they figure it out immediately
tell both of their uncles that they can stop pretending and they get no Christmas this year.
Yeah. And Donald and Scrooge are still blaming each other and then we hear a voice from the Chimney
referring to Don
devin Blitz,
Dash, France. And you know, they notice some coming down the chimney and we get this really neat visual of a teeny tiny
santa
landing in the fireplace.
And then as soon As santa leaves the fireplace,
Santa instantly kind of expands to his full size.
With a a large sack of toys and Santa is not a duck santa it's mh person, the ne user. Thrilled and Donald and sc are both amazed. So to really neat the depiction of Santa. He looks very jolly. And the Nephews they kind of share their so story. He noticed
the santa
is like, there's no stockings hanging. Maybe you don't want any presents.
They break down crying and through so, they reveal that they want to steam shovel. And you know, you wanna tell us this little bit of dialogue here susan. There's a great line where
sc says to Donald. You made a mighty poor i imitate if you ask me and Donald responds. Oh, so, you weren't no bearer more yourself. Mh. Of course, spare more being light it'll bit more. Yeah. Good catch. That's a fun little. Again, a contemporary for this time reference to a little bit of pop culture.
He's the grandfather of Drew morning. I believe grandfather. Yes.
And then tell us what how Santa responds. Santa says, oh, h.
Don't worry. What was this one present you boys wanted it? The boys bond that they wanted to steam shovel. And then Santa says, oh,
why it so happens I have a few x sure ones right here in the old sack. And I love I love the boys, you know,
delighted surprised expressions and Donald and sc puzzled expressions when when sin says this that he has has some right in the sack. And we learn what really should have been obvious all along, which is that the boys wanted, you know, the nineteen fifty, a equivalent of a ton steam shuttle. So Santa gets out Toy steam shovel and he says there you are boys, a two teaspoon spoonful full Scrooge with one candle power firefox Barks. And I like that it it has this little, you know, miniature version. Yeah. The cool engine.
It's kinda cute too that they've... They're triplets, but they've they've asked for one. You know? They they're gonna play together. They just wanted the one. I like that. So Sienna does his his mini
in in reverse, he goes back up the chimney. However, we should point out that Donald Scrooge sc our once again yelling at each other. They wanted a toy steam shovel, which any dumbbell but you would have known all long, and then he says, look who's talking. Right. So a lot of blu from the grown ups in this one. I feel like there were more constructive ways to deal with this
So by the end, you know, Donald races up the Chimney
motions to Santa to wait and Sam like, oh, do you want to present too? And he is a fun gag. He says he'd like a book on how to remember to mail a letter. And then sc tops him in the last panel by saying that he'd... He says, if you haven't got one with you Santa, I'll buy Donald one. In fact, I'll buy him the factory that prints the books. Once again, throwing many around. Yeah. Throwing money around and and har back to, you know, his
previous actions and and trying to one up donald. This is throughout this whole story the grown ups are trying to one up each other and then Nephews are much more innocent. So so this is the last panel. This is how the
how the story closes. We should note that the very last panel of this story features Scrooge pushing Donald backward out of the Chimney and Donald is seen kind of following on this gable roof that is obviously covered in snow. So you know, the implication is that Donald is going to be in for a nas fall. Once again, I feel like Better ways. Better ways.
I'll i'll
I'll assume that Santa uses his Christmas magic. To save him there. I hope so. Really, really neat little closing panel though. I like the look of it. I like the kind of motion that's captured here of Santa's sleigh and the Reindeer floating. You know, one thing that really stood out to me about this art in general is that there's very little kind of
graphical
kind of detail put in to depict shading ordered to pick form. There's a little bit shown on things that are rounded or sometimes a little bit of line work drawn on some of the bricks to show a little bit of texture, but, you know, I I mentioned Roy Lip earlier who
is very famous for using
the kind of graphical dot that are seen I think more in like, say, superman comics. And and Roy life Stein whole kind of approach to his graphics art was showing these exaggerated
scenes of human interaction in this kind of comic book kind of brightly colored style. So, you know, that was something that I thought was really interesting. This is a whole kind of genre of art which is trying to convey a lot of emotion, but in a very graphically simple way, and that's actually much harder than it looks. Right? You have to to show enough without showing too much and I'm sure that was because of the limitations of printing in nineteen fifty, but this art is just very charming. It's very
engaging and you can tell, you know, some of these guys were just masters with the Ink Pen. I think of
like, the curious George books or make way for duckling and you can just tell. Those guys
had
unbelievable
number of hours of practice and they could just draw such absolutely charming little illustrations.
With, you know, just a very subtle, subtle hand or a very gentle hand, and it's create such an iconic look of this time. Yeah. Very well said. It's very iconic and I... you know, Barks you know that one of the things I love is kind of the visual look of different time periods and how we know with not a lot of information kind of when something happened.
So anyway, I really enjoyed the story from that from that angle. Excellent.
And let's talk about, you know, how how we felt about story as a whole. What what were your thoughts? Obviously, it's it's weird that this is the first comic you've read, but...
And and it's one that's, like seven years old. It's not the first one. The first... I... Oh, yeah. He's right. Had me read another donald dot comment. Right. It was ghost of the g. That's right. That was the first one. Alright. So you've got Al adventure one and kind of a lighter story in. Right. And I've read a a couple of others in the intervening years. We have been married for some I'm math right. So, you know, honestly, comics are just not... They're not really my thing. I
I enjoy them from an aesthetic point of view, but honestly, these stories seem kind of ridiculous to me. It's honestly Scrooge and donald.
Don't really seem like very likable characters.
And I I had Al a little bit of a hard time with that. I gotta be honest. Like, I kind of wasn't rooting for either of them. Yeah. I think that's fair. You know, I think I think they're definitely kinda chatter heads in this one. This one's more of an nephews showcase almost. Absolutely.
The the steam shovel fight is Al blast. Yeah. Yeah. I I agree... That's totally fair. You know, I I like to get the newbie perspective on the podcast. You know, the other thing too is this is one of those stories that just... It only works if you absolutely
believe the every one of these misunderstandings could have happened.
So it's it's just so imp. But like you said, Barks obviously wanted to draw a steam shovel fight and he was gonna do whatever he could do to make sure that steam shovel fight happens. Yeah. I'm I'm totally confident. This one was plotted backwards
around that admittedly great scene. So you know, I I think that those are totally valid criticisms.
I do really like this one compared to a lot of the Barks Christmas stories. I was thinking about how many full length ones there are, and and I think that there he did about eight of these longer ones. And I think this one is probably either my second or third favorite. It's it's definitely in the upper
tier along with Christmas for Shaq town and you can't guess. But this one's just a ton of fun. I think it's got some great, like, child like Christmas Al, you know, Christmas wonder,
I definitely think the first half of it is much stronger. That's the... That's the part of the story that I find very memorable.
I think back to the steam shovel fight, I think back to that great opening full page panel. I do like the closing panel a lot with Sand to himself. And then then I love the money fight as well. So there's some great scenes. This one is very much like kind of these connected scenes. More than a a a well plotted adventure story. I also kind of wonder why these stories seem so male centric. You know, where comic books really
meant to be kind of a boys thing. I think back to, you know, my mom grew up. She was born in nineteen fifty. And she grew up with an older brother,
my uncle, and my uncle has very fond memories of the Donald and Scrooge comics as well. And it's interesting because my mom never read them. So comics were at that time, my grandparents bought comics for their son, but not for their daughters. The way these stories are written, it's very clearly coded for males, but also kind Ducktales in a very kind of specific nineteen fifties kind of what we think of as the the typical mil, you know, living in a single family home. Near a city, So I... You know, it's obvious that these stories were kind of drawn for that cohort and not for everyone. Yeah. And that's another really good point to make. I've talked a little bit about that. But absolutely,
these were totally geared towards little boys. It's not say that there weren't young girls that enjoyed them and were fans, but I don't think there's any arguing that these are drawn from a little boy's perspective. At this time in comics history, little girls, absolutely
red comics, but they were a very siloed. Right? There would be girls comics and boys comics. And there were definitely some that were more to appeal to both, but for the most part, I think the publishers
expected that these were mostly gonna be bought by young boys. Later on, they're going to explicitly
ask Barks to do a few more feminine
email geared stories. He's gonna do a short series of daisy Ducktales stories called Daisy Ducktales diary. I don't think he wrote all or most of those. But, you know, it it clearly does not play with his sen
They're very entertaining, but they're a little bit of a train wreck as far as you know, looking at him trying to gear stories towards girls. Well... And, you know, this kind of graphical style is so
clearly designed around action scenes. You know. And you can just tell Barks just loves to do these kind of, you know, very broad gestures with the Ducktales and, you know, this almost like mad cap kind of angles and it really lends itself well to these very action oriented stories, you know, if there are you know, made things a little bit more kind of, quote, domestic or a little bit more a little more heal for girls, you know, to because that was really the thinking Al the time.
And I'm sure that the art just wasn't as charming. You know, you look at this steam shovel fight, and it's just it's great.
Yeah. They're so elastic. Right? These like
machines, but they
they kind of... You can see them winding up for punches on. Absolutely
and you can see debris coming off and you can just tell it just looks like they're just having the time of their lives. Yeah. Awesome. If... And you know what, it's totally fun being on a construction site and seeing all of this stuff at work and watching demolition. It's it's really just one of the best parts of my job. Oh, no doubt. Awesome. I'm a I'm a woman over forty I still get really excited about it. Rightfully. Awesome. So let's see. As far we've talked about how we feel checking in on the index page. You know, this one is definitely a fan favorite. This is very highly regarded. It has a seven point nine out of ten average rating
good for sixty fifth out of all, like, forty one thousand or so. Disney comics that are rated on end It is the second as I mentioned the second highest rated of all of his Christmas stories behind only Christmas for s.
So this one is certainly well liked by the community. I would say
they remember it for pretty much the same reasons I do. It is fun, you know, it's version of like child like wonder and Christmas I do like to talk about how things hold up. We've we've already kind of talked about some of the retro in our archaic aspects of this one. I I would say it it certainly is a time capsule. But fortunately, there's nothing like super problematic apart from that kind of sexist joke at the beginning. Yeah. I I didn't think it was
really
inappropriate in any way. It just has that sort of sexism kind of lurking in the background of and that's very typical and many things of this zero. Right. Did you have any
favorite panels apart from the obvious?
You know, I kinda like this one
with the police car. This one is is very graphically different from the rest. It's got this very kind simple composition where the police Barks Scrooge is up on the street, and it's shown kind of very simply. I love the kind of building silhouette in the background and the full, you know, very subtle kind of coloring there. Everything's shown in this very, like, minimal set of colors. I really like that, you know, as somebody with a a background in graphic arts. I tend to really like these panels that are a little bit more, I would say composed and rather than these ones that seem to be a little bit more informational.
And I'm I'm a sucker for the big showcase ones in this one. You know, the the big splash panel at the beginning, the huge spectacular
steam shovel fight are certainly easy choices as well as the money fights But there are some neat quiet moments in here. Some of the the moments of the Nephews
just waiting for Christmas. I feel like he did a great job of capturing that anticipation. The perspective angle and all of these is really
interesting. I'm looking at this one here.
Showing the steam shovel
kind of meeting in the intersection. Urban
intersections and urban life are are really frequent thing that gets depicted a lot in art there was some great paintings by Edward Hopper that depicts a kind of a similar
Urban Mil yu. Obviously, Hopper is not a comic artist. He is I'll just say it a fine artist, and he has just the most beautiful composition sense and he does such a great job depicting what urban life felt like at that time. I'm also thinking of the print maker Martin Lewis, who also
drew many
exquisite gorgeous
lift photographs and etching of the same sort of angle. So it's interesting to me that all of these different and artists
around the same time even though they were working, you know, Barks it's obviously working for children and working in a kind of a mass production environment. There's such a look to this time, and it's just beautiful. Awesome. You know, I really appreciate that perspective that you can bring the the arts
appreciation.
You mentioned Lit rap. Barks.
Barks did not unfortunately get around to Al lit for this one were in oil. I think it would have been sp spectacular if he'd chosen to do the steam shovel fight.
But, yeah, again, thank you so much. I've been I've been really wanting to bring you in for one of these since I've got this newbie role, although the next steps episode of the podcast. I have another long
fan that's gonna sit down in the chair. So that that'll be fun. I hope that everyone will join us next week for luck of the north.
Sue thanks again so much. Did you have any closing thoughts before we wrap it up. No. I I really enjoyed this, honestly.
Again, comics are not really a thing I grew up with I can definitely see why you love them so much. They're totally charming. And
I
will totally read more. Next. I'm not gonna tell you how many more.
But I I did really enjoy this. This is fun. I'm so glad. I'll have to keep an eye out for a a good one that will benefit from, like, your artistic perspective. Awesome. Well, thank you so much for helping me out with letter to santos listeners. You can drop us line at berkshire at g dot com or on the Facebook page. Again, join us next week, we're gonna get to talk about Al classic luck of the north. And I guess we're in the holiday season. So
enjoy your holidays, whatever they may be,