Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of sc Mc and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge cl of all time join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context, and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Welcome back to Mark's remarks. I'm Mark Sever marino, a longtime Ducktales.
I eager to talk about another of our adventure length Barks stories. And I'm very fortunate to be joined by another long time Ducktales fan today. I've got a special guest I'm gonna throw it over to him, ask him to introduce himself and and tell us a little bit about himself. Hi, Mark. Thank you. My name is Warren Harmon. I a as Barks said a a longtime
Donald Duck fan and a Ducktales fan in general,
and specifically a really
strong and adventist
supporter of the Carl Barks
series of stories. And I'm really pleased to be here. Mark, I I live in Rochester, Minnesota. And been collecting for over fifty years
and started with comics when it deploy and lit the graphs and
back to comics, and that's where I married and now. Just really loving to reread these great adventure stories. Awesome. And you really are a collector
you know, I've I've been able to see in your background that you've got a pretty pretty great collection. I've always been more of a reader. I have here and there a couple of treasure issues. But
what's what's your most treasure would you say? Well, it have to be the adventure and long long form story we're talking about today and that's luck of the North. I was ten years old when my mother brought me my first gold key comic which was the the best of Uncle Scrooge in Donald duck. Volume two, which featured
luck of the north in the seven cities of Ebola, and I
opening story captivated me as a ten year old. I was
incredibly surprised at the detail of the artwork. The humor and the storytelling, of course Al a ten year old. I'm going Al. This is funny. But then go as an adult and going. This is funny. You know, it it it transcend ages and a transcend generation to these stories that was the first story that I ever read. And for some reason, it just stuck with me, and we'll talk about it, but it was it was a
incredible
I did know comics could do this. And I didn't know that storytelling could be done so well with images and expressions and and the words that Carl Barks wrote. So... Yeah, that's the first one and then I started buying the gold key comics and
eventually got into the glad comics
too later on. And yeah. It's been kind of an obsession mine over the years and in Carl Barks also,
you know, who who can't say that he's one of the greatest storyteller of the twentieth century. I really believe he is. It's amazing what he did in his lifetime. That's great. What a great kind of dis
of I think the reason so many of us long timers are Carl Barks fans. You know, I think most of us, many of us can remember the first story that we ever read and that sort of click of what what a great adventure I just read or what a sharp... You know, in my case, my first one was the one that was later called Statues
spend thrift. And like you said, it's such a revelation to a read your first few carl marx stories and then that sense of of wonder. So As you mentioned, we are talking about luck of the north, which is
a great story to have a conversation about there's gonna be a lot of really
interesting
aspects of this. We get to talk about Gladstone gander.
Obviously,
we get to talk about this is gonna be one of his big great north stories. You know, i I would say that the arctic
kind of features in an outs sized sense in the Barks stories is one thing that I was thinking Al I reread this one for the time. Yeah. Absolutely. It it it is it is you're absolutely right. I you know, when you look at some of the other stories that take place in the north country in the North woods and and you're venturing into that when you think about sc and his
Alaskan roots and you think about... If you you wonder if Carl Barks really felt that that was a place he wanted to travel to. Course with his obsession with national geographic. I'm sure he got his fill that way. Yeah. Absolutely.
I think I think this really points to how interested. He he is in the region. It seems to have really held this draw for him. So let's go some into some of the
specifics of this
story. Right? The cover date for this one is October of nineteen forty nine, And I mean, you... You've got a copy, at least one copy. You mind telling us which issue this one was published in? It well, it was four colored number two fifty six. It was of the four color series, of course, and the adventure stories. Yeah. I've I've got two reading copies of that, and I've got my slab copy back here which don't like slab copies. I know they grade them and they're they're supposed to be very valuable, but you can't read them and I love reading those comics. But I do have one. But, yeah, four color two fifty six, like you said, it it was actually
written and drawn by Karl Barks in June of that. Year and
was it was a... We'll probably talk about this, but it was an interesting time in his life what he was going through personally. And, you know, he himself into his work during that time. And it shows in the series of stories from forty eight through about fifty and... Right. A lot of fans will point this most fans. We'll point to this as kind of his his golden age of work. Right? Yes. And as you mentioned, you know, this was a pretty turbulent time you know, we we can mention it now. I haven't dealt too much into that because it doesn't necessarily interest me It feels a little bit sal sla But there there's definitely a case to be made to talk about, you know, the fact that sometimes people have their best art come out of their most challenging times. My my understanding is that, you know, this was the period in his time when his his second marriage was was ending
basically in a very tumultuous way. Yeah. Is there anything else to it that, you know, pointed to a rough time for him that you know of No. I I think I think, you know, his his earlier life and now, of course, he was you know, nearing fifty years old at this time and and he going through his second marriage Al as you had mentioned, and And and I agree with you. I think sometimes an artist of his stature who is going through the suffering pours himself into his work and really I I wouldn't use the word over produced, but he really really became creative and and became even in some senses controversial in some of his stance on some of his story. So
dave even and maybe back then not so much, but,
yeah, I think that was what he was experiencing at the time. But and you're you're right. It probably even back then not that people were thinking about his legacy, but... But you can tell in, like, his, I guess, his legal dealings. Right? He never really hid how he felt about about lawyers and the legal profession. And there might be a little bit of this of that in in this
story, right? Because there's
some challenges with the lot or or legal statute that just feel very
unfair. It might point to someone feeling a sense of of being
taken advantage of. Exactly. It's a very interesting time in Barks life and career. You mentioned the original issue. This one
I've been... The last few episodes were and I've been taking a look at how many times these have been printed in the United States. And you know, I haven't done that for the full series, but this one, had twelve prints
including the original, which is more than any of them that I've checked in on. Yeah. Yes. Just it's in about every kind of media vehicle that that came out it was in a comics i digest
number forty four.
It was in... Like you said, it's been reprinted in the Glad series. It's been reprinted in the large Eva
white books where they really butcher the layouts.
It's been in the
what is it the?
Demographic book? Yeah. Yeah. And it's and, all the rei issues the gold key and from the Dell original and even read a Canadian copy, and it's it's very
it's the same thing. I just love it because this is Canada on it. But yeah. Very fitting from one fitting, but it was very fitting. Yes. But, yeah, it's been reprinted a lot, which may talk about its popularity
a little bit as well. And if... Even if I can add two mark, it it... You know, we we'll we'll probably talk about the advent of a Gladstone Gander a year earlier in nineteen forty eight and the short stories, but this is his first long form story. So... I mean, I did the one for race to the south seas. That one... That's true. So this this would be a sec. This would be the second long form but race to the Cell c's. I don't believe was a four color series in the line... I was the yeah right. Al was in March of comics. So was in March comics special promotion. Yeah. That March comics issue. You're right. You're right. I love that story too, by the way because it takes them to another part of the world. So...
And it is what I've called, you know, I I like to think of myself as pointing the term adventure length to describe these Century. Good idea. That one was adventure length, but it's not cool. Full length like this one. This is one of his true thirty two page. He he only did... He only went longer one time. So this is this is a a hit one of his full length series. And I think this is only the second one where he's got his luck in place at least in the adventure length. Mh. That's correct. His first couple of ten pager. I don't know the exact number. But his first couple, I know he was just kinda donald of obnoxious.
Good looking cousin. Yeah. And and I don't know if you've you've I did lower research on the whole look of Glad don't if you wanna talk about that, but, you know, what he was introduced, the Hollywood star, Joseph Cotton was was the heart drive of many. And if you look at his wavy hair and this tall gander, Al lot of people are thinking that he's based on Joseph Cotton the actor. And I appreciate that. I'll I'll have to look that up because I take can look at that. I... It's there is a resemblance when you look at him and you look at that the way he dresses the Dapper you know, coat ascot scott and the tie, and and everything Maybe there must have been someone who was modeled after. I had ponder that in the episode with the Golden Christmas tree where it were Donald kind of
transforms himself and that's his idea of good luck. Excellent.
So just a little bit more background
trivia. Oh, you mentioned that you read this paired with the story of seven cities of Ebola was it? Correct. That didn't you knows. The best of V roots i. And that's an excellent one. I I read this one first in Glad stone publication that paired it with the secret of.
And I thought I liked how thoughtfully
they curated that, you know, glad stone editor at the time, Jeffrey Blu. He he wrote it up that they were put together because they both kinda start out in the same mold. Right? They're both examples of the Adventure length story. That starts out like a like a ten pager. Mh. And and I think that's part of the appeal of this one. Right? Is that it starts out? Has this rivalry with Gladstone, very gag driven, and then it really escalate and elevate. Not quite to the extent maybe that the secret of Is does, but in a way where it is a good complement to that story. I like that comparison to the to the opening of a ten pager you're absolutely right, as I've glanced down edit it very reminiscent of those shorter form stories. Yeah. Right. Just like Secretive of Atlanta you really can't guess where this one is is gonna go. That's part of the fun, I think. Yeah. Let's see. We've covered already kinda naturally some of the background trivia that I've gotten noted out here. The only other things that I'd like mentioned before we continue onward is that this one to me stands out because it has these early pages where it's just full of interior monologue. Right? This one has a lot more of this kind of reflection and spot balloons then I'd say ninety nine percent of Barks storage. Yeah. And and the the opening four pages is this exposition of this incredible rivalry read between these two, and it starts off with just this this... Just riddled the reader with dialogue and back and forth and the opportunity for Gladstone to continuously prove that he's luck man in the world and and he does that through
event after event after event, and then, of course watching Donald and the thought bubbles as you said, are just building and building. What i love about this is the range of emotion that we see in donald over the for a few pages. Yeah. I I definitely agree. Alright. So we're obviously really excited to talk about this one. Let's before we before we get to it, I will mention
So as far as the value of this one, I think warren you've got a copy of the price guide What's the highest range for this one? Yeah. A four color two fifty six this particular comic
Al a nine point two value is fourteen hundred dollars. Alright. So, you know, these are still pretty valuable, but as I've mentioned in in recent episodes, you know, we're we're getting later on. There are many of these comics now. At some point I'll probably stop mentioning the value, but there's is still interesting to me. I do enjoy Warren meeting a few of the titles from around the world, and I picked up. Yeah. I've picked out four of them this time kind of focus on Northern Europe based on, you know, where we are.
So I'm gonna go ahead and and share for Denmark first printing of this one was called Anders and pa g,
which
means ronald Ducktales green. Yeah. And I'll I'll read the fin Finland version,
And that is Donald Ducktales greenland. And and we found that interesting. Right? Because, like, this doesn't really... I don't... It's not. It's not really near Greenland, but I... I'm... Speculating that the Scandinavian
publishers might have wanted to make it feel a little more exotic. I think they probably wanted closer to home. Do. I I don't know. It's interesting. It it is more exotic.
And then
I I apologize if if I chuckle on this one because you know, languages or languages and sometimes things sound coincidentally like things in other languages. But for Germany, we've got Donald duck
fast.
Donald duck on the North Pole.
Sure. And the... I have the Italian title here. In Italy, it's called,
which is Donald duck and the treasure of the vikings, which is pretty darn accurate.
Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. And, of course, publishers when they reprint these, they might change the titles. Over the years. So this is these are probably not current. But it it gives us an idea of how they've treated these over the years.
Luck to the north seems to be a great title to me. I think it probably felt like it was referencing maybe na of the north. Could be probably in the cultural
sure at time? Yeah. With the es references, of course, of in Alaska pre state with Alaska in nineteen forty nine was certainly an Exotic north land at the time. You know what? I I forgot about that. We're still
Yeah little about one year until Al last been state Al aren't. We good cash. Yeah. Yeah. We're we're we're at the point where it was probably in the news. It was something that national geographic I getting back to Carl Barks great reference material was featuring a lot. And yeah, You're right. It was just just just before statehood. And it was this massive territory of the unknown except we knew they had polar Barks and icebergs. So that's right. Yeah. A good catch. Thank you. I would have I would have gloss over that. So I'm sure that that's probably a big part of why he was thinking so much about the great north around this time. I did get interested in in the coordinates that are so important. I did too. I looked it up.
So so latitude
seventy north long one sixty seven West or I'm not even sure if I read those right. That's right. You got it. I I found that it seems to be located in the tu c part of the Arctic ocean. But yes. Russia and Alaska a little bit north of the bearing strait. That's exactly right. I... It's out there in the middle of nowhere away from the northwest border,
V alaska as we get into that
sea.
And I... And and which tells me that parks did his homework. I mean, he
he found something pretty pretty remote. Yeah. And he would've have he wouldn't have had the Internet to help him out like you and I certainly did. That's correct. Would have been pouring over a map or something Yeah. Good good time to go into just a tiny bit of the kind of historical and geographical context text. I mean, you already did by bringing up el last statehood. So the other thing that's interesting to me is that the the tribe
I'll say Es this one time. You know, there's people have gotten the idea over the years recently that that that word is offensive. And I think it kinda depends on who you talk to. Right? There's this mis that it that it's a.
Mh.
But I think really the reason that it's not in popular use is that it doesn't
refer to the peoples of the north like holistically. I think it only really references
one tribe of them. So it's not really accurate. And it's not
there's just not really a great term other than, like indigenous northern peoples. So, that's true. I I was was trying to look up that term and you're right. it doesn't even appear in modern
reference material because I think they're trying to eliminate that term. So I think, you know, northern indigenous tribes would be more appropriate. Right. And and probably the best, you know, the the most thoughtful way to refer to people would be by their specific tribe name, but those just aren't really in common common use. But you know what it was neat is when Barks is depicting the people that he
he he calls them es, they do mention that they hunt ag.
Yes. A whale, and that was something that I could look up. And googling it, it looks like it's actually on, the spelling Al least, but that that's the name for a bow head whale in in.
The best I can tell, you know, you would you would expect based on the coordinates that the people would have been choo
but likely based on that reference,
they would be best thought of as in.
And you know, as far as
representations of indigenous people that Barks does around this era, this one is not not terrible. Right? I... It's it's not great, but they're not poor portrayed as as savage like. Some of those stories.
They seem to have pretty pretty representative features. They're not overly exaggerated. They're not they're not really deep. Unfortunately, they're kind of... They're kind of there is a plot device. Right? To get
to steer them into the to the Kayak deals. But Agree with you, Mark. I think I think the the balance of introducing this cultural reference within the story is brief. It happens twice with Glad and then Donald. But I really
absolutely enjoy the humor and I'll call it the entrepreneurial spirit of these these people because they they are out there and they're not gonna give to anybody. They're really a good foil for both of the ducks. And I I I thought it was well handled actually. Yeah. And and it's relative terms. Right? I would say that they are relatively well handled. To me it's interesting that this really kind har back to that race to the south seas. Where again, Gladstone is gonna deeply
exploit
a native population. And then Donald is gonna kind of blu her into the consequences of that well mentally. And just like in that one, that group really does have the upper hand and they're shown as as having some real agency. So you know, for for the late forties, not that. I I'm thinking that we can get on into the story here. Yeah. Oh, you know what? Let me ask you Warren. I... I'm very interested because, you know, Barks really changes this up story by story, What version of Donald he got. Right? How would you characterize what version of Donald is he showing here? What version of Donald? That's a great question. I I see a Donald duck that I'm very familiar with, but I see a Donald duck that has this incredible range of emotion as I said earlier. And who becomes in this particular story just so fed up at one point and yet so regret at another point. This
empathy and sympathy rather that he feels for putting his cousin in danger is quite incredible. And I think as a young boy, I found that to be very human. And
very
very decent.
But I'd also like the fact that the only other character in the story is Gladstone, and I find that to be the simplicity of the story allows Donald to show his full range. Yeah. Yeah. We've got this kind of almost
intimate family rivalry story that just happens to spread out across the continent
I think you hit it. Right? Because this one is really interested in donald like feelings of guilt. Absolutely absolutely.
And his need to own him. Self. So yeah, this is an interesting. We don't we don't see this version, this specific version of Donald kind of racked by guilt and consumed And no. No. We don't. And to see that is quite refreshing actually. And Warren, I've asked that we're gonna change it up a little bit this time where you and I are gonna actually alternate discussing the pages. We've had some great conversational already. So we're not gonna get too detailed on these pages. But talking about them does sometimes
set off some good conversations. So i I think it's important
even if ninety nine percent of the readers here are well familiar with the ins and outs of the story. Are are you ready for it? Ready to go. Let's walk through this great story. Alright. So luck of the north opens up with
Al many of Barks great ten pager do with a a chance encounter between Donald and his inc
cousin Gladstone.
And this is going to kind of dev evolve into one of those, you know, bragging fest that Barks really enjoys. Setting off. Glad stone bragging about his his luck and Donald is just stew as he's setting it up. For this resentment. They're just walking through the city street. Glad talking about his his horoscope,
which says today, he might get especially rich.
So then then often off they go on their journey to see if this actually becomes true. And
at first, it doesn't. It looks like Donald got the upper hand because
someone who's out to collect from Glad grabs him by the neck and throws them and says, okay, where's my five Barks and that just re in this. Right? And then, of course, the five dollar bill... Or ten dollar bill floats down into Gladstone hand. He thrust it back Al think i and says, give me my five and change, which is just rubbing it in even more. Yeah. And
and then they they kinda go off and sit see, this is what I mean. This is where the
the the artwork is just second none in these next few pages in my opinion. Yeah. I I agree. There's some great express. You know, this the art appreciating the art in these first couple pages is really about his expressive, not about any great, like, exploration or, you know, views of of lost cities. And we're really seeing on these first couple of pages that setup where Donald is like desperate.
To
view Gladstone getting his come up. Right? Absolutely. I also find it interesting that Donald seems to reference him being kind of a low grade Chi or a couple of times. Right? Like, I I don't wanna buy any of your gold bricks. Right? So U. There's kind of this Al between, okay. Maybe he lucky, but he's also kind of this penny anti lucky. You know, Glad not in some stories he will, but he's he's not always blu into, like, oil wells and grand riches. Some of the stories, Barks really wants to kinda keep his lock a little more low key, I think. Sure. Five dollar bill here, you know, a fifty cents here or whatever.
So on the next page, they head along narrative into an auction which is a great old device that we don't get as much of these days, the sidewalk auction.
And Gladstone
bids
low bids on an old trunk counting on his luck making it worthwhile. I really like the sharp looking auction here. So they take the trunk. And again, Donald is really excited to see that it's empty on first glance, but then Glad stone, you know, he lets his luck lead him to a secret money cash. Yeah He out some money up. It turns out to be what is it about a hundred dollars there? And yes, sir, you can't beat the glad stone, which he kind references that line and a lot of the comics. But that sort of the glad look becomes the brand that he is. So they they venture off on the fourth page. They venture off and they come across the the bazaar the benefit where they he has a chance to buy the last chance to buy a raffle ticket. But he's pretty confident at this point, he says I'll I'll buy that last ticket. I always win these raffle and sure enough they go in. They go into auditor.
I love the artwork there too because you've got the the tumble with all the hundreds of tickets
And, of course, they draw the number o one three zero one three, which I love that reference too. You got thirteen thirteen, which is bad luck, and now you've turned that into Good luck. There's that little minor reference to Donald box license plate of three thirteen, which I which I saw and which I love because it's sort of that I'm always gonna have bad donald to the always good luck, glad. And then the the wins, naturally, I won and I love the balloon there with donald with this.
Amber.
It looks like almost Al an ancient hammer
stone on a stick, tied with rope, that's what I wanna club them with. And then they run into
yet another stroke of luck in that same page where the radio announces the the Jackpot winner of two hundred dollars is Gladstone and Gander. And then, of course, the final frame is donald just having it i himself laying down on the sidewalk pounding it so he can't stand it. Yeah. It's real... It's real tantrum. Isn't that he's enough. I think you're right about that. That little thought balloon with I I read it as like a tomahawk, but.
Well, whatever. It's... you know, it's a great dialogue freeway of just resting his is a great panel. Definitely a contender for favorite panel for me. You know, it strikes me that Donald could leave at any time. Right? Like, Glad up tagging him along, but I think I think Donald is almost, you know, being a tourist in his in his feelings, his...
Yeah. He's really stuck in his bad luck mindset. You know the old cartoons? Do you remember the Donald theme in those, it goes who gets stuck with all the Barks bad luck. No one. But but donald duck. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Ton of continuity between the comics and the cartoons, but we know Barks was involved with those cartoons. I
assume that not That was really kind of one of the the overriding themes that he took from it. Well, then of course, just essential h the what I call the every man quality of Donald duck. He's just he's just a person like you and I and everyone. He's vulnerable. He's unlucky. He falls in love. He he has household issues. I mean, it it's just that's what I love about this character. And that's why I've collected him. But but you're right. That it's accent by Barks when he was a gag writer for the cartoons and and has the artist. Yeah. And and he loves to see Donald as the underdog. So on the next page, you know, this is where we kind of switch to like Donald interior monologue. It's almost in highly thought balloons.
Yes. He's just stew in his resentment of his cousin and he's speculating.
He's really fix dating on this idea. He wishes he could get rid of him for a couple of months And then he kinda gets a revelation. And he
decides to create a fake map. He wants to make a map that shows the location of a loss mine and he picks a random
set of coordinates.
Latitude seventy north long one seventy six West thinking that just sounds like an awfully long way away, not really knowing where it's gonna... Where it could lead him. And and then at the end of that page, he mentions that he made it a uranium mine, which is hot stuff these days. And it's really... To me, that's a really pros.
Throw a reference to the fact that, yeah, uranium is very hot stuff in the very late forties. I I looked it up and the first
nuclear power plant didn't come online in the Us for about ten years, so warren like a hundred percent of the uranium being mined in those days was for nuclear weapons. That's right. I I did a little research on that too Barks.
Hot stuff is right.
And why was he prophetic there in in naming that? I actually went to
and it looked up uranium in Alaska and in that area. And they stopped mining that in nineteen seventy. So it was there. So he did his research. Yeah. Yeah. For sure. There there's a reason that he picked that instead of a gold mine, right, which is the obvious one. Yeah. That's good point. So the next page we see Gladstone now going on his merry way, walking down the the sidewalk, and we see the the second panel on that page shows him gl down at this. What is this? Mysterious looking paper. I love this sequence because we see donald kind spying on him watching him grab the joke or grab the deploy here. And then the thought balloon start in Glad stones head about how I have a chance to make millions and he packs his bag. He rushes out of the house. You still see Donald in that silhouette panel
behind the fence kinda looking at him, so he's following him to the airport. The plane takes off and then he discovers that the seventy degrees North one sixty seven West is actually Alaska. He didn't even know that. He says, oh, that was an Alaska plane he took wonder where it is. So then he he goes home and wants to look it up. Yeah. And Gladstone references
needing to get a ge counter.
And things like that for mining uranium. And, you know, my my thoughts today are like, oh, don't mind the uranium. you're self cleansed don't. But also, this is certainly where I learned. Or figured out what a Ge counter was. Like, I would have been nine years old when I read this. And I find this one. I talk about this man, but I I actually found this one really educational. And we're very interesting and it's like focus on map coordinates
and kind of the mechanics of uranium. Mh. Alright. So on the next page Donald, he takes to look on his globe and he narrows in where those coordinates have led. And he is just cracking up when he figures out that it's clear out in the arctic ocean. And
I think I'll just read this verbatim. And he says, way out where there's nothing, but iceberg icebergs and polar bears Glad will need all of his luck to get out of that jam. You know, that's a a great setup. Right? For the rest of this story, it's very prophetic. And kind of the top half or two thirds of this page have Donald ex exuberance. Right? He's a small thing in in his
successful plan to get rid of his cousin. And there's this sort of like,
deflation of his his
excitement
as he gets a little bit less excited with the night and you know, the I found this very relatable.
Mh. Where you're kind of falling into bed and you're reflecting on your day and you're kinda coming to terms with things. Right? Because Donald d deflate very quickly
and his starting to realize that, you know, his actions have some really profound consequences
here. Absolutely. This is the turning point in my opinion in the story. And you're right, the exuberance and the victory that he finally feels after all these years dealing with his cousin he's now one, but that reflection begins as he tossing and turning in bed at the last two panels of that page. And as we move to the next page, this is where he can't sleep now. So he gets up. He goes to the refrigerator
reflects on the fact that there are no ice boxes full of snacks where Glad is going all ice and no boxes. I love that. Love that humor. He starts eating his sandwich and then he starts reflecting when he comes back if he comes back. And then these next two panels to me if that's the turning point. That's the realization of oh my goodness. What have I done? And it's that looking into the camera. I love that shot. Leaning on the table, and then the fret icebergs and polar bears, which he's already mentioned, and then the last panel on that page has got to be one of them one of the most funny and and
imaginative panels that I think Barks has ever done and that's that only Oh my and it looks like almost
more than half the panel, just a a whole panel is this polar bear with these spat and a hat sitting on the ice float and donald just crunch up there.
And that sort of says Al all. Yeah. You're you're absolutely right. It's it's a hilarious. It's a very funny panel. The the satisfied full looking
or bear. This couple of pages, i... To me, this is the the kind of masterpiece
part of the story. Right? This is I I think this is a very strong story. I like this one a lot. I don't I don't feel as strongly about as you do, but... But I do think this is an excellent story. And and these pages are what really stuck with me even as a kid because it was so stark seeing Donald
trajectory here and
how he came to this realization. And I think you feel his guilt.
Very acutely and very un uncomfortable.
In this one. And so Barks, I think sets up very nicely. The real rest of this story his arc of, like,
sacrificing his comfort and his well being to write this this tremendous wrong. Yes. And and so, you know, we transition on the next page where he raises his nephews he doing Louie out of the bed and
just very abruptly tells them they're heading to Alaska and, you know, they're trying to search... We we transition very quickly.
And they're immediately on the search. And they're they're gonna be for the rest of this story. They're basically gonna be just one step by behind him most of the way. Right? So it's gonna feel very frantic
for the rest of it because they they come across a commotion in this town and they see a guy heading up the hill with a dog sled team. Yeah. They they aren't quite sure who that is, but they'll ask the local on the street in the big Barks with the big beard Hey, who's that leaving with the dog team? He goes don't know his name stranger, but he is the luck elle I've ever saw and then, of course, Donald realizes it's glad. And he bought one ticket and during du I love that during if he didn't win. And
So there's a little dialect there of the county of the the guy in tone. So
the next panel shows that course it Gladstone on his way and like you said, he's one step behind.
Donald claims he's got to catch him, whereas he likely to stop next. And then he says, I can't say where he's going, but there ain't nothing out there, but snow drift and musk cakes, the way he's going. So they he mentions Musk mccabe quite a bit in the story and and I know you would looked that up, Barks. What is that? No, it's like a a bog or a swamp that's a mix of water and partly dead vegetation,
cool little, you know, good and geographical knowledge. I I learned so much about the north from
series of stories that Barks did. So Donald and the nephews
have to have to move quickly now and so they have to get their outfits So the next the next panel shows donald rushing them off to get to get arctic outfits. I love that word. And then later, they're all dressed up in there. I love the the nephew, they've got the blue green and red just to match their
their their identities as well. And they've got the... They got the sled, they've got the pack. So they they they spend some money doing this, but they don't have dogs. Guess who the dogs are. They're the nephews. I like. And they were just they're working their way up the hill. But they also know that the dogs are faster than they are, but donald not concerned because Donald knows Gladstone all too well and says, He's lazy, he'll stop and rest. And so they... There's that moment where you know that they're gonna get close. Right? And it drives home the fact that they can't really stop us. Glad has a little bit more of that luxury. He's got dogs. He's got he's got time. They've got more of a timetable to. Right. Right? You mentioned the color identity that the reprint that I'm reading doesn't have the Nephews Barks is differentiated.
It's interesting when the colors do or don't make that decision. Yeah. I... It's in the fan graphic one and and it's the blue green and red in that order on that panel.
And I'd be interesting. I'll go back to my original four color comic and see if they did that as well. Right. I assume since Fan graphics tries to reproduce my to that. Alright. So, you know, we got some really nice arctic scenery on these pages. I mean, it's very snow filled, but but it's still it's still some cool art especially the one where they head into the level must country. And
they head into a blizzard and eventually, they come up on glad rest, you know, as Donald
anticipated. So he figures out that he can sneak in and snatch the map. Right? And and it's interesting warren to me that for most of this story, you know, Donald is still his pride is not going to let him gear himself towards kinda confessing. Right. This whole thing is I'm gonna get that map. I won't have to deal with the guilt of what I've done. He'll have to turn back. Yeah. I noticed that too. I'm glad brought that up because this isn't about confronting him and apologizing.
That's way below Beneath donald to do that. It's to get him from going any further. So... Yeah. Stealing the map back
And so we get to the next page. As you saw Al glad stone hun down in a sleeping bag they're out in the open, but that that great... I love these these panels because they all show that arctic evening that deep blue and in these pages. And you you see him gl down at this paper. And you assume it's the map. Well, he's...
Donald sneaks up on him after he kinda falls asleep, and then he just, you know, lets us know what that the map will not be there when Gladstone wakes up. He I love the hand reaching in. Under the pillow, you see the...
See the map. He snatch it away, and he's got it and let's get out of your boys and they run on We're safe now, he'll never backtrack and find us we'll camp out. So now they can relax Erin in as much of a hurry, Donald believes he's he's right Al the wrong, and he's done what he came to do. Yeah. And and in the morning on the next page,
they... you know, Donald shows them the map that paused all this trouble and the Nephews are confused because they're like, that's a star chart of some kind and mh Donald realizes to his horror that he's stolen Glad horace scope layouts, and he he rips it up in anger and they head back and and we know that they've just gone hours. In the wrong direction. So again, this is something that I feel very very acutely. This this whole store makes me feel very like, cold and tired
and stressed out on behalf of the dots, the especially hugo Louie who didn't do anything wrong. No night well they're always put in those situations where they've got a help donald through the the toughest of of situations. You're right. Right. And and I would say this might be the toughest of of many of them. Right? Because there there's some real degradation here pulling Al sled... Oh, I know it. Yeah. Yeah it's awful. Yeah. But they're gladly doing it for their uncle. And and as we see in the story, they kind of really defend their uncle quite a bit. So the next page, we see them hit this
massive piece of ice in that first panel and I love this because each of the nephews in turn is they usually talk and finish their sentences, so it goes the coast, the arctic ocean Al last. I love that that vista that that view that they have and they defined it as this big bowl of ice cubes. So
that's where they kind of let's let's get going.
We've got to follow the shoreline. There's to that es villages Donald calls it, and they gotta buy a boat, so they can do that. So they now Can't take the sled. The next then it shoots forward to glad stone, many miles ahead is nearing the only village
within a hundred miles Barks explains. But then he gets this sense that someone's following him. So he dashes into tone,
or into the village he says heidi H chief.
Greetings, very pleasant. How many boats you got here And the chief of the village says two and they're not boats. They're kayak he's very quickly to remind him and correct him but these are Kayak. And I don't know if the term kayak back in nineteen forty nine was a popular term as it is today for recreation.
But he's quickly to remind them that this is a tour that they use. Gladstone Stone feels that he's gonna get one of those boats and he wants to trade. And he goes no deal, can't catch
the whale with dog team. And we are now introduced to what the villagers
want out of the deal. Right. Yeah. Because, like like many peoples of the north, they depend on on w.
I know a lot of them might also hunt seal as well. And and so we've got Gladstone kind of pondering.
Mh.
How he can get their kayak. And you know, this is a pretty uncomfortable part of the story for me because Gladstone just like he was in race to the South sees. He's not... It it never enters his mind, but he's trying to take their livelihood and and and possibly condemn them to hunger. To starvation
exactly the way he did previously.
So this is kind of his little turn that if not out I mean, it is outright. Villainous. It's not meant to be seen that way, I think. Mh man. But yeah. He he is going to... you know, Donald kind referenced in the beginning his gold brick scheming. So he he has a little token, a little horseshoe. And he basically
decides he's gonna try and con them. I get the impression that Barks thought of him is as kind of lucky and kind of a con artist in in this era. Mh. Oh, he he proposes that he's gonna trade them this good luck charm that allows them to draw whales in. And the...
Chief of the village is like, I've got a whole igloo full of good luck charms. I need a kayak. So he's gotta demonstrate it for them to prove, and he kind of... He improvise you you hold it up to the ocean and and you face the ocean and you wanna continue it there Yeah he's making all this up now. I mean, he's just he's just... He's desperate. And. He's sweat. I love this because, yeah. To your point, I think, you know, he... In addition to depriving them, or or not caring so much that there about their livelihood. He now knows his only way to victory is to give them their livelihood and to bring that whale on short. So he's really hoping and praying that this happens. So he holds it up see, you do it like this, and you hold up the and you face it to the ocean. And then I love this next page is this splash panel is unbelievable. And then you just say, whale come short. You already yelled it or whatever he did in that brass voice. Whale comes ashore. And that next panel is probably one that caught me as a young kid more than anything because it was the first big splash panel i'd scene. Of this huge whale. Looks like a sperm wheel, but it just comes and hips there, and
he runs away pretty much not believing his own luck in this case, this was something I don't think he he saw coming. Right. And and then, of course, the next one he's he's out there on his way in a beautiful little single whole tie kayak.
And then we see that the other kayak is not in such great shape. And we have we Al little forced foreshadowing here that we know who's gonna get that eventually. But
And then, of course, the chief of the village takes the deal of course and says whale come ashore. And
well no come. We've been g and I wanna... At some point, I wanna talk about the word g is in this quite a bit, Two or three times and I did a little research on that. G was of going a term coined in the late nineteenth century, but it really referred to and it's a derogatory term. Right. Not used today as much at all. It's from the referencing the G culture. And I thought that was interesting that the word was used. I made some notes on this too like you did, and I thought it was interesting that they they use this quite a bit. You wanna expand on that? Yeah. You're you're absolutely right. It's
it's something that was in totally common par at the time. It was un
to say in that era. And and today, most people, you I'm sure you still have your hold out. But most people would say that it's it's a slur. It's considered a slur yes. To the people that we now call more often Roman money. Correct.
Essentially reducing the people to their actions.
Right? So yes. It's... I... I'm not not gonna pick on him specifically because... And culture early. This is what everyone was doing, but I understand why people don't do this anymore. And you're you're definitely right about that splash panel. That's a great image. It's it's remarkable. It's very funny. The little expression that he uses, great suffering and soft.
This makes it very funny. And I like to imagine I like to kind of speculate on what actually made this way do this and, you know, blu her into the glad look I also like how nervous he is with this, because I think Glad doesn't like it when he has to test his luck. Right. Right. Right. It's too much like work for him. And I haven't mentioned that, but this whole thing he's out of his comfort zone for a lot of this because in a lot of these stories, this would have been too much like work for Glad gander. So it's a little un,
but, you know, it definitely propel the story lot. It does and for the millions of dollars that he sees ahead of him, he's working harder than I've ever seen him work. Yeah. Absolutely.
And so on the next page, you know, we we get the ducks just like they came in on race to the South sees. I I like doing this
series this podcast and getting to kind of figure out these parallels almost in real time. You know, they they come in very excited see this group of locals that Gladstone has just cheated. Right? So of course, these
or whatever tribe they are are not happy to see these ducks. I'm noticing in your reading, it seems like that they've made them that originally the dialogue was probably a little more pigeon than it is in my reprint. I think mine must have been updated just a little bit because, like, mine says
Two pages ago, no deal can't catch
the whale with a dog team. And I think did you're you're reading myth the word a? Yes. That's correct. Yeah. So that's interesting. That's obviously just an editorial update. I think there is a there has been that. Yes. So
Donald asked if they've got a boat for sale and the members of the tribe are talking to each other very knowing. And, you know, they they're like, it's gonna cost you a lot.
They very wisely get the cost of one more whale, sixty five dollars. I I did not research how much a whale cost at that time. I'm guessing a lot more than that. You know, we we at least... I guess it's a little comforting to think that they have glad whale and then they've got this cost of a whale. And hopefully, that's gonna keep the tribal alive through this season. I think it will. I I think it's it's, you know, deal or no deal here. I mean, either either cough up sixty five dollars, which I love that random amount, I think I just love that number. And or you're you're you're not going anywhere. And that's where I love the fact that they have the a little bit of the upper hand here with the ducks. Yeah. I agree. I like I like seeing them get the upper hand And I like Mcdonald's expression, where's this gold plated yacht because that's
really nicely to see that it's a totally trashed kayak. And we see that trash kayak.
We see it again. And then the next page, we actually see that a whole day has been spent modifying and fixing this up. They've lost time, as Donald says, but I love it, they've taken a single whole kayak and they've made it for four people or four, and I love that. Yeah. And,
you know, and then it sounds like they got get out of there pretty quickly. You have the little native children
throwing snowball with one of the little nephews and
they're not welcome there. They're not welcome. It's time to leave. So they hustle off into the water. He's got his little... What is that a sex? There is a little yeah.
Navigation unit. So he came prepared. Again, and I love what the nephew in that fourth panel says just our luck and, you know, the reference of luck in this story, takes so many different meanings even the in the title, of course, too. But it's this is really all about luck good luck bad luck. And that I really love the the introduction of that term. Then the next few panels show that the lucky is not on their side and
the natural consequences
are starting to happen in in this forbidden and the ice breaks up, get the crashes is down and reveals for the first time we see a polar bear, gazing at them. They come to the realization that, you know, we're all here to save Gladstone, but who's gonna save us And Donald says i just don't ask that question. I got enough on my mind. So... Yeah. He's got really kind of ignore the danger that he's putting the Nephews in. His his guilt is really it's challenging. I've gotta imagine here. A really quick upping of the steaks, right? That yes. It's one panel for each of these, like, quick dangers.
You know, I forgot to mention on that great panel
earlier when when Donald is pondering, I wonder if polar bears eat people. The answer is yes that they're like one of the very few animals in the animal kingdom that is said to actively
enjoy the act of hunting and eating humans. I think the the fear of these years ago and it probably still happens today, but in some of the Canadian communities when Polar Barks would wander into the towns in the northern territories and the Northern provinces and and kind of ravaged garbage. It was fearful. Yeah but that's a really good call. Yeah. We have polar bear protocols. If if you ever get interested in it, look up how they handle it on the Northern Island north of
Norway, small. Right? Like no run with them. Well So we transition to the Nephews arriving at the point the, you know Donald Phony coordinates.
Have led them to a massive iceberg
and it's a pretty cool panel. It's it's nearly half page. We see the Ducktales are extremely weary. And they've figured out that, you know, if glad made it, he's gonna be up there. And we transition to glad stone indeed looking around using his ge counter and coming to the realization that he himself has been cheated,
you know, he uses again that that word and and, you know, donald
shows up at that point. We don't see him, but we see his dialogue balloon saying, I'll say and you have cousin Gladstone Gander. The next page really does show this next confrontation. They finally meet of all places in the middle of the arctic ocean. He confess I drew the map. I followed you here up here all the way because I knew you were sucker enough to fall for the gag. Okay. He didn't a credit to anything here. It was you fell for My gag and of course, glad realizes you drew the map, and you've gone on as well goose Chase. Our work here, they're both angry at each other. That's just not talking to each other they're yelling at each other. And, of course, Glad had enough they get into this incredible rolling fight down the hill of nephews watch them. And as they do that, they're pretty careless and they knocked the only good kayak into the Arctic ocean and it does not look like it's going to survive. And of course, Donald blames glad for it. And what of the nephew says well what do we do now? There are five of us and we only have a kayak that will hold four of us and that kinda takes us to the next part of the story. Yeah. And it's a very good job of, like,
explaining what the stakes are and raising the stakes and you know, it really it strikes to me warren that Donald had a choice here. He could've have he could have approached his Gladstone and explained everything and he could have apologized.
Right? But he he hates his cousin so much. Yeah. That he couldn't bring himself to do that. Right? So I don't know if Gladstone would have taken the apology after everything. And and he is admittedly en
but, you know, neither of them really quits themselves here. And and because of this, because of this failure to apologize
and this
reaction and anger, you know, some... Someone is is essentially doomed here. Right? What I found interesting was that the the the Nephew is pretty much just look on in some of the stories the Nephews will actually intervene and try to... And they're always the pacemaker. They think like the reader thing. So they think like, oh, this isn't this isn't the right behavior. Right. But they didn't intervene. They kinda let them both go at it, and maybe was happening so quickly, they didn't have time to save the... To do anything, but I thought that was interesting. Yeah. Definitely. So on the next page, you know, they've got a decision to make. Someone has to stay behind someone has to go for help for the person who stays behind. And so Glad
suggests
flipping the coin. Donald, you know, he he's got know what's gonna happen. He still looks a little bit surprised one Gladstone. Wins.
But, you know, Gladstone is kinda crow about his luck, which is always that trigger for Donald.
Don seems to have cooled down a little bit. He's thought enough to to tell Glad. Okay, but I'll stay here, but you gotta take the kids with. Yeah. Yeah. And, you know, Gladstone his creditors is like, of course, you know, sure. I'll take the kids. But the nephews
refuse
probably thinking, you know, we've gotta be here to take care of our uncle.
They they run away so that they can't be forced to do this. And, you know, Gladstone doesn't really pay a second thought, he says I was never one to mix some family arguments
and very ominous
ominous, he says I will send help if I get through. Yeah. That's that's... I love that last panel and moving off. But... Yeah. So the next page
Al they are
Now it Gladstone moving away from the iceberg, Donald and the nephews realized that the provisions have had left behind the sleeping bag
fish lines and that sort of thing. So Donald is like darn it. I I wish there was more, but... But I love that next panel. It's it's takes up two panels on that line and that page and it's the gl back have the shadow of the viking ship. This is the first introduction of a treasure within that iceberg at those coordinates, which means that after all, there was look. Yeah. It's a beautiful drawing
and it shows that at Silhouette of that viking ship. Gladstone gets in and his head that this is better than Uranium. This is gold. In his mind, it's some something that he sees. And he he
makes a dash for the mainland, you as fast as he can get there. And meanwhile, while he we know he's on his way. I love this day's Drag. We don't know how many days but it's a long time, which is realistic to a degree and they're fishing,
wishing for food from back home. And
now we're starting to see that the days are passing and we're seeing that there's this tropical front or some kind of warm weather front moving into that region. The the iceberg starts break apart. Yeah. Yeah. This is a really neat page. Right? There's a lot going on here. And and you're you're right about that panel of the shipped. That's a gorgeous drawn panel. The color has has to do some great work in that one. I'm am not looking at the original right now. But I think the glad version, it really stands up. It really really elevate that panel. And and then just here right, the way that they set up the the menace of the iceberg melting and the degradation of the docs. It's very cool page. And and on the next page, they continue to kind of face some of these challenges
It's melting. Chunks are breaking off. There's a warship that's using the iceberg for a a target practice, which I I think is something that board passing warships have done over the ages. One of the shells breaks the bird in half and the Ducktales slide down into the the cr or in between. And it's a very...
It's it's a very wrench
panel because the Nephews say, goodbye. Uncle on.
Donald and, you know, we realized that they they know themselves to be doomed. They land though with a thud on that viking ship. This is the first time that the docs are gonna encounter it. On that page too, I wanted to mention Barks, I thought it was extremely convenient for a worship to just happened to be there, but it was a a plot vehicle that Barks had to use for the quick exposition of the viking ship. Otherwise, it would have taken days of days and months to melt to break that down quickly for the reader. So yeah, they land on the viking ship. They led right on the deck of the viking ship. And
Donald explains that the next page,
the planks are here. They're they the next they realize it is the viking ship that they're on this the first time They've experienced that that's right we saw glad still look at it from a distance. They don't know what they land on. Good point. And and then they realize they're on a viking ship. And they look around and there are all these helmets and shields and
axes and things and they realize that this is solid gold. Now they feel they've hit great luck because they've now come in touch with all this treasure. And one of the nephews runs up from the galley and says steaks, there's frozen food here. I don't know how good that would actually be at that time, but it was frozen,
steaks and biscuits and cheeses, and I love that next one. All of of them just dive into the galley.
My favorite my favorite panel is this barbecue scene as if they were in their backyard, I just I just roar, i know, do you like your steaks done Huey,
oh, yeah. It's it's wonderful. You're right. This is one of my favorite parts of story, you know, the contrast between them finding this quote, real treasure of gold and then an even more real treasure because it's practical for these starving ducks. Yeah.
And it's it's hilarious the way he says have another thousand year old state. Yes.
And, you know, if you it it feels
plausible. Right? We probably know that we couldn't eat a thousand year old stake even if it had been continuously
frozen. But to me, if it feels just plausible enough that I'm willing to go with that. Oh, I willing like to go with it. I love it. And I love the little little grill in the the coals so they got fired going, and I love the fact that they got it going and they look absolutely
content for the first time in days. Yeah. Yeah. It's great. Because their luck really seems to be turning finally. And so they're luck turning and they're
being rein
by some goodies eats on the next page, they've kind of got gained a second wind and they're working really hard to chip away the ice that holds ship in place they're stripping the obvious treasure from the ship even though the the ship itself is
a priceless treasure We know that in in these days, an intact viking ship is like an incredible cultural find. But obviously, you know, for the purpose of the story. There's this specific treasure. And so while they're working hard, glad stone is approaching because he's he's managed to secure a boat. He's hired a tug boat and they've tracked where the south were drift is likely to carry the bird. And, you know, while their work the nephews have mentioned with all that that wealth will be well held for life. And Donald like, well, not that rich, but at least Glad can never lord it over us again about his lack Mh He's he's still really just
fixated on not being one upped by Gladstone
constantly. And that's again, he doing it with a g on his face he as he pulls a a gold shield off to pile up, but he is now considering himself the lucky he is stuck then Al as Gladstone approaches with the Tug about captain, Captain, the one of the Nephew c's of coming. Everybody's happy. It's Gladstone. We've been saved. And Gladstone jumps off. The joy of Gladstone is not so much seeing donald in the Nephews safe. It's seemed the treasure that he quickly says ready for me to take without even thinking because he's got this this claim on the treasure he tells this crew he's hired take it away guys. It's my let's to take my riches. Everything's mine. And that's when Donald just shifts and, you know, what are you talking about? He gets angry. I found this ship. Oh, no. No. No. You should be so lucky. I saw it first and I've got the papers. And it says I don't care if you've got escrow
you can't take this gold away from me and the kids. And this gets into the next page where we talk about maritime salvage laws. Thought that was interesting. I did a little research too. So go ahead. It is fascinating. This page though, you know, it's another of these collisions between these two cousins. Right? Oh know. We're Al Gladstone
he poison the well. First thing. You're right. He's more interested in the fact that, oh, here's my treasure and and my ducks, my family, my kid.
But you've been helping the glad tone block. Right? So he views them as a vessel for the for the luck. And and and this is an immense pile of treasure. Huey, can say, you know, you've done all this work. I've filed this claim. So legally this is mine. But, you know, we're we're in this together. You guys have done all this work, let sharing it. But there's just never any consideration of that'll never happen in this world. No. And... But yeah. He you're right. They use... He uses the ducks or he thanks them for finding his goal. And it's not the it's obviously not the story that Barks wanted. Tell. Right? He wants this to be a constant rivalry.
Yeah. But I just think it's interest to to point out that they're on both of their ends there were better ways to handle this. It would have been decent more pricing is nice. And you're right, maritime laws is fascinating. Right? They're there are these salvage laws.
I looked a little bit into it but it sounds like you did as well. What's your understanding? Well, the the the maritime laws go back hundreds of years. So Barks is absolutely correct. I looked for a code thirty two k. I could not find one. I did
that was definitely a made up code. I loved it because not only does he mention maritime law, which is true. He who finds the treasure keeps the treasure but this thirty two k was this, like micro
detail of the law that Gladstone is just w over Donald and and that I've got it. And he's holding it up. I love this shit he's holding it up with Al blues stamp of a seal of approval on it. Yeah. It's it's a good moment. So Donald is just back to stew in his own. You know, he's He's asking what did I ever do to deserve these awful breaks, something
take some gl in reminding him you drew. Phony map. Remember cousin so glad hired help gets everything
secured and they get ready to
to head back. And,
you know, one of the nephews asks if he's gonna take along the old ship. Glad doesn't view it as anything, but a pile of rotten planks. And mean, he says he's gonna give it back the sea. Again, of course, this is culturally and and just Al wise a totally priceless heritage treasure. But and that's not what he's interested and telling. And Donald makes, you know, a a terrible mistake here. He's I'm I'm gonna stay here. He's so disgusted. He will not share a ship back with Gladstone.
His pride of not yeah, giving into anything
related to glad stone look or Gladstone
just not sitting well with him. So he he says, yep. We're gonna stay here. And then, of course,
immediately, he says, I wonder if we made him to mistake. Yeah. Let's try not to think about it one of the nephew says as the tug boat goes off into the into the ocean. And then, of course, days later, So again, they're there for more days and they're sitting on this ship. Now they know think about food,
they don't have the treasure anymore. But at some point, Donald predicts that it's gonna let go. It drops the viking ship drops into the ocean and what I find here, is that they probably had the greatest luck of anybody at this point because the ship is completely intact. You know, so cured and preserved in this ice for hundreds of years. It it's in a remarkable shape. Right. They validate that by saying there's only a few trickle So run up the sale. And I don't know where they got to sale.
Cloth would have deteriorated by then or disintegrate, but they they do. That's a great... That's okay. I buy it. And they start tearing off into the ocean, and she sails like a grease to goal. I like that. Maybe our luck has changed. There's that word again. Yeah, to the glad kind. But quickly in that final panel, we're still having Du luck, which refers to them. Not glad don't but the Ducktales luck. And yeah. I like. A storm coming up and of course, these next few pages are all about the storm in the c. Right on the next page, they're gonna have an encounter.
It's a very
fearful or fearsome storm.
They have an encounter with a polar bear, which lands on the ship. They think that it's a white cap. I think that's a wave that has a ice on it. Mh. If I'm if I'm not mistaken... Yeah. In that in that third panel, that's actually the polar bears head at the top
there. I love that. I I it took me a while to find that. Yeah. I like that detail. And and the polar ver chase is donald around and, you know, when he dodges, the color bear falls into the hold and breaks through the bottom of the boat.
And and then, of course, it goes into the next stage where the polar Barks crashed through the bottom. The the the viking ship has been compromised it's time to abandon ship and the viking ship
eventually goes down Al they fashioned a raft out of it out of the planks and that great splash panel at the bottom of the page shows them basically
know on the on the raft now. They've they've escaped with their lives. Yeah. And you're... And that is a great splash panel. I didn't I didn't remember,
until revisiting this one, how many really great splash panels is Mh have. So, you know, they've just escaped with their lives on the next page they have one more near mist with the polar bear where Donald almost gets his high quarters
it's a pretty funny panel. And and we transition to them and sort of like, cast away mode, you know, they're just surviving in the middle of the ocean on this raft, Hungry and thirsty. And, you know, when Donald asked the kids if they salvage anything.
They... And one of them very t
admits, yeah. I just... I only got one thing. It's an old map that we found
and and Donald flies into a rage because, of course, he views a map as having caused all his troubles. Even though it's, you know, it was his own.
But, yeah, why don't you... Why don't you take us home on that last?
Yeah. So so Donald had enough with maps. As you know, it it was cause of the whole adventure. It was the map that he didn't
take from
Glad stone pillow, and he's had enough. So he is angry. He's in in you know he's red face. He's just absolutely
gonna tear it up. When thank goodness, one of the Nephew says, no wait a minute don't tear it up. What you have here is more valuable than probably anything Glad has and it's the norse map, hundreds of years before the time of Columbus. Which again is going back to a historical fact that the norse, the nor... The vikings were the first on North America and Barks makes that reference here in nineteen forty nine, which I I loved. It's seems incredible. Right? I I don't think it was nearly as well known whole michael. You feel like that's kind of filtered in these days. Right? Every everyone's like, okay. Yeah. The native Americans obviously were here for thousands of years. There's north six explored a few times, but I I don't think that was remotely as well known. So I I I felt I felt like I knew this
in the eighties
better than my classmates did. Yeah. It's a great piece of history,
and the the nephews go to absolutely the necessary trouble to explain it to Donald as he says, I don't care if it's an old norse map. He goes it's more valuable than all the gold of that show. And that's where
lights up, you know, maybe we've got something here after all
they turn around on their map. They've got this norse map now in their possession. And they glance at a coast guard cutter coming their way. And the very last panel shows these
two gentlemen on the
like, North... On the coast guard cutter, and I love it. Four ducks on a raft or out of their heads end raving.
They have no idea. And then the other one says, I hear the singing and then of course, the the wonderful song that they're singing Al they dance around on them on the raft, if you don't mind I'll I'll give it a go here. Who are? Glad s luck worth a shu. Takes a duck to have good luck remember whatever tune you wanna put to that, they are absolutely
ecstatic. Because again, at the end of these stories,
Donald heads up victorious. Right? Oh, yeah. But don't see glad
anymore. I mean, once he leaves, that's it. That's true. He exit stage whatever.
And we end with the Ducktales triumphant, which we we don't always. Right?
Oftentimes, in in these stories with glad, it kinda ends two ways. Right? Either either Gladstone ends up on top and donald this sugar end or Donald has triumph
despite
glad tones lock. In this case, it was a Al ladder. Yeah. Yeah. So that was a great rendition that's pretty close to what I had in my head.
There's probably a little c chan. And usually when they end with singing Al little song, they they're probably singing a snatch of a on from time. You know what? That was great warren. And I appreciate you help and
revisit this story. I'm sure we have a lot more to say about it. Would you mind if I just mentioned a reference of the viking ship because it does... Absolutely because again, it's not the same viking ship, but I found fascinating that in the Golden helmet, which was written three years later,
it's one of the best stories I think too. And it opens with Donald in the museum with the viking ship there. And I it's very similar and look. Could it be the same one, some eyes it possibly could. It some say it couldn't because it sunk but I thought that was an interesting in some of my research. People
were referencing the the rein introduction of the viking ship. But and it's impossible I think to yank out this story without comparing it to the Golden helmet. Right? Because I put in my notes, that this one feels almost like a dry run for the golden helmet. Because there's so many similar themes and similar occurrences and and you're right. The Golden helmet is is just
certainly one of his masterpieces.
And I'll tell you, you know, when you and I were talking
in advance,
I mentioned that this wasn't one of my favorite stories, but part of why I like doing this podcast so much is that
looking at the stories from this perspective, it helps me kinda reconsider them and I'm finding so much to appreciate from this one and it does have so many great parts. I I still don't think that I would consider it in like my top tier. But I do get why people really like this one. I don't think it ever quite lives up to the greatness
of the golden helmet
itself, But but what what a fun story to revisit. What a what Al fascinating a great story with some just awesome art and some really great elements.
I really enjoyed diving into it more than I ever have.
Other than a leisure reading and it allowed me to really explore it once again and I really had a lot of fun doing that. That was great. Yeah. So so you I think you've mentioned that this is your favorite. Right? I think it's my favorite because it was my first. I think that's number one. But the more I... The more I look at it,
there is the the glad known donald relationship is
re told. The range of emotion that Donald displays Al we talked about going from anger and frustration to regret and wanting to save his life
showed me a side of Donald that I really like that that I I referred to him as the every person Ducktales. And... Yeah.
So I think for that reason, but it's it's it's just one that stuck with me. It's just... you know, you have to say what is your favorite
favorite
duck story? I love the second rich duck. That's great. I love Flood heart,
you know, and I I love those. But this one the the the minimal number of characters, you've got Donald the Nephews and Gladstone.
That's it and then the supporting cast. I just love the simplicity of that and of the
great crazy adventure to some place far off and
and the ducks winning out in the end. I... There was just... It it just for me it had everything. Alright. Very well said. I think
that this this has to be considered almost one of his more like,
intimate
reflective stories because so much of it is is about the emotions,
you know, Don inner turmoil,
more than any story I can think of offhand. So that that's the one way that it stands out a lot to me. And you know, it's always gonna I think I think it's pretty universal that a lot of duck fans would peg
golden helmet as the best Donald dot story. It comes up in the conversation a lot. So this one's it's another
Arctic set one. It's about a viking ship. It's it's going to maybe
compare
it's not fair necessarily to control. I think it's a great pre cool to the Golden helmet and know Golden Helmet was his second to last adventure story and
really
I'm looking Al my copy up there on the wall.
Are you... It's the second the last one for Donald individually? Well, it's before the gil man.
I think it was one of the last four colors.
The second four. Of those one shots. Right? For the one shots. Yeah. Yeah. That's right. So double one shots. It was it was later. It was... I think fifty three was the Golden helmet and what an era though. I mean,
that era... I mean, between... I wanna say, even Christmas on Bear mountain with the introduction of uncle Sc to to the Golden helmet is that incredible run? Yeah. I've kind been trying to think where this golden
age this sort of, you know, prime era of has began that I was kind thinking old castle secret, but there's capsule and and, of course sheriff of Bullet Valley, the best cover in the world in my yeah. That's amazing.
But, yeah, I think I think that a careful reading
really benefits this one. I really enjoyed this.
I really enjoyed thinking about some of these
aspects that it's a very deep story. Right?
That that exploration of guilt.
So so I really enjoyed this again. I don't think that I would consider it in my very top tier, but probably in my very next
okay of comics. And and that's kind of where the community seems to come down on this one. I agree. If you check out in Ducktales,
this one has a very high rating. This one is rated eight out of tenth if you average everyone, which which places it as the twenty ninth highest rated story on index. So I actually feel like that eight point zero that this one has might be a really good dividing line for length Barks top tier. You know because it feels like anything that peaks in that that the community can agree has an eight point hour above. You know it's it's at least a near masterpiece.
So obviously, people like this one a lot.
I don't know that I could ever consider a glad story in my all time favorite. Just because he's kind of... The the kind of character he is. First off, I think Barks
makes glad to be a little bit hate. Right? Barks
health. He didn't like him like clyde game. He didn't like them. He he threw that vehicle in there too
really set donald off and he succeeded. But no he did not like him neither as a character. There's not many redeeming values about Gladstone. You see, as you noted in the story, you see have a couple of panels show a little bit of care for his
his cousin.
But I gotta say I agree with you there.
Not a whole lot of
enduring qualities about them about the Ducktales.
the.
I think I enjoy him a little more in the ten pager And then they adventure what I call adventure length, holiday stories, you know? I I really enjoy his turn in, like, Christmas on
or rather
Christmas for Shaq. Mh.
So, you know, Gladstone is kind of an interesting character. But
I guess this one and Gil and man are are probably his best adventure story turns. I would say. So very fun, Very interesting story. It it's off. It itself a little bit better than you might expect based you know, in terms of, you know, I like talk about what's kind of dated what's retro grade.
And and, you know, the depiction of the northern tribe it it certainly could be better, but it but it also could have been much worse. And then I I like how educational this one is. I do feel like it have a good idea of some of the geography
and the culture of the Arctic
and just the idea of the coordinates.
And the use of the sex and stuff.
So I think it fares very well there. What what what do you think about his his lit graph for this one as oil?
My goodness. Do you see one behind me here. I we're on camera here. I've got
three lit photographs of this one. And
I I I really love it. It's... I think one of the best, beautiful color
it's from the cover of the dell comic and the famous cover with the polar bear with the kayak
on top of the of the pause with the Polar bear on his back. I love this Lit graph. It's a mini lit. It's not a large one. And it...
Yeah.
I I... And again, I love the... I love the cover. The cover of the comic itself is
just the colors are really Yeah. It's it's a great one. I agree. What what a trends you got there? And I've got it great there. So you... Yeah. And but I do... I do like the lit graph on this one. And
I think it was... I didn't do my research on this, but I gotta believe it's it's one of his favorites.
I I know that it it just... It's it says everything.
Yeah. So so he obviously,
you know, liked this one,
I think this stuck out for a lot of people. We do have that. With the graph version of it. As far as I know, this one was never referenced
in Ducktales in either of the Ducktales here. You like... It was not. No. And and I've I've expressed this before.
I'm actually
surprised at how little Gladstone gander
appeared.
In those duck
series, because he's only
used
a couple of times in each one at at best. So I think I I didn't... Yeah. I didn't follow the Ducktales
series that much. My son did a lot. And
but you're right, I think that
as much as they were trying to
retail some of the great Barks stories,
they left... They left out the glad character. Maybe because he was just an character and they didn't really wanna play with that.
You know, I know that we have both been really highlighting a lot of piano that stood out as we did the story. Is there one that you would call your favorite in this one? So the panel. Mh. Yeah. I I think that there was one Oh gosh. If I were to say one panel, I think about it's early on. It's not a splash panel either. It's the... Hits the panel with the the thought bubble with the polar bear had just eaten Gladstone. And it just... It just that that ultimate regret... Yeah. The comic turn takes
and what might have been going through Barks his head he was inking that. Just really that one
stands out and the whale the splash panel the whale hitting was the first splash panel that we see out of... I think there are three in this story. Now that just I mean think about it from my point of view as a ten year old seen down last panel for the first time ever seeing a splash panel of a story. To remember back that far and remember the effect hat on me. So, yeah, those two. How about you? Oh excellent.
So I have a pretty un unconventional choice this time because I'm usually drawn to, like, what I consider the gi panels, you know, the really sure. Sure what's yours? But The one that's always stood out to me is the one with his internal monologue where he's transitioning to guilt. The one that says guys can get stranded on those ice flows and drift for months have to live on fish
and his dialogue is
consultant. Right? His dialogue is very, like, crow and cheerful and his face, is expression has transitioned
to, you know, that sort of pre early dawning of guilt.
And it's just such a deeply uncomfortable panel that.
I I think it's showing some very complex emotions there. And it really always stuck out in my mind as that it might have been the first time it really
crystallize for me that your
interior monologue
doesn't have to match. Mh. Your external expression. Mid it's fascinating to me. What a what an amazing panel that is. Well you're right. I'm looking at it. There's a contradiction here. There's the
guys can get stranded monologue that you talk about, and then his head is buried into the pillow. And
this look of dread
completely contradicts what he's saying. That's a really great comment.
But honestly, that whole sequence, those yeah
and and then also a near run app, you had mentioned it that circular panel
with that realization it is is very
keen, very, like, effective.
Yeah. In this very exciting
globe spanning one. That's that's what really stood out to me. So
so Warren, this this has been an awesome conversation. I really appreciate. I I love having
my my good friends on to share these stories with them, but there is also definitely a thrill and in sharing this with a long Ducktales as well. So thank you for doing this. I hope I hope I can have you back because this has been really awesome. Oh, thank you, Mark. I absolutely enjoyed this again to to to dive deeply into the stories I grew up with and to even put a modern spin on some of them which I love listening to your your podcast so much.
That I i I love the different
points of view that people today have of these stories and that's really your goal here is to to to expose these stories to today's
audience and to let them come away with what they want to and do they hold up it with time.
Great. I had a blast. I'd love to do it again. Excellent. Do you do you have any any final thoughts before before we wrap things up? Know, the only final thoughts are if your listeners
haven't discovered the full canon of Barks,
please do, and and don't forget Don Rosa and his great contributions to the Ducktales stories and bringing them to another audience into another
generation
with his re retailing and sequels and pre. I mean, it's great this is a universe that I think a lot of young children. I've got grandchildren and you've got young children. I mean, I think it's just a wonderful opportunity to introduce these stories to new generations. And I think for the most part, I'd say they hold up pretty well. Aside from the cultural imp priorities that we see
the the themes of the stories, the theme of family, the theme of of
trust and loyalty that we see in a lot of these is our our really strong values. And and I think
again, I'll just say, Barks was one of the most brilliant storyteller of the twentieth century and I'll I'll say that from the mountain top.
Awesome.
I definitely agree. Very well said, alright. Well, thanks again. And hopefully listeners will come back for next
episode when we get to talk about land of the tote pulls.
As always, you can reach out to us on our Facebook page Barks remarks, and
email is Barks remarks at g mail dot com. Thank you so much for listening.