Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of sc Mc and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge cl of all time join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context, and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks. Welcome back to Barks remarks.
I am as always mark Sever, a grown man who
enjoys Ducktales comic books. And has done so for a a very long time, and I'm joined by a returning guess. I'm very excited to have him back. I'm gonna let him reintroduce
himself. Thank you, Barks. I'm Warren Har, another adult ent of the duck stories and a longtime carl Barks fan and also a don Rosa fan, but I'll have to say I kinda tip my hat to Carl Barks for opening my eyes to a world that I had not ever imagined would exist
until I was a ten old boy. So
as we talked before, Mark, I'm a longtime time collector, reader of comic books, collector photographs. All things Donald Ducktales to be honest with. Happy to be back and
enjoy this. Excellent. Yeah. And
we get to talk this time about trail of the unicorn, warren,
we were talking a little bit beforehand and and you mentioned that you hadn't read this one in some time. Did did this one kind fall off your radar? It did. I I don't know why maybe it was I think a lot of it was just it wasn't a cover. Call out, you know, in a Dell comic, and and I but I do know where it lives and and was really happy to discover it again and and really had to read it several times to really uncover what I thought were some interesting points we'll talk about and some very humorous points and some odd points, and I we'll just we'll just wait. But I enjoyed reading it again. It's a twenty four pager, but those are great stories as well. So... Yeah. Looking forward to talking about this with you and sharing our thoughts. Awesome. Yeah. It's a little bit shorter than the average and you know it had been a long time for me as well. And I think one of the things is that it's such an embarrassment of riches
you know, to reference one of the lit photographs with the burke stories. Right? Because there are so very many of them that, like, it's easy to go a decade and and be like, oh, yeah. I I haven't read this one in so long and exactly. Like you say, it's it's a treat to revisit. Yeah. It is a treat to revisit these stories that you knew about. You remember hearing about them, and then you remember a panel, which will come to it the infamous last panel, but it was it was it it jared a lot of memory. Right. And and and I think part of why I'm enjoying so much doing this podcast, you know? Is that it's giving me this, like,
systematic and forced way to remember Barks. And I've never... I've never read them the way that I am doing it now, you know, in this mostly chronological
manner. And I'm I'm discovering new things about the stories. Because I never owned, like, the the Carl Barks library. You know, I collected them as Gladstone
and then Disney and Gladstone printed them.
Radically out of order. So so this has just been a fun way to kind of get get an idea of what the the very old timers who are collecting them when they when they came out,
you know, in nineteen forty six,
if you went down to the drugstore and bought it for a dime there, like, That's that's kinda what I'm doing, and that's what what makes this so fun. It does. And I I wish I had been around as a ten year old in nineteen forty six to be able to go down there and with a pocket full of dimes by mint copies and bag them and know what would they no what would happen in the future. However,
like you
discovering them and having this your podcast
unveiled them in chronological order as Barks wrote them and and and pinned them. I think it's just great and it gives me a chance to revisit them again, but also
not just discovering the adventures for the second or third time, but really trying to
get inside maybe Carl Barks his head to find out what he was thinking at the time. And then the cultural differences between today and yesterday, just fascinating way to look at these stories in a different light. For sure. I I had such a good time doing that last one we did where we talked about luck of the north and and I thought it worked out so well how we tag teams those pages. I think that's a good way to do it when I have you and other
long Barks fans. I love love having those newbie hosts son as well. But, you know, they're they're both good, good models.
So we're we're gonna do that again this mh.
There is a little bit of backgrounds to talk about before we we go into the story.
Warren and if you have anything, feel free to chime in, but I'm gonna mention and some of the basics about this. Again highlighting the title. This is trail of the unicorn, and you mentioned that it's not a story with an original Barks cover. That's because this was the the B story in our our last week's episode. I want see land of the total pole. Yeah. Big value. Right? Because this was the B story with the land of the tote poles.
And
we we are finally into the nineteen fifties. That was
as it was last episode, March of nineteen fifty is the cover
date. I think it would have been written into the late forties still.
You mentioned that it's four color two six t three, maybe you didn't mention it, but it's... I didn't that it is four color two sixty three four color two sixty three. I found that this one has a a surprisingly low number of reprint. Index listed only six printing for the Us including the original
color I was unaware of that. I know I have probably in the Carl Barks library. It's in the Graphics book, of course, which I'm
today. Ira and in Glad was one of their first issues and yeah. And I had a cool Don
cover. I I really enjoy the the covers from the. So one a little bit of fun background trivia. Just some kind of observations that I'm making is that to my memory, this is the first of several stories that are gonna center in and around the himalayas. Right? I don't think I'm forgetting any. And and Barks is gonna have fun coming back this part of the world for some pretty memorable stories later.
This one is the second story that has both sc and glad in it. That is, like an adventure story. But it's really the first one where they kind of figure both figuring it significantly. Right? I think Scrooge was kind of a glorified
cameo and race to the south seas. But interestingly, we don't see them interact. Unless not.
No. We don't end this story. We don't see sc in Glad Interact, but I still think sc is used as a vehicle to steer the story we'll we'll talk about that as we can yeah. He's it's very a minor character appears to the beginning at the end.
With all the sc
elements of character that you would expect, but, you know, minor role. Yeah. He kind of book ends it. Alright. So warren we I I really like to highlight some of the titles from around the world as you know because this this has such an international readers.
And I've got a panda to this Scandinavians. Right?
I'm saying that lovingly.
So
why don't you share with us one of those international titles? Well, let's start with the German title. We... And and and this is interesting.
It translates says to the hunt for the one horn.
And then I'm gonna say it right here if I don't do it. Right. You can Al it. The h of the ein horn. So I'm not gonna correct you at all worn, because part of the fun of it is get is butchering churning it and getting it wrong. I think. Well, I don't wanna offend anyone, but
I I think in German, the J the the year sound. So the the, the yogurt of Dos dos Ein horn, which is a.
One horn horse. I I love that. There you go. I I figure if we're making, you know, a good faith effort. I I had
precisely one and a half years of French So I'll I'll take on France. We've got donald cellular at
eco mh. Yeah. So... And and I
that keys. I think that's gonna be on the hunt for the unicorn.
Okay. Alright. And then what do we got next?
Try. Let's try Al stay in Europe. Let's try the Italian which starts with
center
unicorn, which looks like donald duck on the trail of the unicorn. And I'm not sure what interior is, but it must be trail or search. I think so. And we'll we'll know when I do the Spanish because it's
pretty much the same title. Yeah. Got
and
And that's Donald Duck and the unicorn trail. So my speech failed. Okay. Awesome. Our always
discover those titles and what people how they were how they were translating, whether they was Donald duck or... Yeah. I agree. And then I had a little bit of fun switching from the story background to kind of the cultural background. I had a good time worn looking at the the legend, the unicorn myth. I don't know if you got into that at all. A little...
I'd love to hear what you have to say. I I really did go back and try to find that myth and why
decided to play with that. So I mean, unicorns are are like a pop culture fixture, obviously. And I think the classic
representation is that they are like, crowd and noble.
This one, you know, we'll get into it, but, like, this unicorn is is ferocious.
Yeah. This is amazing. I think that one it stands out. Right? Because unicorns are
sometimes they're represented is dangerous
but they're never usually like, aggressive. So he's we're gonna have a pretty unique and pretty cool version here. I I won't go do too deep into it, but this is a legend that goes back really far and it's one of those like examples of of culture parallel culture.
That diver culture. I can't remember the term for it, but where a lot of different cultures kinda come up with the same idea. There seems to be this whole in cultures legends this place
for a proud horse with a horn. I learned that the unicorn myth actually is thought to originate in the Al himalayas region that was really cool to me. It's first recorded and, like me
mesopotamia myths, but it probably got there by way of India. And so the the himalayas pee are thought to have maybe kind of mixed up. Combined four different animals. The Indian Rhino now,
the chi ante, the wild ask Key and the Tibetan wild y and kind of ama them into what became, you know, the the legend. And then I find it interesting too that the the Na wall they learned about the Na wall later on in Europe. Yes. Like viking
traders,
and that probably influenced a pop culture depiction of that sort of spiraling horn. I would glad you mentioned that because I was thinking of the our wall as well and and how that was introduced and actually photographed and it wasn't a myth, and I thought that was an interesting taking the
the legend of what we now call a unicorn, which I love your your description of the Indian culture putting these these wonderful
animals together to form this beast of of significance.
But then we have a real animal that exists and we we put those together and into creating the fable that is contemporary. And times when I think of of unicorn and I think of the, I think of a more docile
animal,
that I found featured in popular culture as
my granddaughter will be four years old on Thanksgiving. This year. And she wanted a jewelry re box with a musical...
Well, we got her the Baller, but there a unicorn on one. And
it's pink and it's smiling. And it's
tied to I think in this particular
marketing appeal, to a little girl, and I thought that was interesting. And then, of course, in popular culture, you've got it an animated feat animated series. You've got my little pony and it's very
rendition of the unicorn appealing to children. So when Barks introduces us to the unicorn, wow, what ferocious beast, and even on the unveiling of it in the story, this majestic beast. Yeah. And you mentioned that it's majestic and it is, but it's also kind of un.
Yeah. That threw me off a little the first time I read it because, like, they're always so elegant. And and you said it they're always kind of usually a little girl's character. Yeah. So this is
Yeah. This is this is a pretty cool contrast. Let's let's launch into the story unless you had anything else to chime in with there. What? The only... The only thing I love to launch the story with is is I have to I have to somehow say and I I I read this. If you go through those first few pages when we will
my first thought was Barks thinking about what was going on in his life at this time? Because he is truly...
We know that we talked a little bit at the last episode with luck of the North that he was going through a tough time, so he poured himself into his work in the late forties and early fifties. But he is truly in a playful mood while writing this. That then the only word I could come up was playful and Gi. He it seems like Donald dialogue and
discovery of sc stayed out in the country and his zoo. I mean, Barks is having a field day
exposing more of his characters he loves so much but giving us more information and having fun with the dialogue, like, almost not caring, but having been really confident in his writing. That that's what I I thought. Yeah. I think I think you're onto something. Right? Because this is breezy story. Right? That's not good good word. Yeah. It's not it's not like careless, but but it is it's it's got kind of almost this casual
tone. You're you're absolutely right. Like he's He's really brisk with the storytelling.
Maybe to a false because this one this one's pretty quick, but there are some really nice elements to that. Two. Right How launches us into the middle of the phone call. Yeah. That... That's interesting. I wanted to share that that that I just... There's a playful going on with him while he unveil some really interesting things in his primary characters Yeah. I like that. I think that's I think that's a good thing to keep in mind as we go through it. So let's
let's do it. I'm gonna I'm gonna kick off and I'll let you take the the alternating pages. But but as always, chime in if you see something that you wanna say, or I I already referenced that we start off in the middle of a phone call. It's it's clear that Donald is
listening.
He he is not steering the conversation. He is guessing,
his uncle sc repeatedly. It's clear that, you know, Sc is the driver of the conversation. Donald ends the phone call with his head swimming and
checking in with the Nephews.
And, you know, Donald has obviously
just been instructed to to get out here as quick as possible. I've got big doing bid business for you because the Nephews can barely get his attention long enough to learn that he's on his way out to sc his country estate. They wanna toggle along and find out what's what's going on. And so we we get the characters
moving. Right? They start out right away almost immediately in transit. They leave duck bird, we got a a great little site gag. You know, i I should pause here for a moment to highlight the fact that one of the super things about this story is that he's near the top of his game as far as the site gets stuff. Absolutely. He knows what he's doing and he knows he's he's gonna win the reader over with these little psychic gigs like, the the love Barks and
leaving Duck. Yeah. It said how do you interpret that? Those two birds? I I interpret that as the mail bird, you know, feeling threatened and and being en.
Yeah get away that... Yeah. I love it. But this one may pack in more site gag per page than your average Barks story. And I I recently did, of course,
land of the tote poles. Mh. And and I didn't remember that one very well at all. And I found that that was the same thing. That had a really high ratio of sight debts.
So Al as they're departing duck, they pass by their cousin glad. He is thrown into the story right away. And we see him lounging and fishing
so that's a really great
identification of his kind of, you know, lack and days
fun v
character.
And and they do reference
before
when Donald turns off to sc private road, the Nephews
are leading the story along and
let the reader know that O uncle Scrooge has a zoo out of this country a state. So that's that's gonna be our destination and
tell us about our perspective shift on the next page.
Right? Right? And... Yeah. He they pass Gladstone. I don't think they see Gladstone glad don't seize them. But he quickly says okay, they're going off to his estate. So we get the Glad stone
peer now from the branch of a tree. He screws up a tree quickly
and says nobody goes there, unless it's important business. And then could the old guy referring to Uncle Sc, a want donald to be one of the animals That's the first of a couple of times where
Donald
character
could be characterized as a zoo animal. I think that's another... It's not a site gag, but it's a verbal gag and I love it. I do tell here. So and then goes not that silly. So he quickly dismiss that thought. You see the silhouette of Gladstone running through this make this first time I think the readers ever see a country estate of uncle sc outside of Downtown Duck. He sees the the convenient drain pipe Oh good. I can ea drop if I'm lucky,
again pointing out that I'm lucky on this, but I'm always lucky. In fact, lucky Glad gander. Is what I'm famous Al. And
Carl Barks
has a tendency to want to reintroduce some of those primary traits in his stories. Just to remind the reader again who they are. And what their traits are. We we we come up then to Don nephews pulling up to a kind of a vent over uncle sc in silhouette on the front porch. Almost like uncle Scrooge we see in Christmas on Bear mountain almost in half kind of cro over leaning both hands on the cane, but he looks Al gl. And then screws right away says jump out and follow me. And this is again the continuation of the famous what I call continuous dialogue of Donald. Yes uncle Scrooge. So what he left off on the telephone picks up again. I counted over twenty yes uncle Scrooge
alone mark. And so then he takes him under this grand view of this... What I would call a not a modern zoo of course, but back in the fifties and the forties, there were the cage animals, you don't see that a lot in modern Zoo now. But you see what he's referring to in the background as the the the the zoo. Yes.
Excellent points warren. Right? Thanks for highlighting that he left off with the yes uncle Scrooge on on the phone call. And it's it's a great gap. Right? Because we're gonna see for for the first many exchanges,
Donald only
response is gonna be yes uncle Scrooge.
To really good comic effect. And and you're right about sc, he's a little bit s over, but you can see that evolution. Right? He's I think he's looking physically
more like a little bit more like the modern sc that... Oh yeah. What what he's gonna land on. Yeah. I last few. I agree and but then, of course, the next frame, he's the spray uncle sc that's off on an adventure. But not him. He's sending the ducks on the adventure on his behalf. And this is where I I said earlier mark that the the playful of of Barks is showing here in the dialogue. Right. Because we've got a lot of meat neat little examples of dialogue
these first few pages at the zoo, they're pretty wild. Right? Because if we all these things going on at once. Right? And and we... Maybe we can just kinda s size this couple of pages organically
because for this Zoo sequence,
Sc is gradually setting up that he has this task for Donald. You know, he's rightly proud of his zoo that is said to have every animal
But in fact, it's missing one animal. The the nephews initially defend Donald because they called back to that goof
saying, you know, sprinkle Scrooge, you can't put Donald in your zoo. And and while this conversation is happening, while Scrooge
is leading up to what what we the reader, you know, can kind of guess from the the title, of course, he's gonna ask him to go in search of the unicorn. And he's brow him into saying, yes, Uncle sc repeatedly. I I have to think that's probably his business sense, getting him
responding affirmative
over. And in parallel,
we have Gladstone
trailing the docs trying to ea on what the big business deal that they've got going is. And at the same time, we're passing by these really like fantastic looking. It's a mix of, like, realistic animals
that are very ferocious
and and goofy animals like a good.
Yep. The good... Yeah.
You know what? I mis remembered that there were more of the goofy animals
Mh in in this one then just the News. And I think that I had a false memory from Don Rose Al like semi follow to this one. That's possible. I I I I have a similar memory of the Ga,
definitely, but then looking at some of the other frames that will will covers some of these other odd animals that he introduced. So, yeah, we've got...
And and we've got glad stone almost
blu into these like, dangerous
animal and enclosures.
And and he just highlights the fact that, you know, if his luck is not he's not letting him access it, it's probably doing it for a reason.
So he ends up in an empty and a pen and we get to the Ducktales getting kind down to business
with. Tell us about message.
Yeah. I mean, the ducks now are are, you know, yes uncle Str, yes uncle Scrooge, I'll give you ten thousand dollars and all expenses to go to Asia. And secure the animal. Would you like to do it? And there's that final yes uncle sc. Echoed by the Nephews and Donald, they look happy ten thousand and dollars is ringing in their heads. And then he just says no, That's a promise. Yes. Uncle Scrooge one more time from Donald. And then he course he pulls down the screen. I love it. It's a little... Like, pulled down Scrooge just happens to be there with a picture of the unicorn on it.
And then, of course, the payoff to all the S uncle Scrooge just comes up at the end of that page, no uncle Scrooge sc.
What do you mean though? As he starts the first page, but I love that that exposition and then then of course, you've got the ever present Gladstone.
Finally,
lifting the grate off the ground in a safe pen, and he's hurt everything. Yeah. And and it's almost like a a classic Abbot and costello routine. Or something. Right? I I feel like it could
yes by, like, who's on first. Right?
Like you said, if you count them up, there's a ton of those. And so it's it's it's it's the rule of comedy where you do that pattern and you payoff off and and it's great. That no uncle Scrooge really lands with a punch. You know, Barks chose to end that page with that panel for for a reason. And wrap up that game. Then.
Which should you a great great
comparison to the comedy
timing and exchange of an happening costello. Certainly, that would be my comparison as well. Right. And this called shirley at that time, that would feel very relevant, I think. And that was a reveal too. You know, you can almost hear sc flourish
the
the the projector screen. And so And so on the next page we get, you know, Donald going. He's defending why he now wants to take back his promise.
He is, of course insisting that unicorns are not real they're fig. He compares them to funds and sat.
And
sc immediately counters with the fact that this is not a drawing. It is a photograph that one of his pilots
snapped at crest the himalayan amount
And so Donald is just
the fact that he's his big mouth has made a promise that he doesn't wanna keep. But, you know, Scrooge just pointing out that he's gonna have...
This is gonna be all expenses.
And more and this strikes me is way more generous. You know, then the model that he would establish going forward. You mentioned that going forward in not too many stories, he's gonna go along for the ride. Right? Harp Marx hasn't really figured out that Uncle Sc doesn't just send them off. At this time, this is this this is like that weird little transitional point. That's a really good point because you search joining them on many of their adventures as we as we move forward in time. But here is it's it's basically give me the last known animal on Earth that I do not have in my ex extremely great zoo and and nothing not... I will spare no expense. I don't think ten thousand dollars is a lot of money, but but that packed then and for Donald and the nephews, that's probably a you could live on that for a while.
Yeah. And I did do... I did visit the handy dandy insulation calculator. How would you come up with?
It's a hundred and fourteen large. So, you know, hundred and fourteen thousand not bad. That's before count the the adventure, I guess in the Pence is paid. And and so of course, Glad has
overheard this. And he's resolved to be in
la, which is the name that Sc says that they're gonna... The name of the city that's gonna be there, like, jumping off point. And and this, of course is a reference
to
the classic story
lost Horizon. Right? Yeah. That was a the lost Horizon was a wonderful...
Well, Frank frank film. Right. Back in the thirties and
and was one of my favorite directors of all time and wonderful storyteller. But... yeah, that was the the s, you know.
And that's
that's a reference that is
super famous. There are a lot of
theories that are gonna parity that place and that concept
you know, again, it feels like one of those cultural touch stones someone figured this out and then everyone came back and told that same story, and, of course Carl Barks is gonna come back. And tell that story again very memo. But this is just kind of a fleeting reference to it. And I'll say on that last panel of that page with the Uc see the the blue great cover the pieces and not a bad deal for me, see you in S
cousin donald. And that's the last we here from him for a while and I wanna come back to that
transition because... Well, we'll we'll go back to it.
Yeah. So, you know, we get this little transitional page next to where Donald is is in route, and he's getting chi to hurry up over the radio comes by uncle Scrooge.
Right. Get some... We got some neat scenery of him flying through a mountain pass into Shane la And he's kind of... He he's kind of just internally,
you know, kind of missing the kids because he opted to leave the kids behind. And and he dis Barks from the plane and is immediately
shocked to see the kids
appearing as though they have been, you know, beaten him there and have been waiting for him to arrive. And that's what we see, we see them leaning up against a wall, one of the nephews
you know, high donald and and they move into they my seeing things. I might have known you kids would follow me over here. Now, we didn't follow you. We s away on the plane. And then, of course, that just frustrate donald to no end.
Great little shot of him there. I love that artwork work. Well, I won't be stuck with you come on. We'll go find a place.
You can stay Well, I go hunt unicorns in the mountains. I thought that was interesting. He was gonna... And then, of course, we... They they trail after him and it begged donald to, not leave them behind you will need our help which is foreshadowing a whole lot.
And he says shut up which I I just classic once in a while Donald will just say that, and it just... That brings me back to my first claim and the first podcast where he's just every man. He's just the just speaks his mind and he says what we think. But then we jump to this new character that's introduced at the time here. This
mystical man who comes out of the shadows and says, I see a man who has come far on a strange quest, and I love that response of what is it to you bud and then he introduces himself. I'm Mo hand or, of course, we know that's I must have a hand out.
Yeah I'm not so sure the reader at this stage knows who that is. I think they do, and I'd love to hear your thoughts on that one mark. Yeah. I mean, I think for a certain reader, you instantly
recognize this Gladstone.
I think I remember Barks to reading this Al about age eight or nine. I assumed that it probably was, but I wasn't sure. You know, he he introduces himself as a fuck here.
Do you know what a fuck here is warren? Yeah. I did a little research on that. And
what I have is from one definition, it's a muslim where Hindu religious
aesthetic or Mend,
Mend, I Monk commonly considered a wonder worker. That's what I found out. And I thought, you know, if you wanna break that down, it was
definitely a part of that culture
immunity, maybe a religious sector or something like that. What did you find? Yeah. That i knew... I knew a little bit about this already. It's it's usually someone who's is islamic. It might refer to Hindu, but usually,
usually someone who's muslim and from this, like,
sex that is kind of concerned with miracle or mystic.
And famously,
they're very... They have like this beg
aesthetic it. And I think there's a little bit of romance to them the sort of like adventurous, magical
aura
we're over the deck in earlier pop culture, where you might kinda slip one of them in if you just needed to introduce a little bit of mystic
into your story. It's it's impossible not to, like, reference the fact that he's we know it's glad
because we're adults and we've read this before. And and he's like, used soot to Barks his skin, and that's obviously,
obviously a very tacky. It was a tacky thing back then, but it was a common trope. Today, you know, this would be this would be round denounced. I am not gonna be as hard on Barks for this one as I have been in kind of what I've come to think of as the like the problematic
three, which would be like Voodoo hut volcano Valley and land of the tote poles. Right? Where where the
the casual
disregard for culture is really elemental
to the story. This is kind of a throw away. So it's it's gross by our standards and in hindsight. I always
recognize yes, this was a totally common trope at the time. I'm not trying to be too hard on Barks but at the same time, I don't wanna alienate people who who would see this and don't have that perspective of reading comics from the nineteen fifties.
And I can agree with you Barks. Yeah. Very good take on this. I I totally agree with that that comment and especially the fact that we know it's it's Gladstone in the disguise,
clearly wanting to win donald over with a scheme, and we also know that the the writing here if you'll if you... He's not altering his voice or his text. I mean, he's he's clearly
speaking in Glad stone speak. And so I think giving Barks a little bit of of...
Yes. Yeah. You wouldn't you wouldn't pass today, there'll be another way to handle it today, but but I do believe the gimmick here that he's introducing. Is acceptable. If it's it's not as bad as it could be. Exactly? I'll give him even a little bit more credit by noting that on the next couple of pages, there are gonna be some passing background characters that are actually shown pretty, like, pretty respectful. They're they're just... They are represented people,
not Al sort. Tropes. So a lot better than this one could have been. And and again, it's just this little element of the story that we move on from pretty quick. And so Donald pushes him away and and the last panel is
Gladstone in disguise saying, alright. Just for that insult, I won't tell you where you can find a
which of course exposes his mystical power that he's been selling down a lot. Right. Because on the next page, he's passing this office fortune telling. He basically is gonna chi ten dollars out of Donald for the information.
And he consults his crystal ball, which the Nephews the nephews of clocked immediately. They noticed that it's
nothing but an old light bulb. And glad is
implying that yeah, there's gonna be a unicorn year nearby, but it's gonna cost you a lot. Yeah. So we we see this. This is where you reference the the background character is having really a nice human element touch to it that bark you find in
Other career an oil painter when he would paint the...
The native culture of the Southwest of the United States, and he kind of brings out the the realism in his character here. He's done it in a few comics as we we'll talk about. But I really do like the way he paid, I think some sensitivity here to the culture. Al we open the next page where you know Donald just needs to know where this unicorn is. He says, will you follow it with a trail of rice. What's rice grains of rice on the sidewalk dope. I mean he's speaking like glad to his cousin, just this great panel of him almost looks like he's balancing on one finger, but you know he's leap up in the air saying this one right here and he's pointing right down at the sidewalk, like, get a grip down figure out what I'm telling you. And, of course, he doesn't see any rice. The minute he says that the nephews notice that the fuck glad has disappeared, and he just wonders now if he's been taken for fifth for ten dollars. One of the nephews acknowledges you could be, but tonight we'll know for sure because they had set up that that meeting place. So closes this off I pointed to the nephew saying, you mean I will you kids are going to be locked up safe in a nice hotel, again, keeping them away from any adventure, any danger, then last you hear from the Nephews, they're out also out of sight. And if you turn around
that we too have disappeared just like Glad. Now this is where I start questioning a lot story plot line and we'll we'll get into it in the next few pages here. Yeah. This this is one of those
sequences
where it's impossible not to read it today being like, how how is Donald not, like, canceling all of his plans to to find his nephews
alone in a foreign country.
Part of the appeal of these stories, you know, the nephews are Al Avatar for the reader and we like to see the Nephews being very independent. Well, we know that. I agree. Yeah. And and we can't have Donald panicking too much Donald knows that they can get along. So he's gonna just spend the next
the next few hours waiting for the appointed time. And
know that the Nephews will be on their own and be okay. And mh. He does come to find a grain of a trail of grains of rice at that point of time. And it's it's nighttime time He follows it to a quote, very old temple that seems to have a lot of sort of hindu looking animal stat around it. It's it's Al cool panel. Yeah. It's a nice panel. In fact, I I make note later that I wish it was a more of a splash panel. There are very few splash panels in this story that are.
That are large. But yeah, then he moves into the the temple area where you see. As you said, these these wonderful statues
of Al elephant.
Warriors,
very much part of the himalayan culture or at least that's what Barks is depicting in this old temple. Donald looking around. He sees the trail of rice and right there at that second panel on that page. And then he yells hello in there. Anybody home and he hears this of course the winnie of oliver of Al horse, and then he says, well, that's a horse something's gotta be in here unless
Unicorns winnie, which I thought was interesting. But then he says, I say, is anybody home and then, of course we see Gladstone again dressed up as most stuff hand out. Who do you think I am bud one of the statues, which again is a little bit of foreshadowing.
And you know what? Warren, I think that Glad is supposed to be
a a totally different person at this point. Right? He's he's la used, basically the same get up. But Oh I never... I never thought about that. Talk about that. Yeah. Because because we're supposed to think of his first
we're supposed to think of his first to disguise as a fuck here. So he's, like, made up to look like a beg. Right? But in this I hear the different whisk groups. Yeah. It's got He's got different whispers. He's not dirty up. He... So...
And and I do remember being confused as a kid because I was like, why is Donald not recognizing him and and it registered for me at some point. Oh, he's posing as yet another. I'm glad you pointed that out in the in the reading I have.
They're they're the
the red turbine and the green cape is what I have on both characters. And i know your story is a little different color Yeah. I'm I'm...
I I see the... I have the fan graphics, but I'm referencing that glad one because I like the coloring decisions.
That Glad stone tended to be so very much. And and they have the same color scheme, which I think is is confusing. But I'm I'm pretty confident that they're meant to be different. Well, there's no question though that you point that out. They are definitely different characters and Donald doesn't recognize the former as the latter.
Right. That's this as the guy who's supposed to hand over the unicorn. So a good good good catch on that. Yeah. And so on the next page, you know, we're we're getting... I didn't talk about at the beginning. But this story has the version of Donald that is naive or cr for at least a big part of the story. Because, you know, Gladstone
in his pose here is basically gonna present what we can tell is a horse. He lays out the price as being ten thousand dollars you know, conveniently referencing
exactly what sp is prepared to spend. He warns him away from the quote, solid gold porn, you know, keep your distance. And so Right. Donald,
Donald forks over the money.
We we kinda reference to three more of the stats use in the background that are better are than nephews in silhouette and and hidden pose.
Warren it's interesting to me. I just did i recorded recently
the and middle aired at this point, the podcast for land of the tote pulls. We have kind of the same trope, right, of a character
dis disguise himself as part of
a native cultures
like stat
or their Right? I don't know what the encompassing term is for an an artifact. That's i with the artifacts of the.
As they did atlanta the tote poles and as they're doing here. And again, the nephews are wiser
beyond their years and
and
we accept them as as as the reader dealing with the story here. Yeah. Right. And Donald closes the page out being proud of how quickly he's gotten this unicorn. But... And and why don't you just kinda tell us s synthesized this... Again, hold on, this is where glad stone now is it's phones in this page and and he runs after him and says, hey, Hand me over that ten thousand dollars. Yeah. You pick my pockets.
Of course, Donald getting into the exchange, I didn't pick your pocket and you know it. And now we see the nephews
show up on top of that fake unicorn. Right here, cousin Glad don't the the the exposed Gladstone. And now this next panel, I'm gonna just read it because I think this exposes for me and kind of a big plot hole or at least a big decision Barks made in saying this, and this was we've been expecting one of your tricks ever since we saw you s away an un donald plane. And what I what I found interesting about that is I studied this a little is that the nephews also s away. So we never saw Gladstone and any of the previous panels get on the plane, but they saw him s away. And it made me wonder mark why
they're waiting until all of this transcend all of this all these panels without telling Donald right away Gladstone here.
Yeah. That's true. It's it's a little bit. Of a plot hole. And I mean, when you consider how small that plane was too, the idea of both sets being s with Gladstone not realize and that he'd been he team. But but I'm overthinking it. I'm overthinking that plot hole a little, but because it's fun that they they knew he was Gladstone from day one. But but I mean, warren. What what else is a podcast for, but overthinking. I I welcome
overthinking. So I don't I do not wanna dis you from from highlighting that. The the way I read it, you know, is that the Nephews maybe they wanted to give him the benefit of the doubt maybe they just wanted. Maybe they just wanted to be a little bit dramatic and maybe they figure this gives them a little bit of leverage. Over
uncle donald. Right? Because they're gonna to kinda swoop in and save the day. This makes for a good transition, actually the next.
Right?
Does Yeah Because this does elevate them. And Donald is so grateful to them for exposing glad tones char and getting the money back. He takes a good look. He realizes it's like a Al horse with a with a carrot for a horn, he figures out that he's been sw. And,
you know, he he at least resolves that he can keep this ten dollar horse that he he's clearly purchased from Gladstone
who he weighs on. I like that. Yeah. You don't see that often you yeah. The nephews get to ride and style. Right? Because this was a nice way to set them up as willing participants
in the event sure. Yeah. And I I I I like that. The fact that they probably just waited until they could expose him for who he was and
not let Don get hurt. That certainly didn't was never part of their plan. But then that act that unfolding of that at that point, it wouldn't have been fun to do that any earlier because you wouldn't have all these wonderful pages So... Exactly right. From a writer's
perspective, and they revealed it at just the perfect time. And I love the last of your page there that you just talked about. They're
t off in victory. They are
beat up Gladstone don't pretty good there. Oh my goodness.
And then you've got this great nephew looking back with that
unicorn carrot horn on his forehead. I just love that. No. You're right. Yeah. No. They thanks for calling that panel out because that's the fun one. And, you know, it's it's interesting to me to note sometimes those panels where the nephews are doing different things. Because you don't see a ton of those. You don't
We got the one nephew goof where he's wearing that unicorn where. So yeah. Go for it. Tell us the about. Well, now the adventure. Now they're on their adventure. Now, from their perspective, Glad is history. He has nothing to do with this anymore. He's gonna look his wounds and head back to home. So now they've got a lot of work to do here as they are still convinced there is a real unicorn. So the first panel on this next page is is an iconic panel, I think. It it could have been a splash panel, but there's some words in it that wouldn't have worked. But... But I love the prodding been oil painting.
Man. It looks like it could have been an oil painting. Yes. It could have been one of the oils in one of the the lit graphs absolutely. But you have donald pulling the nephews pushing and this poor old horse who. The former unicorn he has now turned into a pact and is doing whatever he can to to help them succeed in their their their venture. But at twelve thousand feet, they quickly learned that the horse can't make it any longer and and we know that the horse is going off to another owner, and they've got this great
y now, which is more acc acclimated to to that elevation, which is very accurate. But at fifteen thousand feet, even the y gives out and the weather turns and
Donald so nicely says he's quit.
They did do another beautiful panel here of the far shot of them v and silhouette up the mountain top. They're they're nearing twenty thousand feet and they're just going through this horrendous adventure without any safety net it looks like and there should be nothing but unicorns up here Donald, but then one of the nephews wisely says or nothing period, which brings us back to that possible realism that there's nothing here at all. And then they get up there to the rocks and it's,
know, what what could they eat up here what they survive on and again, the knowledge of one of the nephews. All we have to do is look for a lot of Moss rocks and there will be our unicorn. So... Yeah, I mean, they they now know what the unicorn live on or at least they discover that there's moss on the side of the rocks, and that's what they must on. Yeah. And this is a really quick transition up the mountain to me. Right? It's what's
yeah. From basically the bottom of the mountain to to the elevation they're gonna get to. This is the part of the story that, you know, it doesn't work as well for me as it could.
Because it feels a little compressed in some places. Like Barks is really interested in kind of the sc business deal and then the glad on Al flannery. And I think the adventure part of this story gets just a little bit short shifted. It is condensing it here. And if you go back to luck of the north when they were stranded on the iceberg,
at least it would describe the panel as days pass. And you don't see the days past here. You it's moving Al you said very quickly from the foot to twenty thousand feet and unless than about eight panels.
Right. And so when they're at that height,
There's this really... I I really like this sequence where they are crossing like a snow Barks and they kinda collapse through. And they land in one of these, like famous
sort of hidden Al, right? That's obscured from the world this is like the best of Barks. This is why I loved these as a kid. These little hidden pockets of discovery. Where it's very green down there, at least in the coloring that I've got. They see a lot of these moss colored rocks which you know lens credence to what they're speculating. And they're calling out for their for the unicorn. They've nicknamed him uni which is really cute. And we have the meet this neat little mini sequence here where a nephew is calling out Uni, and Donald is caution him not to scare him away. He speculate that unicorns must be a very timid animal. And then we get our first in person glimpse
of the unicorn which is observing Donald as says this. And it just has this look of murderous
rage on its face and it's got a little sn cloud from it snows. And we we know immediately. Like the... It looks tough in that photograph. But this is our first suggestion. This is a dangerous animal. Absolutely. We now know this is an animal that does not like intruders on his land. And that land is they it back to your page.
When they walk through, that's that's sort of lost rise discovery of warm, shane Rey. And here
and that's that's the fan see. I agree with you as a kid when I read that I just love that. Another they're into of this wonderful
fantasy
land of warmth and green but that's also where the fantasy figure of the unicorn lives and and that's just wonderful tasting together of those two. But then the sn sn and that vicious animal
just rushes Donald. That third panel on that that page where it says Scrooge and he does this about face in turn is one of my favorite art panels of the story It's just great action. You've got that grow face. You've got the the profile of the head but you've got this great action with the cliffs and the legs and hitting that rock and almost seeing this immediate u turn as Donald says run for your lives. And and of course he goes toward this rock, and he splits the rock clean
Donald yells and calls that out grabs the tail and then, of course we see one of the nephews just cornered and what's gonna happen the next. Yeah. The nephew is terrified and he looks doomed and he kinda has this like, hopeless
hopeless little faint. The only thing you can think of is to offer the unicorn some lunch and he presents in one of those moss covered rocks Mh. And it it works. The Unicorn Scrooge to Al halt. It calmly eats the moss and
another nephew
tells Donald who is mounted the unicorn because of the way he like slid to a halt. To cover the animals
eyes with a blind fold and and the unicorn just basically
explodes. Yeah. It's it's bucking wild and and eventually, we transition to the ducks having subdued, probably it's tired itself out. And just like that, you know, again, one of my criticisms of this story, which I do really enjoy, but nonetheless, a criticism is that the pacing is so quick here Right we've only got a couple of pages in this little unicorn chain.
And then they're hacking their way down the mountain and Yeah
there's this little ominous sting panel at the end where they're they're saying, man, we got we got really lucky. That pretty easy. They're kinda highlighting how that feels a bit unnatural. Yeah. They they they now are making their decent and and they they call out the fifteen thousand and twelve thousand
feed again where at. But again, this is a a soil animal now. It's blind folded. It's it's tired. The nephew has carried the the moss covered rock with to n on and very happy that they got out. So they quickly make it to the bottom.
Again, I agree it would have been nice to see a little bit more adventure here, but limited to twenty four pages knows is maybe he would have have expanded that a little bit more.
N on the moss,
the unicorn is extremely happy.
And So Huey, looks looks really tired and it Al a little sack over a shoulder and and Don was just wondering,
you know, what make you so blasted tired. I'm carrying
It's it's the heavy rock I'm carrying. It saved my life and by Golly, I'm taking it home for a souvenir. And that is the rock that Huey, is sort of the star of the nephews in the story and and out handed out out to the unicorn, which he gl ate and that how they they were saved. So Huey, is sentimental
and and wants to take that as a souvenir back home. Right now, it's just a souvenir, but something to maybe feed the unicorn on the way down from the mountain, but nevertheless, it saved my life and I'll never forget it. That's some good storytelling.
Here. They get down to the bottom and there's nothing but great grass. They point that out. Doesn't it look wonderful. We're now on land. We can get back to normal. Donald ties, the unicorn blind folded unicorn up to the tree, you know, I don't think this is a good idea Donald when he says going to go ahead and take the blind fold off of uni. And of course
this is where a little bit of heck breaks out here. Yeah. That's right. We I I love the panel on this following page when they when they unveil the blind fold and let him see the green grass that they imagine he's gonna love. That's silhouette panel worn is spectacular. Barks really shows the power. He's conveyed how ferocious and powerful this is. And Uni
immediately
rips the tree that he's been sn to from the ground and runs off in the death can really do nothing other than watch helpless as their meal ticket
gallo off into the distance.
And and we transitioned to Gladstone
again. This is where we get to encounter him. And he's been living off the fat of the land.
For and for Glad, that means letting his left find him rub and diamonds and he's dressed in all this finer know, he's dismay a little at the run of bad luck that he had Donald, but things seemed to be looking up, and he's kind of highlighting the fact that for him, everything happens for a reason. So he's thinking he can still get his hands on that money. As he sits
lounge is on a rock in front of a tree. I love his reference to
letting Dame Fortune dump a bail of Mo into his last.
I looked up mi
and it's just slang for money. And
again, he's classically
back to the old Gladstone.
Luck is the way of life. I'm dressed in the finest clothes, even finer than uncle Sc and
this looks great. But then gear he gander over at
what he sees over on the grass he goes, I believe those are pearl a a pearl necklace lying over there. And of course, the timing of glad stone
looking at those pearls
and you need the unicorn seeing this new stranger with that again, fierce
look on on his face, come charging toward Glad as I love this, Glad says, I guess I have to scoop over and pick it up. Like, that's too much work. So he does and of course the luck of Gladstone
occurs again when Uni sails over him and that great panel. His top hat falls off, but he doesn't kind of isn't unaware what's going on. He just has the pearls and Uni
plow into a tree and it sort of is that Scrooge kind of action and you see this great last panel here where he's okay. He doesn't know what happened to him, but these in the tree and then by Golly, there's the best luck of all, a unicorn screwed into a tree. He... As far as he knew it was always there.
Yeah... That's an awesome sequence. Right? Really good timing. Just the contrast between the oblivious Gladstone and the ferocious looking unicorn And Barks occasionally will put these little flourish on the borders of the page. Right? There's this neat little drawing of a horseshoe and a four leaf clover. Yes. Yes. Kind of a adorned that ref seeing his luck. I haven't seen that since I did the
letter to Santa episode where it kind of f agreed the panels with some, you know, Christmas finer. Yeah. So glad you pointed that out because it does tie the... This is truly tying all these panels together and just can just accent
glad look. So on the next page, you know, this is our transition back to Duck where Gladstone is casually gonna go Scrooge sc that he's got a unicorn. While Donald then the kids are hopeless searching for for the miss uni. When they finally
call up sc to let him know what happened.
Sc tells them don't bother. You know, you you're fired. I've got a unicorn from Gladstone.
So
and and to cap it off, he tells them that they're now responsible
for their own way home. Or he got Donald learns that he's they're responsible for their own way home because Glad has taken the plane back. So they're really at their lowest points. When they finally,
still away on it work their way home on a channel notes.
They at the lowest point of any time in the story or any time that I can remember. That they they have to find their own way home without any help... Yeah. Mh. Yeah. And and and I guess, we're we're setting them up. They're wind windfall soon. But it it's a pretty low point. When they when they cross back into the city limits, they've got classic
bundle, the h bundle bag on a stick, and they're past by Al Gladstone
in one of Barks great
fake fancy cars, he calls it a super v mean
smart card. I'll I always love his references
to to fancy cars. The names are awesome Yeah. The smack guard is a takeoff off on the the popular car of the day the packard. And Oh, that's right. This smack in the packard, and i just... Does that a lot. And he takes that popular cultural reference and turns it into a Duck
Duck language, and I just love it. So it's Al an a,
of a rolls royce and a background. It is. It is. Yes, it is. And of course Glad stones in his finest hour and there we are with the four of them coming back into Duck. Donald starts the next panel with, you know, he gets the gravy and we get nothing and he just can't take it anymore. But They find contentment there at home, Helium impacts is moss covered rock that he saved for the memories and is
From this adventure that they finished.
Donald looks content. He's sitting back it spent a long time now. They took a long time getting home. It's kind of accepted their their fate at this point and he wants to read the paper. So he pulls over open the paper and my goodness there's news about the unicorn. They at this point knew that sc now has the unicorn in his zoo, but he reads in the newspaper that that the unicorn is very sick and the greatest scientists in the world can't do a thing for him. It says here he won't eat. I love the next panel because all eyes go to that foreground
of the moss covered rock and
that's all we have to see as we move to the zoo where the unicorn does not look well, laying on a bed of hay and there's sc w
one million dollars to anybody who could save my unicorn. Immediately Donald shows up. Said, did you say one million? No. I said two million. I mean, he ups the ante a million dollars right there and that great artwork again of of sc close eyed and just absolutely
once the unicorn to be better. And then Donald just says Hue, again, the star of the nephews in the story, do your stuff. Yeah. This is a great pain. Right? The... There's some very spare storytelling. You're right to highlight that. Pamela.
This this is one of those cases where there's this adventure story with a lot of cool oc,
but that panel is very memorable to me all four Ducktales turning.
You can almost feel the the stone beam with pride or something. Oh, yeah. And and then sc despair.
Really awesome Artwork where. This this might be my favorite. Page of the story. And so we closed the story out with Huey, offering the unicorn a n of that moss from that precious and hard one rock and the the unicorn is again revive like, he was when they were coming down the mountain. Any he with light. Sc celebrates that his unicorn saved and while they're being chased by the re... I I like that the unicorn still vicious as as he ever was even though he's just been saved.
Scrooge is asking about the moss and and the friend from their safe perch on the roof roof of I'll be one of the buildings. Yeah. Yeah. They're they're explaining that it's moss giving Scrooge the key to how you can sustain as unicorn. And
you mentioned this last panel being really iconic.
So Why don't you finish it off because because it it is delight Well, we finally see the first and only huge splash panel and it's just rubbing every bit of victory
that Donald and the nephews have into this great great scene of this long
unbelievable limo car with Horns,
a unicorn
a as a a hood ornament. And and not one but two drivers.
Two so.
And a Tv antenna or something in the middle but donald is just basking glory eyes closed arms behind his head, the nephews Al over at Gladstone in his nice smack rolls smack.
And then one of the drive this closes it by saying one's died small fry. It's just classic. They're absolutely
passing him. There's D d on the car, and it's just a classic ending to again don being victorious over Glad stone, you can be lucky, but there's the ultimate luck in being good. I I think that's the one of the morals of this is just the the Huey, story saving the rock, saving the unicorn. Great way to close the story. Yeah.
It's an awesome panel. This... You can tell that Barks had a blast drawing this panel. Right? I think he loved drawing fancy cars.
I I love the contrast with Glad stone fancy car that looks like a toy when you compare it next to the scene incredibly goody and tacky, but obviously,
ferocious
expensive
luxury sharing mon straw be in the car. It's great. This is something that is gonna have to be Al sketched away Al as we always do, you know, there's not gonna be there can't ever be any continuity
when when Donald strikes it rich at the end, because we we need him to start out by the next story back,
you know, to square one. Donald Donald will go back to being donald, but you're right. This is a a great way to just really close out this
story with, like again two chauffeur. I I just talked one, but two. That's a great touch. One chauffeur for to drive and and one show for to be snip, Gladstone
you know what occurs to me warren, it would be interesting to kind of keep some kind of scorecard
for these Donald Gladstone
stories. Because in my memory, Glad,
one of them probably comes out ahead about fifty percent of the time But I don't know. Maybe Donald does speak Al glad look more than I'm think. So like, yeah. I to the south seas,
he ended up on top. In luck of the north, they they both came out well, but ultimately Donald came out with a bitter prize. That's right. In this one, again, we've got them both coming out well, the donald is coming out ahead. So Donald in the adventure length ones at least is so far coming out more
than not. I wanna I'm gonna I'm gonna do that research for you. I... I'm I'm gonna go take a look and see where the scorecard card ends up on that. That sounds like fine. I I'd appreciate.
One comment I wanted to make on this last panel and and for the Barks collector out there. I don't know if you've seen this mark, but there is a... There was a model built of this card which sold that auction last year. Oh my gosh. No. I
was about four and a half feet long,
completely done in detail. It's sold for thousands of dollars. It is in the hands of a collector. And no if you point that out in your in in your addition to the Barks page on on Facebook, that that individual who owns this will probably put the picture up there. It's
my gosh. It's an amazing
piece of
sculpted
a kind artwork that I could not I could not even begin even looking at to add to my collection, but someone has one, and I think there's only one it is
fantastic. I yeah. That sounds great. That sounds hilarious. You you'll if there is an existing picture, you'll have to point it out to me. But but, yeah, maybe they'll maybe that individual will come out of the one work to that's more. Because that that does sound like a great little piece of of a ep. Awesome. So this this is definitely a fun one to revisit.
What's your overall impression warren? Well, again, I'll I'll go back to saying that I think Barks was in a really good mood when he was writing this. I think he wanted to be playful.
He he introduced yet another
mythical character like he's done in so many of his stories. He has the nephews come out on top. I kind of said, here here's what things he introduced and reinforced. He introduced sc
and sc has this country a state that's enormous. You see a subs Donald that classic
donald with a green streak in a you see a classic glad who's lazy, lucky devious greedy, lucky again, and then once and for all out done by Donald. The boys as usual always a step ahead in the story and become the heroes in this case, Huey, we really stood out, which was nice and and the sheer extra of the final panel.
It's just Barks having a good time. As far as the story goes, I agree I think the adventure part was rushed but I think the adventure part was on par with the rest of the story. It wasn't the... It wasn't the primary focus. It was it was not
about going to the himalayas because I did point out earlier in my notes that he's traveling to other parts of the world and, you know, where I would have liked to have seen a few flash panels introducing that plane coming into the Himalayas. He decided to hold back and keep those panels relatively the same size and then give us that car at the end of the splash panel. But it's a good story. I wouldn't call it a great story. But it's a good story. And I I'd I like like the fact that we have all the characters in there
sc in a supporting role, I will sit still say, and Donald coming out on top with the help of his loving nephews. Yeah. I I totally agree. These are excellent points. I think you nailed it. Right? The adventure is kind of deliberately. On afterthought.
In this not none afterthought, but it's not the main points the the antics
around it are the main point. And and we have so many of these invention store. Here's that that is kind of a nice change of pace. You know? I I agree with you
completely. This one is a this a very good story.
It's not one of his, like, great to me. It'll It's it's a very capable
just solid example of a good Barks adventure story.
You know, this did come in has very, like, this very fertile period where people will describe it as his golden age. I don't think it stands up with a lot of those golden age ones, but it just... Because this period is so fertile and so strong. And it does have some really great elements, you know, the the nice
comedic setup the really good callbacks,
this really interesting hook of a of a dangerous
unicorn and that comedic payoff at the end. There are a few things that elevate it past kind of your average Barks.
Yeah. I.
I enjoy this. I don't think it is as good as the community seems to think. I don't know if you looked on on Ducks. I didn't tell me what the community is reading the story Yeah. So this this is very highly rated. Right? This has an eight point one. And and really anything in the eight point o and above... I kinda, i think think it was land to the Tote and polls where I kinda made that
realize that's kind of the dividing line for... I think it was... Know, it was our episode of luck of the North northwest. Oh, yeah. Yeah. That's right.
That's that was an point. That was an eight point o, I think and an eight point one, but I I will put luck up the north and maybe I'm a little biased, but I will put that above this story because in in a sheer unfolding of the adventure and the character development, but yeah. Agree. I agree. And I I think lack of the north really stands out as as one of the, like, almost
all time best and it's really elevated by that. Like sequence of the the psychological
trauma. This one to me is very fun, but it one out of ten is good for twenty four. Out of all of the stories on on in, all forty one thousand. And again, i'm I'm I don't wanna come down too hard on this, this is a very very good solid story, but I don't see anything about it that like, elevate it to that sort of verified air. Yeah. I don't think it's even in the twenty four best
you know, Carl Barks
adventure length. Stories led. Well, I mean, I don't think there there probably aren't any non Barks stories ahead of it at at that i'd like to hear what you what the listeners think too. It be great to get some feedback on this because I I would agree with you. I I I don't put it in the top tier. It's it's clever. It's fun, I said before it's Whim. It's just... It was a fun story. I do... I will say after a read and even today, I'm I'm pleased with highlighting Huey,. One of the nephews. You where we see that. And when you see that payoff off,
know, as a good deed, back then, I think it was showing some good values in Honesty. And I and I think for that reason, I think it's an important story to to take a lesson from. But then, of course, the large car is just another another classic turn. Yeah. Fun story. Thank you. Yeah. It definitely is. And I do I always find, you know, reading these in an interactive way and and getting someone else's take on it. I... And and thinking about these so deeply I always find these things to really appreciate about this, which is so cool. Oh yeah. It's a very good one. It definitely has a little bit of archaic stuff that hasn't held up very well. Just thinking about other references. There are no lit. For this one. Right? Not that I'm aware of. There's plenty of of sequences like could have been could have been made into a really cool though, but, you know, he wasn't a machine.
This one does get referenced
in... So I I think I'd mentioned that there's a Don rose. I've decided to think of the don rosa sequels in kind of two categories. Right? There are the true sequels and there are the rift sequels where he's kinda r on a Barks story, and he maybe refers to it. So one of the first rows stories I ever read was the crocodile collector. Oh, sure. And that one was fun. I think it was based on a cover that Barks did for a story that wasn't his. And there was a there was a a dell comic, the crocodile collector, which was a cover only for Barks. Yeah. I'll be honest with you. I kinda I steered away from the stories written by the other whoever wrote it. I just... I don't even have in my collection. Yeah. I I don't gather that it's memorable for anything, but mh but being Barks the cover. But but I loved Don Roses follow up, and I I like it. It's not one of those stories where Rosa is really following the same story beats. Because he has a few that I
nonetheless really like where, you know, it's a little bit revisiting it too much. Like, we recently did the episode for super snoop. And i super snoop stripes again or whatever was called was not one of my favorite rosa stories still lot to love. Right? But I loved the crocodile collector as one of Roses first sort of Barks follow ups.
So so that's neat that the... you know, we do see uni navy the unicorn again in that one, even if brief way. I'm I'm looking forward to reread that one at some point soon Do we see the Enough again in any comic? That's what I was gonna Well, Rosa really cranks it up to eleven as I recall where when we return to the zoo, there's the good that. I think there's a whole family of them And there's a bunch of other, like, hilarious and and silly creatures. I found a wiki page that referenced other stories. There have been a lot of apparently Ducktales comics
that have been sequels or follow ups to this.
So there's a story by fran,
Cor
and Santiago Barr
returned to Shane law. That's a direct Sequel from two thousand eight.
Trial of the unicorn. I'm intrigued by this one, which has a lot of callbacks
to this story and it's a straight up seat And then this one mentions that billion dollars Safari is a later sc one, a later Barks story that it's not a sequel, but it kind of is another of these like Donald and Gladstone looking for a fantastic
creature. That that's a fun one. I won't get to that for a bit, but I like that one for later Barks. I how this story can act as motivation for other storyteller to build on especially Don rosa when he did. It it it really acts Al a great seed for more imaginative.
Storytelling. And and I think if anything this this story can be credited for that Yeah. And and I
recall that I read the crocodile collector first. So that this one kind of closed that circle for me when I read it a few months later. So so that is... Do do you have any additional thoughts before we wrap it up. No. I'll just go back to one comment I made earlier and that was that little p other day
But you made a really good point about exposing the story and and any motivation behind Barks decision to to wait until letting donald know. But the more I read about it, and where I think about it, rather, i I like I like how the story unfolded and how they wanted to appear as
the deliver of good news and of course, they did it on top of the fake unicorn horse. It was just a beautiful storytelling in that area though No, it's good story fun, fun to read I enjoyed it. Awesome. I think my only final thoughts is that, you know, I I don't really get to because this is an auditory medium
I would love... If I were making a Youtube video of this, I would really highlight some of those visual background gag in this one because they're there a lot of fun. That might be one of the reasons that this lands well for a lot of people. But but like you said, if anyone would like to reach out and and kinda take the position that, yeah. This is a top twenty five Barks and Disney comic story. By all means, I'd love to hear from you. You can reach out to us. At Barks remarks at g dot com or we're on the Barks remarks Facebook page. As always, I'm I'm very grateful
for the listeners,
you know, we're slowly, but steadily building an audience. And I I love interacting and engaging with the Barks and duct fans and, you know, getting to getting to know you through this process and and the other people that I'm getting to meet has been a real joy one so I'm really grateful for getting to do this.
Thank you, Barks. And again, i the community
that you've rejuvenate with these your podcast and the the chronology, of these stories and and having us be able to all of us that helping you. Well what what a what a treasure
a new a new archive of research and great listening. I appreciate that. It's it's a lot of fun. So I look forward to
introducing a new guest host next week in the the really classic and
creepy story in ancient Persia.
And I look forward to having having you back on again in the near future one. Looking forward to it, Thank you very much Mark.