Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of sc Mc and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge cl of all time join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context, and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks. Hello, and welcome back to Barks remarks. I'm Mark Sever marino, a grown man who enjoys donald dot comics. And who also enjoys con his friends into coming on and talking about them, and I'm very excited about a a first time guest host today who I've known for quite a while. Can you please introduce yourself and tell us
your background in in comics and nerd dumb. Hi. My name is Michelle Mend Vas.
As far as my background and comics, I grew up going to the little comic store down the street from my high school. I was more into
image
and dark horse comics, not so much the mainstream
stuff. I think I probably thought I was a little too edgy.
You know, at the time. And just the stuff that, you know, not everybody was into.
Right. And just with... Every day, every Wednesday would be there with my friends checking out whatever was new and excited to see a lot of my choices were based off of the artwork.
But yeah, It was exciting to discover new artists and then kinda grew up discovering new stuff. That's all. I'm also a part of a local nerdy group. Called very awesome girls where we do
charity work, support local groups that need help by creating nerdy arts and crafts that we sell to raise money. Yeah. That's great. I I love stopping by your booth at the comic con. I usually be on my way to see Don Rosa, another of the legendary Ducktales artists and and you'd be at at a booth sometimes
right nearby him, actually.
And I'll I'll let people do the math on on the acronym that your your group has. But yes.
Yes. So we always would appreciate it when you would stop by. We love the support. Absolutely.
So Again, thank you for joining me. I considered very carefully which episode to ask you on. And and I landed at this one, which is in ancient Persia.
And the the reason that I wanted you to join me for this one is because I know you're a horror a auto. Definitely.
This one is probably the the closest thing that Barks has ever done to, like
pure horror
story apart from, I guess, Voodoo Hut do is is another pretty horrific one, but this one really stands out as one of his creep
and eerie
stories. I mean, I definitely appreciated towards the beginning of the comics, some of the Haunted house vibes.
That they were giving out, and I was like, oh, yeah. The drawings. So I was like, this definitely does have that creepy haunted house vibe to it. Right. It's certainly... It's it's still a donald dot com. You know. It's it's aiming to be family friendly. Although this one, you know, for an early fifties story, it does push the line a little bit here and there. But Mh. Yeah. This one is is pretty well regarded among the the duck. Fan community, Michelle. This is a very. This is a pretty legendary
story as well. You know, I I remember I read this one as
I'm gonna say I was eight or nine. And if you're eating this as a young kid, it it it does stand out as Al pretty creepy.
Well knowing all that. I feel extra honor that you selected me for this episode, and I appreciate that. Yeah. No problem. It's nice. It's nice when people can kinda start off with with one of the more
renowned of the stories. And this one is yeah. Is widely remembered, although I'm sure it's not everyone's company. So let's see this a little bit of background and and the date is gonna be pretty important on this one. This one had Al cover date of March nineteen
fifty.
Okay. This is published in the old one shot series four color, number two hundred and seventy five. So Michelle, four color would kinda publish a different character. Month to month. Until at some point, the Donald Doc uncle sc comics got big enough that they spun off into their own line. Oh, interesting. And I like to mention how many times these stories have been reprinted in the Us because that kinda gives an idea of, you know, how popular they are. And this one this one does have a good number. This one's got about eleven including the original printing. Wow, that's impressive. Yeah. It's more than the average story. It's a little bit shorter for his adventure length ones. It's
twenty four pages long. And I like to mention background trivia. The only thing that I think is is notable is that Barks very occasionally
and around this time in his career would would throw in some real human characters.
Right? Okay. Because these characters,
we we're supposed to think of Donald and the other characters as human, but sometimes the characters like the the scientists in this one would actually be drawn as human instead of the kind of default, like dog knows that he'll illusion. That was one of the things that I was thinking about when I was first it that I it was like, It was interesting that it was a human
formed, but then none of the other characters throughout it were. Yeah. And it makes him stand out a lot.
So, Michelle, something I like to do because this is such an international. You know, there are Barks fans around the world. I like to kinda high like some titles from around the world and and invite my guest hosts
to try to wrap their mouths around some of them. So right. So I've picked out. I I sent you Brazil and Mexico. But let me let me start out. I'm gonna take on France.
We've got
Des sa, which is kingdom of the sands.
Oh, very dramatic. Yeah. That's a very thing. Right. And in France, there are a lot of different titles. So I just kinda picked the one that sounded coolest.
And why don't you go ahead? Okay. So for Brazil, we have
professor. The professor secret.
Focusing on him. Germany, this is a mouthful.
For New guy.
It I don't ask them Alto and pe.
So... Wow... Yeah. That's a mouthful, and it's something like
Like, I was P was at the end. That was all I got. And
it was something... I... I cut off my translation here. I was something like a curiosity warning
Donald in Persia or an ancient. Oh.
You wanna do Mexico?
Sure.
Of
and Persia.
Yeah. So pretty much sure how they would say it.
Yeah.
So. And then let's see. I'll wrap it up with Italian. It's
pepsi.
And this one is Donald dot Wife. Yeah. And the Persian bride. Bride, Nice.
Yeah. I see now where that comes on later on in the story. Yeah. It's really not the focus of the story. I'm kind. Yeah. It seems like a random title.
So we're gonna go into the the story contents
self, but I do like to talk about, like, if there's anything interesting from a historical or a geographic or a cultural perspective in this it and there really is to me because, you know, this one I think can be seen as one of those early fifties, late forties
pop culture
sort of
exploration of the atomic age. Right, the the paranoia of living under the shadow of the recently
detonated
atomic bomb because this was what only like a half a decade after the the bombs were dropped the near the end of World War two. Now, can can you imagine, like, living in the shadow of that and how all of a sudden, so much of media is just is really gonna be consumed with that pervasive dread. Oh, yeah. I can totally imagine, especially because I believe around that time, weren't they still practicing drills for that and the Scrooge,
which means that for a child to seeing a comic that would talk about it, I could see how they would relate to the two and maybe add to the excitement or thrill of reading that. Yeah. Absolutely. This is probably when those ridiculous drills were were kicking into gear. This was around the time that Godzilla
became a fact or in Japan, you know? So this is a very, like, realistic
fear that's that's per
every And and then also, you know, there's a lot of, like, really big archaeological work going on in in the years just before. He did this. So, like in the thirties and forties. There were some major excavation. And one thing Michelle that's notable about Carl Barks is that he liked to refer to his national
geographic
magazines
Al as inspiration. So, you know, in the case of this one, he he actually gave some interviews where he talked about when he depicts the rock of Gibraltar as they fly over it that was directly out of national geographic magazine
that
he would... Oh some of the like, temples and the underground scenes were also, like, references to pictures and articles that he saw. When I was reading it, I was taking oh, Donald Duck is like Laura Croft or Indiana Jones now. Yeah. Those were kind of the vibes that I was thinking about referencing the things that my children and I are into nowadays.
Right. And I think Barks was very conscious probably referencing, like, the mummy movies, you know, the the old Karl off version
because I I read in one of the are columns about this where Barks was a fan of some of the horror classics And I guess, there's an old movie called the old dark house with Karl off that might have provided the model for that that actual house.
Have to look that up. My side note, my dog, is actually named Boris Carly because he is a much, so he's made up of different dogs.
Just like Frankenstein.
Yeah, What a great reference there. That's that's rad. And and I saw speculation that the professor, the scientist is is actually modeled after the the real looking version of Karl off himself. You know that's funny because I was just looking him up. I guess a week ago, and I could kinda... I guess, maybe with the eyebrows. Those dramatic eyebrows that they would used in the movies at the time where they curled up at the ends.
Yeah. He definitely stands out to me, you know, his his very sinister appearance.
So, yeah, The Mad scientist is our big notable appearance in this one. I'll mention Michelle that I sometimes like to kind of talk about what version of the characters we've got in a story because he'll kind play around with them as he needs. you know, there's not like a a cohesive continuity.
And I think Donald is a little bit more like protective and determined than he is in a lot of these stories. And he came off to me. It's very responsible.
Yeah. Which is interesting because I feel like in past stories that I remember of Donald
growing up where he was kind of the maybe the Naughty one Yeah Because they have the children filling that role in this comic.
He had to step up and be the sensible one. Yeah. That's a that's a really good point. Right? Because he... He's always the guardian for his nephews, but he's not always like, really portrayed as being in the guardian Wall. I very much. Alright. So
I wanna get into the actual, like, action of the story here. Michelle I'm gonna be summarizing this kind of page by page. I won't cover every story beat. But as we go through these pages, please feel free to let me know what what's stands out is notable to you if you have any questions.
So
in Ancient Persia
opens up. And I think it's a really striking
opening,
Michelle. We've got the Nephews are kind of trembling in their yard. While Donald is relaxing in a hammock. You know, he's wondering what their shu about because they're all casting their eyes over Al something. And they explained that they just saw a man that they're very familiar with walking down the street. And he always gives them the creeps. He's he's known to the kids in the whole neighborhood,
Al
someone who's very spooky.
And,
you know, that that the kids in the neighborhood have theorized that he's a mad scientist.
It's one of those situations where they're like, you know, we we can't explain it. You just have to see it. So they can install to weight and hiding so that they can see him as he walks past. And he really does look genuinely creepy. I found the panel of him very striking Michelle.
Oh, for sure. And honestly, I don't know what I was expecting, but that was not what it was. And I just kind of remember that old trail growing up watching movies of that one creepy neighbor, You know, that everybody was always paranoid about. Yeah. I'm I'm glad you mentioned that old trope because how does that trope usually work out, Michelle? Well, I was expecting it it to be like a sweet.
Old guy was misunderstood.
Because it... Like you said that is generally
what happens in these types of situations.
Yeah. You're bang on. Like, that's that was my reaction to this too. This is such Al like that that trope itself is like the sub subversion, but it's such a common sub subversion that we're almost, like sub the subversion here because I too expected him as a kid
usually this the moral of a story that has someone who looks creepy is
that they touch a book by the cover. Yes.
Exactly right. And and it's it's all... It's... To me it's really remarkable. How this story is like, no. No. No. You should judge that book.
And then after I got into the story a little bit more, I did take a moment and pause and remind myself what year this story was being written and how some of the socially
conscious ideas of today weren't as hyped up in that era as they are now. You're right, but I think this was definitely already a pretty well established trope by this time. Right? Like, to kill a mocking bird
very famously Have that whole message about blue Rad. Like, this is this is definitely a cliche at this point. And I think it's definitely remarkable that their instincts are are right on. Yes. And we do get a little hints. Right? Because he's got this package that says chemicals do not.
So like that's is why they think he's a mad scientist.
Right. But but I know that I went into this story expecting it to be that old, like, misunderstood
trope. So
on the next page, Donald is
he agrees with them that they look that the man looks creepy. And the kids really want to go investigate him, but you know, Donald not gonna stand for that. He's he's of the very the the cliche
mindset. you know, curiosity killed the cat. So he forbid them. Yes. I noticed they use that phrase several times throughout the comic.
Right. And and the Nephews in that very nineteen fifties way they're they're gonna be a little bit not either gonna they decide he just needs
investigations. So they decide to sneak on out, and they approach his hangout
which is a really lovingly
drawn picture of... You you'd have to call it like a haunted looking house. Right? I thought that that was one of my favorite panels actually was the creepy looking house and I believe if I remember correctly that had, like, the tree that was barren of leaves, and I just thought that they did a good job of getting that spoof factor across by just one picture. Yeah. So right away on these these first couple of pages. You know, I I feel like we've had this great tone of dread set up that it's for sure. Pretty
very fore.
So the nephews
approach, the window. So the... What what seems to be the only lit window so that they can ea drop on him. And
They start snoop. And I really thought it was funny too that they went out of their way to point out that that was the only clean window in the house, so that must be where his secret lab is at. Yeah. You're right. That's a cool detail. Would been like, that's the only clean one. So that must not be it. You know, they they look in and they they see the scientists and this is a really
detailed setup that Barks is showing us. I feel like he's showing us what the scientist is made of really do you wanna mention some of the things that you see kind of on is on his work venture? Just anything that strikes you? Well, just in general, I found the ingredients that he was using very interesting.
I also thought it was interesting that he was reading from, like, a tablet with hi,
but I wasn't as it's not egyptian.
I suppose with the whole persian theme, it could be that. Definitely seeing all of the ingredients and everything laid out almost like he was getting ready to bake. Yeah. So, yeah. You mentioned the, like, the, like,
uniform looking tablets and and he references some of the ingredients like Mer Child and oil of a syrian artichoke
and and sap of Dead sea Ducktales.
It's all references to kind of ancient Middle East stuff. There's a revolver
hanging on a nail in the background in his workshop very ominous. I don't know if you know
now that you mentioned it, I do see that and I totally missed that the first time that I read it. Yeah. I think I missed it too as a kid because I remember reading at one day and being like whoa, There it is. Because at this point, I was like, oh, he's probably just gonna be a misunderstood
guy. Probably had I noticed that Right. And I like how... Up through about the first half of the story, Barks is gonna vas. And he's gonna give you just enough. I mean, he's gonna show his intentions pretty quick, but everyone in a while. You feel like like, he sounding kinda reasonable. Maybe he's not all bad. Until we take that veer.
And so, you know, the Nephews observe this and and they're they're convinced. He's clearly a mad scientist mixing some terrible chemical to blow up the world. He... At the end, he adds this this very meaningful ingredient dust of a dehydrated
beetle that five thousand years old. We're we're not meant to think too hard about how he got that. Right. And then carry that at Walmart.
Right. And then he adds a fraction of a thunderbolt and he cries out in victory, you know, surprising the Nephews who fall over. That would have been when I would have passed out too probably.
Yeah.
So on to the next page, you know, they've missed whatever he's celebrating. And so they go to climb back up. And as they time back up, the scientist opens his window and he spots them and I just... Every time I read this, Michelle, I read this with my eight or nine year old. Eyes, and and this really freaked me out. Right?? Oh, for sure. Yeah. I mean, we grow up, you know, with the whole stranger danger
and all of that stuff and they were warned, and I'm sure they're realizing at this point should've listened to un donald.
Yeah.
Exactly. And And you know it's interesting too the place that we are and in the pop culture or in culture in nineteen fifty is that stranger Danger wasn't a thing yet.
I It was probably being friendly to everybody.
Right. It was. I mean, I think there was still that element of of trust your instincts if someone seems sinister but like, we didn't have the Milk carton kids quite yet. So anyway, he he references what Donald said, you know, curiosity is what killed the cat. He accuses them of being spies and he he grabs them in a way that makes it clear that he is very sinister.
And so we transition to Donald, who is missing them at supper time. You know, this is that very, like fifties thing, I think where you don't worry about the kids until it's time to come in for dinner. Some of us grew up this way even into the eighties. Oh, for sure. We were always out
running around out side until it was time to eat
refuel. So, you know, he has an idea where they've gone. He follows their tracks. He's very like we mentioned he's very confident in this one capable. And he's at the edge of that creepy old house when we see the silhouette of the man come out and and really put some fear into donald. Hat.
The whole fact that they did choose to silhouette him, again just add to that horror and creepy
sinister
fat. Yeah. It it does. Right? Because he's shrouded in the shadows at the twilight and and Barks makes great use of so lot. I think some people have accused him of being lazy with it sometimes, but but here and there, it looks awesome. And his his his remark here is pretty haunting and He says, good evening young man, curious about something. Oh, yeah. And then he takes off the cape and he's wearing fred outfit from scooby doo.
For the apron. Not the cake. We've got the ascot and everything. You're totally right. I didn't I didn't even realize that, but that is that is totally fred from... you know, what scooby do is gonna become a thing like ten years from now. So I guess long has really open his style. Yeah. Hate he liked that ask guy. It was, like gotta get me some of that action. Yeah. And and on this next page, I love the first panel here
of Donald, you know, he's standing up very bravely, but he's also sweating in fear. This is like that true courage thing where people talk about being brave is not the lack of fear. It's standing up to your fear. Because he's looking for his Nephews, and, you know, the the scientist kind of beck him around to the back. And Donald hasn't noticed that he's brandi a Al blackjack, you know, those little c. And he takes him around and he shows him that he's got kind of this secret runway and an airplane in the back that no one knows about. And he's he's revealing this in a very ominous way. He's telling him you know, it doesn't matter if you know about it because he's he's in the process of hon time Donald. Yeah. I absolutely loved this. That he just has this
huge airplane in the back in the neighborhood, nobody knows about it. Yeah. I know. Sometimes there there are some things story convenience. We just got gonna buy it. Just roll with it. Right. And the way this is presented, I'm all for it. So we we transitioned to the next morning. We're all four Ducktales are kinda waking up at the same time and they're in the cargo hold of the plane, and they they figure out that they're flying and when they orient them selves. One of the Nephews notices that he's... So the the nephew mentions that they're flying over the rock of Gibraltar. And... Oh, yes. I remember them mitch several
landmarks
epic
places,
Right. And and so this is, you know, a really good way to symbolize us really quickly how far they've gone and how long they've been out And it's a very lovingly drawn image from the air of the Rock and Gibraltar I I found that it it really ent me as a kid seeing that image. I thought it was a little creepy at this part. Now with them realizing
that they had drank something
that had caused them to pass out. Yeah.
Yeah. Because you're right on the next page, the Nephews reference, the last thing they remember was the scientist giving them a drink of some funny tasting water.
Which is he's very deeply.
Yeah. That's deeply of upsetting. You know? You you're obviously not no good and you're knocking out.
They they figure out it it put and put them to sleep and Don the comments that he put him to sleep with a black. And they're just puzzling over what's going on and
they they hear from the scientists from the intercom, he tells them to stop being curious because you'll know all the answers
before many hours. And I just wanna read his his speech balloon what he tells them this kind of his mission statement for the rest of the story. Right? He says, and I will know the answer to the weirdest riddle in the ancient world. I will be the first man to turn the after into last week. Oh. I was like, where where is he going with this? What does this mean?
Yeah. Yeah. I found it, like, genuinely chilling and and intriguing. As a kid. And and the nephew has a funny comment. These. I wish he'd turned today into yesterday. I sure miss my.
And so they they transition their over some really cool ancient ruins. He points them out Al as ancient sites like Babylon and ke and So. And he says the scientist tells them that Huey, seeking a city called It's,
which lies beneath an empty
patch of, like, Be sand. I'm glad you said that because I was wondering how to pronounce that. Right. So I mean, the obvious thing is this is one of those goofy place names that Barks loves to make. Right? It's supposed to sound like it's a fake or it's a fake.
Right.
And I have forgotten to mention that one of the, like one of the aspects of this story that's cool, but also off putting is that it kind of vac
between this like very creepy and then very goofy vibe. Oh, yeah. You know, it goes back and forth. And so it's this like this tongue in cheek, You know, here's here's the thing I'm about to completely make up. We talk about these real cities and then we talk about the fake one. And so when when they land, you know, he directs them to unload the equipment. They're they're his help. Right? And they're his his muscle for this. I mean, if you're gonna kidnapped someone, why not use them for manual labor? Yeah. Absolutely.
Can you see that top right panel well enough? I love that panel that's from the viewpoint of his gun h. Let's see. And don't get any ideas that I'm not spots around here. Yeah. Yeah. And then it had that... Yes. Like you said, that good close up of the gunshot. And I think that or the gun And for me, that was the first time I noticed the gun. Yeah. That's pretty noticeable. Right or notable because, like, it's kind of verb button to depict gun play in kids media these days. But the the cool thing about some of these stories is they do have this real element and danger. So oh, yeah. That was definitely the point where I was like, okay. This is this guy's is not messing around. He is the boss in this moment.
Right. And so he he cites some... He consult his ancient map and fights the sun, and he tells the dots where they need to dig, and Donald kind of like, he's he's very skeptical. They're not gonna find anything. He's like, boggling over how he was home yes, he was home among sensible people, and now he's digging sand and Persia for a crack that sees cities under every dune.
But sure enough, he hit something.
And after a period of time, day on Earth, what what is a roof corn
that's the like, the main entrance to what we're gonna see is it's Fake. And this is the part that I definitely started thinking of, like, the Mommy movies with Brendan Fraser and stuff like that to the...
Which my family is obsessed with watching about once a month. Yeah. It's definitely those adventures.
Definitely part of why I thought this story would be a good match for you. It's is just a good, like, buck
adventure story that also kind of veer into into horror. Really cool. I I love the art,
the the drawings of the entrance into the tomb are into the city. Yeah. It's pretty detailed even like we were talking about before with the use of the shadowing and stuff that even that adds the details and to giving it that creepy
appearance.
Right. And Donald, and and the scientists are having... you know, what seems very kind of normal
conversation. They've kind of reached this like, at least an existence, a coexistence for now, right? Where they're just kind of almost talking like colleagues. And he's explaining about the how the city disappeared, and and he's kinda hinting that he's looking for one of the the secrets
that's referenced.
Donald mentions, you know, there's a lot of writing on the wall here. Maybe you can find what you wanna know. I did like that suffer and hot
line. Yeah. That was fun. And they think of sylvester the cat. He he tells them he has a better way to figure out what he needs. Know. He's gonna ask the people that lived here. Their still a alive. Okay. So this part, I definitely was like, is this zombies? Are these
immortal?
Where are we going with this? Right. We're setting up a pretty a pretty cool and intriguing
mystery here. And, you know, he kinda on the next page, he sets the Ducktales lighting torches around the gloomy place.
And Donald has this pondering moment that I really like where he's thinking, you know, he he's he's thinking what I was thinking the first time I read this, that every time he gets to thinking the scientist is pretty sensible, he pops off with some nutty statement that would put him in the loo bin. And Donald keeps, like, pondering imagine thinking that the people Barks still alive. And then he kind of realizes, you know, what what if they are and he he talks himself into
into being very fearful and he... He has to clean close to the nephews at this point. I honestly loved that and thought that was prayer. He's like, listen. I'm hanging out with you guys for you guys to make sure that you guys are safe. It's definitely not that I'm scared. Yeah. It's it's very funny, and it because a contrast with that nephew, who is not fearful at all. Oh, he totally has like a nonchalant just looking around and look on his face. Right. And so we we transitioned briefly to the scientists
self, who has found the royal bathtub, which is what he needs for his great experiment. We're not meant to think too too much about the facts that it's still got water and it's totally intact. Right?
Donald
kinda sn tells him the torches are all lit boss. And again, they're kinda getting along pretty well here. Yeah. I kinda thought that maybe he was pla him to help keep him and his nephews safe. Give them what he wants until they have a good opportunity. Yeah. I think that's a good reading. On the next page, the scientist leads Donald down into the cat combs. It's so it just gets creeping and creep, and he encounters this, like, on full of dust and he says, this is all that's left of a group of people and it will do for a starter. And he starts to explain you know, what he's actually looking for. He says that there's a very old history he's found that talks about how the people of its fake. Were always
dehydrated.
While living. And so he explains that this earned contains the contents of the royal family that chose to go to the dryers rather than face a public
disgrace. And and Donald clarifies. Right? He asked, so they were dried, like prune.
But he says more. They were completely dried into
dust.
So I loved that this was like a whole new concept for me. Like, something I was not expecting this
at all, and that was one of the things that intrigued me while reading this was just that it was a whole new concept to wrap my mind around. Yeah. That's a good point. Because this is not some... This is not a... This is not a Trope. No. Not at all. Right. Re people is usually more of frankenstein
thing or a zombie thing or or what have you. But, yeah.
Donald has this really
striking thought balloon, imagining himself as a pile of dust
with a little word balloon quack quack. And and it's again, it's that sort of, like, j position of something very horrific and very silly. And so the the scientists pours the dust into the tub of solution that he's created.
And he's getting ready. He has the nephews go to get some of the stuff that he needs. And, you know, I wanna stop and kinda ba in this page because this was the point where I was so creeped out reading this as a very small child. Because this is such a disturbing idea. Right? And Barks really had to go out of his way to depict death in these stories. But, you know, this is act absolutely like a form of death. Right? Because if you're dehydrated
into dust... Well, what what did you think when you came to this
I was... I... Like I said it was fascinated and intrigued with the whole concept of being able to completely d someone and then, like, my morbid mind started thinking, I think that would hurt. Yeah. Very bad. So whatever this
disgrace that they were trying to avoid must have been awful
that they would choose to be dehydrated over
being shane
Yeah. That my mind went there too because you're like, wow, who would who would choose?
To do something like that?
And then it also made me think of the mum
in agent egypt
and just the whole concept of taking people apart, which obviously it was no... Not on this level. This is extreme, but it may me like, with the urn and they would store everybody too at that point. Yeah. For sure. It's impossible not to think of our our pop culture experiences and connect him to. Yeah.
Whether they're accurate or not. Right. And and for me, this is like one of the first depictions of this kind of thing I ever read. I was just so into these comics as kids. So did you have something else? Well, I just... I was looking at it and remember thinking, how are they going to
re
someone from dust in water. Yeah. And I you know, you can kind of like, be like, this doesn't... This doesn't add up. Right? It's a group of people all make together. How could they possibly...
So I I kinda again, I kinda like that he just hand waves it and he believes in this concept enough to just... Well, I loved that idea too, the fact that it wasn't just the king or whoever, it was multiple people
altogether.
Yeah. So you know, the the scientist is gonna proceed on the next page. We're transitioning to him
repeating that experiment that we saw
him doing when they were ea dropping on a larger scale. Right? He adds the same stuff and he zap it with one small part of a thunderbolt
And Donald is kinda chuckle because he said nothing happened initially. But then they start to smell perfume,
and Donald notices that all of a sudden, he can read the funny the quote, funny riding on the walls. And, you know, the scientist explains that they've actually inhaled some of their thought processes.
Which is an neat way of kind of hand waving away how they're gonna be able to talk to each other. Yes. I did like that he covered those Barks make it more believable.
And now that I know what you said about him being modeled after Boris Karl, I wonder if that little lightning bolt is also a nod Barks to that. Yeah. I I definitely think it is. Right? Because that's the the climax of how the monster is activated and and Frankenstein
And so we do see the experiment start to work. You know, shapes start to form in the tub, he notes that they're gonna be able to understand them.
He tells the ducks to stand back and give them room. And Donald like, you don't have to tell me twice.
Okay. So I guess, full disclosure. This is this is the part of the story that doesn't work as well for me, Michelle. I do I love this story. I do regard this as many Barks. Fans do as a classic, but this introduction now of the ancient
persians in this the ancients it's a fake. It does leave me a little bit cold. They're very goofy and they have this very, like nineteen fifty sen
that he was obviously going for. Do you do you wanna kinda describe them for us? Well, so when I was looking at it, it reminded me of the style in which goofy,
his species
more of that dog like when to human characteristics.
I found the outfits
very interesting.
At one point they mentioned his title
imperial
pot or something like that? Potent ten is like an old fashioned word for like
just a notable person.
Okay. So I wasn't familiar with that word. So I did look it up afterwards and notice that it was in Google, it was brought up a lot having to do with the shrine.
And notice that the hat that he's wearing
or crown whatever you wanna refer to it is similar to what the shrine where have that similar same title. Oh, you're right. That's a great... That's a great catch. I didn't I wouldn't have known that without. Was mainly just because I've never heard that before. So I had to Google it and look it up. And I learned that word from these stories. He uses it in in a few of them. You're right. And so totally looks like he totally looks like
what the shrine believe themselves to be kind of modeling.
And then his outfit, it's kind of has...
It has bright colors, which I don't know if we wouldn't necessarily have expected. It kinda has like, a a to
vibe to it But then the female
is wearing almost like a flap style
dress With the tassels hanging off on the sides. And and around the chest area.
That's true. It does have kind of that live. So just to highlight it directly. Right? We've got what what is what we're clearly meant to understand as the ruler of Neville of of its fake, and he's got another goofy name. Right? King never was just like it's a fake. He's a king never was
and and it's his daughter. And she is... you know, he's very regal and i'm imp looking. And he's going on to to kinda complain about how he's been brought back against his will And and she's depicted very, like, very un unknowingly. Right? Correct. Yeah. I mean, she's
husky woman and kind of has a silly, like it's a goofy
look at her. Right. And we're we're very soon. We're meant to understand that, you know, she's she's dump and basically
in the fifties
someone that would have been considered like un unbearable.
Not not meant for for married life. But she is she is a princess.
Of
it's fake. When she's in the water,
she looks like she's only
slightly shorter than her fault.
Full size lady. But then once she walks out, it almost looks like she's all torso and feet. Like, there's no legs.
Yeah. So Just not the anatomy
that they went with for her was kind of funny. Right. He... He's drawn her as like a car of of a dump woman. Basically.
Yeah.
And and again, it's not it's not one to me it's not one of the better parts of this. Otherwise, very memorable story. So the scientist introduces himself as the someone who revived them. And the man, you know, he's not pleased about it. And the Ducktales are commenting on this and they they listen
has we get right into the explanation of why they went to the drivers. Right? She was
to be married to
a prince named Cad Al Cad, who jolt her at the altar and they they don't wanna be revived unless they can write that wrong. And the scientist is is not showing some very good social perception here because he's like, I don't care about your family troubles I've revived you because I wanna know I wanna understand this
drying process and how people were turned into dust. Right? That's that's on the next page here. It's like it's all about me and what I have to say is more important. I don't care about your family issues.
Right. And and I feel like there's the sub that the scientist wants to
be sinister with this, but there's... I think there's maybe also some plausible den of just he wants to understand it. Is is where I am at this point at at least Mh. In my back in my childhood
And so while while the king and the scientists
are at logger
kinda arguing,
the princess notices
Donald, and she points to him and the king identifies him as Prince Cad Al C. Whoa?
Yeah. And he snatch him up and he says, okay. The wedding is back on your Cat Al cad, we're having the wedding right now. When the Nephew come to his defense, you know, his Barks have conveniently
re propagated and they've emerged from the solution just in time to give him some muscle. I I really loved that part too, honestly.
Yeah. It's it's very funny. Right? Like, I I don't think it's awesome that the that this kind of dev evolves into it like a domestic sq. Although there's a perspective where it's like, maybe it's a cool contrast, right? Between the scientists
grand plans, and this little human drama going on at the same time. Yeah. I mean, honestly, donald... He she he should probably be considering her. She's a princess.
I mean, she's obviously very fashionable.
She's got this great outfit. I mean, it might be a good gig for him. Is sure. It might be. He's not gonna take it know. I like the scientist reading an up and atom book in the background there. He's because he's very single minded at this point. He doesn't care about Donald. Troubles. So, you know, on the next page, the king directs him to to get the prince ready
the scientists asked the king more about the process and the King just kicks in in the butt. And, you know, the nephews kinda of sum it all up. Right? They they have a panel where they say, the best that they can make of things is that Al Cat looked like on Donald, and he must have had himself turned into dust rather than Mary, they say that dumb princess. Again, it's it's definitely...
Come on, boys is not very nice.
Right. So they they figure out that their best bet is going to be
to
identify
the
urn that has Cat Al Cat and see if they can bring him back. And I did love this idea, good bait switch.
Yeah. I agree. This is this is a neat plot progression.
You know, it was amazing the way the story took so many turns that I was not expecting. I mean, even initially from the beginning, this title,
but yet, they're in this rural neighborhood, and I'm thinking, what does this have to do with per.
Yeah. I agree. It's hard to see where this one is going. And and this is something that as in one or two other of his, like, very memorable stories. I'm thinking of in California
where he wants to tell a story that basically takes place
back in time,
but
without actually, like, doing any kind of time travel, You know. So keeping it more realistic, maybe?
Right. But he's still he's still telling this sort of ancient that story. Alright. Can... So does he do it with flashbacks?
So in the other story that I'm referenced saying the ducks kind of have this, like, mass
hallucinations where they basically dream themselves to be in... Oh, interesting.
Yeah. Yeah. Alright. So you know, they're getting ready. They're getting donald ready for the wedding. There's this clever aside about how these clothes look like they're five thousand years old.
Mcdonald's protesting that he's the wrong guy. And meanwhile, the nephews
have found the dust
for Cat Al Cad because they can read that ancient writing. And we got these two things happening at once. Right? The Nephews are racing to recon
Cat Al Cad, and Donald is, like being forced at spear points to go through with this marriage. Oh, I just love that the princess has totally forgiven him. I know for ronda. She's like, let's do this. Come on. Vegas baby. Let's go.
That's right. So they
conclude the ceremony
by saying anybody besides the groom objects to the wedding and the nephews up pipe in, you know, this guy does prince cad, Al Cat, very a dramatic rescue there. Dun.
And so,
you know, Cat Al cat is is confused. He's he thought he had gone to the dryers to beat this marriage wrap And, you know, when he figures out what's going on, he makes the break for it. The King realizes there's the real one this other guy's is an impostor.
You know, they set him... They they set off after the real Cat Al had and donald very un
volunteers. To help. And we we understand as the reader in Michelle. This this is a trope and I'm sure it was very old even back then what is about to happen. Right? Mistaken identity, and which one is which.
Yes. Yeah. We're going into that thing where the real Al had will not
confess because he doesn't want to
made to go through with the unpleasant thing. So... It's like that Spider man meme where they're both both spider man's pointing at each other?
Totally is. Yeah. You could totally...
You could totally take that panel that he is. Yeah.
And Right sure.
I'm plop that in. Yeah. I I I come across a couple of of potential meme worthy ones as I do these. You'll have to start in Instagram it's a companion
that has memes to match it.
Yeah. I definitely should. This is a part where the Nephews
like they're usually very clever in this. Right? Usually, they... They're the ones who figure things out. You would think that they would think to ask their uncle uncles. Something only he could identify. Yes. This part was frustrating for me. Yeah. I agree. I... Barks just wanted to tell this kind of story, I think here. So... Because because this is very out of character. For the nephews.
So the the king just decree. He just wants a warm body for the wedding, and he says they're gonna have a fight to the finish tomorrow. We're gonna lock them up and whoever
survives
will we'll go through with the wedding. Which honestly sounds very exciting and like a great wedding pre game. Yeah. That's true. It would've have been exciting, but again, that's not the story Barks wants tell here because we kinda just transition very quickly to the Nephews
knocking out the guard on the next page and and rescuing Donald. But we understand from the conversation that it's actually Cat Al Cad who is posing his donald. Again, this is a very predictable trope. Right? He knocks donald out, and the kids are not very thoughtful. I guess, I guess you can share say they're distracted by training know that they have limited time. Yeah, they're trying to avoid that scientist.
And again, we kinda we kinda transition very quickly to the Ducktales out in the desert, i'm trying to get away and and and we hear Cat Al Cat revealing himself as, you know, someone who lived here a long time ago marvel at how things have changed. And the nephews are very slow to pick up on this. Yeah. I mean he saw that giant snake.
Right. He identifies an oil pipeline as a giant snake. It does click for them in a moment and and they ask how did he know that? He explains. You know, I I used to raise Chariot horses
at my ranch over there. And so they realized that they they done goof
Cat Al Ka, he heads out and the Nephews p back, very sad about about having been fooled. Yeah. That part was that whole part was very frustrating for me. And then I kept thinking about if I was one of them, Like, how are you gonna capture
the sky and then drag them all the way back there. Right. Yeah. Because they're in a real bind here. Right? And I and I feel like this this is the part of the story that transitions into something. It feels very bleak Right? And it's about to transition to well. It's about to transition to a very dark and gloomy y sort of resolution Because we we land back at the scientist and I get a little bit of a chill every time I enter his thought balloons. It feels very like a very uncomfortable
place to be. Because now he he's pondering. He says that those people were dried by a rad vapor. That's the best guess I can make. And he he goes on to to think somewhere in these ghostly rooms is a container of the stuff. If I can find that, the world will be on my mercy. What do you think? Filler?
Earlier, we had discussed the trope and how, you know, don't trust to book by its cover or judge book by its cover. And even though this guy has shown us his true character and done many evil
things. There was still a part of me leading up right before this thing.
Maybe he wants this for a good thing. Maybe it's a good technology. It's something he wants to help. Nope. At this point, it's pretty clear. Yeah. This guy is not a a great guy. He does not wanna use this to
save the children of the world or help hear homelessness,
No. This guy's a bad dude. Absolutely.
And and just like you, I read it the same way where I i kinda harbor this little, like,
I think I'd been primed, you know, for that
don't judge a book by its cover. Trope, but... But we we learned his true intentions or at least part of his true intentions, and he really is a man to be feared for sure. And and while he's doing this, you know, the king is
grip
about, you know, where where are all the things that make being a king worthy?
Musicians and dancing girls and cook And, you know, his... One of his guards helps him on the next page come to terms with the fact that everything is dust. We are people out of time.
I don't know if they know how long it's been, but they can tell that everything has been a while. Yeah. It's been it's been a minute. And we get this pretty striking panel
of of the king coming to terms with that. And it looks pretty haunted, you know? Like, like, it's a it's a very horror struck expression. Yes. The truth is setting in finally for him. Right. And so he's he's gonna move forward by doing the only thing that makes sense to him right now is
carrying on with the wedding and, you know, there's no need for the fight to the death because they've only got one left and obviously, he'll do. He's gonna make do. The key instruct them to do the old fashioned ceremony. For the bride does hand springs and the groom is carried in on a tray. I thought that was delightful.
Yeah. I like that too And apparently, apparently, Barks took the groom part from Al national geographic article
about a a traditional Moroccan wedding. Mh that's interesting. Yeah The hand springs is totally totally made up. And and I... There's part of me that wonders, you know, this is like well I'll save it for them moment it. We transition to the Nephews who are in a really bad place and it's gonna become worse. Right? Because they made it back to the supply dump the excavation site. And just as they do a massive sands storm, berries them. There berries the the supply dump and they have to, like,
shelter themselves in their shirt. To avoid being completely suffocated. And by the time it ends, they they cannot
identify the entrance anymore to the city. These poor kids, it's like, what else can go wrong? Everything but can will go wrong. Yeah. I really feel for them and
So we transition on the next page back to the wedding ceremony.
She's singing the old cliche here comes the bride song doing and springs. The guards are singing for Donald as they bear him on a tray And this strikes me as like a man being delivered to an unhappy marriage I I know from Barks background that around this time, his his long marriage was dis
in a, in pretty unpleasant manner.
And I think he was gonna go on to rem reenter very happily. But I wonder if there's a little bit of his life seeping out into his art here. Oh, definitely can see maybe how some bitterness might be affecting this storyline.
Yeah.
Michelle, can you see well enough to tell us about the scientists
intrusion into this wedding ceremony. Well i hate comes in very dramatically with his hand raise holding up another urn, and he says, and here comes the end of humanity.
I have found it. The substance that turns people to dust. And then again, my anxiety got raised at this part because I'm like, how is he gonna get out of this?
Yeah. And and the scientist,
this this is something unpack. I'm not going to, but, like, his his aim is to do away with
everybody and have the whole world to be alone in. And all it takes is a little whiff of that vapor.
Yeah. And and he looks so sinister
in this. And, you know, Donald has this comment. And I'd begun to think that guy was okay, which really did match my my thoughts until until I learned on the previous page, you know, what is aim was. But it's such a psychotic thing. Right? It to me, it really heighten his menace that he wants...
He wants to be the last man to Die Barks, basically. Yeah. To literally
eliminate
everyone. It was just such an extreme. And again, they've shown us several times throughout this comic, his character and what type of guy he is. But then when it we got to this point, I was like, whoa. This is a little more extreme than I was expecting.
Right. And and this is one of the shorter adventure stories. So maybe one of my mild criticisms is that it wraps up pretty quickly here. You know, Donald saves the day by essentially just smacking him with his helmet,
causing him to drop and break the urn. But it's gonna transition to this next page that is I'm gonna say it's really
really
horrifying. It's kinda like thanos with everybody dis.
Yeah.
It's it's its own version of a snap. The scientist is the closest to the broken urn which has this very sinister looking cloud of the vapor. He says that he he yells. You've broken the seal. The vapor is escaping.
Weird doomed. And and you know, he's got he's got the fear of death in his eyes.
Even though this is just going to the dryer,
we know that this is... If there's no one recon this is death. Yeah. It took five thousand years for him to figure it out. How long is it gonna take for the next guy Right. So
everyone is terrified.
Everyone is running for their lives. We get this mantle of the
the court the royal court in, like mid
being
overtake by the the dust. And i and again as an eight year old,
this was probably within the first... You know, I got into these comics and I got into them quickly. And I knew I love them. I went back to the comic store and every month. These were the only ones that I read and and there was such a great backlog of these. This was probably within the first twenty or thirty of these hundreds of comics that I would go on to collect that I read. This freaked me out. This terrified you. It was a very disturbing
Yeah. That's pretty intense for an eight year old boy to be reading. Yeah. And and
we see a couple of the guards, made dis
The next panel transitions to the king
kind of resolving. He says
oh well with no eats in this place, no music, no dancing girls.
Cares
and and... I mean, I get it. I do not get where he's coming from. I do too. It's it's such a des,
you know, thought,
exercise to be yank back into existence after this form of debt and then and then to leave right again.
Out of this world, you know, that wasn't yours.
But it's again, his his word balloon trails off into nothing.
Personally when I'm hungry, I tend to get pretty dramatic too.
So I mean, this this panel definitely was relatable for me. Right. So the next time you look in your fridge and and there's just nothing good to. You're just just gonna be all well. If
Right As well d
myself.
Right. You're can... You're gonna go to the dryer and
go to the dryers.
Again, just each panel is, like, more disturbing than the next for me on this page because the next one has the scientist.
Saying air, I must get to the open air. If I'm going to live
and in the next The next panel has him transition and dust as his balloon trails off to own the world
Again, it's a striking
panel because we see Donald
seeing this going down with the the terror on his face.
Yeah. Again, my anxiety, I was worried. I was like, how is he gonna get out of this? But then there was a little bit of relief to know that maybe the scientists wasn't gonna be her ass seeing everyone. Moving forward.
Yeah. And and it's worth highlighting that that this is a a one of those impossible
situations that first, you don't see how how can you get out of it It's a very enclosed space.
And and so by the end of the page, we transitioned to Cad Al had, you know, kind of enjoying himself, he's planning to t over to the ancient city of Per,
which was a roaring boom town last he saw it. And
you wanna you wanna tell us what freaks him out? Oh, yes. He sees...
It looks like a cheap. And I wasn't sure if it was
supposed to be like an army or if it was just people passing by. Yeah. But he thinks it's, like, a metal chariot.
And he said that they roar like lines Right. And it's just... It's too much for him. You know? He can't handle how much things has have changed. It's its own kind of, like, sad existence
overload. Yeah. It definitely is. Right? Imagine someone yank forward thousands of years into the future. So he runs back to its
and he arrives where the Nephews have been sift in the desert sand. And, you know, he, I think because of his heightened panic, that's how we can explain how he hone in and rapidly digs into the entrance.
And and the Nephews are are ecstatic and they get there just in time to see him wind up and take a big running start. And what happens to him, Michelle? He gets thanos snapped and just evaporates into dust. He
he inhale that vapor, I guess.
Yeah. Disappears. And thankfully,
the boys see that before they themselves fall to a similar fate.
Right. Just in the nick of time, and there's this very to me sad po, you know, exclamation point as
cat pad, probably processes what has happened just a little bit too late. Yes. Was not expecting that to happen.
So on the final wrap up page of the story, you know, we see the Nephews
being creeped out by the erie looking vapor calling out for Un donald who who doesn't answer very ominous.
But we don't... We're not afraid for too long michelle. What what Donald figured out? Well, thankfully,
he figured out that he could go hide in that re hydrating bathtub that was still filled with liquid.
Right. It's a it's a really brilliant, like, way I think of of him saving himself and and waiting till the dangerous pass. And I like that. I completely agree because I was stressed out for him.
Yeah. Me too.
Thinking back to being, you know, a young kid. It it really did seem like an impossible
situation, but this is the perfect literal solution. And it sounds so simple.
Yeah. And so the nephews, you know, they wait until they the... It seems like the coast is clear and as they're about to come in, you know, Donald emerges and their static, and he's he's got this stern expression on his face. And and when the nephews finally think to make him confirm that he's really donald he he proves it by by walking men
towards them and asking them to remember what he said about following that scientist
that curiosity is what killed the cat and they kinda tremble
anticipating, you know, a spanking. But he gives them this great big bear hug and said it says, this is one time I'm not gonna span you for disobey me because the right kind of curiosity
probably saves a lot of cats. That's true because had they not been there to stop the guy, he might have gone and dehydrated the whole entire world. Yeah. All he needed to do is, you know, figure out how to reproduce it, and and and you could menace
everyone And we get this, you know, kind of funny comic tagline line where he threatens them to find some supper or he's gonna he's gonna do some corporal punishment, which we know is not really thing these days, but in the fifties was much more common. Yes. And and they're very pros about it. And that's how we conclude the story. I... You know, I... One thing I wanted to add to is I never realized that they said
Donald. Mh.
Yeah. And I was wondering if that's how it was... Or if it still is present day and in the cartoon.
Because if it is, I never picked up on it. Yeah. I think that they
retains that in the first Ducktales
series.
I
I don't remember how they handled it in the second one. But this is really just a convention of the comic. Right? Because they had these uncle donald and Scrooge, and they referred to them a lot. And
I don't think this was like a big societal thing back at this time I think it's just like a Disney Ducktales thing.
I think it's supposed to be an accent?
No. I think it's supposed to be like a little term of and to represent how little kids speak, you know? And and
the nephews are are older than that. We're smarter than that. But I think it might just be something that they've kind of retained you know, and it it might have been in that first cartoon
where the Nephews were introduced. They probably... They probably called him donald in those early cartoons. I think my memory is is correct that they did that. And Carl Barks got his start Michelle as like a gag writer for those old Disney shorts, you know? Oh, interesting. No he he wouldn't work on a lot. You probably seen some of those classic Disney duck Disney mouse cartoons.
They're they're very famous. I watched them just all the time as a child in the eighties. I'm sure I did too, and I
if I was to see it, I'm sure it would definitely bring back some nostalgia. Right. So that's how box got his start. He didn't even... He he was born in nineteen hundred and I was like his one of his many careers and and he didn't actually do these comics.
Until starting into, like, his mid forties.
Wow. Yeah. And then worked and again, just worked as a as as the go to for this publisher doing hundreds of these stories until the mid sixties
and then had this later career doing oil paintings of many of his stories and didn't even didn't pass until the year two thousand at the age of of ninety nine. That's amazing.
Yeah. He had played a career. So he he was one of the first ind into the Disney
legends. You know, Disney has their own like legends ceremony
it sounds like he kept himself pretty busy, which I'm sure helped aid and his longevity having a purpose and a hobby and things to do. Yeah. Absolutely. That's that's a good a good point. And
he didn't even get recognition for this body of work until much.
Much later because he did these all anonymously. They were all like walt, Disney's Donald duck in Ancient Persia. Wow, so what did it... What happened that caused him to finally get that recognition.
Oh man. You're you're just asking the the best questions here.
So this is well known to to the fans. But basically the long fans sniffed him out. Right? They they could tell that some of these stories were better than the kind of like random crap that was off often run in the pages. And so if you got one of the months where they quote ran a a story by the good duck artist. You would start to notice his style. And and then when they got a little bit older, groups of fans basically, I think think into the late sixties
early seventies
started to track him down and
they might have I think they might have gotten in touch with him through the publisher
Someone certainly knew and and he correspond with people And and then, you know, in the eighties a new publishing company called Gladstone Publishing. Took up the license after it went dormant for a while, and they they were made up of fans who had grown up with the stories and and ran them with the proper credits and with really cool interesting articles. Talking about these stories and and that's what I... This is like what I grew up on. This is how I learned to read, like, literally. That's awesome. I'm sure he appreciates
finally getting that recognition. Whether he, you know, was wanting for it or not to finally receive it, I'm sure felt really good. And to be acknowledged for all those years of hard work and dedication to the art. Yeah. No doubt. And and
he was like... I think he was super surprised by it as you might be if you were into your, like, late sixties early seventies and and never expected this. And and he got he was he became a very talented oil painter
later on. Let me show you... Because I do like to mention it in the podcast
when
when he has a corresponding
painting, so I'm gonna put up an ancient
purge
He did a version of of his classic cover for this. When it's a very cool oil painting. So he got this kind second career and he was
even, like a special license to actually sell these stories based on the Disney characters. Right? Because Disney doesn't just let anyone. Oh, no. They do not.
Profit. From... The mouse does not mess around. No. They do not. Alright. Do you have a decent view there as it is it
resolved? Oh, yeah. That's beautiful. I love the color choices.
Very vibrant.
Yeah. So this is Al cool. This a pretty iconic cover that he did. He of these for for many of his stories. And they're highly sought after by collectors and and well out of my price range. I I was a kid who... You they would I subscribe to the comments at one point, and they would send me catalogs that showed the lit photographs and oil paintings things. And I always just drooling over them, but they are and always been well out of my means. Oh, yeah. Those are beautiful.
That's... Like I said, I really love the detail. Yeah. And it's see how it honors the original comic, but then also brings a new freshness to it as well. Yeah. I'll I'll have to... I'll have to pest you by sharing a few more of these cool ones with you. Please.
I think you had read or at at least got to see a lot of the old Castle secret. He did some cool ones based on that. You. Yeah. I really enjoyed that. Story. Nice. So what what are you kind... We've talked about it, but what are your all thoughts on this? What word for you what didn't, you know...
Whatever your impressions are. I want I want you to feel like obviously, I feel very strongly about this. It's okay. If you don't, if you're like I don't get why you like these Ducktales comics mark, but
what do you... I I would say that overall, I did enjoy it. It had that adventure aspect
that I love personally as a geek who enjoys those types of things. One of the things that I really appreciated about the story is that it kept going off into different directions that were not predictable
to me.
I definitely...
I would say like, yeah, some of the things were a little
what's the phrase?
I guess we just had to go with the suspension of disbelief and just accept things for what they were. Which again, that's something that when you're a geek, you become used to, it happens a lot.
I it wasn't nice the way that they portrayed the princess.
But again, that's something that has happened for many years over many mediums, different stories.
Yeah. Al I thought it was a lot of fun I enjoyed the relationship that Uncle Donald had with his nephews.
I enjoyed that the evil character wasn't
what I thought he was gonna be.
I thought the artwork was great. I was really impressed. I think that I might have had in my head of bias that older comics
didn't put a lot of detail in, but that's obviously not true. There was a lot of great detail in a lot of these panels.
In some cases probably more than you would find in modern comments nowadays.
Yeah. And I think it's fair to say that Barks stands up heart, and that's why he still remembered as... Because a lot of these old stories, I think if you went back and grabbed any random one from March of nineteen fifty,
This is just leagues above almost anything out at the time and and wouldn't stand up. There's some good stuff. I I've read some of the old superhero you know, Jack Kirby stuff, but I don't think I can enjoy it the way that I still enjoy these.
Right? Because they're gated, but they they they're they're not dated in the same way. I think they I think because he's doing this with Ducktales, and he's taking them where he wants to go. I think they hold up very, very well for the most part. I agree. I thought this did. I feel like my children would probably enjoy this. You know, ranging in ages from twelve to sixteen, and I feel like they would enjoy reading this or if there was an animated version of this. They would probably enjoy it.
Yeah. Yeah. This would been an interesting adaptation. As far as I know, neither of the Ducktales series, you know, went for this one. I agree with you. It's it's a bit of a shame that this is a boy's comic. Right? And that's very clear. It was it was geared towards boys marriage is kind of a key thing. So he might have been playing into that. But but it's a it's not an awesome.
Representation of the dump princess for comic effect you're right. He's not the last person who's gonna kind of make a character to kinda beat up on them. But but again, that's not what this is all about. And it it's a sour note for me in this otherwise, like, really classic.
Very
disturbing
story. I I... It's all relative of course. This is still a Ducktales comic, but
I... My complicated relationship with this one is that there was a time where it it almost creeped me out too much to read it, but I was fascinated by it. So I kept going back to it and...
And I think that's good storytelling.
When something is scare you, but it captures you so much that you're willing to work through that to find out more. Right. Definitely. And I think like many of his best stories. This one really benefits from, like multiple
readings. And and it's such a great allegory
for the kind of, like paranoia
that there was, you know, the fact that it was a rad gas is is really very telling. Right? Because the world was steep in this atomic paranoia Al this time. And so I I do see this now as an adult as
as a stand in for this fear of atomic.
I think that's one of the good things about the comic overall as it does represent
kind of the moon and feeling of the time. And yet, like you said, it still does hold up today. For someone like me, who's reading it for the first time. Yeah. That's awesome. I'm glad to hear. I'm glad you I'm glad you enjoyed it. This one is very well liked by the community. There's a website, shell that aggregates
reviews. It's very cleverly called index instead of index.
Barks is not the only Disney comics creator. So you they... There are votes for more than forty one thousand stories from around the world from over the decades. Oh, wow. Yeah. And and this one
clocks in with an eight point four out of ten rating, which is good for number
twelve out of all the stories that index. Measures. So it's very well liked
remembered by the community. I think probably because it it stands apart as as one of his creep stories for sure. And it's that whole worldly adventure vibe too, which I think was popular back then and is still pretty popular nowadays.
Yeah. These are stories that are remembered best. Are are these adventure ones that really gave them kind of that that
inspiration to create the Duck hill series. I'll have to have you back on at some point when we do maybe one of the Ducktales
adaptations. You might. Yeah. I remembered that though was growing up and I loved those and the
shipping day all I mean. Oh, yeah. The rescue rangers. Yeah. Yeah. The rescue rangers. I love watching that. With the big Disney afternoon fan. So thank you for all your time. I know we've gone on for a long time over a a disney dot com, but I I love unpacking these with friends and figuring out what people think of them.
Any any other thoughts that you have about this story before we wrap it up? No. I mean, like I said, in general, I I did. I I I enjoyed it a lot more. Honestly, I wasn't sure what I was going to say when you mentioned this to me, but I did find it very enjoyable.
And I probably would
recommend it to my children. I think they would enjoy it as well. And I think that that is... I I think it's a great thing to point out that something that was written so many years ago who when the world was so different and it could still hold up today to such different standards.
Yeah. And that's worth noting.
Yeah, Very well. Thank you. Awesome. Well, well thank you listeners for
listening to us process this very cool creepy story. Let let me know your thoughts or or whatever you wanna share, have Park's remarks. We got Facebook page or Gmail Barks from remarks at g dot com join us again for our next
episode which will be about the pixelated parrot. Thank you. Thank you so much for having me and for thinking of me in the first place. This was a lot of fun.