Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of sc Mc and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge cl of all time join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context, and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks. Welcome back to Barks Remark I am still Barks Sever.
Still a grown man who enjoys talking about classic donald dot comics.
Joined by another grown man and returning for the third time. Is it one? That's right. Hey. Great to be back Barks. Warren Har here from Frozen, Minnesota and
enjoying these so much.
I am a long time Ducktales collector of memorabilia
for fifty years or so. But also a avid
reader of the Carl Barks stories and a collector of all the comics,
the original dell and a lot of the reprint and then more recently
I think I've shared before some of the wonderful lit photographs,
which I just love looking at and remembering all those adventures.
Great to be done. Yeah. Thanks for thanks for being back. I'm having a blast nerd out over these with both
newbies and longtime time fans. And today we get to talk about Carl Barks,
the pixelated parrot, which is just a fun title to say. No. It is. It is. I had to look up... And again, I had to say, okay, pixelated. Now we we use the term in the twenty first century as Ducktales.
You know. And I went wait a minute it's not spelled that way. It's not p i x e l it's P i x i l. So I had to do a little research Yeah. I had to look it up too, because I got curious about how the title was translated on. So... yeah, let let's get into it, though warren. What what does pixelated?
At first it just says crazy or confused and know, okay. I get it. But then I wear a little further and I love this this definition having an eccentric manner as though led by Pixie, and it's an older term
from
a few centuries ago that that pixelated would mean that you'd been
pixie dancing around in your head or something like that.
Yeah. It's it's a funny visual. And like you said, yeah. So kind of an arcade term,
it describes the parrot in this very well, and it's a little nice bit of all iteration.
So this story
appeared in four color number two hundred and eighty two. Warren do you do you happen to own an original I do I do. It's it's lined up along my mounted comics on the ceiling near the ceiling of my collector room and I I love the cover.
Yeah. It's it's kind of a fun they're kinda looking in the vault there with the the gun and the the parrot and it just screams we're gonna see Al adventure in the story. So... Yeah. It's it's a very intriguing cover, I think. And and this one was published or at least the cover date was May of nineteen fifty. So right. We're getting into the fifties here. I I imagine he must have actually created this one in the fifties at this point or very close to it. I believe so. Correct. This one's been reprinted quite a bit. You know, it's it's shorter. It's only twenty two pages so you can probably fitted in most titles pretty easily. I know the longer story they were kinda limited by maybe by how long they were for but... yeah. Lot lot of reprint. I myself phone this in the Gladstone giant album number five. I have, like, a couple of regular
reprint of it, nothing tool though. Lauren I really liked Glad. I think I've mentioned they're they're how they curated these stories before. Yes. The the issue that that was in was a really cool one. They were all south American themed. Oh are for Latin American themed stories. It was
it was supporting the gil man, that great classic story, Right? As well as secret of Hon rica, which is kind of like a a remake of that,
I guess. So what Gladstone did was they put those together in a collection of similar stories or some similar.
Right. Right. So I I really like that. You know, last, I didn't get to mention it but the last episode for an Ancient Persia that had some similarly nice...
The the way I read in that album, had several of those kind of science fiction rooms, all groups. Together.
So I don't have a ton of background
trivia for this one. But I do think it's interesting to mention that this is This is this is a kind of story beat or theme that Barks goes back to a few times where there's like an animal
or or a pet of some kind that has some kind of a quirk exactly. Right right. Or some kind of weird characteristic
that's gonna get them into some trouble. Oh, yeah. And then in this case, the pair, which will see is the continuous thread throughout the entire story. And
and also a vehicle
for the Nephews Donald Scrooge sc to play off of. And and even has a bit of a solo gig in this story, which will we'll talk about when the parrot kinda goes off on his own. But I thought that was fun. Yeah. That's true. That's that's
something that'll be good to point out. You know, I I took it in my notes on my little
Google doc, but it looks like it got swallowed up I'm gonna to do my best warrant to remember the stories that I listed that had that kind of animal with a silly characteristic.
You know, Al bunch of them are ten pager There's like, the camel that they had at one point that that only drink soda pop. Okay. Right. There are the the mice that like to trade in, I think all at c. Okay. There's... I don't know if the lemon with the lock count but it's definitely another another animal that gets them into trouble in a sort of far off land Mh. There was a fraud that only
jumped under certain
circumstances, I think I remember, Does that sound familiar? I don't remember. I'm glad you're bringing this up as a theme sort of that that's story carried by the animal with that. I like that idea. Certainly, this is probably the one that would rise to the top of the quirk little animal yeah Yeah the title as well. So...
Yeah. That's great. I'm glad you brought that up. Awesome. So and tell us, tell us what is the quirk about the parent warren. Holy, the cor he's he's is the accountant it's accounting. Barrett. It's what he does. He is obsessed with counting. It cannot not count
and that's the work. Yeah. That that's that's a good way of saying it. And and it strikes me that Barks likes to do this thing where you've got something that that both gets the characters into trouble and gets them out of trouble rubble.
So let's go into our titles from around the world. You know, we
we like to acknowledge how popular Barks is in other countries so I picked out a couple, and I know you've picked out a couple. Sure. And and I wanna start off with France because I I think this is a really neat title worn. I I didn't... It was hard to verify this. So I could be getting this completely wrong. But I think there's a pretty neat pun in this and maybe a French listener and
confirm or or correct me on this. The title is
So that's Donald and it sounds like para to me, but I I think it must be parents. When when I plugged it into
Google translate, it said it was donald then the care that mattered and matters. But I thought to myself, that actually Comp looks like the word count Mh as well. So I think that it's upon on the fact that the parent both counts constantly and then is ultimately gonna be crucial to the Ducktales
know, ability to get home and
ability to access this forge. So what is the what was the French word that translated as matter.
Oh, okay. Anyway. That leads me to Mexico. Let's let's do the Mexican
translation and it's it's in there a little bit with Con door. So it's El,
which translates to the Para accountant. So there's that C o n
a d o r as the accountant and Peri go translates to parent or repair. Yeah. And that kinda of works on both levels because Ko
would mean both accountant and just counter
in Spanish. Yep. And then I think I'm gonna go with Italy for my other one. Okay, which is
with feedback though is is one way I saw it, which is the
Scrooge parent. I like it's
food or my word? That's perfect. And then sometimes they said just
papa
is the alternate italian time. Oh, I like that. You know And I'll close out our our translations here with Poland, the in Polish, it translates here as poke
Boo.
And that translates as the twisted pair. So sort of the unscrew and twisted. I I like that. Yeah. That's fun. Absolutely. So
Most of those titles, they just really did go for, like, the counting pair. They they didn't try to go for anything. Really unusual like, pixel pixelated. And we're also at a time here where where we we've talked about this before Mark where Carl Barks is at sort of the peak of his output. He's really cranking out a lot of work here.
We know it's early nineteen fifty. We know he's... We've talked about his personal life. He's coming to the... Really to the end of his second marriage and it's not good. And so he's really working hard going for a lot of laughs. I think a lot of good distraction. And this is this is no exception.
This is a very comedic very silly story.
Kinda has the ethos of a ten pager to me a little bit. I agree with you a hundred percent on that. Yep. Like, it's it's an adventure, but no one really leaves the dock for for long. Great? So in that spirit, let's let's
step right onto the dock shall. You wanna you wanna kick this off warren unless was there anything else you wanted to know before let's let's get into the story. Yeah. Let's do it. Take this... You you can start a soft time lauren? Yeah. Yeah. And I I I'd like the... The dev user Al sea port at the dock watch ship come in and as it's unloading bananas, they hear this. They hear this counting that just starts and it starts with the the number twenty three thousand seven hundred and six and ends with twenty three thousand seven hundred and eight.
And basically, that's the number of bananas that the bunch of bananas that came out and the nephew just marvel at that and and know that this ship came from a from a afar off land, they say possibly costa to Rica. And so they're watching them unload and they get to the dock or the sailor and the blue hat with the kind of... And there is the first time we see our parent
continuing to count. And
they see the real parent and they're just absolutely
amazed that there's a exotic animal in Ducktales. Yeah. They're really taken by that parent. And you know, this this is a nice little kind of hint
a way to get the leader. I think. Primed for adventure. Right? We've got the Nephews being all wi,
imagining these far off places.
And, you know, that sets us up to want to see them as well. I also thought when I saw this, I love that first panel because it's Al larger and it shows the shipping port. It just made me think about what which I did as a kid. What does Ducktales look like? You know And here's this now. There's this huge
ship probably from Costa Rica.
And and it landed Al the port in Duck, which ticks you to the ocean and
we know from all of the adventures that Duck
is
extremely
geographically diverse and gotta me thinking about that mark. Yeah. I mean, for me, I I think as a kid, I had a little bit of sort of a little bit of that geo cent
where I I just assumed that Duck was basically like my hometown and that was helped by the fact that I actually grew up in one of the analog for Duck. Right Yeah. Because... Yeah because I grew up in the California Bay Area. And as I i was reading the Barks and Rosa stories, I'd saw all these neat parallels to it. And I grew up in Minnesota, and I saw when they were in the North woods and then they didn't travel far to go camping.
It reminded me of Northern Minnesota, and we both know that that the fictitious state that Duck is in is called Al.
Yeah.
So that's very apt. You've got a a Minnesota. I mean, we're we're a long way from being boys, but
but, you know, we we represent those two states that we do. That's we do. But I love I love the that aspect of all the stories it makes you kinda wonder geographically what Ducktales is looking like and of course, thanks to other artists Don Rosa and and, of course
other illustrator that that we have some good ideas of what it might look like and that just adds to the fun of this universe. Right. Alright. So on page two, you know, we've got the nephews kind of pondering whether they could actually purchase this parent off of the sailor. And and so they approach him. And he's he's a fun looking character. Right? He's got that hoop hearing. Huey,
can tell he's a very experienced
nautical
sailor. And, you know, he's instantly willing to sell the parrot to them. And so they he instantly offers fifty cents. And the Nephews user, you know, surprise, because this seems like a great steal. And And he's he is pretty anxious to unload this parent, it turns out. He says that he'll take a dime if they'll take and they'll buy it right now.
And and as they complete the transaction, he's revealing
what we know about this story, which is that this... This is a parent that is obsessed with counting. He does nothing, but count figures.
And as he's handing the pair over, he reveals that the pair is currently, he's at sixteen thousand three hundred and into the twenties.
And that is him. Three days
behind in counting all of those bananas. That's on the boat. That's where he's got a lot of catching up to do. And the closing panel on that is this great great visual of Men nephew kinda looking rue
at the parent with the expression of of someone who's wondering if they've just been rook if they've just been taken.
Maybe this is such a good deal after Right. Of course, we know they could just let them go, but and the other thing about the parent when we first see the parrot in almost every panel, he just looks tired and weary. He's a weary parent, and it's probably from that continuous counting and not catching up. So they get a good point. I... Sorry I weren't. That That's a really good point. Though. I I don't think I would've have picked up on that. He looks... He he doesn't count because he likes it. He's not Al. It's a comp.
So they take him home and we see Donald just pacing in the in his living room
and Donald is
wondering what he can get the richest man in the world his uncle sc since it just happens to be today is done is Uncle Scrooge birthday. It has to be something
kind of unique and unusual.
And problem solved when the Nephews Russian in with the counting parrot and but what we got for a dime they say and And, of course, the pair just continues to do this little counting on the side.
It's just wonderful when when Donald has to remind them, I've told you I don't want to pair it. So there must've have been somewhere in the past.
And and it's it's interesting. Right? This kit continues onto the next page where Donald is kind of put connecting the dots and realizing, yeah, this is an unusual unique carrot.
Uncle Scrooge is obsessed with counting his money.
So he sees this as the perfect companion. Warren this is kind of odd. Right? Because, like, there's never been anything in Scrooge just characterization that suggests that he'd appreciate a gift? No. It's a good point. That's a good point or much less...
Yeah. I don't know where donald got that idea. But right It's it's a good storyline
be exactly. Yeah. This is obviously the the story that Barks wants to tell. Right here and and Donald has gotten it into his head for some reason. So, you know, he immediately
takes the the bird and heads over to own Scrooge.
And
it's it's pretty neat when we see him arrive warren. Because we've got a couple of pretty cool iconic panels
Right? We we don't yet have Scrooge just money bin. That's correct. This is still his office. Barks refers to it in the original as his gold plated office. Mh. And he is in fact in the process of counting his fortune.
There's there's a really good gag where he's he's arrived at nine billion trillion
and and so on. And then he says, now I'll count the five hundreds.
Yeah.
And and it's...
Go ahead. No. I was just say, I love that panel. And you know, I I was gonna say there aren't a lot of memorable panels for me in this in the story, but that is one of them because I believe and correct me if I'm wrong and and the listeners certainly can. This might be one of the first
shots of inside his safe counting money. I know before we get to the money been in some of the screwed stories, Yeah. I confess I don't know the answer, but I had the same thought like, this seems to be the first kind of inside the vault
rather than just his office team. Right. My the details is fantastic, every layer of bill And this might be
Is this... Is this the first or just one of the very earliest appearances of this his good old canon that... I think this is one of the first if not the first I love warren. I I think most fans would say that this is one of their the the Scrooge
that just cracks them up. Right? Is is... His his old bow war cannon. Oh, yeah. You know, it'll be labeled later on as being from the bo war the where yep. Poised to to just obliterate whatever intruder. Has the goal to come through the door. But, yeah. He's waiting. He he hears Donald knock on the door and he
prepares to strike the match. And Donald
blu his way in telling him that he got him this birthday present. And and sc reacts what I would characterize is very predictably. Right? Warren. Yeah. His glasses fly off his face, and he he's ready to just he's he's not very happy at this point anyway, because he's still counting money, but
but he doesn't like intruders and he doesn't like anybody tell, you know, giving him a gift at this point, just gonna back to your point Barks about... It's kind of odd that he would accept a gift. But
but then
the the parrot is is a bother because it cost some money. It will cost you money to feed it. And what do you think I am a billionaire?
So
Donald continues to
try to convince uncle Sc that
for a tencent cent investment,
this is a good deal because you, he'll be a good investment and
anybody gives you a present, and I love the way he's pinning down our uncle sc down here,
you gotta take it. So he kicks them out and on that panel, I love that panel where he kicks him out because cause, we see something we don't see often in a drawing and that is donald with teeth. When he's in when Barks got into these, we see those cl teeth a little odd, but it's it's kind of an artist
privilege I guess to write that to draw that it's... So. But I love this next panel too. He's just screaming with his eyes shut and throws the pair up onto the Coat rack who continues to count and then goes back to the... Or why don't you quote that one where he's crying out? Because that's a great That's a funny quote. Oh, yeah. So he he kicks it donald Al out and then he just says me with a bird to support. I should give myself up to the poor farm.
And then he calls him a y and extravagant. Right right right that. But that's... Yeah. That's right. Get over there. You y and ex extravagant. And I love that. So he goes to the safe. But he he really is determined to change the combination on this
Right. And and he allude to, you know, changing it and needing to remember it. Right. So this is this is silly, but, of course, this is gonna set up the stakes for the big. A problem in the story. Right? So he... On the next page, he verbal mobilize his new combination
slams the the vault closed. And as he leaves he realizes, oh, I still need to get a dime to get
some crackers for that yeah and comparison.
And and as he heads back
sn, he can't remember the combination and he's
that it costs him two million dollars for a new save every time he forgets it. Yeah. So here
I I I do wait a minute. This doesn't make sense. He's actually
going to spend two billion dollars every time he's forgotten. It sounds like he's forgotten before yet
It it moves then on. He can't remember it and and you see the pair on the coat rack, just like, looking back over his shoulder and who quickly recite the combination that sc
entered right away.
Immediately,
immediately, we see a change in sc demeanor. He gets
extremely happy.
To see that the parrot can remember the combination to the safe. Says he's his official reminder from now on and places him into the top drawer of his file cabinet
We see him in bed the next night this or that night
just a very happy and content at home,
knowing that he can rest easily with a Pair who remembers. And then
as
falls and we see midnight roll around, we see this little silhouette of the file cabinet number still coming out. So we know the pair in there, but then we see these two intruders that show up and our staring right his safe and take from here. Yeah. And they're very familiar looking
intruders. They are. They unless you read this before unless you read these the right order. Because, you know, we've got basically here one. We've got the pro beagle boys. That's right. It's not the beetle boys,
one of them is is named Butch. Mh.
I'm not sure if the other one even gets a name. Oh, I lucky he doesn't. Yep. Yeah. But but they have the mask. They have kind of orange
reddish orange in in my color and, you know, they've got those top I don't know about the original dell and blue pants.
So at least in the addition that I read, they were meant to evo the vehicle voice. Yeah. They they have some of the characteristics with the mask, but
they also have
visually, I think a little bit more aggressive looking with their guns. And we never Al the beetle boys with guns going forward. And the big old boys always ended up traveling in threes and fours. You never really saw a couple of them together, but definitely a precursor to what we're gonna see in a few in in about a year or so. Yeah. And that... And that's a good point about the guns. Right? The beagle boys are are meant to be much more
comedic than that medicine.
Yes. And and so these burglar are pretty funny. Right? Because they've they've broken and not to steal Mc du money, but but rather just to gaze upon the vault and imagine what it would be like if they could.
Because there's no way they can break it and the combination would be too hard to guess.
So one of them says if only they knew the combination,
and then with the precision comic timing,
poly the parent as they're gonna call him pipes up and and reveals the combination and it it only takes them a moment of feeling threatens Al someone else being in there before they
suppose that might be the right combination. And and sure enough, they start to they roll out
ten truckload at least of pure money. No. This this is simply impossible when you consider that. I think this before we have the... That was the three cubic acres of money, but we have ninety tons of money which is setting in the story. And these two butch and his partner, clear it all out in one night. Not possible, but heck. It's it's a great story gag. And Poly, in the top drawer just continues to count. So
they they slam the door shut. They congratulate each other and basically...
But they are pretty
clearly
stating their address right there kind of for poly
where they're gonna go to their hideout. And again, you wouldn't do this, but it's a great story gag that at going to twenty four twenty four twenty fourth Street. Sc in the next morning sc is absolutely
thrilled and he can't wait to show donald that the birthday present did pay off. He shows up to the to the office and it goes in and the first thing they see is that the drawer, the top file cabinet drawer is empty and Poly gone. And Scrooge just starts w.
You know, he can. He blames himself but Donald then he starts sharing the counting from out side the window. Yeah. And of course, Sc isn't
immediately
sad about the loss of the bird. He's sad about his inability to access
the the vault. Oh, yeah. And, of course, he we know this already He has no inclination that they're the... There's anything missing. He just what the birds gone. So on the next page, this is some nice framing. Right? Because this entire page is what I would call a flagpole pull gag. That's exactly right. Yep. And and
Barks likes these. I can think off just off the top of my head of at least two other stories that have like, flagpole pole moments. Mh. With characters
precarious clinging to life trying to get, you know, there's one in the secret of Atlanta I think we pursuing the quarter and then there's one where
donald sales
insurance Scrooge, I believe yes. Yes.
Flagpole plays a prominent role in that story. It's a nice bit of tension and and humor. So Polly is out there continuing his town. He's a bird, so he's fine, but Scrooge
bum rush has donald out the window to try and and catch him and we see donald
trembling and shaking the flagpole pull until finally the bird
is shaken off and and, you know, Sp is chi him to get after him, but of course, he he can't just drop. So they have to they they're gonna have to take it up on the next page Yeah. And and there's a there's a great panel there with Donald the flagpole, Both just shaking uncontrollably and you see what Barks had to do artistic to show the the Shaken Donald, but the shaking parrot. I just love that. Blob of feathers and tails. But You, you mention that this particular
multi panel sequence is memorable. And in this story, I counted what I would say are four pretty good multi panel
representations of the gag. And this is the first one that I came across the flagpole gag. I called it and then the next gag is on this next page and this is what the the angry wife Donald has now been told to go find the parrot fine Poly. Of course, this is where we know that sc won't discover that the safe is completely cleaned out until they get poly They use a term here which I looked up here disappeared into to the city smog. So it may be wonder where the term smog was introduced know they're growing up in the seventies. I heard smog a lot that's morgan La. After some research, yeah, Mo was a term used at the beginning of the twentieth century. And Barks would have been well well familiar with smog at that time. And both absolutely.
Absolutely.
So they they keep looking and this next panel here where he he goes to the phone. I had a little trouble figuring out where he's at here because there's an office door with a phone
symbol on it. Yeah. But it's interesting to see that cool hanging phone book. Yes. You remember those with the great. Yeah. Yeah. And we've got a little bit of real world, you know, there's the mob bell logo go there. There's Al logo. Yep. That's right in the circle. Yeah. So the the the the you show up and remind on where they found Poly to begin with. And
so they decide to go back to the waterfront. And as they're walking back, we past the ships. We know they're at the waterfront on the pier. We see this
hysterical looking angry woman and she's carrying her basket with one fish talking about how angry she is at her husband for telling her that she's got wrinkles are facing that she's not young anymore. And so she just takes it out on Donald. The first person. She's he he's and asks him about how many wrinkles she has. And of course the voice perfect timing is the parrot behind the fence and
Donald looks fl acid because he didn't say anything, but then she melts him over the head with the fish
well Poly becomes visible
continuing to come. Right. Having having just answered her that she has twenty one thousand seven hundred and sixty
wrinkles. That's great. And, you know what? The comic timing and that sequence that gag as you put it. It it is impeccable. Right? It's Mh. It's it is the definition of a perfectly timed to gag I am less
less appreciative of that kind of humor than I was when I was younger. Just because it's it's very like, It's a car
of an egg. Old old woman. Yeah. It's a car. It's pure slaps stick. I I think it would have played out in a cartoon to an animated cartoon to beautifully. It's a little mean spirited for my taste these days, but I know for a lot of people that is that is not the case. And I I recognize that it's it's great time And then on to the next page, you know, they do get a beat on Poly and they're pursuing him and and basically, the entire point of this page is for them to be
distracted in their per pursuit and to accidentally
board an ocean going vessel. Yes they. They follow him down into the coal shoot. Donald dives into a poll shoot. There's not really too much to this. It's it's a very
necessary
transitional page though. Go back to the panel on your page that says as the thought bubble censored. What do you think is happening there? I do like that panel. That that's a good point. You know? That's that's it's really different. Yeah. Yeah. It's it's funny. I think it's it's a fun gag and a family friendly one to imply the where the swearing thoughts. Right? Right. Well it doesn't matter
whether it even is a swear word or if it's just you know, some like slaps stick fiddle sticks type language. It's like it's effectively
covering up what he thinking. But yeah, he dives into that... I don't know what you call that, like, a steam or a or kind of a steam chute on the boat
because he saw a poly fly and
lands into what again I call this the third kind of comic sequence here
panel sequence. Of the soot in the boiler room. Beautiful seas birds
flying around and and kicks
kicks this what he thinks is a black crow who just walks away and realizes that then that it wasn't a black crow that was the parrot covered in soot and that's kind of stares of the camera. What classic take there and, you know, moves on from there. Yeah. I really like this. Right? Because we've got that classic, like, he's da and he sees tweeting birds. Yes. And and he just thinks that the crow is, you know, another of the tweeting birds And and warren... I found it so refreshing that we had a gag that involved, you know, being covered with soot that was not even a little bit intended to Al allude to, like, it's not a blackface thing. It
just it genuinely is. Oh, he thinks the parent looks like a crow. There's no, like, min
mist anything like that. So... No that was refreshing. Right. And so on the next page, you know, the the parrot is missing and there's a neat little panel showing the Ducktales
disoriented because there are so many ways that the parent could have gone. And Barks just transitions. He's not really interested how they catch the parent here. What he's interested in is that it takes
enough time that there they've lost their bearings
and they don't realize that the ship has
set sail
because there's this funny moment and and this is a common trope, right, where they go to they go to find the gang plank to get onshore shore and they have this little moment of
misunderstanding with the captain and and it reveals the the, you know, the drawn camera pulls back to show that they're fifty miles out Al sea. We we get a use of an nautical term a stern. Right? Yes. Do means behind us. It's a wonderful last panel on that page.
Again, it's the closest we come too about it two or three splash panels in this story. Nothing really larger than this. But, yeah, You're right. It's it's a wonderful trope they use all the time. Now they they announce here the
the the new individual who's probably not the captain,
but
grabs him by the neck and says, you know, will we'll take care of that after we get to t,
which we know now we are headed for a a tropical climate
Again, we're moving around the world now. We're we're kind of getting into that short adventure stage in this story as the barrett continues count. They
label these guys at store, and then they quickly put them into the galley or the food bin and here they're doing their time. Doing the standard gag of appealing potatoes Yeah. For their passage.
And and as to notice Poly in the panel where they're peeling comes to a number twenty three thousand seven hundred and eight. And Warren. What what is Donald just said?
Yeah just go ahead. Well, Donald says he's despair. Right? He's saying, I wish we could get just one lucky break. Just one teeny wee.
That's classic. And then Poly comes to the last number and falls down it exhausted.
And then one of the nephews looks up and says he's finished counting his bananas after he's caught up and Donald just joyful. He care he's building potatoes or anything he's just full of joy. That's their break. That's that's their breaking yeah. You got their Teeny Winnie lucky he got his wish.
And then the numbers start again. It he's counting the potatoes
classic great last frame on that page. Yeah. Warren, I'm I'm gonna go ahead and say that this is the best page of the story. Okay? This this is like, the whole...
This is the crown gag of this story.
I I could even imagine, you know, that Barks almost built the the verizon and falling action out of this one. Like the the the the next the rest of it's fine, but
this is hilarious. I I is quite probably. Yeah.
Out loud when I read this the first time. Well, definitely,
I'm glad you pointed that out because I I laughed what I saw that the company... And Night I hadn't read this for a while, but when I saw that you started counting again, I went oh. This is wonderful. And that last panel is probably my favorite panel in the in the whole story just to put them with the little x's over their eyes just passed out and just exhausted it again. But you. And and the pair just county determined. I I agree. It's probably the best one. So on the next page, the Ducktales have arrived in t and And warren and I've been having fun tracking, you know, on the Facebook page, I've been tracking on a Google map Yeah. Where the Ducktales adventures take place. So this is obviously, and other of those made up plans. I'm I'm gonna peg this as being somewhere around like... I mean, they referenced costa rica. So I'll say it's not in Costa Rica, but it's probably near it. Right? It's definitely a central American.
What we would probably
refer to as quote a banana Republic majority. I think so. I I would agree that when I thought about this, i didn't think central America as they leave the port of Ducktales
and continue in the pacific ocean
down down that way, it would make sense that this is where it would be that many days later. Yep. Right. And and so this
this next sequence, the entire point of this, you know, Donald has thoughtfully
attached polly with a chain to himself. And the ducks are feeling much better. Right? Because now they can contact on Scrooge,
report the good news, secure passage home.
But then as they see that there are other parents around predict the parrot falls in love with a lady parent. And when Poly is not able to fly off to her because of the chain, the parrot
recruits a two can. Mh. To use its bill a bird that looks like a two can and snaps that chain. Yeah. And then Donald just... I love the way he refers to Poly now as
the wolf. It was on after the girl,
an old term used
but the nephew say that they're heading for the jungle. They were happy one moment. And now they're just distressed again that the troubles are starting all over again.
Great over... I wish the panel was larger, but I love this shot of the parrot other parents flying around the village. And
he's gonna go to the pay phone and call sc. And this is where the the title of the story kinda comes into play here. Because Donald on his way back salty. I love that walk with his arms dragging and he's just... Yeah. Eyes toward the the the the the boys or toward the sky and he just saying you know, what he said, find that pixelated parent or walk home. And then they basically
have to know that they're gonna be they're looking in this far off land for this this bird who's flown off into the jungle, love the last panel, again another little tiny mini splash panel of this wonderful geography. And good luck in the jungle ahead. Yeah. And so Warren, we've got it's kind of a needle in a Haystack
situation. Right? Yeah. Where where the Ducktales have had to follow a small animal into a distant country
because it is the key to sc fortune. Does it mind you remind you of anything? Yes.
What does that remind you? Oh my gosh. Okay. You're catching me off guard a little bit okay if you can't. It's just it's funny to me. This is the story beats for the lemon with the lock. Yes. Yes. Yes. That's it. So I like that. I... That's that's something that I'm realizing now as I read this. He's gonna build another story around this concept, but, you know, amp up the action. And there's an interesting reference to Uncle Scrooge having to eat in the bread lines while they see that. Yeah. We'll we'll eat the bread lines forever if we don't have some awful good luck in the jungle ahead. Yeah. So then we take this turn into this really odd little sequence here. Go ahead. Yeah. On on this next page, and and it was a good point you made how this is really structured in like, page by page.
You know, they've been deliberately set up so that you're gonna turn the page. You got a new dad. This is this is a gag that again just just like with the ugly old lady. We've got kind of one of these old tropes of sort of the the man hungry
single mother, I guess. Right? Because the the parent is essentially
reeling
poly in. Right? She is very su tree. Barks is actually giving dialogue to these animals, which is pretty unusual. Calls of p, parody. Yeah. He he actually says that he's kind of translating it. And she is basically
drawing him in with the commitment
to
support her and Polly loves struck. So he's agreeing to it And once she has reel him in, she turns to the hole in the tree they've landed on and says, alright, children come out and meet your new papa.
And some totally adorable little baby parents file out in single file line. And again, this is great timing.
It is
admittedly very funny because he has another reason to count.
Right. And he does. He counts to comic effects, and he is horrified to count up to eight children.
And we close out this page and this... Whatever you would call this gag with him saying he's gonna head back to the banking business. I love it. I and I'll tell you, this is this entire page. There are no ducks in it at all. I mean, this is all all parents.
And it got me thinking about the history of parents in the comics and in the movies, you know, you've got
Jose Carrie or Joe Ka, who is
I think our south American listeners make a point of calling him,
Cardio and. Okay. That you're not getting it wrong. It's just it's just funny. He such a popular character.
This this pair does, like, kinda look a little bit like him, I think. I think so. And if you go back to finds thyroid Gold, you had yellow beak, the pair and and I think there's this repeated gag of the bird and that we didn't talk about it earlier, but we see now the the the three cabal and and Ka. We see yellow a little bit, but we see this inherit creating their own characters and their own
personalities and
breaks away from the du story and has a little parent story, but You're right, there the counting of the of the the silhouette of those whose children marching on the branch is hilarious. And then so he flies off and then the all way donald in the Nephews who still way down below in the forest have no no chance of finding them, they think so. But Donald comes up with the idea that maybe they ought to start counting out loud and maybe that they'll attract him that way. And sure enough, as Donald starts counting. Poly looks down and senses where it is and
tears down in a in a hurry and lies under Donald shirt
I love the angry, the single mother. So he Donald now knows that Polly is gonna behave from now on. Takes us to the last panel. We have a lot of
story wrap up here that the they didn't know that the adventure would take them all the way around the world, but here they are back again. Sc is extremely happy to see them all very proud of even and Poly for the first time in the story looks happy.
Besides the Love bird sequence,
he looks really happy. And now sc announces it's time to open safe with that combination. Yeah. And and this is a really interesting moment. Right, Warren because, you know, we the reader have known for a while what's about to happen the Yeah. Characters have no idea. It was a nice resolution The way I think Barks resolved the lost parrot and that first problem. Right? And anytime you have a problem get wrapped up that title, you can kind of sense that the next that there's still another big problem. Well, we know there's going to be interesting. We we just don't know how it's gonna resolve itself here. So the reveal is is very predictable, but it's satisfying.
Poly cooperate
completely when sc asks him
to
reveal the combination. Any any spits it out very proudly,
and
sc is pondering, you know, if I only his memory. I wonder if there's a little bit of the kind of the the germ germ termination of his premise for back to the quan. Coming out of this story. Right? Could be? It's a good point. But, you know, we get the reveal that yes, in fact, the safe is empty, it's been robbed and and sc is pretty quick to realize what must have happened. It's it's a little path but we don't we need for the sake of the story. We need him to to know what's happened. So that he's gonna chase the ducks and the pair out and anger.
And we're gonna transition
to the Nephews
despair and they they do the thing that always
gets us to the next
part of the story. They wonder out loud. U. Right? The the
sc wondered out loud what his combination was the the Pro beagle boys wondered out loud what it is. And now they've wondered out loud, where would Burglar take ten truckload of money. And Polly,
I guess, is this the only time that he says anything, but a digit
says twenty four twenty four twenty work. But yeah. I think it is. I think it is instead of just twenty four twenty four twenty four. Now, it would give them nothing, but the twenty fourth with these smart nephew gives them what looks like Al address. You know, I I I agree with you on this page that you just summarize that Scrooge just pretty quick to find out. But remember, we're coming to the end of a twenty two page story. And I think this is a classic... What happened we've seen before in Embark stories where. Oh, I better pick it up here because I've only got two pages
yeah. And what we'll come to the end of this page, and I'll summarize here, but
they quickly realize that it sounds like a street address and they all go off looking for that address, which it takes us to this abandoned feed company and as they look through the knot hole in the side, they see these two weary
burglar
sitting on the floor down to their last coin of splitting the ten truckload,
the ninety
tons of money
which they got back here.
And I'd love it. I'll just quote one of them as they get weary here. You get ninety billion oc trillion dollars and I get well, likewise. And I and I wanted to comment on their other accent too they got the Oak they got the hug you get. And so there's that I don't know Burglar.
Yeah. That's street tough. Three tough talk that you getting out in New York
or whatever. I I don't know. But it's it's fun because they're they're really playing that up. And then they're of course all in pain Let's flip to see who goes by
lin. So as they flip the coins, the only resolution to this in tire sequence happens very quickly as you can tell there's a policeman who puts the cuffs on them and you just see one of the burglar kinda stare over his shoulder. I thought that was really interesting because we go right to the next page and we don't see them anymore. We don't we know what happened. What are your thoughts about how he wrapped up that sequence? Mark? I mean, I think it's
an example of the strongest part of this story worn is is the timing it. Right? It it may be a little rushed, but everything
to me in this page is or in this whole story is an exercise in ending the page with like a a gag beat. That is
incredibly well timed. This this is almost just a bunch of his one pager
strung together into a story. Yeah. And think gets back to my my comment earlier about these strong sequences that it could be one gig stories. You're right, and they do link together beautifully. And and I'm glad you read that quote, because that that was very very funny to knew what he said, just you get this fantastic sum of money and I get well, likewise. My likewise.
Yeah. So I like it. I like that wrap up. I like the unseen policeman
slamming they.
I wouldn't have thought of that. Be honest with you. I thought that was brilliant. What he did because Huey, wrapped it up so efficiently.
Which takes you to the last page. Yeah. And and we got one final great cap of a gag on the last page.
As he is finally able to access his safe again, and and he's learned his lessons Scrooge has. He doesn't want pair anywhere near as he changes the combination. And
he un,
you know, this is still somewhat pro.
Right? He's gonna reward them with a fine dinner. So they go to a hamburger the joint. And when when the bill arrives, he realizes he doesn't have any money, because he he never has money on him apparently. Not even a dime for Barks bird crackers earlier. All his money is back in the safe. And so we get the classic bit where they have to resolve their bill by washing dishes.
And and the bird is just happily counting away
as the docs
dishwasher. Perfect ending, perfect ending with the happy poly perched on top.
Smiling for the one of the first times. Yeah. So so this is a pretty fun one. Right? Warren. This is this is a very gag heavy
story. What what are your thoughts overall about this story? Yeah. I I... What I what I appreciated about it, were the gag
then again, it got me thinking about my destination with Duck right away. Where it is what it looks like. It took us to a far off land, which I liked even though seemed a little rushed again. But, yeah, i i I think the the the gag sequences that were were beautifully done, you made the up observation wonderfully that these could have each been a page gag at the end of a comic, but he he strung them together with the counting parent as a theme. I really did like
the introduction of what would soon become the big Boys kind of a precursor
with these two bundling burglar and the idea that the money bin would come out of this as well. So yeah, there were a few memorable panels for me, which we talked about and
classic uncle sc, and again, classic dongle nephews. I just thought it was a fun story, not not one of my top at all. But but a fun story. Yeah. I agree. I think this is a... This story is a nice little diversion. Right? It is
a lot of fun. It's a very funny it has the trapping of one of the adventure stories and that there is a quest,
but
much more than a lot of his even as funniest as stories. This one is much more concerned with being funny with selling a gag when well. I do like the
motif that counting parent motif. Yeah that ties it all together. As far as a high concept goes, it's a neat one. So that that really works for me. You know, it stands out because it does have the pro beagle boys. That's one of his it's one of his first Latin American stories that's not in the Andes.
Yeah. Yeah. It it also gives us another look at
his fascination with with, but like I said, with Slaps to humor and what was going on at the time and popular culture
at the end of the forties and the early fifties was you had
your Abe and Case costello movies and you had your slaps to comedy, you had Tv coming into its own with Sid caesar and and great comedy. And So you you had a lot of things happening
that America is being fascinated with, and and he just he just capitalized on that. And again, we know that Carl Marx wrote these and the children read them, but here we are a couple of grown men, reading these and laughing out loud at these gag. Just I'll say it again. He's a brilliant storyteller.
Knows where knows timing so well and and was was drawing and writing these at at a turbulent time him his life, and I I give him a lot of credit for staying with his art and and the output is just Al incredible. Yeah. Yeah. You kept up a great a great pace. You know, if you look at the stories that this one came out
nearby. Mh. This came out right after
ancient Persia Mh, which I think most fans would probably pick as one of his all time greats. Yep. I would agree.
The next story that he spent on release is gonna be vacation time. Yeah. That's one of my favorite as well to be out with you. Oh, yeah. That's that's a great classic. This one's really sandwiched by a lot of classic. So if you're looking if you're looking at the stories chronological,
it's gonna suffer a little bit from that. Yeah. But but it I think it's very successful in doing what it sets out.
I think it's a comic. It's a comic breather, you know, if you wanna use that term. It's a it's a it's a change of pace while he's getting ready for his next adventure. And and he just uses humor so well here. Boy. It looks like he had a blast doing. Yeah. Yeah. It's a lot of fun. And and I think that's where the general community is two. Mh. If you look at this one on index, it's got a a very, like, capable rating. It's got a seven point seven.
Okay. And that's good for a hundred and thirty eight. It's not bad actually. Yeah. No, it's not. It's... I would say that this one is probably
very average to good Barks, but that just that place is you in in very high company. Right? Yeah. Yes. I as I read this time too, you know, I I do like to talk warren if there is anything
in a story.
Some of these stories are gonna get adapted
later on into, like, episodes of Ducktales.
And
for the most part, we don't get to talk about that because
more of those are naturally gonna be on sp stories. Right? That's that's true. Yes. But but I was I did notice that that
hide out that feed building hideout out that the burglar were in, at least the little peak of it. It looks a lot like the the visual of the beagle Boys hideout out in the original Ducktales
cartoon.
So that gets stood out. And, Don't have to... I'll maybe I'll post an image of that on the Facebook page and people can decide. It's not like a dead ringer for it any. No I'm looking forward to how you post that because I think that would be good too good to look at. I I'd never really did follow Ducktales my son did a lot and that they're that disney afternoon,
I was working like, crazy. So I didn't get a chance, but but I could go back and enjoy those you. It was a fun series. I think even even back then, I I loved the series because I was, you know, right in the prime, I I would have been about nine or ten when it came out. But even then the the comics were my true love. So... It's notable too in this one that we're still in that mode where Sc is not joining them. A a good point. Yeah. He did not go on the strip again. He sends them off. You. Right? Even even when they're chasing after the carrot, even at the beginning, he doesn't even join for that. I think I think Barr is still is still thinking Scrooge just has just an old man. Old man we'd like to stay at home and count his money. And he's gonna his money at home and that's a really good observation. Of course, we all know what happens later. Yeah. It's not too far now. Not too far coming up. So for for some reflections, you know, I I think this one definitely feels a little bit dated. We've got some
some stuff that definitely feels like an artifact of another time. Fortunately, it's not one of those stories where I feel there's anything that's too problematic
other than the. Like I said, those jokes didn't really rub me the right way, But but I don't reg people for appreciating them because they they are very well times. I think that's what that... The story did for me too and we'll recap Al little. I think it's the... It's the gag that string them together and the comedic timing in each of the gag. Whether they fell shore or hit get home.
He just does that so well. No. No lift raf, no oils,
as far as I'm aware of on this. Nothing from this one, but as you talked about the next one vacation time, there's the wonderful
oil and lit graph from that one, which I am very fortunate to own. Oh this. That's great. Yeah. It's wonderful. I love it. I I did note looking it up that there was a story published in Denmark that... I don't think it was a sequel, but it did use Poly again. Mh. Okay. So haven't read it, but it's it's neat to note when there are people who use elements of these in follow ups. Any are there any favorite panels that we
didn't get to already cover warren? You know, we we talked a lot about some of just the nonverbal panels when the nephews land and the cold shoe in the ship, but I love that one. I I think I think my favorite panel in the story I have two,
and I get i'll go back to the beginning of the story with Scrooge sc and his money bin. It's gotta be the one of the earliest
in his vault, I should say, because it my really doesn't exist. I just love the detail of that shot and I love the way he's counting. It just... It's classic
sc obsessed. And
I love that.
You talked about the Canon and welcoming them to the... That's just to me brilliant. And and the... But I will call mini splash panels of those
lower panels that take up to two normal panels. Just the the the grand and the detail of the geography.
But nothing other than that, How about you? What was a memorable panel for you? I know you like the potato page.
Too.
I I agree with you about this ones inside the sc office building.
But I also think it's interesting that you could almost
predictably
point to the very last panel. On each page as being, like, the stand of that page. Right? It's to the gig. Yeah. Exactly. If you flip through this one
pay special attention to the very last page in the panel. They all either have a ga beat or some kind of hard hit any It it almost makes this one feel like one of the classic
newspaper
serial comics that's been collected Yes, which I by the way as a twelve year old Minneapolis tribune, I cut them out and made my own scrapbook Barks of every every
comic series, and it wasn't just Donald duck yet was Dick Tracy. It was everything crap. And I I cut them up because the last panel, I had to wait until the next Sunday comics to get the continuation of the serial Oh, man, you just jog a memory of my.
Wonderful. But you write that last panel of almost every page and I'm going through it there are few exceptions It's the payoff panel. It's the... It's the great panel and
Again, back to your favorite page, it's probably my another favorite panel. It's the the temple
pass now in the potatoes. And I just love it. Yeah. That that one is a riot. That that is definitely
something that this one is very strong and is the gag payoff. So I would encourage warren... Oh, do you do you have any thoughts before closing this one out? No. I'm good. I I think I shared my thoughts. And and again, it's a it's a great comedic story in with lots of gag and great character definition too. You you just see you see the joy and the anger of sc almost more than any other story in this one from from the kicking donald out to hugging the parrot and American Hardly take out of joy. So those are... Those are some of the memories for me. Awesome I'm glad we could revisit this. I would encourage people as they are if they if they choose to reread this to really pay special attention to those closer panels. On each page and and think of it as that sort of vin yet.
Alright. Well, well, thanks again Warren. As always, listeners
can
reach out to us at bar remarks at g dot com.
I get a lot more I get a lot more engagement on the Facebook page, which is totally fine. I like the give and take. You can find us Al on the Facebook page as well. And
join us next time when we will get cover one of those all time greats that weren't alluded to vacation time. Yeah. Thank you, Barks. Enjoy it very much. Absolutely.
Take care. We'll see you on another adventure.