Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of sc Mc and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge cl of all time, join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context, and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks. Welcome again to Barks from our I'm Mark Sever, a grown man who enjoys duck comics,
especially those done by the legendary Carl Barks. We are back with a really
exciting story to talk about. We're gonna be talking about
vacation time
before we get into it. I have a returning a returning guest host. Can you introduce yourself and let us know about your experience with camping vacations.
Hi Eric hartman. I have been on many camping vacations. One of the cases where they kept have discounts we're two times with my family.
And none of them where it adventurous interest as you would find in comic. Yeah. Awesome. So i Eric, I am gonna lay my cards out right away. I think this is just just a wonderful story. I think this is one of our all time best. And so I'm I'm very excited to talk about this one. This is this is one of the issues
that you know, when I thought about doing this podcast, I was like, oh, it's gonna be it's gonna be neat to talk about stories like back to the k and land beneath the ground and and vacation time was one of those that came to mind and that's kind of unusual because this is in some ways, it's like a much more id.
It's a less adventurous story at least up until the end. Well, certainly less fantastical
than Barks the quan and may so many other stores for codes. And there's new worlds or strange pictures or mad captain pinterest which put adventures. That kind of a thing. It's certainly less of that than how else said Brad? Yeah. It's true. This one is it's kind of a more, like I don't know if intimate is the right word, but it's definitely
unique among his adventure length stories. There there's a lot of special things about this one. So again, thank you for
returning,
talking about this. I know that you've done a lot of camping in the same kind of area that I have. Right? And when I when I read this story, I can't help, but think of my own vacation and camping experiences,
which were mostly in California.
Right. And I feel like this tracks pretty well. You know? This one definitely has like, a northwest feel to me. I think that's deliberate because Barks grew up or spent a lot of his time in California,
Southern California when he worked for Disney studio, And
before that, he he spent a lot of time in oregon.
Yeah. It has a lot of up and the mountains kind of things Here nevada is for, you know, there's not a lot of people, you know, there's still rivers of trout that are flowing and animals still coming around. But they're not i'll run off by development. Yeah. It's it's a very like
classic.
Almost
mythical
American
feel to it. Right? Yeah. It's got that sort of, like, un
un unnamed Wilderness,
which
you know, if you know anything
about American wild lands,
none of them are really long wild. They've been shaped by humans so much over the over the the centuries and millennia, but it still has that sort of, like, almost prime forest feel for for parts of this one at least. Yes. But, of course, it is in a very obviously a very managed state park and And part of the neat thing about this is like that respect for the respect for managed wilderness that I think that I think it's showing. You know, That's... Absolutely.
So this issue has a great appreciation, not just for
the nature in the habitat
but also for those who service with the rangers and the fire service that are out there in respect the them they're not, they don't come off Al,
or villains. It's it's it's a really
neat to see that because they're an authority figure that's respected, which again is not all that common in comics, you know, either the the foil or they get in the way. Yeah. And and in this they're like, I mean, we'll talk about it, but they're almost like comic noble
or for you can did bit of run time. Yeah. It's it's pretty neat. Alright. So
a little bit of the background of this story.
Again, we're talking about vacation time. This comic,
this is not one of the ones that was originally
published in the American
one shot series that's called four color. This was its own special ish you in an issue called vacation
parade. It's it's like a limited title. That was published occasionally.
Some Barks Christmas stories were done in Christmas parade. So you know, every few years, Western publishing would put out a special limited run like this. And so they ran all vacation themed stories. It came out in June of nineteenth, fifth team. So we're right at the... Right at the beginning of the fifties.
We're in that, you know, post war era. This this definitely has that feel right people are more focused on fun and leisure. This this one really stands out for one
special reason, Eric. This happens to be his longest
story that he ever published.
Yeah. As long as Ducktales comic, at least. It is or one page longer. Than any of his others. Most of them maxed out at thirty two pages. For whatever reason,
they gave him that extra page, which I I have to assume is that, like, title that gorgeous
initial
splash panel that that we we'll get to open with. But Yeah. It says only thirty three pager.
And that's not weird. Yeah. I know. I I think that it might limit how often this one could be reprinted though because it has
surprisingly
few
reprint. I I saw six listed for American edition. Yeah. So this this is
about Donald and the kids
enjoying a nice camping vacation.
There's obviously a lot more to it. Thinking about some background trivia. You know, I already mentioned that it is his longest It's one of a a very small number that has one of those full page
splash panels. Mh. We got to talk about another one, which is a story letter to Santa.
I got to do that with Sue my wife and that has a really cool full page spread and I believe there's at least one more that it's escaping you right now. So that's okay. No fact checking.
But what I think is kinda unique about this is it's one of the, like, very small handful of times that Donald really gets to be truly her. This is true. I mean, in in in most of the Barks stories, you know, he's he's interested in keeping him down on his luck or or as kind of Al every man character, so he wants them to be pretty relatable. And he never acts like super heroic in this one. It's really just about kind of keeping as cool and
and being a rule follower. Yeah. Usually one he wants to go to what he wants to do, or he is a foil for the boys
for the nephews and giving them trouble putting
excessive rules on them to make them miserable. And they have to kinda against him and that's interesting it's not quite that way in this one. Maybe do come to ahead a little bit, but it's nothing quite like they're and during in an and
situation with each other. Exactly. The docs are very cooperative for this whole story. But but it never feels like even though it he is more heroic and noble than normal. To me, it never feels like it stray too much from his care you know, Barks make sure to have him tu
with the the the bad camper that we'll talk about, you know, he kinda... He kinda bring some down a peg of a few times. So I I think that's pretty effective. I've got a quote from Barks
about the background of creating this one. He was interviewed and said, I couldn't create suspense without having them in real danger. And real danger means the fear of death So all of the times these ducks got in bad situations, they didn't have that opportunity of dying in case they got collaborate hit it made it more true to life to have them up against these impossible
situations in which they could lose their lives if they didn't win. And in the forest find sequence. You bet they were in danger. It made the story memorable. That is definitely true. That was a
very different because it's normally than harold from a villain or some kind of crazy
circumstance. But this is very pretty
a forest fires Al legit thing and
how he describes and how it goes on to it which... I mean, thinking about it nowadays right now in Americas
there's plenty of four fires we just had a big one and going on Colorado, where there there various serious things and they you have to know what to do in those situations.
What thing making it so real.
Certainly did surprise me regarding issue. It it is kinda of surprising. Right? The first time you read it, it it's very striking because a forest fire does feel like such a realistic and and men
threat. So I have to ask no in in in respect to timing, where is this in regards to Bam being
broadcast because I think it's an interesting in touch position between nature and fires and ducks and fires that kind of the thing. Yeah. I'm I'm glad you brought that up. Right? Because it's some possible. I think not to think about bam as you read this one. Right? Because mh there's a deer that plays like such a memorable role in this way it ends with a forest fire. And I I have to assume that, you know, Barks had bam be in mind. Mb was like, huge in American culture. It came out in forty two, and and that was one of Disney's very earliest
animated films. I think it might have been like their worth or fifth or something something like that. It was very early on, and it did leave this like big
footprint. I'm sure you remember vividly
damn. So many times, I mean, once does a kid being chuck by and traumatized them my sisters and my younger siblings watching just seeing all the time. I I know the story by part. And yeah now i'm thinking about it reflecting on. And that story still holds up. Absolutely.
Bam is great. And I don't mean to suddenly veer and talk too much about bam, but but it's super appropriate, right? Because absolutely.
It's it's the same story in in a certain sense, but for the Ducktales happen to be there. You know, that dear almost
have been the King of the forest or a assumption. That this could could have been like bam from another point of view because it has the same sense of we get treated to this really beautiful
depiction of a forest. Just lovingly
lovingly leo I'm I'm gonna say that this story features some of Mark's greatest Barks
in his career. Yeah. It's beautiful. That's the the scene is is fantastic. Yeah. And and Bam likewise is just it's a slight story, but it it's just so lovingly
animated. So So yeah, that's a great thing to mention. I don't know if Bam would have had a a re release recently, but, you know, how those those stories, those... Those films had like that long shelf life when they Mh first created. I think Bam was really a current matter when when this story came out.
So before we talk about the the structure sure the of the story itself You know, Eric that I I like to pan to the international audience by talking about some of those titles from around the world.
Let's follow means and pen. Let's do. So why don't you start us off? I give you a couple of couple of s country you're gonna go with Sweden or Spain first.
I'm gonna do spain because that's what I can do, and I wanna end on a low note because that's what's entertaining. Yeah.
Spain is most bum
For going on vacation. Yep. So pretty straight, you know,
none of these are gonna be really
intriguing titles. They're all pretty close translations.
I will go with Germany. We've got family
Ducktales
far in fat.
Alright? I only read that
fully, as I as I read it out loud here. So I know I had at least one other title where the translation included that that word fast. Or that particle fight. So so... Yeah,
that translates to the Ducktales family on a holiday trip. Alright. Or it's Sweden
labor larger leaf, living cabin life if my any bikes ikea helped that pronunciation, they have go, but there. Yeah. I'm not I'm not sure how the how the a with the oo lau or the d
goes. But for all I know you did great
And let's see. I think
I will end with
Netherlands. We've got matt.
Which is on holiday or probably vacation, You know, these will translate is in inconsistent. Now Barks before we give this this tell done andrew never question. Yes great as this story is do you feel the title is misleading because he has so many other great back to the declined and these other, you know, so many great titles for stories, vacation time, I... That's just so bland. Yeah. It's pretty pedestrian. Right? It's... Yeah. I'm doing like... Oh, It's vacation time. I it to now to me growing a vacation time usually, it's going to a beach or getting, you know, going out town, but I've never... I mean, yes, I got camping, but to me camping was, like, radio camping, but it's on this vacation because camping is a lot of work. To me vacation is relaxing taking easy. Going for California that was me going to the beach. So the fact that vacation time doesn't even mention camping or wildlife or what they're doing is just kinda surprising to me. Yeah. I mean, I think that's a great point. Right? I I think you nailed it. Amp, I don't slot in as a vacation. It's it is something you do for fun, but it's it's a different it's a totally different animal because Sure. You're you're waking up at dawn, you're doing all your cooking and you're cleaning and maybe burying on unspeakable things
in in the woods. So, yeah. But I guess, I guess you and I wouldn't have been as like,
surprised going into the story. And and I'm remembering the first time I read it when I was probably like nine or ten years old. Really being shocked that it ends the way it does. Mh.
Yeah. You know, if it was called Donald and the forest fire, you know, maybe maybe it wouldn't hit as hard. I'm gonna guess. I don't know this for sure, but I'm gonna guess that the title was picked by the editor
specifically for that, like, vacation
parade issue. I guess that makes sense. I would've have gone to, like, camping adventure or adventure the mountains or some kind of, like, yeah. I mean, the buck is such a a focus of this one. I I would... That's probably what I would think of. I try to consider Eric what titles I would have picked. For some of the ten page ones, because Barks almost never got to title those. And so they've been retroactively titled
by fans. Okay. Or or by, you know, the the publishers, that kind of agreed on like, a set mh. And there's actually a ten page story that is literally called vacation time. So so, yeah, i I I think the title is pretty mil toast, you know, it... Oh that's that's how everyone knows this story. And and this one is this is a very famous one. Eric you No. Absolutely.
You can look at on the other hand though is that simple title lures you in and oh, okay. It's just gonna be simple adventure and then it's a prizes you was such a great story. And such fantastic art that, you know, know it kind of does the bait switch a little bit. So that might be another to be one call. This
surprise Was expecting this. Yeah. For sure. So let's see. I don't have too much to talk about, you know, for background and historical context of this one, But I I do think it's worth noting that we're so lucky in the states.
One of the
rapidly diminishing great things about living in this country is the the national Park system. Right? And I i people like this. I feel like Barks really wants to editorial.
Here. Mh. Or the importance of wilderness
preservation.
He's taking he's editorial
in this more than he does in most stories.
Yes. Yes Yes. I looked up. We can talk about this when we get to it. But I I I'd spent just a little bit of time researching
how to survive a forest fire. Nice in this one. And
there's there's not a... You probably won't be surprised that there's not a lot of super consistent advice but it did come up a few times to say that like a firefighter
as a last resort that's battling
ablaze will put up a heat reflecting shelter. Mh. They
small hole in the dirt to breathe through. Yes. Being from Arizona, there's a history. I don't know through my story of the brennan mountain Hotshot. Oh, I do. That was devastating. It it really was. And then like I said, there's the forest fire strike going Al lot of people in the American West. But I mean, reading that, maybe think of them. The the how the fire... How the fires we thought by the rangers and the firefighters was
surprisingly accurate with going in and, you know, building other fires to fight that file which is an actual common incentive actual actually of doing it. I thought that was a very good way of portraying that these, you know, the how of professionalism
and how serious they take these things. Yeah. Yeah. You're totally right. It's it's kind of leading. Right? But but in in the few panels where he addresses it. He he does it in a way that you can tell. He's learned about it thought about it. Alright. So we got a lot of great stuff to talk about in this one. Let's let's let's hop into it if you're ready. Go. Alright. So so vacation time, Eric
as I mentioned,
it opens with a a full page splash panel that is super legendary.
It's it's fantastic stick, it's not really that connected to the entire story
but you could tell that Barks probably was just tickle pink to draw this. Do you mind to Scrooge, and you don't have to go into gruesome some detail, but but telling us about this amazing opening panel. Oh, absolutely.
Absolutely.
Got the
Donald classic card, which is overloaded with gear going on a... It looks like it rather precarious mountain the road done was briefly excited by on camping. The boys are freaked out of their mind, because it looks like they're all that bounce out. Behind them is running a bear chasing them and there's is a river flowing beneath it, looks like they could phone to that. And then on the left side, Above it above them, it looks like there is a there's Al panther and tree branch weighed to pounds.
Which I will note in the American West that should be a mountain Lion not a Panther
due the color characterization of the. Yeah. And it's a color a choice. I'm sure I'm sure there's been times that that big cat was shown as a Mountain Lion. That's a whirlpool beneath them too. It's it... Oh, my gosh that is. I even notice that It's just such a great contrast between the oblivious Donald and the terrified boys and
you know, it it's gonna set us up for a couple of pages of him, just stalling the virtue of the simple country life and and being oblivious to the the dangers
passing them by that the Nephews are gonna be stressed about. It's...
Yeah. That's true camping is not just fun games. There's actual parallel involved, pushing doing up some of.
You have to know what you're doing. I I've been on a few of those. Roads. It it amaze me too that this was the opening page. This was not the cover. The cover art for vacation and parade was a pretty, like, a bland
cover by Think
Carl b or or someone. But later on, this will be used this image will be used as a cover and spoiler. This is gonna be a a pretty rad Barks oil painting as well. I i can imagine
So on the next page again, we get more of these contrasts, you know, they're like, narrowly passing
locomotive at a train crossing.
They're getting edged off the road by a big hay wag and there's all sorts of wild animals waiting to pounce
Donald changes the flat tire. And and and he's just blissful ignorant the whole time while the nephews are, like, covering their eyes and dressing out. And and every panel here is just so great to look at for me. Yeah. I don't know if any of these really stand out to you.
I I love the... One the know, the one again, I love Barks use of shadows and allow you to see shapes and focus on the whole picture not just in my details. The train one particularly stands up to me and now contrasting and some of the other brighter colors
enough. Sorry. They're they're close enough to actually be in the shadow of the truck. Yeah. There Barks some really great angles he's he gets pretty experimental
throughout this whole issue with some of the very irregular
shaped panels. In a way that the
never gets to do again. And just so the perspective through this story is pretty special. Yeah. And i I just love how he takes the time to Scrooge. Up man. I never have to do this and like, you know, by the deal at this pub in the city, while he's dealing within the woods in the mountains, but it's completely believe touching not in the city. It's a fun position and just...
Yeah. Oh, and and I will mention that that is
in in the panel where he's changing a tire. He says, imagine me fixing a flat at the corner of Wi s and Vermont, I'd be taking my life in my hands. That is a real intercept and I think in near Hollywood. And, of course, he doesn't see all of the wildlife life that's about pounce on him. So on the next page, the ducks come to a fork in the road on their way. And they can't tell the right way to go because hunters have shot the sign up. So Donald picks out and he he blessed her a bit about having
senses like a homing pigeon. And
we know that this is gonna be like a moment where he gets deflate because the road just peter's out more and more and it goes to such a great extreme, Eric. Where
do do you mind mentioning that the funny extremes that they take that Barks takes it to with the road. But it goes down and it eventually it comes the right. And then the road just flat disappears And like, this was even a road? I don't even know anymore. Huey, using magnifying Barks try to find the road. Right. I like that using a magnifying glass and we've got these random hill.
That say.
I ordered and I couldn't throw what they're saying they're okay So if if you're not if English is not your first language in the in the American whatever revenue
is is a a comic way of saying the tax collector. Yeah. Okay. In Hill speak. One of them understand But that's what turned me off. Right? The Hill
cracks me up. It's certainly not not that kind, but it is funny. Ride an automobile
fast one i have a seed. They do eventually realize that Donald has gotten them on the road back to Duck and they get a good crack in about. You really are a home pigeon. It's kind of a lot of pro log. You know. We got these three full pages before where they get even into their their campground.
But on the fourth page, they arrive into
these beautiful backwards. Donald is is just Scrooge it for the Nap,
really just installing the virtue of this old forest.
It looks very... It looks very northwest to me Eric. Right? These look like redwood or Sequoia or or similar. Probably. Yeah. And I'm glad imagine it's he spent time in Minnesota as well. There's gotta be kind of an ama of of the Midwest and the Pacific Northwest here. But Donald takes a turn into the Ranger station.
And
one of the Nephews asked why are you turning in here i'm donald? Do you mind reading his response? It says there can't be instructions set a fire commit. We want the scene to still be here when we leave. And and this is like, it's almost like, I wanna say heavy handed, but it's not. It's delivered very natural really, but this could have been like a smoky, the bear, you know, public awareness campaign. It's it's just delivered in such a great way that makes you wanna feel virtuous.
Absolutely. It's like you know, i got. This makes me think of back in the day, I had to do report on pop Cassidy, and I had to watch a lot of this stuff and he was... He made himself such an idea and one that teach kids he's such a a an icon a roll of his tim that he would always try to do his shows and have that respectful teach the kids to be respectful. And, you know, respect respect these authority figures and be nice your teachers be extra parents, but not doing in a heavy handed way just trying to teach them and learn. That's what it's strikes me as because they know have to take care of it, and we're visitor here. Yeah. I I think you're right. The the through line that runs through this comic is a respect for nature and respect for authority. Not that like problematic,
un thinking un
or expect for authority, that's not that's not the kind of fan. But as you say, the rangers
are are the experts
In this case, these rangers are really supposed to represent
a thoughtful
stewardship ship of the four and the the ranger here, you know, he's inspecting. You can tell that Donald is eager to show off. How
he is. The the ranger runs through the checklist of of the things that indicate that
that the Ducktales have come prepared and
you know, he gladly gives them the rule book and tells and I assume the fire permit.
We even have the little Woodland creatures kind of approaching the Ducktales. You know, I think it's kind of symbol the forest, like, welcoming them because there they're planning to do it the right way. Absolutely.
To forget Al camp, make sure you know what you're doing because the preparation
really helps make a better experience, making sure you have Al things are feeling camping. You always have to take extra time. Can't just still up in car go, you need to make sure you have their got a good plan. And you can enjoy your time out during the woods instead of worrying about what you didn't have. Going back to store i also like how it's a little bit of a set of by time about the hand of man even past cigarette, but the account pretty that shows the you know, beautiful shots in the forest. Just setting that up for later on in the story. Yeah. That... That's an excellent point. There's some great setup. There's some great fore.
He's really letting us fall in love with the forest. Right? Because it's been... It's gonna hit that much harder when it's in peril. Mh. So he's establishing the rules for a good camp site. And you wouldn't think that's gonna play pro later on just jones showing off, but I think to see how he transitions that uses that it's contrast to the campsite they find later iran. Because that would the reader nose. Hey. This is good Camp. We've earned the rules of a good camp side earlier on what it's not. Yeah. That's true. He he sets it up. You're right. On the next page, the ducks are gonna find their campsite, and it's it's a really great page because it's it's almost an instructional
on how to do as you said an ideal campsite.
But we've got this really funny ass back where Donald is bus directing the nephews where to pitch the tent where to set up the table, how to build a careful thoughtful fire
and it's it's funny. Right? Because Donald not... The nephews are doing all the work. But you know, yep
he is actually showing some good leadership in this one. Yeah. And we get a nice comic sting. I... I'm sure this has happened to you. Right? He likes the fire after bragging about checking on everything.
And immediately, the the smoke bill right into his face. That is the worst thing when you got everything said you relax also some the smoke to the complex you. Are you
people that is magnetic for for smoke, whatever side of the fire you you decide to step onto to. Certainly feel that way. Yeah. It does. Alright. The the next morning, and on the next page, we get the classic gag of the
contrast between the experienced camper and the new campers
where
Alright. Are you the guy Eric who wakes up at or before the crack of Dawn Ready and ra to go?
Not when I'm camping. I mean, I do, but not because I wanna be up. For some reason, camping, it's really hard to sleep and maybe it's the weather maybe the sun hits the ten. It's but i I've always looked up early camping. Yeah. I've always hated it because I'm tired. But then you get up and you see the wilderness that is in the fresh morning, and it's just amazing.
Right. And it it's why there. And, you know, we know in the majority of these stories. This is the reverse, the ne user their junior wood chops. They love this camping life, Donald the little little bun ahead who who isn't really good at this. But this is the story that Barks wants tell, you know, he he has the nephew start the breakfast fire while he's off to catch some trout. And right away, while fishing he gets us strike and
he gets pulled through the river onto the land and we encounter this bot this this deer that
collide with him, and Donald instant reaction is to think about how lucrative it could be if he captured a really majestic photo. And and this just... This is so neat and it's it's a it's very quaint. Because I don't think there's quite the market for this kind of photo these days and there probably wasn't back then, but but for the purposes of the story, it makes sense. Yeah. What also established the fact they got camera. And has the fun little adventure in the middle of everything trying to keep that camera and that's comes the classic Donald story of. Want to get something done and he just keeps on getting foil by whatever circumstances it's it's kinda that classic
screw ball comedy of. I just wanna do what they be great exact. Everything in interrupted. It keeps it from happening.
Right. This deer is gonna do a great job of driving the story forward.
It's gonna become his obsession for for a lot of it. So Donald makes his way on the next page back to his camp. But but on his way, he himself gets hooked by an, you know, asked
a cast line. And
we meet the guy that I just think of as the bad camper. Sure. He pulls donald up and he he says well, a blasted
duck. We've got this kind of Brooklyn
street tough
speak from him. He says
uses the dumbest look fish I ever caught. And he tell us about the bad camper thing that he does immediately. Alright. Well, he meant like cigarette and then flip them the match into the grass, which is just not unbelievable. Mean. I can't... Yeah. Hate to see it. Oh my gosh. I didn't camping and seeing people literally or like why. Blatantly me own appear Al lip max in a way it's just oh my gosh. I wanna reach through the colleagues and through time in the screen and find him and just... Gaps. Slap the believers out of them for what he's doing. And we I think we're are conditioned to really feel Donald, you know, despair at seeing this. Because because on on the next page, Donald is chi him. He stomp it out, and the guy makes it excuses is. He says, you know, that grass won't point its wet and any he Mcdonald's face in it. So he's really rough with him Donald decides to whittle him down to to his size and we transition past what was apparently a very
unsuccessful fist fight because Donald it's is leaving looking pretty beat up with the guy on
unscathed. So this guy is more than he can really handle. We know he's bad news. Yeah. So on the next page, you know, Donald
gets back to Amp,
the Nephews are disappointed that there... There's no fish. They've gotta have flap
oatmeal. He tells them the next phase of their trip now is gonna be taking pictures.
He tells them all about the really majestic buck deer. And and he wants the Nephews to drive the deer
so that it'll give a really majestic pose.
So they they split up so that they can do it and tell us about the Nephews encounter. Well they go looking for it here which and then they come across a little baby deer who was heavily in a tall grass trying to hide head them up and they kinda of it say, hey, we can see you. It's okay. This very, very cute. Right? And yeah. And we transition on the next page. Donald is wondering
where the kids are and tell us about that this encounter. Well he's like, well yeah what's going on. They should done the already and make you let we come up like, hey, we had a whole block of beer. They were really it all of the the little wildlife like talk little buddies and Al these little baby deer in lots of dough. The Female beers the no plaques. And so very said by this they're no take a picture with these babies you know, they name them Sam boat prince Oscar, which are just fantastic names. Yeah. And so dogs... File do that takes a whole bunch of pictures, and now just gotta go place the whole role so, you know, back in the day. You to have enough sale for everything.
And you're back to camp to reload the camera. What Al blast from in the past. I I definitely remember film. Oh, yes. So so this is a great setup. Right? We know what's about to happen on the next page. He's he's has gone through the whole role taking these cute photos.
What is the encounter when he gets back to camp And well there, of course, it's the bug, just reading all the food became site. And just sounds like, no. I don't have any.
So here's where we get our little
comedic child of abuse gag. Right? This was your total total convention back in the fifties and and even later, you know, the adult holding the switch threatening, we rarely see anyone actually getting w, but but the threat hovered, you know, he's holding up a switch telling the kids, you know, you better flush out that buck, but on the way as he chasing them through the forest. We encounter the bad camper again. We encounter him slumped over at his campsite.
And Eric, why don't you tell us about the situation on the next page? Oh, it was it find him something
not taking fire they obviously going on. And Was like, hey, this isn't safe. Yeah. Like we leave me alone. It's like listen. You've got this fire built right. But when comes up, it's gonna blow. And again, like, I'm gonna up the water and grows down. Like, I'll pull the water like this and they start to light another the cigarette because apparently when you have the wood, you just got smoke. And then they've boys noticed, like, you doing have a book at of water he's and he's got no safety precautions. Yeah. We we the reader hate this guy. Like the desk. He he bad news. He calls... He calls Donald these these nickname names like granny Boy nature boy,
He's the worst kind of city slick. And and I see that as a city slip, you know. Yeah. Alright. So
we transition then after that unfortunate encounter, you know, the Ducktales are still looking for the buck. They they see him in the distance. So Donald instruct the nephews to flush him over this rock because he wants to get a picture. And Al he's waiting for the buck to press the rock, a bear comes up behind him And we get this onto the next page. We get this
very silly set up where the Barks snatch the camera, Donald tapes right and and he and the deer
collide head to head at the top of the rock. This would have been a pretty great picture if the Barks had snapped it, but the bear The Barks snaps of an maximal picture of him self and scares himself off and Donald is is just really annoyed. This is admittedly a hard one to narrow it because it's very visual here. It's it's just a silly in inter lid. Yeah. It they became it's just one more comfortable thing they get in the way of it's taking a picture. No it's kinda rolled and film in the camera, but Camera gets swiping in the butt gets away again. Honestly, I would like see the develop picture of the Barks
self portrait because that might be anything as well. Yeah. That that one seems like it's worth more to me than the majestic Barks. So, you know, we got more setup up on the onto the next page as they they continue to track him and and the Nephews are grip about how, you know, they're just being marched all over the place. They thought they were on vacation to rest. And this is some of the most beautiful scenery as they're tracking it. Mh. It shows these, like, nice like fern and and waterfalls,
really just gorgeous art. I'm committing the Cardinal Sin Era of of podcast
tell telling you in an auditory medium.
You really gotta see it.
But I I do. I really hope that people will have recently
reread their back issue or maybe or even paging along as we go through this story. Because that...
Understandable. Absolutely but no set member. They're using the auditory podcast to talk about a visual medium and the fact that that's coming. So... Yeah. You may expect that one. Yes.
It's your fault listener
So so we get another of those great gag that came up a lot on the next page
when you're in the Wilderness.
Tracking some. What is this trope era tell us? It's the choke of writing circles of you under
confused
Al there's people on here. We gotta to go find them. Let's keep volume them else and they went. There's even more. But there's a lot of people on here, so you realize no. Those are own tracks for going on in circles
Right. Get the bright idea to turn around and they immediately encounter the butt. And again, they have another little funny moment where Donald falls into the river. The point of this page is that they're still tracking him. And on to the next page, we transitioned back to the bad camp who he's thinking about catching some fish he's thinking about the wind that picks up and we understand this to be very ominous because we see the smoke from his fire moving farther away due to the wind. And we transition back to Donald, who is very eagerly
awaiting the the nephews to flush the deer.
We don't even see the deer, but we we see donald
na where it is. And right is he's about to snap his great photo.
The the bad campers fishing line catches
his camera and pulls it right out of his his hand. And so on the next page,
these two opposition campers have an encounter again. Obviously, there's no love loss and they immediately get into a to a pretty bad fist fight it. Donald barely gets his camera back. And the moon changed Eric at this point. Right? The Nephews really wanna quit. And it seems jinx to them and they noticed the wind picking up. Donald really wants to plow on. And so they do. And
you you wanna tell us about what happens on this next page in the goalie? Well, Al they're doing wanna be noticed that the winds picked up and, you know, down was like oh it's just getting... Wind always, you know, sound scary trees, but the boys notice and even the animals are getting little scared. And tell us tell us about the following page too. Donald actually walking along following the tracks and it inadvertently Barks on the back of the buck and it's trying to stay with them in the butt just swings him around and it's a right for dear life mcdonald's trying to figure out what to do. As he's going on that right, the boys or noticing like, man, the wind is really picking up. You know, Eric? I just I just heard the wind buffet my
my room here. My third floor attic office here. Pretty often to kind of.
It was coincidence instance here. So the... This is kind of an interesting little sat piece on to the next page, you know, Donald been riding him like a bro for a while. And and he he wins. Right? The deer
gets worn out. And so Donald, like, pushes him up to the top of this rise so that he can get his great picture.
And I love this bit of payoff. Right? He's he's beating the deer down. Just he's tired him out and finally has him right where he wants him and the dear is too exhausted to do anything but kind of sit there pant,
looking the opposite of noble.
Donald got a a great censored
expression. And he wants to wait for the deer to to revive and on the next page, he finally gets that perfect pose. And as he's fumbling
to take the picture, one of the Nephews wonders what he's looking at, and Donald sees smoke from the from that So he climbs to the top of this rise and he and the deer are... It's it's striking to me the right that the deer is so focused on the fire that it doesn't run away. And the deer, they feel like they're on the same level. They feel like almost.
Yeah. Because because they're both looking this the fire that's been started, clearly by the bad camper in horror, Donald is is running in terror onto the next page. He he tells the kids that they've got they've gotta get back to the campsite to save their car so that they can get out. And they, you know, there's a little bit of acknowledgment from the Ducktales that it was the the they call them the tough guys camp that's burning. And we transitioned back to the tough guy and he his visa his his expression suddenly. Cracks when he realizes that he started the blaze. And he's terrified as he realizes his his entire camp including his car has lined up as he says burned up. And as he flee on foot, he passes the Ducktales car. And...
Boy do we hate him here? Oh, absolutely.
So so on to the next page, you know... This is a troubling panel. Right? Because the Ducktales russian one way and all the wildlife of the forest is rushing the other way because the ducks have to get to their car basically to make it out in time. When they return to their campsite, they they find that indeed the bad camp or has stolen their car. And how did you feel when you got to this part, you know, and you see the ducks like, wandering around in a in a smoky haze and then nephews
real... Once once they realized the car been stolen and saying that
it was interesting because I mean it's it's a real
immediate peril and, you know, these are the facebook of neighbors
about of like, prior burning it fire, like, you know, fire you can escape. That's that's it's legit thing. And so I mean, it's it's it's a very
scary you know, good could even make even worse.
As a parent who and responsible for for young children
dealing young children and this situation is even more scarce and I I don't wanna think about too much honestly. Oh, I know. This this is a very real striking moment. You you you know that the Ducktales are gonna be k because of the nature of the medium, but it's still
it's very affecting.
So Donald, Donald does something really unique here. He really keeps his head. He he tells them that they need to stay together that he's gonna think of something. They start pondering their options. One of the nephews suggest diving in the crate, the other says, no will be boiled like eggs.
I I understand that that is like a real danger if you're in a small enough body of water. Sure. I think I think a large source of water can keep you safe. But... I mean, yeah. I mean, if there was like, a lake to go to that middle, like, just, you know, shed water and over your okay.
Smoke and the eighth of you know.
Yeah. But a creek is not the way to go. So so the they observe on the next page that the fire is circling
around the ridges, which is, you know, Barks sets it up nicely that they are trapped. So so Donald says to grab their shovel and can't teams and they're gonna go off and search for a clear place up the road. And we transition to this not so nice fellow. This tough guy. He's
oversized driving Donald little his his good old be fire and about. And he realizes that he if he doesn't wanna get
you know, in trouble, he's gonna have to get rid of the evidence. So he he pushes Donald
car off a cliff. You hate to see it. Those of us who are big big fans of the... I think it's a nineteen thirty four be fire around about is the made up model Barks
called it. And and so Donald, we transitioned back to Donald who is
driving the kids on. And, you know, he asked Huey,,
why are you carrying that camera and and Hue tells us that there's a picture
in it that I want. To save. So this is kind of our first inkling of
of the justice that's gonna come. I guess. Yeah. Oh i because if there's also been big. No. It's type you know, several pages back, you would see the boys pick up the camera, but that it's a silent panel. They pick up the camera, you see any true Barks to make sure to include the camera is in the story the not getting lost. It's not just a crop for the one straight by chasing the deer or the buck. And but the plays Al larger role the boys are carrying around. I think it's a very good way of bringing that note and that thing through the story and not just
your later on thinking my camera. But you brought about. Like, no. There's it was in this in the panels, they'll longer me make with everybody else. Yeah. Yeah. And it was very purposeful.
And I didn't mention, you know, when Donald was
chi the guy terrible campsite. I didn't go out of my way to say oh, Donald Donald had one of the Nephews,
which which was hugh hold the camera. Because it's a very subtle moment he doesn't really call too much attention to it. Oh, we get this really unique on the next page. You wanna tell us about the the handful of panels that describe the cut off that fire rescue operation. Oh, it's it's a great set of panels. And like three of them, but they
explain, you know, the radio stations
and plural so the all buzz around at the same time have, you know, form of fire firefighters service go up to five the five they have tanker trucks, then you see the
the plane dropping the
smoke campers out to start back fires to fight the blaze.
And know, they have Al helicopter monitoring it, you know,
making observation well. There's anybody there there no way they could survive this far it's due dangerous
a good job of the reaction time of those
rangers and the fire place to get to that fire, which is really impressive normally requires will be going off a little bit long, you know, be burning well before they can get that reaction. But again, this common can against, but it's a very good portrayal how they fight those kind of Barks
wild wildfires. Right. And I am i'm sure it's best case scenario showing them their, you know, full efficiency, But it it's a neat
way of setting up the response. And we get two separate
kind of narration of the risk here. Right? You mentioned that that the helicopter ranger talks about it, how no one can escape with their lives And then also, we get the bad camper, you know, standing kind of like, tall and proud almost
observing the blaze
saying, you know, there's at least there's not any witnesses. And and then we transition to the Ducktales
and donald his finally led them to an open place and tell tell us Eric about what he instruct them to do. Well, he has the dig the trenches
wanted through the light in, the voice notice that, hey, you know, we'll let's put line down and in in a hole that he's gonna get us know like they'll. It we'll cover you up the dirt. That's kind help it. The next page it turns into, you take up your jacket soak them with that water. Put use yourself of the trenches pretty coats over your put your weapon jackets, what pulls up your face. Help protect you. Boys like no. No. You they have they you put they're like, no you sub us and say... No. So I'm gonna put this shovel bit over your overhead as for the protection, but leave air holes on the side, so that way you can still breathe this to be air, but you still be protected for anything on top of your. Right. Smoke my get, but you're gonna be okay. Yeah. So that that those curved shovel blades, that's where he's gonna leave the little
small amount of ventilation. And So I have a lot to say about this. And i I should limit myself, but, like, first off, this... Maybe this is not a great myth. To me Barks has set this up as being a very good last ditch. Right? You would only wanna do this if you had absolutely
no other options.
Right. Last it black blast adoption, no pun intended. Right. Right.
So it's not a great option, but he set it up in a way that that Al least seems logically
sound. Right? He's not I I saw online. I think it was... I'm trying to remember it was backpack dot com where I had read that, you know, what what a surrounded fire or might do. They talked about how you don't wanna just cover your face with, like a damp cloth because the water will like, sc you. Really. Yeah. But this double layer of the dirt and
and the cloth, it it seems like a good math it seems very clever.
So it felt like a it felt when I read this, like a brilliant way to escape this
impossible
situation. Sure. I mean,
it's a fire. Picked the clear area for reason. And I haven't heard it over it's not the fire is not gonna stay on top of them and burned down. It's that initial first as it goes through and then as it burns down, because the fire is moving, it's not gonna stay what's fine. And it could be the clear area with little brush So it's also not gonna sit there forever. And we're burn that place down. And then hopefully, you just got enough of ability to survive that that area that you can finish when you come back up. It's it's moved on and you're with with the aftermath. Yeah. Definitely. So the other thing, Eric that strikes me about this part is is it's in a that it feels like the ducks are ding their own graves. Right? Yes. The the image of the Nephew with his head covered lying in the trench, it's really horrific looking. It's yeah. Absolutely.
That's.
So so this is a very frightening frightening page. One of the scarier things that I think he's ever done. And it feels all the more scarier because of what a realistic
scenario it feels Mh.
Yes.
So we we close out this page with the fire racing over them.
We transitioned to the the bad camp who's kind of coming out of his hiding place. And encountering
arrange and and he poses as a survivor and he immediately
blames the ducks.
To to, you know, kinda set up his ali. And so we transition again, we're just with the the the camper who is at the range or headquarters where he's telling his phony story. And, you know, we see the ranger or chief. Looking a little bit skeptical and and annoyed at the man blowing smoke rings. In his station.
He says, in response to the guys and dumb Ducktales left their campfire boy and the the Ranger says careless campers, start lots of fires. Same old story and, you know, we're we kinda wonder if he he might already be skeptical of this guy. And it it's my experience that rangers
can easily
identify bad Campers
you. They just do a cursor you like, Yeah you which doing you're gonna be a problem because if they can tell in a split second of locate whose prepared is not. Right. So Another ranger comes in and he announces the fires under control. And we do get a nice little moment where the the chief acknowledges. Okay. So least, we've
saved some of the flo, which, you know, makes the reader feel better. And and the chief has no choice, but to take the guy's word for it, so he says let's be on the lookout for some du. And and it hasn't been too many panels, but it feels like a long time since we've actually gotten a check him and we we do come back to the depths and here first that they're okay as their word balloons are poking out of those those trenches
Wondering if it's safe to come out. And, you know, tell us about Donald merging. He comes out. And he says yeah. Is it safe, but makes that fair comment of well... There's is that gonna be another prior for a long long time as you see that escape of just charred ground and burnt trees and
for how rush all the artwork work has been before. This is now just bearing and sm during with the smoke wing, but the lots of smoke coming up of Al these burn trees and it's just it's just sad... Yeah. Yeah. It's tremendously sad. And you know, we understand that, like, forest fires are a natural part of the cycle of the forest, but this is a human caused one and and was needless
and and is sad. So on the next page, we only get a couple of panels of the Ducktales wandering through the the now b or burned up forest,
but it... But it still feels very impact. And and they finally arrive back at the Ranger station. And the bad ga is there and he's horrified, of course to see them because, you know, they're gonna mess with Al. So he races ahead to demands that the rangers arrest those Ducktales for starting the fire. And and on the next page,
Donald is a Huey,, you know, because he says that's the guy who's started the fire. And
and he also says he might be the guy who stole a car. And as they're about to come to blows,
you know, the Ranger said which side has the proof and and that nephew with the camera. Hue gets a little pit line off. He says this side the inside referring to camera.
And and he asks the Rangers to develop
the film
because he reveals for the first time. What is he reveal or? Well, him well they were arguing doing with they got Al kid about camp this morning. He did a picture of the whole setup, like he was preparing, you know, in case something goes to cell phone when I proof that, you know, this guy was deployed. Right. And so how does how does the bad camper take that on the next page. Oh, he is that happy. Like, no, I gotta get that camera. I'm gonna true the film and
amazingly
the
super heroic granger with Al little bit of j and self defense. And twist of arm puts them over and says...
What are you still worried about? Know You your making accusations, then you may have something maybe or guilty.
Right. I I love that little too flip. It's it's a great. Like, it... It's a little bit
maybe Uber heroic of him, but yeah. It's still funny. And so he develops it, but I I like that at this point, you know, he of course sees the photo. It it shows off. It's it's just the perfect dis.
Of the terrible
situation. It totally exon Donald who's clearly in mid her. And I like how the guy
indicates you know, as if I didn't need more proof when the guy was trying to destroy your camera, It's nice to see the ducks get getting some credit. Right? Mh. And and it's nice to see Donald proud of Huey, for having the foresight because he pat him on the head.
They're really cheering him on. And and the rangers, you know, they they give them the run of the what's left of the forest. So that they can still enjoy the rest of their rate, they're gonna get a nice camping outfit furnished for them. And and before we finish this page, one of the Nephews makes an interesting request to the the range or
do you mind telling us on the next page about that request derek? Oh, yeah. Yeah. That this for whisper class it and
the range goes... Oh, yeah. You're camera dog. I'll have to keep it here. And i needed for evidence conference.
Allowing him to line the voice and not be responsible with the camera, the source of their pain and frustrations from on this you know, air vacation
is now gone so they can actually just enjoy time together and have fun.
Exactly. It's it's a great bright idea from the Nephews.
And and so they do have a great time for the rest of their vacation. We get, like, a a solid four panels
of them fishing and sleeping.
That that looks like a great time doesn't it. It it really does. There's gonna something just about being out in the woods. Like as time of earlier my vacation been on the beach. I mean, there is something peaceful Barks in chair like empire
snooze in the woods. It's there's something very relaxing about that. Yeah. And and they're playing the very classic cowboys and Indians or I guess,
trap and Indians, because we got an nephew dressed up with the famous Daniel Boone hat. Mh. And
I'm just gonna read
the the contents of the last panel because it's it's great.
The narrator box says everything would be perfect.
Except for one thing.
And we've got the the buck posing majestic on Rock and Donald
groan in every evening at sunset, that big buck comes and poses on that rock and me with my camera and the safe at the station.
It's just it's like the perfect way to close this one out. Yes. Yes. It is. And and I think that's like why this... This story there's never really a part that doesn't work for me. You know, it's it's long. So it has these kind of me
stretches, but the overall structure of it is is just perfectly paced and perfectly
plotted. It's a vacation story so it's even okay that it end a little bit. Mh. Absolutely.
No.
I'm glad you like this one, Eric. You know, we've we've already kind of been installing it's it's virtue.
Do you have any other thoughts on on you know, what makes this one work? How do you feel that it compares to... You've read a good number of Barks stories at this point. Well, I mean, there's some various aspects to it.
There is
Donald still it's spoiled at the end. But if I to that that wasn't... Know, it's it's not what he set out to achieve on the first panel.
Oftentimes in the beginning of the stories, don't set out bitch with one thing in mind and then the end oh, nope. That didn't happen. In truth, he gets what he wanted. He wanted that time away from the grind. And he gets it. He doesn't really realize that because now that buck is i,
but it's not ruining everything. He's not being oh, this is horrible it's the worst thing ever why we do this. He's just lament the fact that he had this very not do now that he had all this interaction with the button and that it's now mocking him, which is great Yeah. And, you know, the boys
are bit of a foil in the beginning, he was giving them a hard time. And then in the end, they kinda way to kinda spoil his plans, but still
everyone comes out on top because they get to have that vacation together, it becomes a true vacation And now that be made sure in the fiber and the fire that is over, they get least have the time of the woods and that time together and doing all that fun stuff and so. I mean, it was kind of weird to see that the end... The the the final result was good, but yet, still you have to need to download a little bit at all times. Yeah. He's...
You know, he's had this this really heroic turn at the end. So I think Barks had to take just a little bit of yeah. Yeah not competitive.
Yeah. But just a little. Because because by all accounts, they're having a great time for the...
Oh, it's two grand weeks it says. So that's still... You know, if we assume they've had a couple of days at the beginning here, and boy, you definitely need to recover after that or ordeal. That's just they would be so so smelling and discussed yeah. Even one week forest fire in the air.
And forget about year quality. Yeah. Yeah. We we we won't we don't need to let that in true too much. So no no. No. They are right. As...
We we know what's going on with the west.
The west in United States these days. What a great vacation
story, it seems very appropriate that it's kind kind of had its own title here.
This this is a really really a special one. I found this one so memorable. I loved coming back
Absolutely. It's got a lot of great stories. And it's got a lot of little bits that you can enjoy. The, you know, Donald really gets the the tough guy donald getting full another, but Al saving the net, you know, the wisdom
or survival
expertise he's displays and, you know, rebates and are relatively
competence
in, you know, actual real world manners, you know, hey, that could be applied
far as extremely dangerous.
Try this yourself, But it it's just... Has the neat aspect of the danger rescue. There's, you know, some slaps state comedy. There's you know, a billing, you know, oh you're. You really love. I'm sorry. Didn't mean to talk over you. You you just... You love to hate this villain. Right? Oh, yeah. It's, paint so well. And I just... I'm like, why is this gonna camping? I mean, keep going through all the trouble they get up there and then you're being a lazy camper and you made this kinda is effort to get there? you know, I'm I'm glad I was thinking I'm glad this villain is a one off. I didn't need him to be pete or anything like that. That's true.
It also occurs to me that kids we as kids when we were at kids, we love to read like, survival, I think. Mh
Imagine yourself surviving. So I think part of the appeal is this is such a terrible
situation, and he sets up such a possible seeming way. But I think part of the success of this story is it really makes you feel like you you wanna be there. You wanna take this. Yeah. Not the forest fire part of the vacation obviously, but the rest of it. Well, this is this like again, this is this is in a real world setting in a mountain. So this is something someone go anyway. They're not going to some Florida swamp and that has weird creatures that you're never gonna see again in the whole hidden society, you know, that's completely made up. This is fishing and blah. Appreciate and camping. Yeah. Anyone can go do that. That's right. And I I love my Barks hidden civilization stories, but it it's a testament to his skill that he could create such memorable story out of out of a camping trip. Yes. So you and I love this one. U. I'll I'll go out on Al limb and say that this is probably somewhere in the neighborhood of, like, top ten
top fifth team for me. I I do find this one that memorable. At least have the Donald duck stories.
Yeah. Probably counting the the Donald Scrooge screw stories. This is
extremely highly regarded by the Ducktales community. This is a top ten story
among people who have rated stories on on in
that outsourced
website. It gets an eight point five out of ten And as of now, that's good for eighth place among the forty one thousand
something, Disney
comic stories. Oh. Yeah. So the the community views this as an all time class. Here on the podcast, this is,
I believe the
second or third
highest ranked story that we've covered. I think lost in the Andes
is the only one that might rank higher so far. It's very close to adventure down under, which I I don't think
rates nearly as well as the story. So.
Yeah. That that's just that's the community's. That's the community's feelings regarding those stories. In the case of this one, I I think it's right on the money. This is extremely memorable.
Because because of the kind of story it is, I think it holds up it extremely well. Yes. You know, there's
maybe a little bit. It's a little hero where a should of the rangers, but
you know, it's it's kind of a good and evil archetype then it's trying to explore too. Well you could you could easily substitute his camera for modern term modern cell phone and instagram, social media accounts. So ruining of meditation. Yeah. That's true. This this... I mean, there's definitely something about getting out a town that is probably harder to do these days, but it's mh ill still achievable. Yep. Appearances and other media, you know, I don't I'm not aware of any other any sequels or anything to this. It doesn't seem like the kind of story you could.
But I did mention the
oil painting that Barks did. Do you mind if I send it to you really quickly? Go. It's fun because he kinda combines
couple elements from that panel, maybe it wasn't in oil, and maybe it was a lift of graph. Well, while you do that, I'm gonna mention weird a few things. Yeah. Go. I really enjoyed the story. But one thing I felt... The one left post Al little bit out of place was, you know, that's typical, but the the page with the
and getting lost. I was like, okay. I guess the I can see the be Barks to it, but overall to the whole story, it felt like it was just a time pillar.
So when you coming in that it was thirty three pages of instead of thirty two. My thinking was look had it down that's the page to lose because if it had nothing to do with the rest of the story, nor if it's a big only pigeon or we're other people or the state bridge
whatever was to Duck,
just that Joke could make you fun up the Al being on my pitching. Anyway, I mean, it still... It was still enjoyable and, you know, that that happens on road trips you get lost and you make you crack jokes. And then the one other v want to dimension is when Donald sees the buck and has the picture of i wanna take the photo because it's gonna be surprise winning photo. It's in color. When they go to the range jason that developed the picture of the it's in black and white. Yeah. That's True. I didn't think about that. Obviously, it is the color choice. But
I think that was the case on multiple printing. It's a good way to show us that this is a photograph. Oh, i. You know, Absolutely. Absolutely. I just I have some... I have some looking for those through
go like, what is this intended? Was it not? I don't know. Which just something funded notice. I think you're right. I think that's a good catch. I totally agree with you about the. It's... It it cracks me up, but it it's it's the least necessary couple yeah in it.
And it it did take me a little bit out of it. Right? Yeah. It it kinda goes back to the title, like, when I some of the bait switch, you know, the first thing that happens is he gets lost. And so so so you think oh they're gonna get lost on this vacation and it's gonna be spoiled. They're gonna be set out the wisdom doing whatever. That sound like a typical difficult donald story of them getting boss and being stuck in this weird position and Then never hear away out of it. Right. Yeah. I I think you're right. I think that's fair. I just sent you the link in the chat. So take a look. It's a cool oil. Looking.
Oh, oh with the bolts now? Yeah. I think I think it's meant to be the eagle from the other panel. Sure. Kind of kinda a super
imposing it there. It's it's pretty good. I don't know. I mean it's very good for far as picture goes, but I kinda like the one that's in the but it's actually in the comic myself. Sure. It's a different... It's a different animal. But Yeah. But you know, these these oils and lit graphs did are all always no. It's it's very pretty. It's it's quite it's quite striking. Done Al this happy they'll milwaukee itself driving over Al collapsing wooden bridge and and Al these just panic beyond Al belief. It really amps up the apparel. So, yeah,
I'm trying to think we covered pretty much everything I wanted talk about. We we do always talk about favorite panels. Mh. This one is such a such an embarrassment of riches to me. Is there any
anyone that kind of stood out to you Eric? Yes. It's the one where he's bro busting the the buck. And the boys in the foreground,
he's in the background and the tall trees have existed really neat perspective, beautiful the trees and the scene. And then him in the background just railing and you've got you got some of the accents in there. It's got the actual, but it's got that one perspective about. I think honestly, I think it's the best job for because you've Gottfredson at different angles
and you got the shadow that I like, but dear just very great action
drawing of the deer and the boys and and then it's stunned of what's going on. And I just... I like that because I could see myself looking for the woods and seeing that I picture that looks like a real forest that's a good choice.
There are just so many great ones. It's it's it was hard for me to choose. I was really struck by the trees has they've just, you know, emerged the burned trees that. Yeah. Struck me. I really liked the one of the the Ducktales rushing in the opposite direction from the animals. You know, that one really highlighted
the danger that they were in for mh. And then I like to highlight the one, it's just a quiet panel, but the one where they're walking for some time and they passed by the waterfalls and the fern. I oh yes. Those were really really lovely. So but but again, you could pretty much
flip to any page and and you get some of the best Barks
the best art of Barks career in this one. Yeah. Great story. This is a good one if you're really trying to, like, hook someone
get him into Barks. You know, there's there's nothing really problematic about this one that that might be in some stories. It's a very, like it's a very relatable story It's very timeless and it's great storytelling and great art. Yep. That completely agree. Excellent. Well, Eric, thank you so much. For joining me i a great time talking about this one with you. I'm so glad you could join me I think this was a great one to have you on for. I am very much looking forward
to the next one, although it's it's a very dark story. We get to talk next episode about the magic hourglass.
Mh. So, yeah. If listeners
wanna share their opinions, you can join us on the Facebook page, mark's remarks. Or
email us at Barks remarks at g mail dot com. And as always,
thank you for listening. Right.