Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of sc Mc and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge cl of all time, join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context, and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Hello, and welcome back to another episode of Barks from remarks. The podcast where we talk about the long form adventure stories of the legendary Carl Marx. We've got a great
episode today all about a very notable
story called the magic hourglass.
I'm gonna i ask my returning guest host, to introduce himself. I'm Mark, Warren Har back again. Glad to be here again and
really looking forward to the story being a longtime Barks collector and debt collector this story painted so many different dimensions of the Ducktales and and a storyline that deserves talking about. Yeah. This is a fascinating one. I'm I'm gonna just say kind of right off the bat that I have kind of a I think a complicated
experience with this one, you know, I first read this in that big Donald duck collection
that was printed in the late seventies.
I I don't remember what it was called. But but it presented like, ten of his most notable
kind of golden age comics.
And
this one it really stood out as like, very dark
compared to a lot of the others. You know? It was it was one of the only two stories in that collection that featured Scrooge Mc. Who i I had already had a lot of experience with His comics
and
sc is
so un
for for so much of this story that it it made it a hard story to love and I feel like I I went back to this one less frequently than I did the other stories in that collection. I hadn't read this story myself for quite some time. I remember having that same feeling when I read it again and Scrooge dot is not the sc we want to
admire. Is the the character that we
really want to try to stand. And and while this story dives a bit into his past, which other stories do, but a little a different origin story if you will, about his wealth, I think we are exposed to us sc isn't likable. And that bothers me. Also the the fact that some of that early on, there's this un unlike
with Donald in the nephews as well, and I'm really uncomfortable with that. But I think a story needs to expose itself to pay that off. Right. Yeah. That... That's a good point. And and when I think about the stories that I don't and always enjoy as much. There they're often the stories where I don't find the ducks very likable. And you're right. There are some some parts of the story where they're less likable than others. I think most everyone is is mostly redeemed by the end, but but this is a dark and challenging story. I will go ahead and say off the bat that I I do still think that this is a great story. I don't love it in a way where I consider a personal favorite, but but I have this experience with, like, media
sometimes with Barks or movies where I I feel like I can recognize something is great even if I don't have a personal love for this one.
I don't love it either, but I respect it a lot. And I I respect what Barks is saying here. And there is a maturity of him at forty nine years old when he wrote this
when he was again in that when we knew you and I've called that great period of storytelling that he was in. But this one's this one you have to wrap your head around and understand what's happening. In the country in the world. You know, and then and then, this is a children's story. This is Al children's comic and it's so far beyond that Yeah. Yeah. This one has some very
mature themes for sure and it has a lot to say about the world at the time. So so let's go ahead and get into it. I I know we've got we probably have a lot to say about this one because more than more than most common this one says, I mean, most of these comics have a lot to say about culture
and and society but it's it's more often it's meant to be inferred. And and there's there's more text than sub here. I I think. So so,
So this the magic hour you mentioned this was published. This has a cover date of July nineteen fifty. And we're we're way up into four color two hundred ninety one. Is that right? That's right. Okay.
This one's been reprinted fairly often warren. We've got eight of them counting the first printing in the United States. And it's a long ish story. It's not one of his longest. It's twenty eight pages.
Also had a wonderful paper Barks follow up not too many years ago
that came out in the comic stores. I remember I I looked to that when already I already already have this one have the four color issue. I've got reprint it a few times. I didn't really wanna buy it in a format that took it out of it original panel structure, but but it's been reprinted and yeah it'd be for a lot of good reasons. Yeah. Yeah. It's it's very notable. I will I will add this if that's okay. It's
on a fun side before we dive into the story
for color two ninety one
and then of course
the next Ducktales story that top Be number three hundred, we have the unique unique inequality of being the first to the of the animated covers. The of the... Which there there were a total of seven and well, Disney had, I think three or four in their to Donald for sure, I think one mickey maybe two. Yeah. So
I I recorded an episode warren for Big top Bed before doing this one. And I saw that. I didn't encounter for this one because I didn't
I didn't look up the original four color one, but I was I was talking with my brother who joined me for that one about Ally i. I wasn't entirely sure of how that worked. I don't know if you're to, like, wear it is a mask or something, but
how's that cover supposed to work? Well, if you look at the cover of the original book, I believe it's got the shark
coming out of the water and there's a little dotted light around the shark mouth that you're supposed to
you encourage the kids to go grab their scissors and cut out that. And then
moving up and down to cause that animated effect. So it's all effect. And it's all just a way to engage the kids. But.
All the same concept, but interesting. Yeah. That's very fun. Thanks for mentioning that. So boy, warren... I like to talk when we do this episode, you know, part of what interests me, of course is the story.
Part of what interests me is the culture that it came out of, you could
you could go on and on
about the cultural context for this one. But
I know that you and I both read
the the book. We both read the book called Carl Marx and the Disney comic on masking the myth of modern maternity by Thomas Andre.
It... It's an interesting book. He talks a lot
about some of the stories and he talks more about this one than than many of the others. And I I don't always agree with what he is reading out of these stories. But but in this case, in the case of this one, I think he really hit it right on the money. Because after after I read, reread this one, I was like, wow, This one really has a lot to say about about capitalism
about
imperial
about the Us involvement in the Middle East.
I think that probably sounds heavy and a little bit too cerebral for, like, a funny animal comment. But if if you read this story with that mindset, it's it's almost
unmistakable. How much this is
about. This has the sub
of American
involvement
in the Middle east and and resource extraction and
wealth and and everything. It does. We're looking at nineteen fifty or five years past the end of the second world war.
Not only is America booming, but it's also becoming more
involved in the Middle East and oil reserves and making deals with the Saudi Arabian.
And all of this is happening. It's new for America. There's is a lot of prosperity that's being promised. There's a lot of building going on
as he is so apparent in the opening panel. Yeah.
But, yes, this is a story about success. Certainly greed, and not just the imperial and capitalism of our culture or the American
society, and also of the underground
shake, And again, I read this story for the first time and it was an adventure story. It had shades of raiders of the lost Barks has shades of the mummy of the black fraser. In a shades of all these little wonderful adventures, but there's is so much deeper than that. Yeah. You you know what this really reminded me of actually in in a sequence was the old God
mickey mouse comic, Mickey joins the foreign legion. Mh. You know, that yeah. That was a trope
back into, I think the the twenties thirties forties
into the fifties that we don't really have anymore. You know, there was this like, romantic
randomization. And and Donald and the kids don't join the foreign legion, but the little excursion that they have, it... To me is really reminiscent of what Mickey did in that comic, but that that was that was one of those genres of itself. There was this like American fascination with running away escaping and joining the Usually, it was the French foreign legion. It was that that was popular not only with in the comics that in in God story with Mickey, but it was also very popular in in the short with Laurel and Hardy in the three studios. They did the same. Yeah. Was going to a better life and getting a better a start
and it was also... Yeah. It was it was very popular.
Right. And and so I think we'll get into this, but when you read this, you have to see that you have to think of that red sand that they're gonna be thinking of as a metaphor for oil. Yes.
This is an extremely turbulent time in the Middle East, the nineteen fifties
historically is when the countries across the Middle East were
essentially
trying to
assert their control over their own
resources
and you know, try and try and shake out the old imperialist
ties that are entrenched
themselves and and as you said, America was in this new era of prosperity and i was very focused on where it was gonna secure these resources. You had this push and this poll of these countries wanting to
understandably
be masters of their own destiny with their own resources
And then
the United States and other powers
really mu about the the Cia is heavily involved in in things like d depositing the shah
or or rather prop up the shaw of Iran.
Andre talks about this being near the time that
Saudi Arabia
successfully
asserted control over much of its oil. So that that is what I think we're supposed to think about or at least, you know, Barks, we talk about how he was reading national Geographic. He he was also reading the news
and how could he not? Yeah. Back then, it was it was major story in the news, especially how the interests in Foreign lands were becoming interested in American investment.
And
and you've mentioned to the with the
clan
affairs of government and whatever it's difficult to separate that. But as it as a ten year older, a twelve year old child, I'm not so sure that's what the intention was. But I Barks a whole lot of credit for for sharing his his take on what was happening in the world. You know when you think about him too, He was making minimum wage or he was making a... A honest salary. He was going through multiple
bad times in his own life at this stage he was getting closer to a second divorce. And
that he's making comments on wealth and excess and capitalism. You have to imagine money was never never far from his mind, but he but he obviously had some some really interesting ideas about wealth that come out Just in this story. Alright. Lot lots to say. So so let's let's do it. We're we're gonna go through the
structure, the plot of magic hourglass. But I I have no doubt we're gonna take a few little
side d tours to just talk about what it all means. But but I I don't wanna lose sight of the fact. This is is a really interesting and memorable story even even without those baked elements.
Mh.
So on the first page, you you had alluded to the opening panel, which has the du
surveying
Ducktales,
which is just being incredibly developed. Right? It's it's skyscrapers
and it's a bustling
port and the Ducktales are ad
it.
And Donald is
when when the Nephews
talk about what a swell view of the city it is, he goes out of his way to say that it's a swell view of some of his uncle sc property.
And and this is kind of the first little disturbing bit
to me, it's disturbing. Right? This is the story that he wants to tell. But the ducks are in this kind of weird
debate. Over, you know, their closeness to their uncle sc.
Donald is bragging about how his uncle
owns all of these properties and, you know, he lists all of the types of industries and the nephews
are taking offense at this because they're like, you know, he's our uncle too even if we're more distant,
and they accuse him of sc not really liking him very much because he he's never given him anything and they point out that he did give them a dime once.
So one once... Yes. Yeah. So so this is the setup. Right? This is the conflict
between the Ducktales. But what really stands out is that we've just looked at this. We've just seen this panel that that represents Duck bird and wealth but it really represents capitalism and the that idea of mid century American
progress.
Beautifully done too. I I I really do love that splash panel. I I I I remember that one as a kid as probably one of my favorites because it it it it showed me a Ducktales that I had not imagined. A Ducktales of the future, you can see just the modern looking structures. Yeah. And and and you're right. I think this also immediately sets off this battle or competition between, you know, who likes me best. And
yeah, well said,
but even though they gave him the dime, Donald still implies or or it basically insists that he still likes
me the best. We go to the next page and we see now we're we're cutting back to Uncle Sc. He's in his modest kitchen as they say, I love the first panel and I think this is where it kinda of sets up this whole destiny
story here because this is a story about destiny. As an if you are arguing they beat they show the and with destiny across the belly on the on the nest, and we know what's coming. Immediately, we see a Scrooge with this hourglass that he uses to time his eggs. And and it goes through the panel. And and what what struck me about this particular page is not so much the fact that the the eggs did not come out the way he wanted them to too because they should be with this with hourglass glasses, it's a little symbols everywhere in the kitchen and on the table that have dollar signs on the or more paintings with coins in them. Again,
emphasizing this importance of wealth at least in uncle sc mind. But the eggs did not come out well and
he immediately
blames it on this old hourglass glass. It's worthless
time to get rid of it. Right. As soon as this hourglass
fails to time his soft boiled day perfectly. He's ready to to give it the He h. And there's a lot in in where he got the hourglass. Right? Because heat. It references finishes some of his beginnings as a poor cabin boy on a cattle boat. These are details that, like, are gonna come in later that Rose gonna use he mentions buying in a thieves market in Morocco. So we kinda su out that this was was stolen at some point. And he knew it at the time. I think this is what's important is to know that... So he bought it intentionally in a thieves market, and it makes you kinda wonder where where his identity will come from. Right. And and this is a big part of why the story off puts me immediately. Right? Because we've got this version of uncle sc that I don't like. You know, Right. He's he's a sc draw. He's villainous, if not an outright villain. And you know, we we haven't even talked about the fact that I'm sure it offend you the way it offend me, the notion that Sp
wealth
was
Al results, we're gonna learn later that, you know, this is a lucky tal basically that that brought him as wealth. And and Barks, you know, he's gonna just sketch that away. But so we can accept that this is not canon. But but this is a Barks story, you know. And and he obviously hadn't developed the character he hadn't
even if he changes him up all the time. Going forward by the time we get to only a poor old man and others, we we know that he's hard hearted and he's mis early, but he at least has this decent
core yes. So this this is very, like, upsetting, I think. To to a big fan of the the real Scrooge.
So think. You think that Barks was was playing with his character development at this point and not quite sure himself.
Yeah. Exactly. He hadn't... He hadn't landed on that yet. You know? He's kind of vac back and forth because in in Voodoo who, he's he's again, sc
villainous,
but in the old castle, secret his second adventure length appearance, you know, he was much closer to what he would end up being. So yeah, we're we're kind of vac back and forth and this is definitely towards that sc side. So on next page warren, we go through some of his morning routine where he's checking up on his industries, and he learns from a port that he has a fishing boat called the junk two that is not worth the powder to blow it up and he can't sell it. And so he has these two items that are upsetting him that are worthless. They don't perform their function anymore. And so So he decides that he's gonna summon his nephews
and
he's gonna kind of do, you know, he's gonna kill two birds with one stone, and he presents...
He presents the junk too to Donald. Who is overjoyed? Right? Immediately becomes
extremely joyful that he has now been proven to be the favorite. Right. And the Nephews user are thinking that they're they're gonna get a better deal than him. And why don't you take us on to that next? Yeah. So they're they're little humbled and they're looking up at him and and graciously waiting for their gift and their Scrooge masks this know, his disappointment in the hourglass is charming old hourglass and gives it to them and, of course, the next panel, they're while walking away. Boys Barks silicon Donald just absolutely having a field day saying that he got the better of the of the deal. So immediately, the kids start just w and moaning while Donald goes off to see what kind of boat was left him notices that the jump to is
not in terrific shape and laying on its side in the harbor. So that's where we end up. Right. The junk two lives up to its name. I I guess there's a type of that is called a junk. Right? It's a Chinese ship, I think. So it's... The term
a first a ship out of Asia. Right. So it's not that weird
there's at least plausible den.
So so on the next page, you know, it's Donald turned to silk about it. But but he he consoles himself by thinking, oh, at least it's better than the hourglass the kids got. And then a man strides up to him purposefully. And and this is a gag that Barks goes to a few times. Right? Because I I saw this in... The the man presents him with the bill for dock rent and and obstructing
navigation. So this this is just like the house boat that they got in terror of the river and I think there's at least one other. Period where
someone gets a boat and and they're on the hook for for Ducktales.
They get they get the bills thrust in their face. That's right. Right. So we transitioned back to the Nephews who decide that it's not worth it to do anything with the hourglass
and they they seek out a junk man, but he tells them it's not even worth a dime. And and he kinda casually
says, don't try to tell me that it's a magic hourglass
just because of what's written on top of it. Yeah. And and and right away, one of the nephews glance down at the etching which we see in the drawing, and there's definitely something on there. And
they don't know what it is. They probably never saw it or if they did they thought it was a decoration, but the the pe on with the car on the street just happens to know exactly what it says, which is great. It just kicks right to the soil. Yeah. He's fluent in the an ancient arabic Barks.
Ancient Arabic yeah it it says as long as this glass keeps perfect time, its owner will be grow richer hour by hour, and then heat That's nonsense. So he just says here, boys I'm not interested. But I love that next frame because immediately, the nephew
sense that that's how uncle Scrooge got rich. Just like that. And the Peddle moves off down the road
says that only it only takes the special sand and that special sand is a red sand that is only found in the Cigarette sahara desert in Africa. And so what they... Now they're trouble because they don't know how they're going to get there. And immediately, they realized that Donald was given Right. And he does specify the name of the place. Right? No Isa No lisa. But the little territory or the little area within the Where that that red sand only exists. And of course, one can take those two words in Lisa is... Well
it's No. It is. Right. Yeah. This that's a very Barks
place name. So we have this neat little transition here where Barks
his narrator box
represents them burying the hatch it by presenting a a literal buried hatch. I love that frame. A lot. Just think it's great. It's a huge. Because they're they're they're trying to figure out. They've got a a purpose now. They're like, okay. We we should try to fill the hourglass.
But how are we gonna get there? We don't have the money to repair my boat. So they land on the idea that
maybe there's a little bit of magic left in the hourglass Gladstone,
and they decide to try and close their eyes and and feel where the hourglass
is gonna direct them. And, you know, it's it's interesting to me warren there's a lot of these stories like this where there's this faith in a sort of magical lucky amulet you think about how often Barks talked about like wealth and hard work, there's there's a surprising amount of this stuff too. And they they creep up often. That's correct. And I also see that that of course without glad on this in the story. We see shades of Gladstone would experience to.
And there's this fine line between magic and luck I think in this story. But you're right. They go they close their eyes and they walk down the pier. And
they're not aware of it, but they end up actually falling right into the water, and I love the action under the water because they see danger immediately with the two approaching sharks. And then once the sharks hit the dock, knock themselves out, get groggy, the nephew is
immediately jumped to the conclusion that hourglass brought them bad luck. But Donald becomes very resourceful immediately and immediately sees an opportunity here to transform
these two into a way to salvage the boat. I wanna point out too before we move on to that great next panel, that there's there's something happening here with the dialogue. This is the think the second time that one of the nephew says, man, man, and I and I don't know where that came from most popular jargon of of teenage kids those in those days, but... Yeah. There's some some odd bits of dialogue that kind of are striking in this one. Yeah. It is just a little side thing that I noticed. You're right. That next panel is pretty
spectacular. It shows the results of the Ducktales having a harness to the two sharks.
To the junk two and
they are crossing the ocean on shark power with Donald cracking the whip to direct them. The the the narrator box needs to be read out. It says father Neptune has seen some strange ships crosses broad oceans, but none stranger than the argo of the fortune hunting ducks.
Okay.
It's it's a crazy panel. It's it's ridiculous, but it's... I I I love it. It's it's it's a wonderful panel. And we transition at this point to back to uncle Sc. In his offices, he's getting in these reports of his businesses going
catastrophic broke, wells running dry
minds running out of gold. He is beside himself trying to figure out what's going on on. Yeah. He can't figure it out, and he's soaking in his desk, and he just says he was making money all the time up until that morning, what happened and it just is he scratches said and tries to figure it out, he remembers the fact that it may have been... Or might have been that our last. So he bolts out of the office runs through Duck. He said that old hourglass was the secret of my good luck and that is his
realization that his lifetime of wealth was due to that hourglass. But he never believed it. Right That's a that's a key point right there that he never
believed in a moment that that was it, but he's sure of it now that he's going broke while it's missing. Right. So we know that he...
Yeah. Sorry. I I was just gonna say we know that we know that he did know about the alleged Right? It's not something. He he was aware of it. He was aware of the legend. I'm sure when he bought the hourglass glass and he was aware of it, but he never really about it. But he races up to donald House and wraps on the door says open up I've got a whole dime here new time to pay for that hourglass Gladstone wants it Barks to really. Yeah. Not desperately enough to to offer a market value for it, which it was just gonna... Which is gonna come back to bite him on the next page, he learns from a neighbor that the Nephews have indeed headed back to Africa. So he knows exactly what's going on that they're gonna be
trying to fill the hourglass.
And we we transition right away to a sea port on the coast of Morocco.
It's a really nice
drawing of of that coast and and a pretty bustling city behind. We've got a really cool panel here of him desk Britain and sobbing at... I guess, I'm sure some ind person has calculated his fortune based on what he says here that if he's losing a billion dollars a minute, he'll be broken six hundred years.
It's probably one of a few times where you could actually point try and calculate how much money he has. Not that you can ever find anything consistent.
Right. Right. And so he does
spy a speck on the horizon that resolves into a ship. So we know that sc sees the Ducktales approach, and then we transition back to them. They've they've nicknamed the sharks. I I think I didn't mention that. One of them is named Samson,
and I don't remember the other one is Caesar.
Sam's. Are in Sam So they call out Samson quite a bit in the story. I think that's
Oh yeah. Yeah. At the very end. That's when he said they say whoa caesar. What what was Sam snow caesar?
But Donald get shanghai, that he gets captured immediately by a couple of thugs
that sc is hired. Right? So this is this is part of that pretty villainous behavior that sc
participate in. And
part of what makes him pretty despicable and Well I think so... And and and he immediately wants to use brute force to get that hourglass back and we don't know how he's going to do it. So we're really compelled to turn the page. Before we do that, i wanted to ask you Mark, if this was the first time we see sc Mc Ducktales traveling outside of Duck to a to a global destination, because he is now in Morocco. I know he went on dentures with the nephews. This is a little different. He's out there to get the nephews to to bay basically... Yeah. You're right. I... Because we we'd highlighted that in in his earlier
stories where he
participated he had generally sent the Ducktales off like in trail of the unicorn. So, yeah, good good catch. This might work.
I think this is his first venture out of Duck
Unfortunately, it isn't in partnership with the nephews.
It's it's to really track them down. And and as the studs ring donald to sc
he donald this that hourglass is not for sale anymore. And so they embark on a form of humorous torture, Z and I could think of here with a feather
tick Donald, which I think it's fun. And he's laughing hysterical and it says
you won't sell that hourglass piece. Yes. Yes. It's it's okay. Let's go board. And so he finally gets tired of being tickle and Scrooge follows him on board. Where they realized that the hourglass is gone, but so are the nephews
sc points out that they they've gone shore donald loves every minute of Right. The the tickle torture bit is
it's funny, but it's also disturbing. Right? Because I think it's supposed to be an analog for this is a a kid's comic. But but Sc is really compelling him here. So well no no question about it. I think to to get the point across any other form of getting donald to talk would not have worked for the kids. I think this was really an important way to say yeah, It's still unfortunate that screw just doing this. But it it it was done in a way that I think is more humorous we're gonna do it. Well I don't like it either. Because I think this is showing side of Scrooge, I do not like it all. So so the next page is all about Donald having separated himself and trying to find the nephews
before
sc and his minions do. And this is really
it's set in Morocco. And this is that that old trope of North Africa
you know, it's the North Africa of like Casablanca
and and and the French foreign legion stories
It's a very mysterious place full of, like, un
people. Right? It's it's very stereotypical.
And and
Donald is nervous and he gets caught by who he thinks is the thug, but is really the nephews.
So they're able to they're able to get away, but it's just an interesting little
Into that kind of stereotype of of Morocco. Yeah. You see a lot of that in the in the nineteen forty three film casablanca with the Cd characters and in that part of the world,
And here we're seeing it again and I love that most of that page is done in the shadow. Mh. And it's not at night. Adds a bit of mystery to it. But the good news is that the nephews and Donald can now go off in the next morning, there they are on the on these beautiful panels that depict the Sahara desert.
They're basically
waiting for what to do next. They they know they need to find where no Isa is and the red sand. But they don't dare ask anybody because they have Al feeling that sc has his fingers and everything now. Then they're approached by this mysterious
soldier he looks like to me. Turns out to be a shake, but soldier on top of a camel and speaks fluent English. There's no broken English here or anything like that. He also knows that the ducks are in trouble. And donald immediately gets on the defensive and wants to know why, he says what I heard about you from your uncle Scrooge, So again, sc just been talking and wanting wanting is nephews captured or detained. And this is my classic donald fighting pose. I love it Yeah.
It's just it's just super classic
you won't take us without a fight. You get see the first real close of the space, this men face. You don't know if he's good or evil. I really didn't know. But he immediately says there he is not interested in a reward. He wants to
recruit them as mercenaries for him as as soldiers in his is cause.
And now we know that there's this battle going on or at least we get this the beginnings of this battle between these two. Yeah... This is really fascinating to me for for a few reasons. Right? Because this guy, first off he's he's a human.
Most most of these Mer moroccan characters are humans
they're they're really drawn and and represented in a pretty refreshing way to me because as you said, there's no broken English here.
This guy has total agency. Yeah. And he feels like he is a real person to me in in it in a place with its own history, and he has his own like, motivations.
I I like this sequence a lot. Like you said he's very dark, mysterious. And this is the part that remind... You know, this is the the foreign legion, the character join the foreign legion trope. Because that's not what exactly what this is. But it might as well be because like you said they're mercenaries
now they're they're rifle men and and they need to this this guy his trading caravan, it seems that every time he crosses a certain
stretch of desert, they get attacked
by this ambush and we're gonna learn that those people he's convinced that they are coming from that legendary
Oasis of noah or No.
Right. And that he wants the Ducktales to help protects the caravan.
And so they come to a... There's this fun back and forth, you know, where he seems like he might be crazy because he he says it does exist. He says it doesn't. It it gives us this nice hand tantalizing, you know, idea about about the raiders and the place and they come to this empty patch of desert
and he he tells them to be very watchful at this point. Yeah. And it is just in this is where they're looking out at this vast desert. And
you'll you know, still you, soon see the raiders
coming from any other place. And immediately, they go down to the the the base of the rich where they find this watering and both for the camels. And
they are... I think now it's being accepted as members of their caravan.
The du relax now. And as falls, it says in the second frame on the next page, it's getting quiet. It's it's that quiet before the storm and immediately, we see these panels that unveil the attack, the raiders. They're asked to kind of strategically
aim where the where the gun flashes is coming from about the nephews, I know Al little bit more. And they're say, well, no. We have to follow the action. So there's a little little tactical
strategy which I like them employing and of course, one of the bullets from the nephews goes right past one of the raiders
and they start running off. Yeah. So this this is a pretty intense battle. Right? This this is a gun fight. They're real bullets. Yeah. This is this is where someone could get hurt. This would not be allowed,
you know, to be
printed this way and story that was submitted in in the modern con.
Disney now has, like,
strict guidelines about this kind of
Okay. But it's really interesting. It's very exciting.
Even if it's still a little bit cartoon ish. But, you know, the the the base gist of the next page is that after the battle after the Ducktales have successfully contributed
to the safety of the caravan, the leader there, that shake or whoever he is you know, he thanks them. He gives him a reward, and they separates to go in search of the Oasis. And he wishes them luck and he
cautions them not to go anywhere
without a water back. And... Right. And and that's gonna be obviously very important. You're always you always need to be thinking about water in the desert to someone who who spends a decade and a half in Arizona
i I still have trouble going anywhere without a bottle of water reflex.
And we feel the Ducktales loneliness immediately feel the vast of the desert that they are now alone in. Yes. And they they absolutely
see that and as they are going away, they they see a lame campbell kind of in the distance wandering and they are suddenly encouraged to follow that camel, It may lead them to something positive, maybe water
or something and it is. The the camel leads them back to where they were into that oasis. That wasn't happy about that, but the boys are resting and they're everything's kind of peaceful now, but they immediately recognized that the camel that they had followed back to that watering hole is gone. It's vanished. They don't know where it is. So the ducks look over and they look over at the water and they noticed some bubbles that are coming up from the at the surface and they realize immediately that the camel
is probably and wandered into the water. And that's where they begin to pursuit here. Right. And and I like this element a lot. This is one of my favorite parts where it really takes this mysterious cool turn Right? Because they realized that the camel
trains to do this. Yes. And and they they swim down and they discover this
Sub
passage, this water way that leads them to what they call a natural subway.
We get this neat little narrator box that describes it as a channel of one of the Sahara
underground rivers that supply the Oasis
This this really, like, sparked my imagination as I when I read this as a child. I remember. Well, I remember Mark two, I'll just add to that that it reminds us both of of when the unicorn when they discovered the unicorn when they go through s,
is this discovery of this Land didn't exist and it's that's what as a child I just remembered just brought joy to me that they're in this new land this this adventure
is continuing now in an unexpected place. Yeah. Yeah. Well said, it's it's that great, like, entry moment that Barks is so good at. Right? Okay. Not first glimpse of the hidden civilization or society or whatever and... And this isn't quite a civilization, but they they stumble upon an underground palace.
Seems to be pretty well populated. It has a bunch of the old, like middle east tropes, you know, it's got the veil woman
that seems to be like a con vine. And
we get the perspective of a couple of the raiders we're talking about how their shake is furious because the raid on the caravan
was beaten not. It is Shake is the the other shake, I'll call him, the the not so nice Shake who and tells his
men to go
bathe and cleanse yourselves because you're un sanitary,
bathe in the red sand that brings good fortune. The first time we see now the origin that the sand is going to be here. We see it immediately then in this wonderful pile and he's these these three guys walk over there kinda salt like, oh boy, you know, I hate take a bath. It's beautiful. It's good humor. But then the next frame we don't see them right. But we do see the Nephews and donald as they approach donald as this quick plan to fill the hourglass and leave immediately. Well, I always wondered On donald here at the base of the of the sand just fill it and get out. And no he climbs to the top and the humor starts there with the
collecting the one of the men on the head. Who they all pop up and they they captured donald sees them and bring them to the to the shake who
says that they all came from America to find the oasis of Louisa, and he's not happy at all. So he wants to basically take the hour last Barks. Right. He he demands an explanation and the Ducktales Donald,
he he's not thinking very quick. He tells the truth. He shows him the hourglass
and and the guy recognizes it immediately as an old tal
from... Again, we got one of these silly Barks names H, had haircuts.
Magician centuries ago. And he references that it was lost
And, you know, it's been it's been or it's about to be refilled. So they immediately get their version of good luck coming to them
because one of the one of his man references that are uncle sc is caravan which appears to be very rich is approaching the water hole. And so they abandoned the Ducktales they go off to raid that care of that.
They believe they're undefeated at this time because he's now got the magic Al and he's holding the hourglass
ducks alone. Right.
And and this this is kind of a weird little trope. Right? The the raiders bathing in sand.
It's it's funny, but but it's it's pretty weird. Yeah. It's it's it's very different. We're about to go into this sequence where the hourglass is basically gonna start to change hands.
That's gonna characterize
most of the rest of this.
So Scrooge
the next panel we see sc with his caravan event that he's bought, and he's...
Regrets being sting old fool, but I'm gonna make up for it my past mistakes. And and right now, he knows that he's got a saddle filled with a billion dollars.
We'll pay those boys for the hourglass. So he's now feeling he's doing better than a dime you learned some of the lesson now. Anyway, I think i again, I just can't help but think they're forgetting their family, but I guess this is how this family
operates. So the raiders come out at night, and they start attacking.
They use a term here that I had not heard before it water covers are removed from their guns. Breech locks are clicked. I really love the the paying attention to the detail of the of the armor Barks realizes that the
guns would not work if they were submerged in water. It is not in tell. Yeah. The raid was on. Course the last demo shows up, some of those bullets flying through Scrooge hat. Yeah. The this little sequence where the raiders emerge very cool. Right? This is a bit of a payoff to me. It's Al little mystery of how the raiders have been attacking the caravan so mysteriously. And we we already knew how working, but it was needed to see it play out. And now we know that they're emerging from the water, and that's that that's silhouette capital it's really quite nice. Yeah. And And so, you know, the the fight is really one sided uncle Sp
his his hired men are routed, i like that neither of these
groups of characters
are really car,
you know, they're not. This is a kind depiction that he doing in a lot of these stories. And you know, there the raiders now are reaping the the good luck. Right? Because
they've got Scrooge billion dollars. They've got the rich supplies from his camp and they're celebrating this, holding the hourglass
loft and and Donald
Donald sneaks in at the end of the page and he snatch it back and flee for his life. So here the hourglass is now back with Donald and they are hiding in the desert again as we see the the the rubble and not the rebels, but the caravan
kinda salt away now without the hourglass now the the tal the the hourglass.
It actually has this power apparently to make people the way they are. And
that's not saying that we can't say that in this particular story, Sc isn't a bit of a bad guy because he is. And they're they're they're happy now, Donald got the hourglass
So they're in the desert. Donald holds that hourglass up in the air. Kind of like that Soldier did the other the the raider. Yeah. And
now he declares that the whole world is in our power. That's really ominous, and I... And that really bothered me that the... He this this perhaps evil
spell of the hourglass is now back in Donald. But they realizes Al they walk miles later, they're getting thirsty with the magic hourglass, anything's possible. We'll just keep walking until we find water. And they walk and they walk with their eyes closed like they did off the pier and they see a water bank. Link in the sand. Yeah. It's a really cool image that water bag half that they're so excited to see. I think warren that this couple of pages here is the best part of the story. I think that this is where a greatness lies for this one, because, you know, at the beginning of the story, he set it up like a moral plan. Right. And and this is where we're getting that moral coming back and really paying off
you know, you talked about that power that the hourglass
seemed like it was holding over him. And
that was a great point and it immediately reminded me of the Golden helmet. Mh. It's the same dynamic where the the helmet seems to be corrupting
otherwise, good people that hourglass does as well. So, yeah, I love this next sequence where the Ducktales are they're desperate for water they've just been led by the hourglass to the water bag. And when they pour it, it
it's gold dust. And Donald kicks the bag away. He cries out that it's nothing but a bag full of old dry gold dust. They're just disgusted. Right? Because The most important thing for them right now is water and that is literally worthless
in their situation. That that first panel in this page I think was the cover art for the old
Donald Ducktales too. So that feels with with the with the tongue hanging out, a very rare depiction of Donald tongue. Yeah. But That
that is on it. Give it to me.
And and this this feels like a real monkey pause situation.
Right? That's that's the sort of, like, it's it's one of those be careful what you wish for. Right it's right because they've been so focused on riches. It's like, It's like the hourglass is trying to teach them a lesson because after after they encounter this water bag full of gold dust, they see a lake in the distance.
And we've been conditioned, I think to suspect that it may be a mirage that old desert trope. But in fact, when they dive in, we can tell that it seems to be jewels.
And and they say this line last one is an old
scavenge camel. I guess, I guess that's like a term for swollen hoo or or swollen feet of a horse. I I did have to look that up. Okay.
No. But but here they are all of a sudden given every element that we recognize as great wealth and it isn't good enough for them. It is not what they want. What they want is water, what they want is life. And they they don't see it here. And this is this is where that morality
plate really does peak. And this is where I love it as well. Donald thoroughly disgusted it in these old hard dry diamonds
know, makes it a point to call them dry diamonds of all the dirty petrified luck in the world. I mean, is really having tough time about this. That's that's a fun line. Yeah. It is We then see sc turning around and wanting to know what's happened to Don the boys and he starts to get this little regret and he's starting to feel like maybe he's he needs to go look for them, so he takes what he has is the water bag. He sees that the boys are choice absolutely
des. Their lying in the sand. He knows that they're needing water desperately. And this is where I was hoping we would see just a little ray of Uncle Sc their uncle coming to the rescue, But he doesn't let another opportunity pass without driving a hard bargain. He's thinks to himself the above being generous
and I have somebody at my mercy. I drive a hard bargain. And he wants to now trade the water bag for the priceless hourglass
and that look on donald faces. Scrooge just kinda lifting his head out of the sand. It's priceless as well. So take it take... Here's the the key part.
Yeah.
You're right. This is like an opportunity for him to redeem himself. And and I like that at least initially, he did have
that motivation, you know, he wanted to check on family. It's only when he realizes he's got them over a barrel that he kinda reverts to that. So so on the next page, you know, the du of course, they've just... They've already learned their lesson basically Al as Barks wants them to learn it. So they they accept they make the trade of the worthless hourglass
from that priceless
water Barks, because that's what they've just... That's what the desert has just taught them. And so now we transition back to, you know, the shoe being on the other foot.
The the five Ducktales are walking through the desert.
Donald is is kind of foreground the lesson by saying out loud. Well, our dream of Riches has gone fu or flu.
But so wet. I don't know if he says we're happy. And Sc is initially happy as well. He's kinda singing but then he starts to get thirsty and he is
he progressively offers the more and more for just
of water. And the Ducktales tell him that they've had a lesson in what things like golden diamonds are worse. And eventually Scrooge resorts to what what he feels he has to do to offer them the hourglass
back for a drink of water. And
and Donald says that they've been he's been waiting to hear you say that And they just give him the one
instead of taking advantage of. Yeah. I love this part. This is humanity now. Now it's
it's you understand uncle Bridge, what what your greedy nature is done to you. We just wanted to hear you say it. So keep your old hourglass, the water is yours. But with that drink, you have to accept another gift and this is it's kinda a Baffles screw just know what to think. Remember that fishing boat. Well, eat Al Tells Because you have you have to go back on the fish boat it. We see on that last page of the story. The boys are re in it Scrooge accepts it.
I'm sure but then we see Caesar and Samsung taking kim impact on the big fishing boat again as the story wraps up. And yeah that's where
sc now admits that these boys did drive a hard bargain wondered what did you think about the end? I mean, I like, I like the image of the end. It's a funny inversion to see him riding back on that goofy shark boat. I like the lesson and I like the closing of the morality. It is a little packed to me. Right? It it kinda resolves quickly.
I think this one if it had had the, like, four extra pages,
maybe to kind of resolve things that some of the thirty two pager did, It might have risen to some of those heights. Because some of this stuff at the end is a little bit abrupt, but but it's a cool ending
I I do think it works pretty well. I did like it. I I did I reading the story again from the points that we've been talking about. And and Barks his comments on the world at that time and on wealth and greed and excess and capitalism.
Was really deep for me.
To that point, I I find this to be a really good story.
I did like the depiction of of
the Saudi. I think that was really respectful and and a little bit of that that history
explained. I like the mystery of the the oasis and the the Red Sand mystery
brought it to Al adventure level that I thought was great. But I think the big payoff was that like, you were saying it's it's that Donald really having the the wonderful lines at the end about what's important in life
That's I took away from Yeah. I I I think you're right. I I do think that that ending sequence, the sequence right before the end,
that's the stand for me, you know, where they are where where they're
identifying the riches, the things that we would usually think of as rich as as being worthless.
That's really memorable that stands out to me. Like you, I do like the aspect of the Oasis and the hidden raiders there's a lot about this story that works for me. It's hard to get past the like
darkness
that the this sort of, like
it has a very cynical
Yeah. Read on on, like, human nature. And it's not just because I don't like to see sc in this, like, outright villainous
role. You know, that those panels where he's got them over the barrel barb, goes out of his way to draw his features is very devilish. You know? He's got... Yes. With the up turn dies and the point. Yeah. Definitely does. It it's it... That's that's kind of upsetting to me. I mean, it's his character. He can do what he wants, of course. And we know that he's he's just developing him still. But it's weird that there's this darkness in this otherwise, really cool story. And and it only works because of that Barks. This. But... But, yeah, It almost feels like if he had done this later,
this might have been like a
sc and flint long
store. Yeah. A different kind of competition besides because he teams up with the boys,
serving down many more adventures.
Much more friendly and they they kind of tag team on there on their pursuit for
whatever they're looking for. But this one did again, that we earlier, I think Barks was experimenting with Sc a little bit here. How Al I gonna develop this character? I'm certainly going to make comments about what's happening in the world. And
and I think he does a good job with it. Again, it's probably an important story and I wouldn't call it more of my favorite feel good stories, but it's a it's an important story nonetheless in the canon, and I think it has some great great turning points and great plot points some wonderful artwork.
So some like, we pointed out some of the writing was a little bit
some of the slang was maybe to the times in the early fifties.
All that aside. I think it was a it's a good story. Yeah. You mentioned that wonderful artwork. And I think from me what stands out on this one that I really like is the
expressions or or what I really remember, The docs has some great expressions. I I like just even the one just kinda jumping into favorite panels. That that one on the last page with Donald pointing
Al at screen. Oh... Oh, yeah. He's got that same look on his face almost Al screw head. Yeah. Yeah. But but it's more determined than devilish. You know, I I... Or it's it's more of a gotcha. It's a gotcha. It's a definitely a gotcha. Yeah. Yeah. This one is this is a very highly regarded story talking about, you know, how the community
saw that Yeah. What was it, like, number twenty eight or twenty seven? I can't remember? Yeah. As as of right now, because, of course, these these are live results and they fluctuate a little bit, but never too much. It's it's ranked Al twenty eighth on Ducktales.
Which means, you know, there there wouldn't be more than a couple of non Barks stories
below that. So that's good for an eight point one So this is like not quite top top tier, but it's very high tier.
I like you. This is not a favorite of mine, but I recognize it is a great story just because of what the the kind of the themes that it has are very successfully told.
And it's interesting.
I just find it a very uncomfortable
story. I appreciate that it holds up pretty well. For for one that came out in the nineteen fifties and is and is set in,
you know, North Africa
in the in the Western
Sahara because there are a lot of... It definitely has some of these like, exotic and orient
tropes. But you know that that shake that the man who recruits them He's he's a character with his own
perspective of and his own history. I like the Barks
allude to him. You know, he says, you think I'm crazy Al a camel driver as the Gi i's that I freight for in the war with put it. You know, that that was just It was one line, but it was... It really showed him Al like an individual. So I like... It's refreshing. I like him too. He wasn't he he left on on a good terms with Donald nephew wishing them luck. Gave them the water. So he was some... He was he had good intentions. And that's what I liked about that character. And yeah. It was honorable. Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. Right... And and it feels... It definitely feels like a real plan This feels like at least his idea maybe from National Geographic of real world,
north
Northwest Africa.
Do you have any favorite panels that we didn't already kind of highlight warren? Well, I like the I like certainly the opening panel just the the sheer grant of it sets the stage for Barks is talking about. That one is probably my favorite with detail and just welcoming the reader into the story. Al the story shifts around and and finally moves to North Africa. I I do like the Sahara. I the and the Camels. I think they're they're accurately
drawn.
You see a lot of that influence from national geographic, certainly. Yeah.
And, yeah, I I... That's kinda I'm just drawn by that. I would say the the classic fighting donald scene it was something that was just refreshing to scene. Don't see that a lot in Barks stories. You see it in other comics. Yeah. Other depictions. But... Yeah. I would say that overall, oh, and then that when we first Scrooge it kitchen. I thought that was really interesting how all the depiction of the dollar science kept pointing to wealth as something that was was consuming Scrooge in every aspect of his life, including his salt and pepper shaker and is, you know everything. And I like the fact that the the little side panels the...
What you call those were the destiny on the chicken, and they buried the hatch it those panels were
transitions for the story to keep moving. Yeah. Those are kind my memories of this story. I agree Those are cool. I I'd already mentioned that couple of pages or so or they're finding
they're finding the worthless
riches.
Kinda reminded me of that story where Sc, I think it rich as riches everywhere.
And and, you know, he couldn't help but find riches.
But that that really stands out. I don't believe this one ever got the whale painting or lit holographic treatment. No. This one did not. No.
But but this is a really interesting story that demands a careful
reread. I think it has a lot of interesting stuff to say about imperial and and maybe how
how hollow
that search for wealth and that sort of resource extraction that America is... I I mean, this was America's destiny for the next decades really that that bar saw. They were gonna be we were gonna be focused on that red sand.
Well, here's here's the irony here where seventy years later,
He's using the
the red Sand Al an allegory for oil. And just this year, we see this new film come out don't look up which is about the asteroid that's, you know, aiming toward Earth, which is an allegory of climate change. So we're we're we're seeing storyteller
really begging the reader to understand what we're doing and and Barks was doing this seventy years ago. Mh. In a, in a fun, adventurous way but also with a very
important and and meaningful sub going on in the narrative. I I thought it was again, another another proof that storytelling was his art and he was ahead of his time. Yeah. Really spectacular for a a funny animal comment. Awesome. Thank you so much, Warren as always for joining me and
unpacking this interesting and dark
story.
Really enjoyed it. And listeners should join us again next time we're gonna be talking
about
Boy this is gonna take a big left turn. We get to talk about big top and bed one.
We'll have fun with that one. I I appreciate this. This is great. Again, an important story to discuss. I'm glad we were able to,
review it together. Awesome. Thanks so much. Alright. That's that's a wrap.