Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of sc Mc and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge cl of all time, join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context, and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks. Just a quick technical note. This episode has a little bit of audio if C I likes to record during part of the beginning of the episode and had to used my backup recording. But midway through my guest audio should improve a lot. Regardless enjoy the episode. Hello, and welcome back to Barks remarks. I'm Mark Sever marino a grown man who still enjoys donald dot con.
And I am excited to have a new guest host this time to talk about our circus themed story. Guest host. Please introduce yourself. Hey. I'm Dan Sever Mark's, little little brother. Good to be here. Yeah. Thanks a lot. So you know, I I've been... I've been wanting to get you to join me for a while because
I I love to talk about these stories and it's it's a great excuse.
To make people I love, read them. I don't know if you remember me having them litter my room and and the house as we were growing up at all. Oh, definitely, I remember comic box after box, You know, there would be six, seven stacked up on each other.
Very fond go through them. Yeah. I was a big fan. I think you and our other brother James read them occasionally.
I don't think I ever really got you into them. This one may not be the best one
to
get someone into reading Carl Barks. It's it's a it's a bit of an unusual one.
Today, we're gonna be talking about big top Bed.
Which as I mentioned, is a circus themed issue. And
Dan, do you have any kind of opening thoughts on the circus or circus in general? Or are are you a fan of the circus?
I've personally
don't ever remember it going to this circus
even though you told me we went as kids, that's that's about the knowledge I have that. I like certain things like that. Except for the animal part. I I I think Zoos can be fun, but there's always a little bit of guilt going there. That takes away from it. So the animal expert... Long story sure the animal
exploitation can can be a little downer But other than that, you know, the... Everything else sounds like fun. Sure. I think that you're in good company with, you know, the guilt. Over animal
exploitation. Right? Because that's that's what's happened in the last few years.
Yeah. No one likes the circus anymore. We had the big
ring brothers, Barks and Bailey,
whatever basically
stopped touring just just a few years ago. Once they got rid of their... Once they stopped using elephants,
I think they felt like they were
not financially viable. And it's fascinating
to me how, like, this was such a huge part of American life for for a long time for like a century. Right? And and and that's the thing that kinda comes across to me and this issue.
Is the excitement when the circus comes to town. If you think about, like pop culture for so long, there was always this kind of issue or this kind of episode. You know, the circus themed
episode of older Tv shows was a thing
in a way that just isn't anymore. So, you know, that's something we can think about as we dive into the story. I also think that clowns have pretty much fallen out of fashion in these days too.
I know my kids
are my kids have never found clowns to be anything
anything less than horrifying. Maybe that's the fault of Stephen King. I don't know. But again, back back in the fifties, clowns were mischievous and and fun and and accuracy.
And it
they're just not in fashion. So... Yeah. Let's let's talk about a little bit of the background
of big top bed
And this this is a story that came out
The cover date is November of nineteen fifty. So dan, I started,
you know, the podcast about a half year ago. I've been going through these adventure stories chronological,
we've just gotten into the fifties. Right? So that we're in that post war era here. This was printed in four color number
three hundred, and that probably doesn't mean much to you, but four color is this series of one shots and they would feature a different character every month or so, you might have like, bugs bunny one month or one week and one of the Disney characters. And eventually, Donald Duck is gonna get his own series, but for now, Carl Barks stories are just getting published in the the one shot four color series.
I also always like to check out on how many times the story been reprinted because it kinda gives you an idea of the popularity.
This one if you count the original printing, this has only been reprinted five times, which is much less, much fewer than
most of the stories that I've covered which usually range between like, eight and twelve reprint. So I suspect that this one just doesn't seem that relevant
for the for the publishers
who
reprint these. Because that's very few over the last what seventy years now? Yeah. This is a twenty eight pager. Pretty average
for these
stories. And let's a little bit little bit of background trivia. This is one of the last stories that Carl Barks is gonna do that features human looking care.
Yeah. I don't know if that stood out to you. But usually, the Barks stories will feature that kind of Disney like dog knows for the background care.
I did notice that with some of the
a couple of the people on the street, I believe. Mh.
Yeah. Right. Right. And and and Zip himself
is human. And and these characters are all human is kind of the position of Barks. They're just some of them are humans that look like ducks, some Huey, humans that look like dogs. But Al at one point, his publisher basically said stop drawing regular humans it's distracting. Okay. So, yeah. We're we're just a few stories away from that.
And then I I noticed looking this one up that the cover first off, he he did not get to draw the cover for this originally. It was done by I think one of the editors carl B. And the cover actually says that it's an animated cover and there were instructions on the inside for how you can make it move. So I don't I don't have any insight on how you actually do that, but a little thing of note. So, Dan, I like to take a little bit of time to kind of pan her to the
international listeners.
By mentioning some of the titles from around the world. And let me let me go ahead and drop one in the chat.
And if you don't mind, I will ask you to read this one. I'm gonna give you the German title
Go ahead. Hit me with your best. This is the German title. Okay. D
no.
I have taken six semesters of a chairman.
That one is a little bit above me. I can I can run it through Google translate. I usually have. I double check myself on the Spanish anyway. Oh, yeah. I actually knew what y meant from our recent one, the trail of the unicorn, because I looked it up before, and and that means the hunt oh like yeah your hunter. Right. And that last word is bro. Right? I like
little out at that one. Right. I why would you be it's that little it's that Al little pin of daisy. So that's Al that's a pretty weird title. Right? Because that's like not
of approach. Yeah. That's not the point of the story at all. Alright. What's our title in Spain. This is called
Is see.
And
like you, I I do speak this language, but I have no idea what Al auto means. I know N
Is in the circus. Oh Al
is uproar. Oh okay. That's a pretty good translation of the word bed I'd say. Yeah. That's what I was thinking Yeah. Let's let's see. We'll go one more. I'll do... This is interesting. France has a couple of different titles, but it looks like the most
common one is
chat var
on deli.
So Google Translate is failing me. I'm gonna guess that it's circus in Deli. Because it's just saying Sorry var again? Yeah. It's like a a a per raid. So I think it's probably a slang term for circus. So anyway, notable appearances in this one, I would say are only real notable appearance.
I mean, I guess we've got daisy in this one, I don't get to do many of these stories that have Daisy. But our quick change artist
Zip. Yeah. So he's he's pretty notable. He's definitely a character. Yeah. I definitely will have some thoughts on him, but... Yeah.
So, Dan, I usually have a lot of kind of historical or geographical context to talk about in the background for these stories. But I mean, apart from just being fascinated by how the circus was this huge American institution and then basically
side, this really noble death.
I don't I don't really have too much to say about this background wise. So let's just launch into the story self. Alright? Yeah good. Awesome. So, you know, here and there, this this one is is a lot more slaps stick. It's kinda filled with mayhem so I might I might summarize a little more than I usually do. But big top bedroom opens up. I I actually really like this opening. Right? It it feels very quintessential all American. It's got the Ducktales enjoying some fishing and they see the circus train crossing this, like, beautiful tres bridge
pulling into town. The Ducktales very excited at the prospect of seeing the circus. And and you know, I think this was one of those, like, very American experiences. When the circus came to town
historically,
people would get so excited.
Sometimes I know that cities would declare, like a holiday. People would just go home, get ready because it was it was just the the big entertainment. So I know it's like a little bit before our time. It was like, you know, the circus or the county fair came of town. You know, it was important years ago, but I think it was more so a little before our time. That was just, you know, it come in big deal, everyone will go type things. Yeah. It was it was a community isn't event. So so the docs drop what they're doing, you know, and they get ready to head to the circus
until Donald realizes that he's broke. But Okay. But he he's gonna... He's got the idea that he's gonna raid a secret money cash. Of his. And so on that next page, you know, they they get home and he
he's kinda revealing his money cash here. And and this is another of those tropes. Right? He's hidden it and a Star can't sa
ten, and I've seen these in old cartoons, but, like, never in real life. And there's a little reference to, you know, there was a previous scare with burglar.
So that's why he was hiding it. No one would look in there and it's pretty stinky. And unfortunately, Donald realizes when he looks in that he'd already raided his money cash to pay the rent. A good reason. Okay. And they note that the only thing in there is an old heir bro
of of da.
And they're all kind of staring at it. They're they're all tempted
because it seems valuable. And Donald is is pondering. Dan, do you mind reading what he says on the very last panel?
He's talking about the bro, and he says I could it for a saw book. But...
Yeah. So... Right. And and that's that's a fun sentence to me. Right? Because, like, hawk is is a very specific thing you do when you pawn something. Do you know what do you know what the sa is dan? I do. A ten dollar bill. Yeah. I I I just I like that. It feels very dated in a kind of a charming way. But I'll tell you before we proceed, this setup
stresses me out. I hate this trope. When anyone does it, when when someone is going to pawn, something that belongs to someone else, I hate it. Yeah. Because you know where the story is going. Yeah. Alright. So on the third page, you know, Donald does kind of rationalizing,
you know, the the timing and and how, okay. He could do it. Huey, can he can hack it and he can have it back in time. And and so he decides to do it. Right? Because this is important. It's the circus. It's in town. And Donald is heading towards the pawn shop. We assume
he's kind of
rep by the bro because it's it smells like sardines. So he's tossing it around a little bit to air it out. And
he we get one of those, like, pod piper moments. Right? He doesn't
realize that he is starting to attract all of the Al cats in the Vicinity.
And.
And one of them snatch it in mid air and runs off with it. And, you know, here we got. Good to cat. Yeah. Yeah. Why I wouldn't it. So this is a fun little page again. Kind of a stressful setup. In short order on the fourth page, Donald is chasing the cat through the city
he grabs it by the tail on a bridge
and the bro is lost into the river. And well i I I found interesting that the cat. Just the noise it makes the e.
Yeah. Just that sound effect. I was trying to imagine how that would sound from a cat. Right. Well,
anytime you're walking through the house in the dark and you step on its tail, I imagine that's it.
So on the End of this page, we get this, like, immediate
fulfillment of the trope. You know? It's not... This is total happens stance. Right? Daisy,
enters the scene at at the worst possible time. Donald is horrified
to see her. So he's just accelerating this. You know, I'm I'm snapping my fingers probably obnoxious into the
microphone. But this is just advancing the story really quick wait. Do you mind telling us what Daisy wants from Donald here? Well, she begin saying she was on the way to your house.
Al sure enough. She wants her bro.
Exactly. She she wants the bro. It's incredibly convenient, and Donald makes a snap decision here. He is going to tell lie
about a large a great big man who knocked him down and took off with it. Again, this is that kind of trope that I find very stressful, very uncomfortable. I I hate the character gets caught you know why and has to cover it. I know. So Daisy
responds very predictably.
Right? She she wants to call the police as as you might suspect, and she makes the
she infer that people from the circus came into town. Right? They're they're well known. I'm I'm sure it's a reputation like like, carney or people who work at the fair, you know, they're fly by night. So she suspects that someone from the circus must have done it and she haul donald off to to go call the cops and and get it. Yeah. I mean, she just has such an in sense about her and you can't help, but
you know, just know. She's she just... She's so well meaning. And he just feel bad that she can't find her approach you know, she has no e inkling that her boy
possibly did something with it. Yeah. You're you're right. She looks very innocent. She's very bright eyed. When she when she comes on see. What do you... I just noticed, what do you think of her hop? That is very noticeable. It looks like
a pile of fruit makes to the flower. Right. I don't know if it's supposed to be like a Carmen miranda thing.
I will say Barks doesn't doesn't do a ton of women characters.
Sometimes, daisy is not depicted I would say with the most I don't know that he always knows what to do with her, but
Al looks like she's got some, like
fashion here or something. So
she drags him to the circus.
Or rather, she's dragging him towards the the police. And he says that, you know, he thinks he can get it back and and he basically ends up talking
himself into a corner. Right? Where she... Where she gives in the ultimatum. Alright. We're right here by the circus. You go and get that. Where you recover my bro,
don't come back without it or I will call the police. And so he's just kinda standing around feeling sorry for himself at the periphery of the surface.
And he chances. He's he's kind of thinking to himself that there's no chance in a million that he's ever gonna see that pen. And right as he's thinking that he smells sardines, and he sees a guy tossing Daisy pin up and down. What else about interesting
funny when he, you know, welcomes the lion and to I eat for lunch. That's how that's how much You gonna bind. He thinks he feels said. Yeah. Yeah he's, like sitting right in front of the lions cage. And and Dan, I I already kind of alluded that this is not my favorite of his stories. I really do enjoy a lot of this background arc. Al lot of the, like,
illustrations
showing the surface itself... Did too. So
Donald takes off on the next page after this random guy. And he kind of start him. He alarms him a little bit because the guy
slips under the the big top tent and
Donald follows him and Donald can't tell. The the first person that Donald encounters
he's dressed pretty stereotypical,
he's got what seems to be a turban he's speaks with, like, a pretty unfortunate
sort of pigeon dialect. And we can tell that it's the guy that it's the guy that he was following. Yeah. That Donald doesn't know Right. So we get that guy's perspective for just a moment, and he says that how that duck sure wants to see me about some So we we can tell right away that this guy
seems to be part of the circus. Quick change seems to be what he's good at. And he doesn't wanna be caught. Yeah. Is a quick change artist.
Right. And on the next page, we see him enter a tent that gives his little, like, mini bio and it labels him. Tell tell dan what
how he's how he's labeled Zip world fastest quit change artists and it says keep out. Right. So he's
he's probably the star of the circus. Right? Donald is
tearing all about the circus looking for this guy and causing a bit of a commotion and he essentially gets kicked around into realizing that if he wants to be able to look for this guy without getting bothered, he's gonna need to get a job.
Lot of really interesting panels on this one. You know, we we've got Donald walking past Al lovingly drawn elephant
And then in the very next panel, there's really a a pretty awful
representation of
of a black person
with the the capture of big lips. I I think that the the reprint of this dam that I read that was published and I'm gonna say eighty
seven or so. I'm pretty sure that it had censored. You had, like, tried to clean up that image. Is the one I'm shack sharing with you is the original the scan scan of the original from nineteen fifty. Yeah. It's
not the most flattering image. But no. It's it's it's pretty bad.
Fortunately, it's it's it's pretty brief and it's not that importance to the story. But the ring master says that he can be bull cooked to the elephants.
I don't know that means
But we see a suspicious looking man next to the Ring master, telling him that, you know, little guys got some talent, and you should let me use him in the clown act and
we do see that that's zip and casually toss and that bro up and down.
And on the next page, we transitioned back to the nephews stand. Do you want tell us a little bit about what the nephews user are up to? They are
upset because they want to go to the circus themselves and they think Donald just leaving them
leaving them Right. You were telling me before we started a recording
that you were kinda surprised with the nephews in this one. Yeah.
I don't think I've seen
this sort of hostility they show towards Donald
and other stories as say as i show and this one is...
Yeah. You're right. They're they're pretty
sour towards him. They're they're don't usually see them with that kind angry expression that they'll have through a lot of this one. And they're mischievous a lot especially in the older stories, but they're like, they're almost mcdonald's foil. In this one. Yeah. I mean, Zip is just real foil, but they're like this
extra,
you know, source of
And what Barks does in these stories is he really does adjust the characters as he needs to. And he just wants to tell the story this time. Right? So he just needed them to have this dynamic I suspect. I think that's part of why this story doesn't work for me that. Well, I don't I don't really like to see them as hostile as they... Yeah. I to seeing them.
And anyways, the be the adult to him and come through come through for him when he's in a bias Right. Yeah. That's a good point because they're usually very resourceful and they do sometimes save the day like the adults.
So they they decide to dip into their own stage. So they had to the circus
themselves and
we transition to Showtime
really beautiful drawing of
of an elephant and a dancing girl and some other performers
coming out and sort of old circus ga. Yeah. The elephant has a very
natural hooked to it, especially in its eyes where it's it's got that wild look. It's not a goofy elephant or anything like that. Yeah. You're right. It's it's very realistic.
You know, we we get the Nephew point of view at this point after the Rem master introduces
the circus. And they're just enjoying this spectacle and its some point, they see Donald
walking out dressed as clown.
And they're instantly
in infuriated
because they they have put two and two together and they're assuming that he, you know, forgot about them to get
himself this plush job in the circus,
and they're man sing holding up a sling.
Basically, this is setting us up for most of the rest of this story where Donald is going to be looking for the bro and the guy who has the bro
and nephews are gonna be looking for an opportunity to basically mess him up. Anytime Al slingshot comes out, you know, mischief is kinda follow. Right. And and that's another big marker of this era. Right? Because in the nineteen fifties, this was a totally normal thing for a kid to have and we really don't see them these days. And so on the next page, you know, we
realized that the...
Person doing the introduction has actually
been zip
himself and he changes he changes from his ring master guys into something that looks like I guess Napoleon bonaparte
and he immediately
proceeds to basically give Donald the works.
He fling him onto a little bicycle
and he launches him
onto the high wire, and we're gonna get all of this kind of like circus
slaps stick. And I'm trying to decide, like, none of it is very narrative at this point. Right, Dan? No. No. There isn't much narration. It's just
it came pretty abruptly.
You know, It just started throwing him on
Circus acts, basically, but there's there's no, like, now I'm going to put him on this. Now I'm going to... Right. So like, the this one is is an unusual story. It actually kinda reminds me way back at the very beginning of of doing the podcast I talked about Donald Duck finds pirate gold, which is a story that he did. I it was originally supposed to be a Donald Duck cartoon.
And this kinda of reminds me of of that. Right? Is it's almost like a cartoon story board here, because
it's it's just a lot of slaps stick We have Donald being put into some sort of circus peril. We've got zip
changing into some new disguise.
On the next page, you know, Donald is kind of biking really high on the on the high wire,
zip
transforms into a gorilla ton falls.
There's some cool perspectives on this page, I guess. Yeah. The... The the change the gorilla is pretty impressive itself... Yeah. And what we're gonna see is donald
catching side of the bro.
Zip wondering
how Donald keeps knowing that it's him and why he's coming after him. And then Nephew being sour about the crowd
being impressed with Donald.
And looking for the opportunity to to pay him. So... Yeah. Then you can mention that he reads he stinks. Right. Yeah. And and so we kinda keep transitioning this way. Zip changes into a firefighter fighter, he kind of terror Donald with some
clown mischief
on the next page, Donald is like retaining water in his clown suit and zip
changes tell me about his that that quick change is is pretty surprising. I think. Oh, yeah. The devil that was that was it's almost creepy, you know Like just surprising, you know. Right. Because he's, like a a devil with underwear or nothing, but.
It's it's pretty weird. It's it's it's some neat nimble drawing. Any poke semi
with his pitch for it because trident whatever and he he leaders he jira that he's leaking like, a water wagon which I think is another
dated reference.
And i was clearly just humiliated.
Right. On the next page, we get another quick change where he's dressed like a skeleton, which makes Donald think that he's pulled everything off except his bones. And one of the clowns has him run through a little paper target right into right onto a donkey keys back. And and then onto to the next page, Donald is always a step behind Zip right who zip directs him to put his head into, like, a little portal where he gets... He gets the classic custard pie. Thrown at him by a clown, custard or lemon? Yes. Yes. And we get one custard and one lemon. And then that user just... They're not enjoying this show at all. Right?
No. They think he's having a good time, but... Right. And one of the Nephews is still biting his time waiting for an opportunity to to peg him with another sling.
And all this like Mayhem and Slaps kind of escalate
that we haven't really alluded yet that
Zip thinks
Donald a bill collect. Yes.
That's a good point. Right? The reason that Zip is trying to avoid him is because he surmise that he's a debt collector, and he says that
he's never paid a debt before.
So all of this slaps to kind of
escalate
into this big gag he zip lures donald into
really
impressive looking cannon that is is clearly the classic surface trick, the human cannonball ball. Yeah. And
this this is gonna be an opportunity for the Nephews.
Right? Because Zip wants to launch him for the crowds benefit,
but
whichever angry nephew
has the slingshot,
to tell what what ends up happening
it seems Zip is going to give him like a regular launch, but somehow
correct one of the nephews is able to time it So he peg Zip in the rear, makes zip
sort of sq and
launch him full blast It's exactly right. He gives him a really mighty launch
onto the next page. You know, he ends up landing
outside of the circus tent. And this is Donald head enough. He's gonna quit the circus even if it means not getting that pin back And he's kind of mu over his bad luck, you know, walking around all objectively.
And he happens
on the little poster
advertising zip,
and he puts he finally puts two two together. Do you mind reading that last pack panel for us. I get it I catch on quick. That's the guy that has that has the pin zip. It was all those guys, so he knew he's the same person and.
So I I I like that a lot Right? Where he says he catches on quick. Yeah. And clearly, you know, I don't know how many is mayhem we just went through, but it was definitely the bulk of the story there. Yeah. So Donald decides to lie and wait.
You know, till the end of the show, he's gonna hide on the next page in Zip
chest. And we transition back nephews who are like too demo
to watch the rest of the show. So they leave bit early.
And we get to see Zip
in the end of his act.
And
it's it's a pretty cool finale dan. You wanna tell us about it Yeah. Yeah. He he just zips in and out.
Really quick. I mean, he's a fast quick change artist, so he's able to go from Native American to well, it looks like could be like a Spanish bowl. I don't know. Yeah. Yeah. I think you're right. Then finally, to what appears be like, a beautiful woman. And
think that native Americans meant to look like the old Cigar store Indians. Have you ever seen those? Yeah. Yeah. I have
So the the crowd is... This this is a fitting grand finale. Everyone's very excited.
And it's very key that he's finished by transforming
to a woman there. Right? Because when we transitioned back to Donald waiting in ambush
what happens?
Well, he he jumps at him and
immediately regrets it because he thinks he's
rushing a woman. Right. Right. And and
Zip disguised as the woman
says you thought what? Get out you mash... I I like that. That's such an outdated term. Yeah. I I don't... I mean, I have an idea what they mean by that, but I don't know the even that term in that sense. It's a very gentle way of
describing a man who tries sick advantage of a woman I think. I see. Oh, that's funny because that zip goes that far with it. Right. And
so Donald Donald gets
hung up as he tries to frantically get him out of this himself out of this pretty awkward situation. He gets caught up on Pin and he says what Pin
Donald says. And on on the next page, zip was telling him about this pin that fell on him
while he was swimming under the bridge, that very morning. And so Donald has figured out you know, we we kinda transitioned so them having kind of a nice moment. Dan you mind telling us about their little moment together? Yeah. I mean, they're the laughing of the story.
These
you know, Zip says, oh, I I thought you were a bill collector and it's... Oh, I thought you're you were one of the people who are after me over some of the like un moral things I did, but you're not. So that's great or so right. Right. Yeah.
They're very buddy buddy very quickly, considering all the mayhem that they just went through. Mh. And so Donald
heads off thinking of, you know, thinking of ward off Daisy anger,
So as he crosses the bridge on the way back, the the boys,
spy him. They're back to their fishing.
One of the Nephews
is is the only one who didn't get a chance with the slingshot.
And and we're gonna see it go right back into the into the drink. Al as the Nephew
hits him swear on, he loses the bro and back into the river and he's extremely d.
So he decides that his only option is to go and until Daisy the truth. So This is kinda of one of those things where you're like.
You could've have done it that at the very beginning, but obviously, we wouldn't have had our slaps stage story. Well, at least he learned his lesson sure. So he goes back hat in hands ready to confess to Daisy.
And he
explains the story
and and the narration box makes sure to Al us that he he tells her everything.
You know, that his his original plan to hoc the Pin. The his his encounter with Zip. And Daisy
reacts. Could could you tell us stan about her reaction? Yeah. But she gets hysterical and
says that she wanted to go
Club banquet.
I guess she wanted the the bro. Was it to be Al classy at the museum? Or was was right Yeah. I think it was meant to be her, like, for Al little show piece. Right? Because it's a family heir.
And Donald has this moment of wait. We
because she allude to you were gonna take me to the banquet
and
We got we got this over the top like, sort of domestic
strife
internal monologue where Ton is saying, oh, could anything have been more awful?
He says any punishment will be easy to take now. This is
his internal monologue.
He what does he offer daisy, see, Dan?
Just says can you take the rolling pin and
massage my scalp, I think he says. Yeah. It's a good... It's a good line. Giving me a good old
goal massage
yeah. I'm implying, you know, go ahead beat me with this rolling pin. It's obviously,
like, over the top for a comic effect. It's still it's very uncomfortable and hindsight. Right? Yeah. Like, it's these old comics from this era. There was a lot of, like humor in...
I don't wanna call it domestic violence exactly because it's coming from such a slaps stick point of view
on the face of it, though, it is
domestic violence. That's definitely partner abuse. There's also a lot of joking about corporal punishments.
In in these stories, you know, kids getting
span and more like hit with switches. So this is just don't I don't know about you. That this is not the kind of thing that I really find as funny these days, but it was it was a totally mainstream
trope. Yeah. I view it more Al a trope. I mean, I didn't find it particularly funny, but
you you can see that he's just
happy to not be going and that's not have to go there. That the the beating is zone take is is
preferable.
Right.
And it is pretty funny to me. Daisy reaction. Right? How she's basically...
Because he told the truth finally,
She thinks that he's suffered enough.
Not only
is she not going to continue to be mad Al him. But
she actually wants to cook him up a a really nice dinner.
Tell tell us about what she offers to make him. She offers young quail on dumplings.
Right. Give blood of young and dumplings.
And and so he's just ex.
He is
so
happy about out. This this turned out best paced scenario for him when all is said and done. And
Unfortunately, the doorbell...
The buzzer sounds
and
is is gonna rain on his parade.
Because
on the next page as Daisy goes to see who it is,
Donald
start a little bit to hear her greeting Hue Louie and Dewey. And
and tell us,
tell us what he doing in Louis. Present to today's. Well, they...
What they found inside of fish they caught was
the very same pendant that Donald for the second time dropped into the river.
Right. So we have just all these crazy one and a million
coincidence.
Right? It's all ver one in a million. So... Yeah. I guess the... I guess the story is pretty consistent on that aspect expect. And then we get, you know, Daisy, of course is delighted and and the closing panel
has
Donald and Daisy at this museum ban it and
everyone at that museum
is just this sort of, like, high
society
weirdo,
essentially. It's it's all these dope looking
rich people
listening to a professor keep minds telling us what he's what he's
po
about dan.
He's seen regional artifacts of the early far era contained the most interest. Worn holes, blah blah
a white barbie and I like that rub rhubarb. That's very Barks.
And Donald is just doing over this incredibly
ban boring bit of high society torture that he's
to you know, it's it's one boring evening,
right? And probably a pretty good free meal, but... But that is that is big top Bed.
So, Dan, what what are your what are your thoughts about this story?
I I think Zip is... you know, he's like at first, you see as an antagonist, but at the same time, not really, he's just a guy that's caught up in his own
his own
game and...
But I also thought, like a a quick change artist. Is is that like actually a thing. I think back when you had, like circus,
it probably was more of... I I know. I can't imagine, like, going
to see some live entertainment that involved
that unless it was like a concert where someone was also singing or dancing.
Yeah. But Yeah. I mean, it's it's good. You know, even there was... I even saw some, like, innocent innocence and Donald in the same way I saw it in Daisy when he keeps falling for the prank.
It just feel like he's a little trusting
even even in his position. So... Yeah. So
I don't know. Like, usually, when I have someone start the podcast, I like to give them a pretty intriguing story. This one, unfortunately, is not not one of my favorites, but it I think it's an interesting one to talk about I'm gonna have to make you read some of the some of my favorites because this one is so slaps stick. And yeah. So odd
that
it really stands apart.
And like i'm I'm sure for that reason that it's some people's favorites,
but I know that I didn't really come back and and read this one very often as kid. I think I probably haven't read this one in a good twenty five or so years. Yeah. Some of the other ones you've shown me are definitely
more adventurous. They go travel
you know, to australia or canada
or something like that. And this was more of just
a day at the circus.
And, I don't I don't have a problem with that. Like, they don't all have to be adventure stories, but, like, it's so not Monday mundane. But it's like it's just very
little. He it it feels more like one of his ten page gag stories. Because a lot of his stories. Most of them are much shorter stories that are meant to be more slaps like this one. So this one kinda feels like a a ten page gag story that's been stretched out and just has this really interesting setting? Yeah. And I I do think that the art is pretty cool on this one,
it's
it's got some... It's got some fun stuff. But but again, this one's really not not a favorite of mine. Yeah. Yeah. So just a few more reflections, you know, I think that it was almost
required that at some point he do a circus. Story. Right? Because it was it was like being a kids show at the time you would... You have your Cowboy
episode.
Okay.
A kids show today would have like, a time travel episode.
You might have, like,
it's it's just one of those tropes that you had to do. It's like having a haunted house
issue or episode. So as far as that goes, it works okay. Other Disney media, like I I really like the old Dumb cartoon.
You know, that's a fun circus set thing. Yeah. Wonder. I I expect that that was probably something that he was thinking about as he did this one. Dan when I reflect on these, I I like to think about how well these stories hold up, you know, if there's stuff that's like dated or archaic? We talked a lot about this, but it it really bears
repeating
that the circus is almost
completely irrelevant
today. And and just how incredibly quickly that happened, it still blows my mind, right? That this story seemed like a normal
thing to write about and to draw an issue about and no one thinks about surfaces
anymore. Yeah. I think
I think today's kids would probably find a circus to be very boring
to be honest. I have but rather.
Hit much rather look... Look up some some silly tricks on Youtube
and I can't say I blame them in some ways.
We know there were a few retro things in this some some problematic
depictions. But
fortunately,
the story didn't really
ride too too hard on it. And and there there wasn't even a lot of the, like, animal
angle of the... Like, there was an elephant and there was a lion, but most of the circus stuff was even human performers. Yeah. Specifically Donald. Right.
I I like mention if there... If Barks was famous for doing oil paintings and lit wraps that went along with some of the stories. He
to my knowledge, he never did one for this story.
And I'm not aware of, like, any Ducktales or other cartoons that tried to adapt this. I didn't ask you
to keep a favorite panel in mind, which I usually do. So I don't know if anything comes to mind. So one of the panels that I actually really liked
was kind of a mundane one. It was his like, relieved expression
near the end where he's, like, thinking about how we dodged a bullet and saying, could anything have been more awful? I actually i like that one.
Yeah. There's also a lot of really high angled shots, you know, him him up at the trap he's during one of those slaps state moments was pretty cool. Also
overlooking the the river at the top of the bridge as the bro
p in the water for the last time. I also really like the panel that
showed the perspective of the canon for the human
and involved that one was really yeah. I mean, I particularly just like some of the scenery in the in the beginning with the bridge, and
they paint really well the opening and it's got the the old fish sticks where it's like
edition poles? Yeah. They have no real. It's just a stick with the line on it and a hook. Yeah. I agree. That that's that's a pretty awesome panel.
And it's it's so
quintessential
mid
twentieth century there. Right, the circuit train in the background, the fishing and pulls.
Yeah. Like, that's just it's good old wholesome fun. You know, they're they're and around talking, while fishing, you know, there's couple
brothers just at the fishing hole basically. Yeah. That's the name panel. Any other thoughts about this one again. No. Not particularly. I thought I was pretty straightforward. You know,
like, I I did happen to like Zip.
The part at the end, there's only three little
panels where it shows them, you know,
socializing and having a good time, but it's it was a little heartwarming to see that there was was no
bad feelings between the two of them. Yeah. That's true. Zip wasn't like,
of villain. Right? He was exactly. He he kinda reminds me of, like, low key from the marvel movies, you know,
haven't seen it.
Well, he's got kind of that, like, tricks
energy that
that loki does, I guess. He's he's a bit of a anti hero I'd say. Yeah. Excellent. Why I really appreciate you joining me for one of these. I'll have to forced you to read a couple a couple of the others that I think pulled up better. I don't think this is a bad story per s. It's just it's just such Al like
artifact. Oh, and you know, I almost forgot to mention what the community itself thinks of
So Dan, what what I also like to do. There's a really neat resource called Index instead of index, very clever, where
people can vote.
And they can rank rate the stories.
And so if you look at the story, the rating for this one. Mh. Response pretty well regarded by the community has a seven point seven out of ten, which is good for
one hundred and thirty eight.
Place,
that ranks all the Disney
stories, the disney comic stories that have pretty much ever been published, which is some like forty one thousand some of them. Oh wow. Yeah. The Barks stories they do tend to rate very high and he did he did over five hundred stories. So to be one hundred and thirty eight. You gotta figure at least half of those are non
stories.
It's it's well regarded. It's obviously not regarded as one of the all time greats. But but this is from his kind of his golden era. So so and obviously
hands up holds up well for for many members of the community.
Yeah. So so, yeah, I I think this one's worthwhile,
especially if you're a Barks man. I don't think I'm likely to revisit any time soon, but but I'm glad I could
I could remember it and and enjoy some some pretty great art. Absolutely. The are are it's really good in this one. It it stands out pretty pretty...
I mean, the colors they use are very pastel like So... Yeah. Yeah. You know, Barks
himself wouldn't colored these. He would have drawn them in black and white. So a good color
was really important to, like, bring these out. But again, I really appreciate you coming on. I hope that I can get you back for another of these. Of course.
I appreciate you having me. And I I I'd love to come back, you know,
maybe a little less nervous. Like that didn't show it all. Well, I'm I'm glad I could... I'm glad I could voice
another of these stories
on on friends and family. So thanks again. I hope that listeners
will
join us next time
When we get to talk about one of his all time great Christmas stories, you can't guess. People can reach out Al Barks remark. At gmail dot com or on our Facebook page.
And I would I would tell everyone to go out and enjoy a day at the circus. But
really clear.
I'll you're looking forward. Awesome. Alright.