Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Mc Ducktales writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge con of all time. Join us as we have explore has longer adventure stories in their chronological publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical contacts. And how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Welcome back to Barks remarks. We've got a special Christmas in February edition of the podcast.
As I've got multiple guests with me to discuss Barks Christmas classic,
you can't guess. Why don't so we hear introductions
from Warren? Hey. Mark would to be back again? I am a Carl Bark Fan and donald debt collector living in
Snowy Rochester, Minnesota and great to be back for this this fun story. Thanks for being back. Hi. I'm Sarah, Santiago.
Usually, I come in as some random jack of Al trades, but this one didn't really come up with a topic except, like, receiving gifts.
As a something I could be an expert on, but I'm happy to
you know, bring my experiences.
My lived experience is receiving gifts to this podcast. Yeah. Are you are you guys more of the give or receiver of gift? I am definitely fine joy in giving, but I'll tell you. I do love, especially when you have two small grandchildren and nothing beats that reaction. Yeah. There there's nothing like like giving gifts to kids. I I love giving gifts to kids, I find giving gifts to adults a little bit stressful.
But when when you nail it, I I feel like that is really satisfying. Yeah. So
this this one really is about gift giving. Right? This one is a lot of fun. As as mentioned, we're talking today about you can't guess And, you know, it's it's snowing outside so I can pretend that it's seasonally appropriate, but it is important to me to to release these chronological
in order at least with these long form stories, thus are a little Christmas in February,
and
I I really enjoyed this one as a kid. I've got some pretty fun memories of this. Warren is this one that you hadn't visited in a while or
Well, I'm so glad you asked me to help out with this one because when you told me about it, I went. I don't know that story. I don't think so then I went back and I looked at it went oh that story. That's the one. I I ate this up as a kid. This was one of my favorite stories for a lot of reasons which we'll get into. But... Yeah, it... I didn't know the name of it. That was my problem. I... It's right there on the flash page, but I I did grow up with this story, and I have a lot of fun memories. Yeah that's true. It took me... I I I hadn't really internalized the title for this one because it's pretty generic. Right? You can't guess. But but it's a fun little bit of wish full fulfillment.
Some of the Barks stories, I think are at their best when when they let you kind of feel like a kid
imagining yourself in in the Nephews position.
So a little bit of background about this one.
This one was released. This was released in October of nineteen fifth be in the publication Christmas
parade. It'll be interesting maybe to consider warren because I know you've read this one how you think this stacks up against the other great Christmas plastics. And Sarah, I did have you read another
another Christmas story. Right? You've got to do the Golden Christmas tree. I did. Yeah. This is not my first Donald Duck Christmas rodeo.
So that... Which feels surprising to me. Right? Because
I don't feel like that much time has Al elapsed since you've been doing this podcast, but clearly, you've covered many multiples of years enough so that I've come on and this is my second Christmas
episode. Yeah. It's true. So
Pirate Gold warren, was that in forty
or
well pirate gold was forty two
forty two. That's right. So we're we're up in nineteen fifteen now, late nineteen fifty. So he's gone through a few of these Christmas cycles and
that... That's one of the things about comic books is that they really like to cover Christmas stories because it's an easy hook to sell a story. So so Barb got assigned to do one of these every year.
Whether he liked it or not, I would say,
Sometimes he had a great idea for a Christmas story, and
sometimes maybe he didn't. But but this one is widely considered to be one of the would you say one this is like one of the three great Christmas stories. I'm gonna put it up there. I... It's my favorite of all of them for a lot of reasons, maybe
it doesn't compare to
some of the others, but
in its storytelling
format, but I I like it because it just features so many of the classic characters at the same time. And and and I love the the fact that the Nephews are are really prominent here. Yeah. It it is fun. To see... I I really like the Donald Inducks family.
Story.
Sarah, did you did you enjoy or or was that kind of a notable ass back to this one for you how we got to see kind of the extended Ducktales clan. Yeah. It was glad that you'd
had me on
various
episodes to introduce me to Gladstone
Gander.
So I knew who he was and what his story was when he
when he came in. So I felt like an old pro reading these even though, obviously, this is a lot of my first
exposure to the donald dot com and economics in general. Now I feel like I
I already knew what was going on. Thread that you've got so much needed background. Yeah. So let's see. This one has been
reprinted
Pretty consistently,
I I saw seven reprint including the original for the United States, and it's a twenty eight pager
a little bit of background
trivia about this one warren, feel free to jump in if there's anything that I miss. But This is one of the few remaining stories that does have some human drawn background characters. There's some very
very neat looking
humans in this one. I really like that Donald car
is so prominent in this one. The good old Be fire run about. That's right. Nineteen thirty four Be. That's right. A nineteen thirty four Bell fire run about as he has he titled one of his with the graphs warranty.
Do you have that one? I do. I have two of them. Find. I know why do I have two of them? Well, that was a happy accident, which will say for another podcast.
That's great. I I love his car.
So so that's a fun aspect to this one for me. A little minor detail will see into the story. This is the first time we see Scrooge bathing and a money bathtub
That's right. You know what? I happens to run across for this one. The the rate the Barks was paid for it. Oh tell tell tell us more here. Nut trivia. So I I found this on the...
Is this the c Barks dot d k, I think, page And they said that on May twenty fourth, nineteen fifty, Barks was paid for the stories twenty five pages at his standard page rate of six dollars and fifty cents For the story and twenty two dollars for the art, so seven hundred and twelve dollars and fifty cents all in total. Yeah
Have you figured out inflation and today's dollars, what that would have been, that would be an interesting
exercise wouldn't it? And it what. I'm doing that right now.
That would be worth seven hundred twelve dollars and fifty cents. In nineteen fifty is worth eight thousand three hundred eleven dollars and ninety five cents today. Okay. Pretty good rate. But, you know, when you consider it, he only did... Generally two to three of the the the long ones. A year. I lauren. That's right. He would do the four color series and then these Christmas specials and the fires specials and yeah. Right. So... Yeah. I thought that was cool. Any any other trivia that you found notable that this one lauren? Well, you you already mentioned my one of my favorite donald Inducks props and that would be his car. The classic three thirteen, which many listeners and readers might know that March thirteenth is his unofficial birthday, meaning it's the comic book birthday versus the June ninth
wei little Hyundai.
Nineteen thirty four. But that's... I've always loved the car as well. Let me ask you, Mark,
which issue
did you look at and what color is the card that you're
referencing? Yeah. So I I did this one in there awesome
publication of Christmas parade, number one, and it's yellow and that. Yeah. Yellow here in the Fan graphics one as well, which which is a little different than my recollection of his red car. So I
just a little bit different there. But I love the the pick of the nineteen early fifties late forties these toys. I'm I'm I'm very very fortunate to have color
footage of my father at the age of seven opening up Christmas toys under his Christmas tree And honestly, they're much like what we're seeing in these pictures. Here. Definitely, these toys do feel classic. Right? In a way that the before toys went all digital. This this feels kinda like the default. What of what Christmas toy should look like. Absolutely.
Yeah. They seem very kind of simple and and not branded. Not flashy, you know, not tied to the big toy company or the latest
superhero cartoon. Right? Just toy. That's right. That exact definitely part a big part of the charm. So you guys want want to go for some of the international titles here? Yeah. You like to pan to the international audience?
Warren and why don't you start us off? Well, I'm gonna I'm gonna start off in with our scan friends, and I'm gonna
talk about Norway and Sweden. Let's let's do Norway first. The
Nor norwegian
title of this story is Khan D jet. If that's pronounced right, and it's can you guess. Can.
Sweden is pretty literal. It's neat khan, if the. You can't guess. So they're right right along lines with the the the perfect translation. Right. Straightforward.
How about yours sarah? We have
Germany is guess ones, which is rat and mall.
Mexico though is kind of the outlier and it's Uv
go.
Rain of gifts, which I think is
quite a bit of a spoiler.
Yeah. I like it when
when they don't kinda give... Give away a big element.
When I did vacation time,
a couple episodes,
Eric, The guest and I were commenting on what a generic title it was. Yeah. But but it's it's kind of a nice little treat because it concealed, how dramatic it's gonna turn? And so I've got France which is kai
Pearl Noel. What gift for Christmas is the question that one Barks.
And in Netherlands, the dutch is year rat to
you'll never guess. So but most of them are are just variations on the the regular one. Background,
cultural
context, we can talk about that as we go. But to me, the the most interesting
sort of cultural part of this, is the the place that the famed e set used to hold in the childhood
imagination. They never actually call these construction sets or e sets, I don't think, but that's that's pretty clearly what they are. Yeah. Very very
I never had one as a kid growing up and I'm closest probably to the the demographic of some of these memories. But, yeah, The construction set, they don't use the word. It'll your rec that do they. No. But classic metal parts
I don't think you'll see that much today. Sarah, are you familiar with the classic director set. I know I've heard of them. I never had one. I don't... you know, I was a girl and I had very gender toys and so nobody I knew had one but, you know, I don't know. My sample size may be skewed. Sure. Yeah. I I I didn't have one either, but I know they're very famous for, like, how versatile the they are and and they're... They weren't thought of as, I think it's a really special toy. Right. That you could do anything with. A lot of the kids who got them turned into engineers I suspect. So I I think when we see them in the story we're supposed to think oh, this is like, the big ticket. Toy while also not being like a a licensed
teddy Ru pin or or whatever. I also suggest that it's
precursor to the Legos
of friday today. They're extremely versatile in their
building
ability and other creativity
Right. Yeah. Good point. Alright. So you guys ready to dive into the story itself Let's go toy a shopping. Excellent. Let's do. I'm I'm gonna start us off. This is one where I I left out a little bit of trivia
because this is a really cool opener. Right? This is a big, beautiful
full page
splash panel with the kids peer into
a Toy shop that has some of those
classic looking toys that we were just talking about but it's it's a really nice looking page. It's ornament with little bits of holidays
and this is the last time the last of three, where he gets to do one of these full page
slash panel. It's our other Christmas one letter to Santa has the great opening
with steam shovel vacation time rather. Vacation time, love it with the the animals and the bridge and the... And again, the classic car. So we've got the Nephews looking in the toy Toy shop, and they are
indecisive. They're trying to figure out what they want for Christmas.
And as we transition to them going in the Toy store, we have this, like, kinda heartwarming
conversation between them where they're acknowledging
all of the nice toys that they already have and how Santa Claus has been so good to them every year that they can't think of anything that they really need, and they make this really nice, big hearted as they call it decision that they're gonna skip Christmas.
And so they write Santa a letter and tell him to give their presence to other kids. And I I like this you guys. I thought this was really cute. Really sweet. It's kind of predictable that as soon as they put their
envelope in the Barks, they're gonna... They're gonna see some thing that It was suspicious right away. I was, like, I wrote down.
What's the angle?
U.
Are they gonna be greedy, are they gonna be... Is Donald gonna cause a problem? Like, I hadn't I haven't read enough of these to see what direction
this is gonna lead them. And, you know, often I'm finding, like, even in, like, the simpsons. Right? Like, the first, like, five minutes of the show
sets up them to go in a completely different
direction and has nothing to do with that five... First five minutes Oh, oh, I also was wondering if they were gonna go chase down, the mail truck, are they gonna get in themselves and trouble that way. And then I was like, no, they're a little bit too smart. That's sounds like something Donald would do and the kids would have to rescue him from. So I was on edge honestly.
I was right. Sarah, I was probably a little bit more morally optimistic that these boys were gonna do a good turn and be Al little good junior would check But then again, we would have a pretty boring story wouldn't we.
So
but what a noble gesture? I just love those panels of of sheer joy in doing something nice for someone else
talks about how not simple that their lives are, but not in a derogatory way. Right? Like Right. They know that they're cared for... They have all of their needs met. They have it
they haven't realized how much of a parent they've become. So they don't worry about wider issues like, bills or whatever. Right? They're just like we have everything we need and it's these toys,
and we're solid.
Yeah. I I think that's a really good point. I think this really paints a picture of some kids who feel comfortable purple and secure. Barks is obviously
positioning them to be good at the beginning of this story. Right? Sometimes he positions them to set them up to be missed mischievous. So he he doesn't use different characters for that. He'll just
decide the kind of the version of characters.
That he want. And so as they leave as they mailed their letter, they see
a toy that they don't already have that they realize Oh, actually, this is something we've always want. It's a building set. And again, it is a e set. I think that's a branded word. At this time. But but we are meant to see this as the big hot toy for many decades in fact, and we see these really cool instructions, you know, in the display shop. There's a ferris wheel and a crane.
These are things you can really do if So they they realized that they've got a rush back, stop the mailman man, but it's too late. And this is all basically been a nice set up to the fact that Now, they can't depend on Santa claus. They've gotta ask their uncle Donald to see if he'll buy one for them. And so we're kinda side stepping Santa. For this Christmas story. Right. And they they race home,
optimistic that Uncle donald will bail them out.
So they see Don shoveling snow. They humbly walk up to him and and then I love the the faces on these and nephews. Now they they... They're just all please
not begging
quite so much, but asking donald for the
opportunity to buy something for them. And donald this is kinda clueless as to what's going on. You want me to guess Oh, no Tell you, and they they explained that they do want this new buildings that they saw. And the donald
is is I kinda like his parental
choices here. He's saying, well, you know, I don't believe in giving things so easily. Let's we'll have to do something to earn it, then I thought that was pretty cool. So they start wanting to do whatever it takes. Chores around the house. Nope. You don't get my point he says when they asked to shovel snow or do whatever. You should not have to work you should have to worry. That wasn't interesting, like, why?
It's Sarah
Yeah. We're all kinda making, like,
faces. Half marie.
Was so mad. That was a poor choice of words mister Barks. I don't know.
What you think was going on there, I mean, that's such a... I was as you were talking and you're were, like, you know, they're gonna tell them what what they really want. I was thinking about the spice girls. So tell me what you want what you really would want? And donald like, no, you have to guess. I want you to worry.
I'm glad warren that you read that. Lying out. Right? Because that that really
struck me every time I read it you... You should... I don't mean you should have to work. You should have to worry. All I can come up with is that Barks really wanted to set this
specific product.
I don't think he found an elegant way to do it So he made donald Al little bit a little bit of a jerk here Right? Because he's he's toy with them. It's it's weird,
but it does... It does set up what he wants. And I do like I really like this lot elements, right, where they have to guess what he wants, I think it's really fun. I think it's really intrigued. I don't think it's set up in the most elegant way. Although, you know, it's not that weird are donald, I guess. But when you look at the very next panel after that odd statement, which which we all reacted to. I love what Donald says in the first line. Well, let me put it this way. That's what he says. Let me put it this way. So he clears the air a little bit and says you'll have to guess what I want and I'll buy what you want. And I thought that was... Okay. Now we've set up the story. Right. It's very... I'm sorry To interrupt it. It's it's it's a good little bit of economical storytelling.
I just wanna ask you guys, do you think it's generous to to think that maybe Donald wants them to kind of practice some like empathy put themselves in his purse perspective and and be like, oh, there are things that don.
You're shaking your head sarah. No. This is this is totally in character for Donald. Right? Donald has poor boundaries. He makes his problems everybody's problems. One of the
Barks of poor boundaries is not using your words expect
people to be mind readers and then being upset when they can't read your mind. Right? So obviously, he's not be becoming upset when they can't read his mind, but he's still putting the burden
of communication and and reading his minds on the kit Right, sarah. And I'm gonna go up one level deeper and say, we have just seen some selfish on b on behalf of the Nephews and now we're seeing donald Salt as well. And I'm... There's an underlying little underlying theme of selfish going on here. Would you agree? I would say that it's more age appropriate for the kids.
I think that Mark is right that, you know, like, we should be teaching kids, like,
have some empathy think about, you know, somebody else's experience besides yourself, but we already know they can do that because that's why they come to him in the first place because they've already told San to give their presence to somebody else like, why
why?
Is not question.
Yeah. Good. Yeah. He's he's being very selfish and he is acting like a child. And they're also, you know, they want something, and that's okay. And they're acting age appropriately. And I will say that we now know that the Nephews have always had one up donald in many ways and so they're they're sort of intellectual piers if not a little bit superior that way. So the next panel is so you want us to guess it are very excited because I think they know they can guess and donald says, yep. You just have to guess because I only want one thing he says. So they immediately start start rattling off a list of things some practical,
some not so practical.
New radio a television. I get that but
Al applying sauce.
Now while he's doing all this, Donald is just walking around doing his household Barks. He's
s the fire. He's sitting back in his easy chair. He's addressing Christmas Barks.
And they keep coming at him with all of these things and you probably spotted this mark, but then an Adam bomb, and then I I could immediately thought of the other
the other series that we saw that Adam.
U. U. Yeah. But he keeps going, and and I they realized it isn't very easy. Harder of them they thought. And I think they believe them. They really can't guess what he's wanting. So
they ask him again is this the deal I have we have to guess and Deals he looks the letter. So they go off and they start thinking
about them some time passes. And I love these next few frames because it's just so exaggerated and so Santa's Christmas list.
If you kinda think about the historic and traditional Christmas list that the boys have already created their very long list of things, and he reads off several
odd crazy items. You wanna read them off foreign?
Sure, I'll read them often in panel two on that page. It's a cy run, a camera tool set fishing pull, tenth hive of bees
cow bell spinning wheel, butterfly,
net, gun, Canary, and then about twenty, etcetera
what I would call the the homer Simpson dope moment, you know, would be the boys just kinda like false
because he doesn't get it. They don't get it. And don't you got everything here, but you haven't guess the one thing I want. And then they're Groggy, they're exhausted. They say wait, I think we can find out
when Uncle donald falls Al asleep tonight, he'll give us a clue. And boy, fortunately for them, he laid down and starts sn really quick warren and I Yeah. I just wanted to say, I love that little sequence where i you do is. I agree with you that sequence where he's reading through the list. It it strikes me very much like, careful what you wish for. You know, you you kinda brought this on yourself, Donald as they come in with this
list that must be able to wrap all the way around the house. It looks very funny to me. Oh, it is. And then of course on sleeping. He's he's not talking plain American. I thought that was pretty cool. And then, of course, my classic favorite fighting donald comes in to his thought balloon and you see this boxing fighting donald with the eyes clothes on the couch, and we'll come back to favorite panels, but this is probably to one of my favorite panels is the next one with the silhouette of the three Nephews, and I just have to read what they're saying. It's no use. All he dreams about is fighting. And I thought that was just setting up donald for who he is. But then the ask well, how about boxing gloves? We got those. How about not nope got those
so we thought of those, but he didn't want them. So they finally realized the only way they're gonna guess with don wants for Christmas that one item is to seek out his girlfriend daisy Inducks. So they race over to Da, house ring the doorbell and you take it from here. Before we go on, what do you guys think? Warren you you like that sleep fighting bit. I I agree. I thought that was hilarious. What did you think of that sleep fighting bit, Sarah? It was very
much
characterization that I understood of donald,
you know, constantly
under threat from his own Inducks insecurities even in his leaked So... Yeah. Alright. And and we don't usually see the, like, cartoon behavior, bleed into the comics. I feel like this donald is much more, you know, He's plain spoken,
but that this is something I could imagine being out of the classic cartoons.
Right? It also is a good
bit of foreshadowing
as to his encounter with glad.
Right? Yeah. It's setting him up as
a flight picker. Right. And Sarah, you're gonna tell us about this part where he where where they go to daisy, but I I just wanna mention I really like how Barks gets... He sets up this neat little structure for the rest of the store. Right? We're gonna see this cool pattern
where they're gonna approach
relatives
or close family friends. And
and and I like that. It's it just feels like very clean meat storytelling. So Go for it. Yeah. So he takes us... So the boys decide to go see daisy and two of them stay home to hold down the floor, and one of them goes hat in hand to to Daisy and it's just you you know, do you know what Donald would want for Christmas and she does so she decides if she's going to take them Al to a mind reader who will be able to figure it out. But when Donald duck sits down with the mind reader the readers becomes very offended because she's
decided that what he wants based on his deepest Barks thoughts is a picture of herself so that he can
scare the boys with it. Which is, you know,
she's not she's drawn with some extra wrinkles very much like the old witch in in snow
white and a big hooked nose and she's not conventionally attractive.
And I think he was right to be offended. And
and kick them out for that insult. Yeah. This this part feels very
discord to me. Right? It's very jarring because, like, the mind reader is drawn
deliberately to, like, provoked the reader to think about how how ugly
she supposedly looks. And and it's it's a big joke on her appearance.
Yeah. And she's... you know, she's drunk. She's not... She's wearing, you know, kind of the equivalent of a mum and a house code, she's rather large.
She's wearing
slip on slippers.
She's she's like meant think of her as as French. Right? Some sort of generic European, I guess. Memo
d
is her name dick. And it's in the parking mountains on the couch. Mine's pumped out twenty five cents. I thought that was pretty cute psychic gig. I have so many thoughts about this page. Like first off. You guys I thought it was so sweet. I I read this to my my daughter,
a couple of weeks ago as part of my prep for this. And I kind of... I stopped her eye warned. Okay. I really like this story. But there's a part where, like, the joke is is at the expense of this characters
looks. And it's not very nice, and so she was prime to see it. And so when we when we got to that page, she was she enjoyed it very thought fully with me. And when we got passed, I was asked her, what do you think? And and she was so sweet. Like, that's me. She's beautiful.
It comes So I was so proud because she's like she's fairly drawn to provoke this reaction, but she's also, like, when we see her talking and private with daisy,
You know, they're just speaking very.
She does seem very nice and very sweet until she reads Donald spots,
and is very...
Calls him an insulting mom
to to wanted her peak to frighten he's nephews with Barks you talked about the the characterization of this character, this mind reader. And it may be wonder
if and it happens again with Uncle Scrooge, but it made you wonder why they had to leave their place of residence and seek out someone to to convince them. I thought they might have some other way of doing it, but it's an interesting
story telling concept by reducing these bit characters to Well, and you gotta get him to drive valet away in the cart. Oh you're right. Thank you. Yes. You have to get that repeated
roping in there. Yeah. Thank you. Right. Go ahead. And so to that point,
after
to it kicks them all out,
daisy demands to be taken right home.
But the car breaks down. Mh. And Donald says you or Daisy. The kids and I will have to get out and push. She just gets so mad. She's just like, nope. You do it yourself. Barks off, And like, thinks about it, you know, as she kind of processes for anger. She's like, you know what he really needs is a car. I'm just gonna get to on hold a car for Christmas.
And I'm sure we all had the thought of, like, that's a really big gift. I mean, she she's doing it so that she isn't
you know, she doesn't have to write around in that up too. I can kind of understand. I've given gifts where I'm like, I'm a little bit inconvenience by this aspect of your life. Here is a thing that that will make me happier.
Let's totally get it. Yeah. And it's not out of bounds for, like, a girl end but it it is interesting. I I couldn't help but think of like that kid that little kid lack of understanding of what a car cost versus what director set costs, you know? Mh. I mean... Yeah. I had to put aside so much of my disbelief for was like, okay, Okay. This is for kids. This is not for adults who how much things actually cost. I would this is just as possible as a wife buying Lexus for the husband without even talking about it. Dressing with a big bow on top of it. And then we we shouldn't gloss over the fact that we've got, like daisy duck walking into the bank to
make a a major
purchase
as a single woman in nineteen fifty. Right? Yeah. I was make of the same thing Mark here she is. The last panel is her making that entrance since it's a bank, although she's disgusted, she is absolutely deep Herman. And I I don't know the specifics of it. But but I know that it wasn't really common for... I I think bank loans were still, like being denied to women at this time in American history in general, but Barks is kinda showing this like it's just a normal thing. So I I has as much of a right to, you know, a bank account and credit as as anyone does. I I didn't notice that. Thank you for pointing that out. That is really progressive. Right. Yeah. He he has his flash. Here in there.
Alright. So we're we're gonna we're gonna basically
proceed now to the next member of the Ducktales family. Right? He's the the kids have gone to Daisy,
and things went pair shaped. Now they're gonna approach their uncle Scrooge
and see if he can help out. And we don't quite have Scrooge and the money did. But we do see him shoveling his money into like, these large.
It is called the money bin. Right? Because there's some signage there that points it out.
Double decker money. Yes. The double decker Money pepsi. So we're kinda... We're kinda getting getting there. This this Scrooge is pretty close to the kind of the final version of his character.
And and they asked him for the help guessing.
What he might want, and he's outraged because he just sees this as he he hears the word gift and he's like, someone's gonna angle
for me to give someone a gift, and that costs money. And,
you know, as as he kinda shoes the nephews out, he starts to kind of process and he thinks to himself, you know, if if Donald doesn't get the kids the building set that they want who's gonna have to do it? It's gonna be poor old uncle Scrooge.
I I love the ridiculous thought process he has here where he essentially tops himself into...
Into everything,
He determines that he needs to get an next skirt. And so he like daisy. I had a question about the... How to interpret Scrooge just motivation. He knows that the kids aren't likely to get their toy unless he helps out. Is he motivated by wanting to help them? Or is he motivated
out of just kind of recent resent
obligation for
this, you know, family attachment that he has. I think we're supposed to read this as, like, the resent
obligation but that there may be, like, the colonel
of Karen, somewhere buried in there. That's my take on. That's a good question. So Scrooge
likewise kind of shuttle donald to another mental
and this is something that's always interested me about Carl Barks. Right? Is so many of his stories are like about hard work, and and rationality,
but then he has a lot of stories with this kind of like hit
and mind reading and and past lives stuff, it it it almost reads is a little bit hippie ish. I think he had kind of his, like, his hippie side. Warren you can probably think of ton. Right? Oh yeah. You see that in so many. He's out there. If a lot of the Yeah. And and it is a a good storytelling hook, obviously. You have to get... If you wanna tell the kind of stories he does.
But
he takes him to a hit test named professor Or
or, and
he consults in the same way days he did with the hip saying what he wants, and we get to see this he do the classic me mesmerizing thing and it results in Donald
only being able to clock like a chick.
Which is quite ironic when you think about a deduct being a chicken, but
Right?
And so the the professor like, oh, you can't talk, but I think he can show us. What he wants for Christmas. He directs him to go pointed it out, and they they follow in in the car as Donald leaves them to a feed door and he points to a sack of corn and Scrooge is outrage and the the hi twists
admit. Well, you know, I I did the best I could, but All I can do is advertise people so they think they're chickens.
I love that. I I love that stupid gag. I I think it's great Did you like that bit sarah? I did. I thought it was funny. It was interesting
to see how his
was kind of in the media. Right? You know, we grew up on this ideas and partly
informed by these comics that hit
was a way to control people, you know, all of these things that you're saying were just felt so normal within cartoon Sphere. Right. So as I was reading this, I was like, oh, of course, he would. Because I've been to, you know, hi for for therapy type reasons. There's a lot of really good evidence
supporting hit
in certain situations
that are therapeutic.
Obviously,
not the type where you make somebody think they're chicken. And so I was wondering
where he was going with this
and went where I should've have expected it, which was... It it was it was very interesting.
Right. It's it's the throw a silly humor. And it has a really good cap where the guy it's like, wait. Wait. I. I know someone who's a goat test you can making thinking go as if that'll help One of my favorite moments, Mark, if you don't mind on that, reach those. When he does right before revealing that he... That's all he does is make people think their chickens. I love how the boys are just pounding the floor. The little mouse sticks up and looks at them. And the boy say something that's a little un
because throughout most of the stories, they refer to their uncle Douglass on donald, But here they say we want to know what donald Duck wants for Christmas, and then you led to the next panel where he like, hey, this is all I do. But I love the little gag in the background because you see two, maybe could've have been characters.
Ro Ru and Henry Al a hand. So you've got this funny animal
naming convention continuing on with characters that have never you'll never hear from again, but they're out there Inducks, so I don't know. Just a little bit of his side. Right.
Yeah. There mouse. Yeah. That little mouse is cute little size guy. There's a lot of good size gag that we've kinda gloss over here, but they're they're definitely worth looking for. So just like how a goat hit
is not a hip
fore goat, or hi twists, who is go? It's a hit who makes you believe that you're go. Right. There's clearly a big Barks dot for a needing to be digitized to think your different animals. Not the first time either. Donald was hepatitis to think he was a kangaroo
in one of Barks most famous stories.
So again,
they had home
disgusted
And again, we get a pretty spectacular car failure
screwed refuses to help
and the nephews have to push the car home while Scrooge is left to ponder,
what Donald needs?
And he decides that he is gonna buy him a new car because he can never tell when he may need him to drive screws someplace. And that's all the hand waving we get to explain why
why Scrooge would spend so much money. But as far as these things go, I I found it pretty believable. And and at the conclusion of this page, you know, they pass their cousin Gladstone
gander
docking
at Donald predicament.
Being pushed by his nephew. What a great way to introduce the third member of the the family here and to see what happens here. I was really love this part I love what he says here. He says greetings slowly worm. And so I went wait a minute. Lol worm that's richard scary that... That was a children's book character.
So I did little research, and it turns out that Richard scary started his career in nineteen fifty as an art student. And he created Lol Worm. The character for his funny animal books in nineteen sixty three. So I have to say he was a Barks reader. Wow wow good Al.
Yeah just gonna I just read a book to my my two year old with lily where I'm minute it and just a few nights ago, and I never... I didn't even pick up on that.
That's where he got it. I'm gonna... I'm gonna say he did. I'm just that I'm that optimistic about the Okay. The community of artist and Huey, back in the fifties and sixties that he was inspired by mister Barks. But anyway, Gladstone yells out
to
donald in the Nephews. They're... The nephews are pushing down louis card
tyson Gladstone gander. And then there's then the battle and Sue here, the battle of words, the battle of greetings Donald just can't take it anymore after he installs donald and and his ability to not drive his car and you need a new car and you're a big wind bag and and they they go face to face eyeball bought eyeball and, you know... Honestly point
right Severino the car. Yeah. He's never owned a car. Yeah. Yeah. And then he goes well, I can if I want, I'm lucky. Huey, he. Well then start wanting one.
I gotta be show.
I love it. And again, the classic fighting donald here, circling around you're lucky to find nickel nichols but not but automobiles are clear out of your class so you you're you're a lucky guy, but you're a you're like a like a down and Lucky guy, you know? But now if you can you can really show me if you get a car. And he says You know what Yeah. Sorry. I didn't mean interrupt.
But you know what I love about this fighting sequence.
Neither ever heard throw a punch. They're are justice
just circling each other with their fist cock. Just.
And since so that won't convince you that that I'm gonna buy a car for Christmas by Golly, I'm gonna get a car, and I'm gonna get one for you too. And donald still doesn't accept it. The Vaccine seen is they're moving to the super service station is the nephew saying know, he couldn't buy a cl out of a fend. It's go look up. Group it again. Yeah. Gray line. And, of course, the last panel on that page is glad stone absolutely
regretting his statement. So he this next series of panel shows him just at his absolutely.
Down t worse. Ducktales dragging on the floor droop face as he wander and wonders how he can Severino he needs to be lucky like right now. And sure enough, he walks past... Who I I kind of kind of a margaret Du kind of a character
from the March Brothers movies is very wealthy and very social... High social standard. And I love what she says, I can't stand seeing anyone unhappy at Christmas I can't stand and you this grown off panel.
And she turns out to give a few thousand dollars to chew them up a little bit, the next panel, great panel, and he's just handing the cash over to the car salesman who wants to purchase not one, but two char,
work car with red side wall tires.
Imported
sports bottles
imported not even domestic. You guys adult me lu this page so much. Like child me definitely, my favorite page is is probably an obvious pick, but this is hilarious. I love him rounding the corner with that like, long face and the comic
over the top drawn wealthy social.
Just like here a few thousand dollars to help you buy some joy for fellow.
It's a pretty good art too. Obviously, for opera glasses
are have little lines radiating from them to kind of draw attention to them for jewel, have lines radiating from them to their attention to them and to, you know, show that they are sparkly
and
luxurious.
You know exactly where to look, and that's one of the things I've always appreciated Barks is art... Yeah. She
os tai well and just that idea that she's like, well, it's Christmas Have a few thousand dollars to stop being? Sad.
But again, my fate one of my favorite depictions of Glad is it is most down down his luck. Kind of.
Turns here. Great panel. Yeah. So that wraps up Gladstone little episode, and the kids have moved on to
check in with grandma
duck. Because there's a grandma duck, which I haven't met yet is she
has she appeared so far? Yeah. Grandma Inducks she... She's definitely appeared. A good few times. She doesn't usually make it into the longer.
Stories except for, like, some of these Christmas ones. But she
she appears in
some stories. I think some stories it's i think she might occasionally appear without some of the other dots and I remember right one? Yeah. Grandma mad Ducktales was a story angle there to kinda introduce other ducks in the clan, if you will, and there was a the a series of cop called the Inducks Family albums she appeared in and in a lot of the ten pages. But, yeah, she did appear her own series with Cousin
Gus goose, I think is it or... Yeah help me. Yep. That's boost her her hired hand because she's usually... I we don't really see her farm here Dewey we, but she's
home farm friends. And so what's her relationship
with Uncle Scrooge then is she the mother? Boy. That... That's a whole thing. There there was... There have been pages and pages
about the gen
and and
Don Rosa
eventually
will basically sketch it out. But I I think that Barks did have kind of a working idea. Of the gene theology.
She she is actually the Nephew great grandmother. And Donald Grandma
and not related directly to Scrooge.
Okay. So she's not scottish. Correct.
Okay.
Don Rosa will kind of, like he'll... Hill rat on these different relationships
into...
He'll actually put out a a neat little Inducks family tree that's that's rather acute. And and it's it's basically kind of become more or less canon. That fun repo to she's Al.
El dot. Is...
Personal name. Nice. So the kids the boys show up
and they're asking if she has any idea. And she says, no. I don't know what
he might want, but if you find out, so I'll buy it for him, which is kind of new. Nobody's ever said that out loud to to them, you know, the We donald although they asked for them to guess what he wanted. He didn't actually ask for the thing. So it's very kind of her.
And so they take off and they're look really excited
that they have at least her support for that, but they just are so
frustrated.
Might as well go home and give up
and donald
pulls around the corner as they're walking home and offers to
drive them the rest of the way and wouldn't you know it the car breaks down in a big
choke louise and then a whole panel that says lamb.
Again.
So it and the the the There's
fluid leaking everywhere. Looks like steam from one end and exhaust from the other. The tires are all of you
and Donald just...
Donald just opens his heart and starts speaking from there. And he says I can't pick this old heap any longer. I have to get a new one as he's steering while the boys are pushing.
And then they catch on. Oh,
that means that he's he's telling us what he wants, he wants a new car. And he really needs one. The kids are like, yeah. He really needs one. So they call grandma Inducks and
tell her the good news and it says land states a lot is which is just the cutest old lady
introduction? I if I ask really quick. What what do you guys think of like the the nephews like oblivious
here, how how over the top it is that they they clearly should realized this.
Couple of breakdowns i ago. I'm gonna suggest they should have realized it when they brought out the list that was about fifty feet long yeah this can't be the first time and in their world
that that car broke down three times of the story with the same bla and the tires and the smoke. Yeah. I I find the possibility here a little bit awkward. But think. Ask the reader, I never know. Right? Because I'm trying to impose you know, real world rules
and logic onto this cartoon, so I never know
what plot and what's
suspension of disbelief. Right? So I had just been using my suspension of disbelief this whole time. Right? That that's very common thing that, like, he has car problems never occurred to me that that was what he actually wanted until I started noticing that people were buying him car But if you had, like, sat me down at the beginning with the boys, I would have a guess of how about a car because to us, that's a big... Everybody needs a new car. I just bought, you know, my husband and I just bought a car ourselves. And so, like, it's a thing. And that adult The adults need having the new newest cars. It's a nice thing, but I put that aside because that's a
adult Right. Literal thinking sarah.
What?
I don't know what donald duck. But see you just said it though, and I think this is the classic point in the story. It's... What do you want Donald Inducks? Or Uncle donald versus what you need and every character, every character ended their sequence if you will in this storytelling
structure with he needs a car. It wasn't he wants a car. You're absolutely right, Sir. It never dawned on me. To even think. In that first, it was what do you want donald Uncle donald. It wasn't what do you need? That was brilliant in in his storytelling techs. Yeah. I really like this element of it because I think to me, we get we get this rule of three thing. Right? Barks is really good about his comedic rule of three. We've got three breakdowns here. And the third breakdown is what finally clears them in. I think most readers by then are seeing that it's screaming obvious. Right, that it is what he needs. And so to me, there's a lot of humor in their in there like oblivious
because the reader is just wants to like shake them. Like, it's a car. It's a car. So I think it would probably be common to read it Al, like they're being frustrating
naive,
but I it's just it's just funny to me. It is they're like this dent. When they're usually very very bright. So, yeah, we we see
grandma and her adorable
little buggy heads to the store to order one for him. And then we transition into really a neat little sequence where Donald remembers his bargain, and he goes to the toy store, and he asks that one of those building sets be delivered Christmas morning. And he stops himself as he leaves. Because he has that great stereotypical
adult
recollection. That wait, there's three of them better by three of them else they're gonna fight. And this this is what's gonna happen
in sequence with each of the relatives. Right?
Daisy is doing some last minute shopping.
And she takes it upon herself because, you know, she's thinking. I don't wanna see the boys miss out so I'm gonna go by them some something. And she talks herself into three sets, and we we flash
to sc in his in his money tub. Thinking to himself that that that tight law Donald won't by his nephews a thing so he directs Jarvis, his butler to go to the Toy store and buy a building set. And, again, we get that cap where he corrects himself, better make it three. Else they're gonna fight all the time. Did anyone else read that service go down to a toy store and buy a building set in Iron man's points I I definitely thought of thought of the Ai. Yeah. This time. And so we see Gladstone do the same thing. All of these relatives are coming to the same realization, but they're doing it in different ways. Right? Right. Daisy is doing it to be sweet. Scrooge is doing it to be sweet in his own way. But he's being cast as very grumpy,
and reluctant at the same time.
Gladstone
wants to show off, he wants to have a little icing on the cake. When he delivers the car, so he goes in search of the most expensive toys and decides to spring for three sets
and and grandma.
Go go for a line. No. No. I was just gonna suggest we go all the way back to the beginning when Donald did it to fulfill a bargain. And that was he was happy to do it. Yeah. So... I I liked I like the little
expression that he's got as he does and like, hey, at least the kids will have a nice christmas. You know be that part. Yeah. He was he was definitely a jerk in the beginning, and I could seen a way for him to have, like posed it more as a game than a threat. You know? But we get a little bit of, like, we get some nice caring and warmth from him at the end lease. I did wanna point out that
the super builder
that
Gladstone
gets is one hundred dollars. And apparently, that's not even the most expensive gift that they have at the Toy store. Those are all sold out. The hundred dollar building sets in nineteen fifty would be worth
one thousand
one hundred sixty six dollars and fifty nine cents. Due to inflation,
which is
wow.
Yeah. Like
yeah for your three nephews.
That's a pretty big flex. That's clearly where where all the motors are gonna come the the end from those deluxe ones.
So Grandma Ducktales the final
relative to walk into the store and just know the don to scatter brain to remember to buy gifts for his nephews. So she goes in does the same thing. But she says send one of those sets to Dun Barks house, make it three. They now are all set. And, of course, my one of my favorite little character moments is the clerk is just so happy. I.
You've made his day.
I love
there. Yeah. Is it that great I knew it? I do it. I do it. But the next morning, you've got this classic Christmas snow covered duck burger moment is Christmas morning, and you hear the joy from all the different houses in the neighborhood. But that that the docks, these just the other kids in the neighborhood. And so the doorbell rings the boys wake up. Donald is g and says go get the go answer of the door, there might be Al delivery man with your building set. So he's explaining now from bed that he got them the building size. Hey, Warren. Isn't that panel just so lovely? Oh it is. It's it's not christmas learning at all. It's
it's it's a wonderful life. It's it's a it's your classic Christmas panel. Yeah. But think, Sarah. I thought it was really calm, and I like the touch of the gold,
yellow,
steep and the trees that have had shed their leaves, but there's still a fur yeah. Very.
Very calming But donald, it looks up and and says go get your building sets, so they're being delivered.
They there we see the five delivery men, or we see the legs of the the one on the far left And they have all the different versions of the builder set. I I love that. I'm glad you pointed out early about glad getting the
super builder.
Yeah. Because they're all by Jiffy builder.
There's deluxe builder and their super builders there's different versions of it so they can connect whatever they their hearts and minds imagine. So fifteen buildings sets
Donald gets up. And this is the sort of the unveil now of the payoff of all the kindness and all the payback But donald gets up runs to his window opens it up, delivery men everywhere. And then the sort of disbelief that there are four new automobiles for me for me, Donald Inducks, and each one is a
representation of the buyer. Except for uncle Scrooge jump Al little. Yeah. That deep is a little bit confusing.
Yeah. Yeah. No. Thank you. You guys that jeep is perfect. What year is this? Nineteen fifty. Nice empty.
It's a war surplus jeep. Yep. After world four two, He got... He got it for cheap.
Oh, wow remember the
from volcano Valley service
Barks.
And yeah. Where's was... That would have been.
It would have been obvious back then that that... But it reads weird. It's like, oh, that's kinda
utilitarian.
Maybe that's how it works. But no. He picked it up from from uncle Sam for song. Great call Barks. I'm glad you did. I I love that then it makes so much sense. And then, of course, Daisy car is freely and it's got the little french on the hood, and it's got the little skirt or the lay on bottom. Grandma duck was just practical and bought the grandma Inducks would buy. And of course, Glad stones got the char
import with the red tires. That's donald great surprise for that morning. I love... I love this page. The this this is section neat that have grown up wish fulfillment and child
fulfillment,
but it's like, grown up wish fulfillment from the perspective of a child.
What do you think sarah of those different cars that reflect the givers?
I... Carl Barks is such a master
at character.
And any tool he can he uses
and this is just another example of that. Obviously, I was confused by the jeep, but the I could tell who which one was you know, without reading the tags. Right. So each car was from. It's just... They're so good. Mh. And and even glad stones even the tag
he's underlined his name to be like this is from Gladstone.
Grandma was the only one to wish Mary Christmas.
To gray. And then Donald
to the boys and... Yahoo. Who, y. This is a mary Christmas ever,
and the kids ask
what are you gonna do with four automobiles and Donald says he's just gonna have a lot of fun picking which one to write? As an adult, I I developed the favorite probably and then just drive that one exclusively give the rest of away like. I would have a hard time accepting them. And then if somebody was, like, insisted
or if it was in the case of uncle Scrooge or...
Where... Or Gladstone
where I was look, he's it's fine. I would just be like, okay, either, you know, sell it or give it to somebody else, know spread the wealth But donald, of course is not so anonymous. He's just going to choose... He's just gonna have fun using.
And I think that's probably, like playing to that little kid sen
Right? Oh, I can drive a different car Severino day. Right? Right. But the kids are a little bit more practical. As far as scalability, and I kept thinking about that, Like, oh, I bet they're gonna make something really good with that because, you know, you can't use four cars that once, but you can use fifteen e sets at time and make something just really awesome. And they already have plans. And so later on,
Donald is trying to get everybody rounded up so that they can go to grandma's for turkey dinner, and they just, like, can't be bothered. So he leaves without them and gets to the dora at grandma's as he decides to to drive the one that she gave him to show his thanks
and he arrives and it says grandma, the boys just wouldn't come. And she's at the door and
she's pointing behind him and says that's what you think Donald look behind you.
And the kids have arrived with a giant quad peddle dog looking thing that they've built with their e set
singing jingle bells from the top of it. Yeah. What what a great closing
panel. I I think this is a masterpiece
conclusion. Right? Because we've got it it does a little hack need Christmas thing where the other members of the family
all show up together, which maybe isn't isn't too realistic, but it's cute and it's warm, and it just feels like such a neat bit of kid wish fulfillment. You know, the idea that we're gonna use all these that to to create something really cool
that gives us a little bit of independence.
I love that. As a kid this was my favorite panel. I I remember this panel. And when I saw it again reading it this time, it brought back so many memories, and I think it was that sort of final
Merry Christmas wish to the family from a family and everybody that's in the story, the main characters are in this panel, and it's just a Christmas greeting. And Sarah, you described that that animal or whenever they're they're riding on beautifully, it's the familiar, the snow and the house. And the extremely absurd and unfamiliar all mixed together and one, and it's just... It's because it's just a classic panel. Great way to close the story. Yeah. What you think of the conclusion there, Sarah? Thought it was adorable. I was very excited to see that I was right about the scalability of their building sets Yeah. Fifteen. And
they they did a good job because, of course, they did.
I'd liked the articulation
of the like, the limbs of this monster thing they created to right around down it
It does look very much like a dog
as far as, like, where the joints are and stuff I think this one was my favorite panel for sure. Nice.
I like too that it looks... It looks fantastic but it also looks just realistic enough. You know, where you where you can imagine it. Really really neat little closer there. So, yeah. What what are your overall thoughts on this one warren? You you alluded to this being your favorite of the big Christmas stories. It is and I and as as I said earlier it it... I just love the outcome. I... The way it started, there was a little bit of that and I'll just classify it again as a a sort of selfish push motive from everyone through Scrooge, so you can't break him from his mold, but
And and so it's Gladstone, but there were such...
But when you had that su streak in the Net at the beginning and then donald, then there was the shift to kindness
and gift giving, which I really liked and all five characters are in there. I mean, you've got the the family rather with Grandma, making a cameo oh and
everybody just... To me, it was just a classic Christmas
story Inducks berg with classic behaviors by all the characters. It sorta of came full circle for me as a as Inducks fan. Awesome. How about she's here. What are your overall thoughts on this one? I thought this one was very beat. It wasn't
exciting.
It was
so well
characterized
that it wasn't
surprising or jarring
And so it felt like it would be a good comforting
solid
and enjoyable
comment. To read as a kid. Yeah. For sure. I I loved reading this one as a kid. I really love this one. This one, I think think you described it really well. It's very comforting.
Both you described well, because it has a lot of nice, like, warmth thin kindness
just a couple of discord parts. But it almost feels like a a classic
Christmas
special a Tv special, you know? And like you were saying Sarah. It it really is all about the
characterization in this one. None of the characters
apart from Donald and the kids are even in it that long, but there's just so much
character,
you know, not development. But
the the story is really
drawn out of who these characters are. And and that makes it really really fun to rate. If you look at the the splash panel at the end, the the panel we love that that pays off the story. And then if you go back like I did to the first panel, mark the one you beautifully described as that that big full page I just saw that there's a little fore foreshadowing going on here with a yellow car on the window. Just think about that for a minute and
So I don't know if federal Barks is was playing a joke on us or if he just knew what he was gonna get into,
but I wanted to bring that up I'm glad you did. Yeah. When we we're looking at it this time, I was like, Oh look at that. That that car is going to be a gift. Or at least a car is gonna be a gift. Oh, it was there the whole time.
Yeah. It's hard for me when I think about, like, the three famous Christmas stories.
And and there's no reason to pit them against each other other than it makes for a good topic
conversation
But you like this one better than shaq town and San and letter her to Santa Warren. Well, I like I'd like letter to Santa.
Shack down. I would put third, but I would say this is probably a close second
updated I be letter to santos is probably a close second to this one for other reasons. But, yeah. How about you?
I love letter to santa, but it's like kinda two story. Right? And I like that steam.
Part more than I do, the kind of santa apart at the end. So I would say that the the first half of letter to Santa is my favorite of them. But this one, this one might work best overall. But but there's something about the Shack town. It's really a big emotional punch too. Yeah. It's more epic I will say and even in a way letter to Santa is a little bit more of an epic story. Yeah. So that's a hard one. Like, if you if you would asked me before I revisited,
letter to Santa. I probably would have said that letter to Santa was or or rather Shack town is my favorite And this third, but they're all really great in their own way. So. I'll have to think about that when when I finally get to Shaft town, and maybe I'll have to pick. Yeah. I'll take another read of check down to. It's been a while, but
this one just brought back a lot of memories,
and I'm I'm kinda stuck in my memories as a kid. So maybe I will have you guys Barks for Shack tone. And I'll ask Sarah to do a letter to Santa for some homework and
and and we can, you know, debate the three of them. Not again. They're they're all great, but but the community
has its own idea. And
this one is is highly regarded. Those three are are definitely
like the hop of Barks Christmas stories. So this one rates quite highly. It's a seven point seven on index, which is good for one hundred and thirteen.
Out of all forty one thousand or so. So
Shaft
is definitely his highest rate by the community and I believe that Santa letter san to out this one by a little bit. But but not quite as much. I might need to double check that though. In general, I think this one holds up pretty well apart from that sequence
with with the mind reader, which just is is a little needlessly
mean although,
I should I should acknowledge that Donald private thoughts are his own private thoughts. And he had the good grace not to say anything.
She was insulted
by thoughts that he kept to himself until she read his mind. So I admire Barks your... When you do read this to your daughter, and when I read this to my granddaughter, which I wanna start reading the dex stories to her. She's now four. And I think we'll she'd loves sitting through stories, but I love the disclaimers you can give on the characterization because I think that's really important. To let them know that this isn't appropriate or this isn't what we're looking at get their reaction. I thought that was beautiful.
And I think these Ducktales stories with all their side characters and even their main character behaviors are wonderful elements for teaching kids what is good? What is great? What is luck? What is this? What is that? I I think
you've you've kind of convinced me to not just read these stories, but read through these stories with with the little ones. Yeah. It is a great opportunity. Right? Because I love these stories deeply, But there are definitely parts that I I do think it's important to contextualize eyes and you know, tell her okay, this this was something that he wrote seventy years ago. And generally, today, we wouldn't do this or or
sometimes people today
still do the this and I I don't think it's right, but but it's just a good a good opportunity to have those conversations.
See any any closing thoughts guys anything we didn't get to cover that you really wanted to mention. I I do think it's a it's a shame warren that... And and someone on the Barks Facebook page had pointed this out in response to a question I asked once. I asked once
what lit the graph or oil painting. Do you wish Barks have gotten around to? And someone had suggested that, you know, the closing panel of this would have been a really nice subject.
Well, I think it would have. Oh, yeah. There so many though. The more we do these and the more I look at at these comics and more I say, oh, just think about what he his editing process of saying, no... I'm not gonna do that one. And he did far more oil paintings than he did look the graphs, of course. Right. Yeah. Yeah. And then I I guess I didn't... I... We've talked about some panels we really liked. But are there any favorite panels that we didn't get to mention or that anyone wants to highlight? No. But I always appreciate when you do bring attention to the art because I do my things sometimes where I get stuck in read mode, and I can't switch to picture mode So I really appreciate
when you point out little things like that car in the window, warren or just everything. I like the attention that you give in this podcast. And I hope it's useful
to listeners who may... Might not have a copy of of this economic rate in front of them. To hear us talk about various panels.
Yeah. And i think was and aside from the splash panels that we talked about and some of the wonderful artwork work that Sarah pointing out. Think this is another great. It was a cluster of panels that really stood out, and it was little mini scenes like the the the incredibly long list of things that they... That they thought donald wanted, and then you jump to the next page and it's donald fighting on the couch.
Those little sequences are just classic in in itself. Maybe for me, it was... The Nephews who kinda nominated this story early on and and throughout in a way way. I love their their moments, I guess. And it's probably one of my favorites. Awesome. Yeah. That there are a ton of great panels in this one. And most of my favorites are super predictable, you know, the the end one and the beginning one and the the automobiles. But I gotta come back to that one with Gladstone with his long face because it it's cracking me up ever since I kid. Yeah. That's a winner. And and I I do love this story. You know, this one is is so much fun and I love the way that he constructed it in a way where the story almost tells itself. Right? He like puts it. He puts it on this track and we get to see this relative come into the story and handle things in their way. And the next one, and then they all come together in the end in a way that is to me really satisfying.
So I I think I think this is a great story. Holds up really well. And i'm delighted we got to talk about it. So
I look forward to having you guys back again at some point really soon very soon. It happens because
in in our podcast order, I'm gonna be pushing out dangerous to Disguise next week after this one. So hopefully, listeners will
enjoy coming back. I I think we had an awesome
conversation for that one because we've already recorded that. I'm very happy how that turned out. So if if listeners
would like to, they're welcome to reach out at Barks remarks at g gmail dot com or on the Barks remarks. Facebook page. And until then, Merry Christmas in February to both of you. Thank you, Barks. And to you, Mark. Thanks for having us. Yeah. Lose Al pleasure. Again, always great to play the money bin with you guys.
Always.