Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of sc Mc and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comics of all time, join us as we have explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context, and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks. Welcome back to Barks remarks. I'm Mark Sever, a grown man who enjoys duck comics,
and I also
enjoy spy thriller. They're not my favorite genre of all time, but we have a very special story to talk about today. And in keeping
how special this story is. I'm trying something new I have both a newbie guest host. And a veteran guest host. To join me today to talk about dangerous
disguise. So I... I'm gonna ask I'm gonna ask each of them to introduce themselves and, you know, let us know if you do enjoy spy thriller, and maybe if you've got a favorite. When we start with our veteran. Hey, Mark, It's Warren Harmon back again. Glad to be here on this very special program today. Yeah. I'm like Al longtime Barks collector and Donald duck van
can't stop collecting that the the duck stuff. So having fun with that. And yes, dangerous disguise prompted so many memories of my fast nation with foreign and t and international Spies. And yeah, I'm a I'm kind of a a longtime
fan of two genres, one would be the the classic James Bond Saga
which which Ian fleming started to write with Casino Royale one year after this book was written. The other is alfred Hitchcock and his wonderful
what I would call his English years when he was in Britain, and my favorite favorite story of all is the thirty nine steps. Nineteen thirty five, classic spy story. So yeah, thanks. This will be fun. Ops and how about our newbie? Hi. I'm Sarah Santiago.
I'm your resident
Jack Ball trades
knowledge expert,
and this week. And this episode I'm coming
at you as your resident
Spain expert.
However, I am not any kind of expert
whatsoever at thriller at spy, anything
there just... I remember when there was double crossing and triple crossing, and then I just got so lost in, like, what, like, I think like the second pirates of the Caribbean.
And I was just like, what is going on. So
even this woman was, like,
slightly confusing to me. Intentional with it. Excellent.
I thank you both for for coming back. You're definitely the the stories that have some intrigued, they they require you to pay pretty careful and attention.
I like how Barks kind of lamp prune that a little bit in this one. I mentioned that I like spy throw. I do. But I kinda quietly like them. They're never really one of my favorite genres. You know, I I enjoy a good mission impossible,
I enjoy a bond movie, but I've usually rather watch something else. You mentioned casino Royale Warren, that one is like very reminiscent of this story. Right? In a way that's kinda surprising because it did...
It it came out after, even the original version of it. So it's in nineteen fifty two. Yeah. Yeah. It's it's interesting to me that a lot of my cultural
touch
when I think about this story, came way later the the bond movies, the the mission impossible movies. You're right. It's it's more of the, like the the old hitchcock thriller that I think he was lamp and referencing in this one. I'm trying to remember what Barks so Cloak and dagger, I think. There's a great legacy
of these
spy thriller in in movie and book that I'm largely not familiar with but they're so like ingrained in
the pop culture
subconscious. Then everyone knows when they read this. What Barks is is both celebrating and making fun. And and that knowledge
cross this generation. Clearly, right? Because Mark you're in my generation,
new and warren generation new. Absolutely. There are no boundaries here. I mean, there are there are different... There are different approaches to the international spy story. But Barks was caught up in a time. One of the things I love about our podcast here is that Barks, we get to talk about the time he wrote it. You know, this is right at the beginning of the cold war, right at the beginning of Mccarthy right at the beginning of he's a communist. No she's the communist centers that
pointing the finger out everybody. It was it was suspicion going on. There was paranoia going on and he captured that in this story in a in a kind of a fun and wacky way, but also was able to really point out the themes
so eloquently.
Yeah. That that's really well said warren. Because you're right. This is like
with this funny version of Paranoia
that really had to reflect the the world. We're we're only a few years
from the dropping of of the bombs at the end of World War two and we're well into the beginnings of the cold war here. We have all of this frantic
atomic espionage
that had to be really
consuming the headlines and and that everyone would have been steep in, and I bet it would have felt like it came up all of a sudden, right? Because the world was
preoccupied with the second world war, and then we almost immediately switched gears. Into the cold war. And I was I was interested in knowing what was going on you know, historically.
And This was... He wrote this like a few weeks
before the arrest of Julius Ro. Do you guys know the Ro Barks the trial.
So I I don't know that that specifically informed him, but this would have been, like very relevant
in the news. Right now. And was it was the time in the country where we were dis discussed was actually unfortunately, of your neighbor of who's that person down the street it had that again, that cold war tensions. And I tell you, I have to give Carl Barks a lot of credit he. In this my opinion in this story for many reasons we'll talk about
exercised fierce independence and said I'm gonna tell this story by way. I'm not gonna let my publishers tell me what to do I'm gonna say it. I'm gonna draw it, and I'm going to lamp pun it. And I I just thought that was a wonderful take that he had on this. And it probably one of the reasons it's a highly rated story as well. Yeah. That's true. I feel like it should be known that I have a cat on my lap and I'm padding it very
miss doctor
Ish.
Oh, yeah. In the manner of the bond villain like, well originally.
Oh yeah. You're you're be very sinister looking there, Sarah. It's very interesting.
Thank you. That's the look I'm going for. Yep. So Warren you you mentioned it. Right? This one is very highly rated and very well remembered by fans. And and when I have these stories coming up that are like landmark Barks stories, I get really excited to do them, but I also feel a little bit of the pressure. Right? And so I was like, this this seems like a great one to get these two different perspectives on I also feel a little bit guilty because I don't I really like this story, but I don't love it like a lot of fans do. I think it's not like one of my all time, favorite Barks stories. But but I think I definitely
get why it's so well remembered. And and why it's so well appreciated.
Sarah, I'm I'm curious, you don't have to, like, tip your hat completely. But what what are your kind of initial impressions on this one. Do you do you feel it like lives up to that
reputation?
I can't speak to everybody else's taste and standards. But for me, this was the first, like,
straight
actually
enjoyable.
I didn't even feel like it was problematic in any way. So it was actually one of the first that I
enjoyed. Just kind of at the level it's supposed to be enjoyed.
So I can see how people without the barriers
and and the and the tastes and the, you know, like, social
justice
types of brains like I have. Could really like it. Yeah. I'll just
in your in our messaging about this mark. You were like oh, it's one of the last where he had humans in it, and and I was like, oh, yeah. The... It's it is kind of Huey,. It is kind of weird to have humans in it. But like, that aside. Like, okay. Yeah. This is this is quite enjoyable. Yeah. That's so cool to hear. I'm glad you got. And I realized too, I've been having you come along for some of the episodes where I I need to process some of this stuff, so that may not be fair. But I think I'm making a point too every once in a while having you join for just just a noteworthy and enjoyable episode. So so good. I'm glad I'm glad you enjoyed this. That'll be fun to talk about. What about you warren? Do you do you think this is, you know, lives up to the reputation? You know I I... It's not my favorite story either. However, I know why I think I know why it has such strong appeal among the fan base. And I think it's sara so nicely put it. I think there's a cinematic quality to this story. It's it's it's like a movie
and it it plays like it. And that's when he wanted. You know
intrigued. There's not a lot of
controversy
there, except when we get into some of the...
Maybe Thomas Andre andres thoughts about it,
which might be classified as controversial and the fact that Barks editors didn't like this story. But I think it it serves the reader well as a thriller as a kind of a comic thriller. So to me, it was in net vein of if at the time the abbot costello movies were the buy movies and the... Because there are some slaps sticking in here as well. I think because it's so different from all of the other Barks stories for this. What is this four color three zero eight, I think. I believe he's kind of breaking some new ground here and I think the fan base said, hey good for you. Yeah.
Again, very well, said, and it it feels like some of the appreciation to me might be almost in hindsight
that he didn't really get to do this
anymore. You know, it's like it's like he used up a lot of his juice and a lot of his goodwill. And then he got
restrained a little bit. And it's not that he couldn't do
Obviously, he's got some of his greatest works coming up, but he really had to work within the limitations. He he edged right up to the line and he figured out where it was and he had to pull back a little bit. So let let's go ahead and talk about a bit about some of the backgrounds
of this story. We've definitely gotten into some of the cultural stuff already. Dangerous
disguise is in nineteen fifty, late nineteen fifty, you're correct it was from four three zero eight in the United States.
It hasn't been
reprinted as much as you might expect seven of them in the states, including the original and this is a twenty eight pager so it's on the longer side, but not as long as some of were. And we mentioned it already, but it's very notable that this is the last story that Barks gets to do that really
prominently feature. Human characters. Right? Here and there, he'll like sneak them in in the background
or whatever. But
but it's almost entirely humans and the ducks in this one. And
there there have been a few interviews about this with Barks. You know, There's some good source material that where he shared that he loved
drawing humans. And if he could, he would love to have done something like the old comic strip prince val.
I was gonna say I didn't read it growing up, but the lavish artwork, the realistic
depictions of people, that, like and Steve Cannon,
the other
adventure comics series, I think were
inspiration for Carl Barks and and you're rightly the the interviews clearly
expose his love for doing this. In fact, he started to work at a comic strip with live action characters and because of his pressure deadlines from Western Publishing and everything. He had to abandon that strip. And so his his true love was to was to
figure out a way to continue the drawing of the human figure. I think for his stories. And of course, you know, you Barks, we go all the way back to about nineteen twenty eight when he left California to come to Minneapolis. Yeah. Definitely that it's it's impossible not to talk about his work with the calgary eye opener when you when you think about this story. And and the Calgary eye opener...
I love the name of the publication. It's so evo. Right? Because... Because it really was. It was these
Sarah, I think I sent you at least at least one or two images from the Calgary Eye opener. So... I thought this was like it sounded to me like some kind of a ride at a world fair or something. It doesn't sound like a publication and all. Yeah.
Well, it does have a very unique publication. And and basically, what was it more in into the into the late twenties?
Started in the twenties and he was recruited to Minneapolis where they published it in twenty eight and stayed there through thirty five and almost became editor of. He was like the staff the cartoon
for it. Yeah. Yeah. He did it. He draw over the one page... The one panel gag that... Two panel gigs. He ended up because the staff was so incompetent there at the eye opener. His work ethic, which I think he got a lot of training there to do the output that he did in his, you know, formative years is those... And I think he just... Yet became... And it was a girly magazine. Let's.
I mean, it was a humor magazine where he wrote the gag. He sketched the gag with these roaring twenties, flap women and men and Dapper looking, but they all had an an edge to it. Yeah. It was... It it was a girly magazine. And it was obsessed with sap basically as much as you could be as much as you could get away with in the late twenties, you know, it looks a little bit it definitely looks tame maybe on the edge of R k. But but there are numerous
jokes that are double ent tons
regarding sex of all kinds.
It is absolutely
focused on a lot of his drawings. Some of it's just like silly
Scrooge ball humor, right, about people's work ethics
and
lamp pruning pop culture of the time. But a lot of it is really making fun of the the male gaze, the male
fascination with the the female form. Right? So there There are lots of very loving detailed drawings of figures that should remind us of Mad Triple act. In this. Right? So so if you you're very familiar with Barks and his early work, that's what My Dom Triple x immediately reminds me of Y, yeah. Those the... Think... Absolutely.
Also from the Hollywood, we talked about how Gladstone was based on Joseph Cotton. I think Madam triple x but there's a little veronica lake in there too. Yeah.
Patel is his they call it. I did have a question
about Madame triple x was triple x Did it mean the same thing
as eu
back then as it does
today, like, as a as an illusion to
sexuality or or sexual material, don't think it did. I think that that became...
I think that that became a convention when the
the motion pictures
association adopted the x rating, which was like, into the... Yeah.
Sixty early... Yeah. Started than sixty eight. Yep. So so triple x became, like over the top way to basically label it as porn graphics. So no. It's it's that's that's a good question. It's not supposed to make us think of any anything like that. We're deaf... I think, you know, we're definitely supposed to recognize her Al like warren said fe fatal, a very su looking woman, Barks
clearly re drawing her. Yeah. And gotten trouble for it a little bit too for too much of the female form. And again, I have to give him credit for his fierce independence. He said I'm gonna do it and he knew he was turned it in after his deadline. He couldn't go. They couldn't go back. So I guess he got swat on the on the back of the hand for that one. Yeah. So so let's talk about that moment. Right? When when he went to his editor.
From what I gather, he he completed this one a little bit closed. A deadline, which probably
gave him the leeway where they felt like they had to publish it because there wasn't really time to do to do any kind of a revision. So so he took and I'm quoting from a nineties nineteen seventy one interview that Michael Barks did with him. He said, as soon as I took dangerous to disguise in and Karl B took a look at it. He said that doesn't go good having real humans. It takes the Ducktales of their world. And after that story humans were rarely used again. And
also told him that, you know, He's really butting up against Western publishing
strict
against
showing people in a section
provocative manner. It was gonna be a few years before like, the comments industry got cracked down on a couple years later, they would never have considered doing this. Everything was sanitized
much tame, but but B famously had him
reduce the bus. Of a female character in one of his very first stories. Life life card Donald, I think, Warren. I think there was it was Al early comics and stories. Wasn't it. Yeah. Yeah. I think it was called life days or lifeguard guard Donald.
It was you have to to go back in the red
the bo if you will or the bust of the the Ducktales figure. It was the Duck character. So the... you know, the fact that she has memories and that is is is pretty uncomfortable as it is. But... Yeah.
But, yeah. This is a situation where he he got away with what he could and and then B are basically gave him the the guidance, you know, never again, and and he never did, unfortunately.
I I've got a hot take though. I I think B was right. I think I think it does take me a little bit out of the story. And I I think it's it's to the stories benefit in in this case. Right? Because it does make the... It does make all those characters feel very mysterious.
And jarring, but I don't know if I would want to see it in all of his stories.
Going No. This was a this was kind of a refreshing break for me, but only this time and maybe maybe if if the storyline called for it, but, no, I think this was a great one and done kind of thing. Yeah, I don't wanna give b too much credit because I'm not a big fan of most of his covers. He did. He did a lot of early covers. He didn't... He did the Goody Goody stories feature during the little bad wolf, you know, the son of the big bad wolf I actually do enjoy those, but I I think Think that's his lane that he should have stayed in. Let's see, Boy. Lot of background trivia, but I don't I don't wanna dominate the conversation. Anyone wanna chime in really quick before I catch my breath and and talk about
Triple x more. I think the other
inspiration for the story, which I read doing some research mark and and Sarah was The idea it apparently came from an unused cartoon to idea from nineteen forty. Called Madam
Double. Apparently, that got scrapped. If you think about it nineteen forty was when Carl Barks was working Al his
story man. Yeah the Disney studios and he was working, you know, on the shorts. So it makes you wonder if he came up with that idea. I don't have much more on that mark do you? Yeah. So you're exactly right. You know, this is based on that
used short. And from what I read, I found a website that that referred to some of these shorts
and and he was heavily involved in that one. Like, he conceived a lot of the structure of it. It it would be neat to think of, you know, a short a short cartoon with Donald chasing
Chase. I like this. I I kinda went down the Rabbit hole and had fun looking at some of the
un produced Disney shorts. Some of them would have been awfully fine. Yeah. The only the only other thing that I really did wanna to mention is that one of the most iconic things, I think about this story is it's
fantastic cover. Like, I I love that cover it's obviously
recognizable
to fans because they used it in the
Carl Barks library, the big lavish publication in the early eighties. That was one of a few
that got to, like, a adorned the front of the hard covers. But but it stands out. I I kinda feel like when I finally got to read the story, I I kind felt like it doubt it over played how much of it's about bull because that's that's what I felt like I was sold to expect but a lot of love for this this cover. You know, I have to almost disagree with that. I i I'd like the cover, but I think it it it was a safe cover. It was just a a panel or two in the story. So it it it certainly makes sense when you read the story and you get to the bull ring, but I was hoping for a little bit more of the spy thriller in espionage
themed to come out in the cover. So to me it was okay. Oh, but then you would have had to put humans on the cover.
Yeah. Then then the secret would have been revealed. Listeners can't see me, but I'm leaving as far back from the screen possible because I don't like the idea of more humans. Yeah. It's it can be a little jarring. I don't know. There's something about his pose that looking back over shoulder It's a great pose and mostly balanced visually.
It's it's so well balanced visually. Right? You have... It... It's it's swoop from the bottom left corner up to the top right as he's like, kind of stretching over to the side, but holding up the the red cloth. I don't remember what that called. And then
kind of counter
that down over to the left is the bull looking angry and and of course, donald looking very
scared as he is want to do. It's very striking in the use of color in the in the balance. I I agree. I really liked the coat the cover. Yeah. I it's got a great composition. I I agree warren that it doesn't. Set up the story. I like i when disagree though. It's it's interesting.
Well, yeah, I I i again, I didn't... I never kinda sold me too and you did too on the composition. Aspect of it. It makes for a great intriguing
cover and you'll wonder what this is all about. So I that actually did kinda hit me as well. So for sure.
So let's let's pan to our international audience a bit guys. We've we've got some of the the titles from around the world. I'm gonna... I'm not start off by mentioning what it's called in Germany. This one is Ga,
dangerous
game. Mh.
Warren, why don't you give us one? I'll do Brazil. This one's
kinda straightforward, but it's Aj,
Secret
the secret agent.
Sarah. In Italy, it was
Donald and the Atomic Spy. Awesome. And then probably the most interesting one to me is in France, it was once called
Tom say, deceptive appearances, which sounds like, like a cinema synapse thriller alert to me. Yeah. And then Sweden is far for Glad. That's a straight up translate. Not dangerous
disguise.
Great. Okay. Spain, Mexico, this Spanish speaking countries has also got it. I will I will do the Spanish d since they are
ostensibly in Spain,
which is another dangerous
disguise or a dangerous costume.
Awesome. Thank you, guys. I love the English title. It's a great bit of Al. You know, It sounds it sounds very intriguing. I like it too. Alright.
So we we already talked about my little sequence where I like to go over the cultural historical Barks. The only thing that I wanted to add is that we are three years after
the
creation of the Cia in nineteen forty seven. And then out of the manhattan project,
I think there was there was so much espionage
that was hitting the the news stands. Over the
the atomic rivalry rate between the Us and the Soviet Union that that's that's what really captured a lot of the popular
imagination We've got a couple of very notable appearances. They're not gonna appear again in the comics, but we've already mentioned Madame Triple x
a
What miss miss Georgia Ko was it? Vi poland. Yeah. And
and then Don El.
Yeah.
Rest rest in peace.
Oh, you know, I I didn't even mention that as part of the, like, significant background.
Didn't talk
deaf and dying.
This is
this is one of the most gruesome,
you know, of of his stories. Like, there there is more deaths it's all off panel. It's all off Scrooge. I I guess if you really wanted to to stretch it, you could argue that no one really dies because because you don't see it, but...
But there are some almost ina
violent deaths in this one and and gun play and and even a depiction of a suicide or attempted
suicide. So this this is a pretty dark story while also having
having
that comic edge
Sarah, Or you were you surprised to see that? I I was I was very shocked not so much about the you know, these people are very disposable along the way. Right? We're just... We're so used to that. We have our marvel movies and hen, bad guys, under.
They get thrown off the sides of ships search whatever. We never know whether they make it all the time. Right. And then this one,
the guy
decided to throw himself off of a building
out of a window
That that was a little bit shocking.
We don't see that so much. Or was that
necessary?
Let alone kind of acceptable for that time period. Am I looking to add it through twenty twenty two eyes?
I mean, I think you could argue that. It it was definitely
shocking. Right? And I I will get to it, but I think it's really supposed to be an indictment
of a certain country and a certain leader really, Know? Because he does it because he he knows what is going to happen to him in his home country, which is a a thinly
veil analog for the Soviet union. So that that's what what
Is going to do, and it's upsetting because he looks like Donald too. Oh. Yeah. It's right going he his fe he very dramatic, but didn't wanna face the consequences of going back. Yeah.
Let's do it, guys. This we we've got some great stuff already to say about this. So so dangerous
disguise opens with this great establishing
shot and
narration box that shows the Ducktales ad the scenery
of the French riviera. This is like one of their first real visits to Continental Europe. It's a great setup. Apparently, they've they've ticked off their uncle sc because he paid them handsome to get out of town. And that's how he kinda hand waves that they're in this very exclusive place. And so they are ad
a beautiful beach they're looking at all the very rich people around them, the Nephews are kind of a go and we're getting this great
rundown of all these characters
he's listing off gambler and gold digger and black,
and then he mentions that you also see spies. He he says that there are probably half of the spies in the world slit around here, passing their secrets. And and this is gonna really
animate the Nephew
imagination. Right? Donald was kinda telling them this as a fun little throw it. But now the nephews are just seeing
spies around every corner and behind every rock and they're they're kinda getting freaked out. They they mentioned a guy with a long beard,
nephew says that he could have he could hide the plans of a battleship in those whispers and and they see, you know, a bathing beauty and characterize
her as likely being an awfully dangerous spy. And they they keep going on until Donald starts to
regret that he said anything at all about spies because now that Nephews user just freaked out, and totally
fixated. And so Donald has to kinda separate himself to cool off. So on the third page, he's walking off. We get this great panel that is... It's just a cheesecake panel here. He says,
beautiful scenery and a beautiful scenery. This this is the life for me. And obviously Barks knew what he wanted to draw here. He's he's drawn some beautiful women in period
appropriate
bathing suits and
very clearly in enjoyed doing it. And and that that stood out as a twelve year old the first time I read this. It's like this this one does seem a little bit different here. Yeah. And and and I and I think the prior panels that you just went over Barks kinda show the Nephews in a bit of out of character.
They they got sucked into this in intrigued, which I think is a young boy myself reading this comic, I could relate to their their fears. But I love how Donald just turns the tables. And gets mad, but then it's then he's in heaven right now. Yeah. Warren, it is one of those those the kind of atypical for the comics where the kids are acting
their age and the adult says something and and the kids run with it and then annoy the adult. Yeah. They good point. Yeah, That's true. Sometimes sometimes he really wants the nephews to be in command, but sometimes he needs them to act more like kids. And before before you talk about the next sequence one, I just wanted to really mention the all of the
images.
The mysterious people on the riviera here, they're they're really straight out of Hollywood. Like you were saying at the beginning. Right? This definitely sets us up to feel like this is a cinematic thriller. Oh, yeah. It is The framing. Oh, yeah. The framing of the the panels. And as Donald walking off. He's a convinced he's not gonna to get into any trouble, but then we see the first soon sinister spy under the docks and under the here talking about about counter spies and being followed and introduces us to Madame Triple x, but he's got to pass on some secrets and so he stumbles across Donald who then walks up nonchalant lee and asked if he could do a favor for him and I love Dom response. What you feet sore. You
then he looks he looks very worried the spy mentions that he doesn't dare seen near a lady. So we just toss
looks like a lipstick stick tube, and Donald nonchalant walks over. And as he walks away,
the spy now is talking about the message that's in that little canister and
begins to think about foreign agents approaching that he hears and then all of a sudden we see agent after counter agent after counter counter spy appear, and then a wonderful
last panel on that page shows
a series of six spies pointing guns at each other as they talk about shooting each other. This is kind of the drama now that we're we're starting to see unfold. And then as Donald walks away, we hear this singular bang and can only imagine what that means.
He thinks it's just fire going on. I did like the all of the agents kind of showing up and pointing guns at each other.
You know, it it does seem kind of scary intense, but there's operator x and operator double x and and counter counter spy, and I just love the they're like, oh, here's operator X. Oh, I'll just like, was there a sign up sheet? Did they have a Zoom meeting about this? How did they coordinate different names? One looks like he's coming out of the sand like he was better in the. That's that's what gets me. You guys I love this panel
so much. I am I could tell.
I could talk about this panel.
First off, it is
hilarious.
Right? I I just... I need to read these in full because it's great he tells he tells the counter spike he says
you I have too late t me with the goods. What are you gonna do about it? And the counter spy says, I'm gonna shoot you operator double x
super spy. Warren and do you wanna read the next one? Sure. But not before I shoot you cloak Dagger counters spy.
Sarah And I shoot you operator x counter counter spy.
And then and I shoot you f b Nick i counter counter counters
spy.
And then we get a man who's, like cut off the panel, but he's clearly keeping the sequence going. They're all, like one foot away from each other, and it's just this amazing
lamb pruning of
both the the, like real life spy activity that it must've have seemed like was going on that was peeking into the newspapers and also all of the ridiculous over the top spy and counters by
hollywood stuff. So
this panel, this panel is is a work of art to me. And it's one of the greatest parts of this story and maybe one of the best things that he's done in the duck comics. And they're all imp dressed on a Sandy Beach. I just love that. They're new guides. Yeah. It's a classic. And and you're right warren, it closes off with one singular bang, which means that they probably all shot each other dead simultaneously.
So this is our first bit of implied depth, you know. Yeah there are several of the big wu
coming out of that the side of a panel, but only a singular Barks.
Alright. Dare I take us on to the next. So Donald thinks that that singular bang is fire crackers, and he's so innocent like oh, how nice. Fire truckers.
And walks up to
triple x, who has already seen him coming because she's looking in her contact compact in the mirror and her compact. Right? Because she's
med triple x, super spy. She's on top of everything.
And he says, heidi home, i was ill. Did you lose your lipstick? And she comes in with a french accent.
Oh, so I did.
Thank you so much.
She plays the, like, c to him him and he gets literal stars in his eyes and starts to mimic her accent
that voice says eyes, z lips, and she smiled at me
love
He opens
lipstick,
she
decides she needs to find an isolated
place to read this and
has found a place that's within eye of the boys
and decides it's safe. They are suspicious and they see her open up the lipstick and see that it's a dummy and read that there's a message. And then she decides to leave it on the beach because we're encounter spies are closing in. I don't know why she doesn't eat the paper. I mean... Yeah. No time
no time to chew it up and swallow it. So she hides it in the sand.
The kids, of course, go up and and un it
and
see that it's just
a message in English so they can read it and they say, whoa, that's serious. And they all scream oh donald.
Yeah. That... This is a really nice setup. We get this really good look as at Madame Triple x as someone who knows what she's doing. I love the little sn and sn as she walks past the counter agents that she's out fox.
I did wanna to point out with it
out of all of the women
that parks is drawn on the beach, and as you said, markets it's very clear that he took some care to draw them. She's
wearing
a bikini you know, the a more modest type of a bikini, you know, compared to what we would wear today. But she's the only one showing any torso. Yeah. It's definitely pretty revealing, especially like you said compared to the other yeah. Because they all have you're right. They all have one piece. So she she is the ph fatal patel here. So the nephews bring it back to Donald and he immediately
recognizes it as the lipstick. And he reads the message, which just says Madame triple x deliver stolen plans of Us qb to operator forex x in Chile be. There's a lot there. Right? It's So we... We're referencing the a bomb right away as the qb Barks. So we've got some atomic paranoia here. He goes on to read operator for x is known into the world as Don El,
the bull.
The the reader, of course, immediately knows that this is gonna be a Donald do gainer, that he doesn't
recognize this.
And so, you know, before Donald was annoyed by their
spy fear mon, but now he realizes how serious this is. And he is unwilling to go to the police because he he says that the case is too big. The story is propelled forward here.
Because of the the cold war paranoia of. We can't go to the police. This is two important too dangerous and that might seem silly, but we did just see the Atomic bomb dropped a few years prior. So kind of everyone knows the stakes. And so... It's also
totally in character for Donald and his super poor boundaries. Right? Everybody's problem is his problem, and his problem is everybody else's problem
So this is just an example of him deciding to take on something that isn't his responsibility. Right. Everything is gonna become the Ducktales business. Right. And he says we have to be suspicious of everybody and everything.
And he resolves. They've gotta get to the Chile Berg area
and hijack the plan and we learned that Chile Bulgaria is a country west of here. It's gonna be kind of an
for Spain like you said, sarah. Right. So they get on the train now, which is going to take them directly
to the Chile Be
Area and
they they assume by getting on the train that they are either with step or one step ahead of madame damn triple x.
But they did see her come on board the train, but they get a nice comfortable car. They seem to be in control of the situation when
they look out the window then. And...
But they do see all of a sudden a passenger jet Zoom by and
is now convinced that she may have taken the plane and will get there before they do. But just then we see our first counter spy who
jumps out of the seat that Donald was sitting on from underneath, a very men looking figure in a black suit holding a gun pointing it right at the ducks. He he says, and I'll say it, i operator minus x, counter counter counter counter counter counters spy have other plans. Again playing on the whole by being back and forth. And he orders donald that he just says you're gonna jump out the window. Donald immediately says no, not at eighty miles an hour. And as he ready to jump out the the triangles into a tunnel and the the frame turns completely pitch black. And I love this because it sets it up for a series of gag. But he says, well, I I can't jump now. There's a tunnel
you see the counter spy curse.
But just then one of the fuse is ready to poke him in
the the seat of the pants with a a sharp needle. It says you can jump now. Chu. And this is that poke. And this great panel sequence here where you see the kind of diagonal
drawing with the train on the bridge and the counter spy falling out presumably to update passing here and then Donald says creep spies pop out of every place. What happens next and we see this great shot of Madame Barks Know start jumping from the plane to see the parachute
landing
on top of the train and this wonderful shot of her kind of looking down in there. As she says I jumped from the plane, may I come in, and then, of course, Donald completely surprised, but also just marvel Al her again and sort the nephews A lot of Gladstone take in here mark sarah. Is the
pin in the bum? Is that a common
trope because it felt familiar And I read it and I lash out loud because it's so silly, but also it felt, like oh, yes. This. Like I'd seen it before how how common is that? Yeah Absolutely.
For someone who is like a gag man in the old Disney cartoons, this is something that you would have seen in in a lot. Of those. Definitely Al a common trope. So but you guys I love this train sequence, and I I didn't remember how much of the story really takes place with the train until I revisited this. But it feels so classic, you know, European
set spy movie, of course, a lot of it has to be set on the train self contained in one of these train compartments. The nephews and Donald who helps trip him, and they they murdered this guy. Right? Like He he is not surviving this unless we really lean into the cartoon logic, I guess, he could have landed
safely in the body of water down there. I mean he could have been rescued by Hydra and turned into a super soldier. We don't know or that now now it's justified. Right? I'm not I'm not like accusing them of doing something improper here, but but they're definitely kinda need to process that.
I don't think the Ducktales knew when they poked him with a pin that the train happened to be on a bridge. They just knew that he left out, but
not. And he's not a sympathetic character But yeah, it's it's vicious.
For sure. I just definitely wanna highlight Al all our instances of of characters
dying
this
Right. You know, you touched on something that that sparked an idea in my brain Warren. He's not a sympathetic character. And and it's made clear that he's not a sympathetic character, not just because he's pointing a gun at Our Ducktales.
But because he's not drawn as attractive.
Right. As the sympathetic characters
are, and it's not just
Oh, well, she's a woman so we're gonna draw her attractive.
It turns out that she... Well, maybe I shouldn't spoil that, no. But you you make a good point though. I mean, if you look at him too, he's got shades of Peter Lori, the the kind of rap kind of looking
James C when he was a bad guy then he became a good guy in a lot of those movies. But to me, this chain sequence was right out of thirty nine steps. There's so many shades of all of these great hitchcock trained movies This guy's is just pure bad. I mean Barks took extra measures to say he's gonna fall a long way. I'm guessing
I'm guessing he drew that river down there as as like, prop
against his editors telling him. I can't show him dying. Oh, absolutely. Wait. Well, that's that's classic Disney. Right? Like, nobody can actually
die. They can only fall off of things. No. You you don't show the death you can you can... But this one
walks up to the line way more than than most and them. So Madame Triple x comes in
she's holding her purse. She's she's dressed the pink dress now
instead of just her bathing suit. So men and the planes scared me.
Think say wanted just this bag.
She she butters them up. She says, thank you for for having me and making me feel safe Donald offers her drugs. Yeah.
Can't i give you some sleeping pills, M hell you must be very
And she says no.
I'm sure I will go to see without any help and then she falls asleep. It looks like a trap. Right, Like,
Ducktales
everybody nudge he
her
now that she is asleep because they want the bag. And as they as Donald reaches for it, cl, a knife comes down in between his fingers and shields yields.
So you would like to steer my little bag black bag.
Jump all of you up the window chip. They're back in the same predicament.
And
they goodness another tunnel,
this spice, she says curse
And it turns out
they do jump. It is safe once they get out of the tunnel
And
Mcdonald's demeanor has has clearly changed. Right? Because he like,
volunteers.
Oh, yeah. Not only is it clear for them to jump out, but
they kind of willingly do it. And
he says, okay, madam triple x, now, we will jump
Al,
and they jump into a stream. I've Gottfredson
restrained myself from talking too much about this sequence, but but again, There's so much going on here. First off, you're you're right. She's like she's clearly laying a trap. Barks does a really nice job. I think of giving her some agency
here. And and as as a woman,
she... She's judging that her best way to to test these new people
is to look like she's letting her guard down. It's really clever. Right? She... This is the first time she brings out her s.
And
you know, she can give as good as any of those spies. So she's willing to to tell him to jump out the window as she knows she needs to. And I don't think that there's anything unto word about what the ducks do here, but it it definitely
looks deeply uncomfortable.
They're they're really eater expressions
and the offer of sleeping pills and then the n
you know, just to be like around this beautiful woman and and waiting for her to go to sleep it in in the context of this story, It's very reasonable and it's very
understandable. But the way the camera
lingers on her and the overall situation it feels
extremely
unsettling.
I I didn't even think of it that way because I was so focused on the mac.
U
But you're so
right.
I mean, the Ducktales are focused on the Mac. You know, they're they're not thinking about anything else, but, like,
it's as a reader, it's impossible not to think about that. That situation. And and
the comic book's camera
has like been so focused on her and how beautiful she is in and look at that second panel you guys when she has just gotten into the train car and she's like, my her hair. It it it looks
incredibly su.
It is. And she's positioning herself as this ph patel and she's... I loved what you said about her.
Testing the ducks. What I love about it is we we move down toward the
where they they become the guilty culprits of being spies themselves by almost being the counter spy to her
by stealing it they're. They're just as guilty as the other spies, maybe not as lethal, but they're guilty.
And then I love Donald because this is classic donald, but we gotta draw a peace treaty. Come on. We gotta do something. And then the icy cold jump
before the Tunnel sequence. The little spikes down from that speech bubble. Yeah. I see cold exactly. It's great.
Warren and you're absolutely right. They're they're playing... They're playing in the mud, you know, they they feel like they have to because they're doing this on behalf of their country.
So when they land and what is pretty fortunately,
you know, a shallow
retention pond or whatever. The nephews are a gas that he didn't try to put up more of a fight. But
we get this nice reveal where he's like, you know, on yourselves. I Donald duck Super spy got what I was after and he pulls out the black bag, which he has
secreted in his clothes.
And
and he takes a look to see if the qb bomb plans are safe. But he's horrified
to find only
rib bread and Al salami. And and we get this great pan back to Triple x when she she is chuck to herself hoping that the that z joy might lunch.
And then we got another great moment of the counters spy appearing
the other
seat is also sea
a a counter spy who says I hope you enjoy lunch with me in
handcuffs and introduces him self as Scotland ex,
counter counter counter counter, never mind, counter.
A great little lamp shading of of this ridiculous back and forth.
And so the Ducktales we transitioned back to the docs while, is dealing with him, and and they've noticed that their train is making a bend. So they get ready to board the train again and as they look like they're going to, Madame triple x
does her own
and lands bodily on them She has jumped out of the train. They all
tumble
down the ravi into the water
and
She
explains that she didn't like the fresh gentleman
that popped from under the other
who wanted to put bracelets
on her wrists. So we've got this interesting little bit where she's she's clearly referring to, you know, he wants to arrest her, but but she's presenting it like it's a come on. And and we got this little moment of d
now where they're kind of on the same level, They both just out of the train.
So they do get that little almost peace treaty and she offers to have some of that rye bread and Al salami. Yeah. Mark, the the narrative panel introduces sort of this next sequence where... Yeah, I think there's they're a little at peace and I love the transition from her bending over and her hair kinda must and she's dripping wet. And the boys and Donald are clearly happy to see her, but the next panel talks it kind of refers her back to the the spy who still has the hidden plans
perhaps in her shoe.
They're curious. And then if you... It's she's w and humming
gladly now becoming sort of the domestic
character
preparing them a meal with that.
Salami and Rye. Ducktales don't look so thrilled anymore.
They're waiting for an opportunity to get the upper hand once again, but still very very worried about getting those plans to the other spy in Chile Be. So
they are eating the sandwiches,
a little far shot of her clamoring up the hill in her heels, which I think is really interesting.
It was a pleasure to dine with you. I'll be on my way and now boys.
Wait. We'll go with you. We'll be your bodyguard
and she just looks over her shoulder and she goes
boys. That is so the role.
And she starts laughing
and as they clam up the hill after her,
the Nephew starts getting a little dr. This is where Donald looks back at the sleeping nephews on the bank right near the track, Donald finally realizes that madame Triple X has Al laced their sandwiches
with
what does he say?
Sleeping pi
and he
kong's out
dangerously
with it the long Ducktales neck over the rail on the train, and that's where
we leave it off there, Sarah. What do you think? Yeah. I just wondering if the sleeping pills that she used were the Ducktales own. I thought about that if if she was able to find them... Okay. I have a feeling she had her own collection. Yeah. She's also
she's also
so skilled. I think she could have gotten theirs and not how to dig into her own stash. Sure knows how to use that s though. She can use it as a weapon and as a kitchen.
I like that. Right. So she continues to
climb the hill. She says those widely streams won't to be following me soon.
I can afford to snatch a little rest myself in the cool tall grass. She's gonna take a nap of proper nap while they're drugged out on the train tracks.
Meanwhile, the cannonball ball express roar near and nearer And inside the the train, the drivers, the engineers are are asked them. What time is it Pierre? Six o'clock, gaston dawn?
Six o'clock, sexy Barks stops the train. Why what floor? At six o'clock, we trade men go on strike have you forgot
And they train
just stops in the middle of wherever they are inches away from Mcdonald's Neck. I feel like that was a little bit of the kind of look that Gladstone Gander would have. And I was glad that to see that Donald had some of it. But he doesn't even know it. Right? That's the way that he's allowed to have that kind look. And this sequence here was to me the the little slaps stick sequence Al little you've seen this in Harold Lloyd movies you've seen this in a lot of these silent films with the train that's... Now for for this reason, they go on strike, which is pure comedy, perfect timing And and the characters, I will say I don't know about both of you, but the
Pierre and gaston
look a little bit more cartoon ish. They don't have that real stick human features. They've got extended noses. Whether they're they're getting French car.
Right? Yes. They are Al that. Yeah. They're supposed to look like the french
branches.
They have like, stereotypical
French names again. I really like how
suspense this bit feels. Right? Like, he's he's Al asleep on the tracks. It looks very dramatic. And then the fact that he gets saved by this far
And this is Barks poking fun at like this common... What's it called? You know, this this is one of those stereotypes about the French. And many Europeans, but like, this is well known that French rail or rail rail workers are always going on strike. And this is a little bit of Barks, I think poking fun of a little bit of fun organized labor. I don't think he's the biggest fan of
lamborghini
Right. Right. Alright. So the Ducktales eventually wake and and they encounter this this deserted train here.
And you know, they don't really even register how close donald came. But they're they're kind of despair that the train is completely deserted
they're annoyed because, you know, this could have been a great way to get to Chile Berg area.
And and they resolve it kind of dawn on them that, hey. Maybe we don't need to be super honest because we are doing... We're we're doing what we're doing in the interest of saving country.
So they
decide to take the train and Donald gradually figures out how to operate it, and we get this nice little shot of the train gearing up as it passes the sleeping mud triple x.
She
sees that as a good opportunity to herself to get to chile area and and she jumps the aboard. And we get this
nice little short segment where
again, lamp
organized labor.
That we've got this runaway
locomotive, but
a switch man refuses to just do the simple action of throwing the switch to derail it. Telling the mayor that a switch are on strike. I love the whole idea of Madam Triple x
lounging in the grass and the the opportunity
to
jump on a train,
certainly not knowing who's piloting the train or who's the engineer? I just I just love her so much.
She's like, okay. I'm gonna take a nap. Because
resting is important.
Yeah. Yeah. And and then she sees an opportunity and she takes it. And she gets back on the train. And then there's another instance of
donald and the boys getting Gladstone
type look with the train switcher, also being on strike. So they just get to pass on through and do whatever they want. Yeah. And it feels like that kinda happens stance that happens in these movies. Right? I thought of that too where she pair right onto their train car. Right? Oh, yeah. No.
Really kind of fore foreshadowing and a lot of the great spy movies of after this. So if we pick it up with the train
barely into Chile Be,
hours ahead of of of Donald and the Nephews fond Hopes.
I find this kind of an interesting sequence because then the boys and Donald jump jump off what they think is an abandoned train and of course, Madame Triple x is surprised in this next panel as she either awakens or just looks out the window and and notices that they're barrel through Chile Be.
She
holds the emergency stop cord on in her car and we see this
incredible sequence of this train
breaking down
in the track buck
to a a fierce stop.
She's not injured, but boy that next panel shows her determined
that full engineer. I'm gonna give him a piece of my mind. And then she realizes and almost faint when she realizes that There isn't an engineer in the camp. Did you guys notice
her accents slip out here? I did. I noticed there's no z There's no... And it's almost like she breaks into Georgia Corn a little bit. Yeah.
What do you think? You think that was intentional? Did Barks let that happen or did Huey, make a did slip. Yeah. I mean, she's she doesn't need to, like, keep up the facade, but but I I remember as a reader the first time I read this I didn't notice. Right? He has the
luxury
when he's writing the dialogue. He can write it Wait. I didn't realize it until I went back. And read it again and oh, you know, we...
I was just
inserting her accent
here, but but she's not. So I thought that
It's a very good play by Barks knowing that she's alone, and there's nobody around her so why she have to put on a show. Good. Call. But the reader is not... They're not gonna notice it unless they're being really a astute. It's interesting to hear that when she lets her guard down, she she doesn't have to keep up that facade. It's the only time we see her kind of at a loss and, like, looking very emotional.
Yeah. I didn't I... you know, me and and Barks accents. I hope had kind of
blocked it out. And so when it wasn't there, I just hadn't been paying attention.
Oh, my gosh.
That's...
Genius.
Okay. So
Donald,
So they're clearly in Chile Bulgaria, which is,
you know, spain. And during that time, it was under the rule of general Franco.
An enemy
to the allied powers,
at that point.
And
they are
trying to locate
operator for x
And then here's a
here's another accent so bad
that I feel offended on behalf of all of the brown people
that he's used it on previously, but this is a European.
Yeah. So I have mixed feelings about it, and I'm not going to imitate it
Da La crackle is in his dressing room Al deb boo
obviously,
bull fighting has is is very, very steep in the culture of
of
Spain and Portugal
literally
every town of above a certain size
anywhere
on that peninsula
has its own bull.
And Americans, of course are familiar with it from hemingway weight back you know, fifteen, twenty years before. And so they go to find Donald El,
and
and they realize he looks just like uncle Donald.
Except with black hair.
Donald gets a super wonderful idea,
we can guess what that is.
And one of the boys recognizes
Med triple x
coming up the way and they have to work fast to execute Donald idea.
Yeah. Barks version of Spain kinda looks like Mexico to me. I don't know If i'm off base there, but it looks like Adobe pueblo. The traditional dress on the woman in the window
indicated to me that the the veil,
especially
kind of like, oh, yes. This is Spain. It it is kind of non.
Right?
Okay. He's not drawing it as lovingly as he does the French riviera.
Right.
So
so the docs do exactly what we think they're gonna do. Right? The the plan is very obvious. They get the jump on Don
Cla, Donald,
very amusing
refers and to himself Al Don El Ducktales to you bud and they have to get him out of the way to keep him quiet. And and they while Donald is getting dressed,
and
coloring his quote, hair,
black. The nephews
are figuring out that they can put him in the shower
and run this cold water hose that's labeled Ag f. And this this is kind of this very cartoon ish analog for, like don't don't move or you'll get it. It's it's instead of the nephew holding him at bay with a gun, they're holding him at Bay with freezing cold water. It's it's kinda ridiculous. It's kinda funny and it's kind of uncomfortable all at the same time to me. And and Donald Greet my triple x just in time, and he really lays into it after he kinda sykes himself up. He does he's now into his disguise and he's playing this character. He thinks to the Hilton and what he what he should be acting like Don convinced he's playing part here. But them Triple x
comes into the room. Notice his accent kind of goes away there. And of course, now we see a lot of the
cloak dagger here. We see a lot of the back and forth of the the counter spy activity with
Madame triple x basically just a moment Eager beaver. You look too much like a I met on the train. So she's seen through this.
Prove that you are don El.
And this is a funny gag. He sees these this great portrait of himself or the the ronaldo on the wall. Goes Well, there, there's a picture of me. Yeah. I got to see better credentials than that. She says as she spins I could see her spitting this s letter with her hand. It's a classic panel. Just then you see the
the
administrators of the bull fight, they kinda come in and so they're ready for you, then although
the crowd is waiting for you. And of course, Madonna triple x says that's it. Where we can see you must fight the and the donald great little gag not quite looking at the camera, but he's looking away
in
disbelief that he's got prove it. He's got Al little lump at his throat. You can tell he's swallowing hard on that one. He was so confident
until
she told him that he had to find the bold to prove who he was. I was really proud of him because you know how sometimes he doesn't have confidence.
Yeah. That's true. This is a great page. I I love this page. Right? This is...
The sequence almost
too short for me. Right? Because this is the dangerous
disguise of the title. Right. You know, he's instantly in this situation.
She's got some great hoses
in this page. Like, you you mentioned it warren where she's
spinning the s at and then that very, like, su tree
look as she leaves the room. He
he had fun drawing music. Yeah. Barks isn't afraid of the female form and he wants to accent it anytime he can. And again, we think we said it before, he's taking really good care in his drawing here.
Almost a a a hard contrast to the
the animated human like features of the others in the room the men. Yeah. They look... They look goofy. I think supposed to remind us of Laurel and hardy. Well, maybe here's what I thought and see if see if the readers the listeners Al may agree with this. There's a wonderful
short
animated
silly symphony called Ferdinand and the bull. If you remember that, and it was
done in the mid forties. It's known that the one of the Mat in that storyline
was purposely
i
Walt Disney himself. And if you look at this one here, who's coming in, there's a Disney
kind of look with the mustache and the shape of the face. And I and I couldn't help, but saying, was Barks kind of borrowing from Ferdinand the bowl and that little side gag of one of them, the mat being walt Disney. I thought that was possible. I be right. That's fun. But there definitely is a laurel and Huey, to now that you've mentioned it especially I was looking on the next page too that Sarah. Yes. Yes.
So Donald is thinking I knew it. I knew it. Something awful would have to turn up and spoil my good luck. So he is recognizing that he's having good luck, but of course, he's focusing
on the bad luck. And he tries to negotiate
asking for an older sick
and the men who are organizing the bull fight her
Nun but the wildest fiercest bull's fight in the ring at Chile bulgaria, is a matter of Civic pride
which bull fighting is
the utter... like, the ultimate test of masculinity.
Right. As
the other Mat saying this. He smack
the third mat in the face by accident.
So, you know, very very physical comedy
another kind of call Barks to or another reference to Laurel and Hardy. And and and back in Don Al Cla dressing room. He's doing the
Your
will be showed up for his... The for the fake he is.
The kids.
Shut have you dirty spell. You make me still dogg on med and they squirt with the water. Yeah...
Daring to open his mouth. They've turned into ruthless cap.
Poor Al with the cold water. I don't know how Huey, said duck.
Cold waters. Easy. Okay.
And then there's a a wide shot of the bull ring. The crowd is cheering for Donald, but it's their cheering for
and that
tease the bellow beast into a towering rage
then outs
the mat,
calm courageous is cock, but it's donald literally sticking his toe in the arena and.
Those last three panels on that page are pretty awesome. It it reminds me when I talked about vacation time and there's a great just short three panels where
Barks does this amazing summing up of modern firefight. And in this, you know, it's it's only a couple of panels, but you get a great idea of what bull fighting is all about and and those narrator boxes. He refers to it as the art of getting killed. And has been Al into a rip roaring show.
And I... You know, it's a very controversial
topic, obvious sleeve, but bull fighting is is is it's pretty gross.
But that's a funny
contrast between the com courageous just cocky.
Narration and Donald t watching now. Alright. Alright. So
so the bull fight
is I think it's exactly what you would spec. Right? It takes up two pages.
It is the kind of slaps stick that we we know and we love we've seen this in Loo tunes cartoons. We see an enraged bowl charging. We see Donald barely avoiding. And we see him basically do a good job of fighting the bowl by complete accident.
Right. The whole time my triple x is is watching. And and he basically
it's great, but there's only so much that I can describe it here.
There's a lot of great near misses. He essentially blu and p falls his way into the bowl crashing
through the outer wall,
breaking the fire hydrant flooding the entire arena and and the crowd just
loves it. It's been a great show. He's carrying... He's h out on their shoulders as they
parade through the flooded arena. And and it's it's gone as
well as it possibly could. And this is one of those cases where if listener if you haven't
read this in a while. You you just gotta see it. I think the panel that you're ending on here with them just just ex. They're just celebrating
Donald in the guise of Don aldo
is absolutely a little surprised he's sitting on their shoulders as they're h them up as a hero.
I love that. And we we see now that he's back in the dressing room. Madame triple x, she's back Al her back against the door and now he is absolutely
convinced who he is. He's done Al and he's going to continue his his char aid.
And ask for those plans. And now we see the real although just
cow in fear as those fierce cap as Ci said are are ready to point that hose and give him another spray, but, unfortunately, the water pressure gave out
and
then although
immediately lunges out
knocking over the nephews
comes into the room Now we see Donald and then aldo together with Madame Triple x and the Nephew great panel there. So he's now kinda wondering who's who and
Alright. Although, you shall have zip plans and z y metal Al watch and sq.
And this is where
she does a little bit of
great espionage
work here and that is she peels back her nail where she reveals
I guess a microchip of some kind, they called it a micro photo
of Zip lands marvelous.
Our dictator. This is he's now he's he's got the plans in the dictator. The the Mighty B of Iron Huey, will hang a medal of x around
your neck, Madam, triple x. I hope it choke you your ugly old hague. That's donald now. Screaming from the corner. And that's a great shot of her kind of, you know, away
the insult. So as they then although is peer at this microchip chip this micro photo. So these are the plans and Barks
decipher them on twenty
It looks like mess of sulfur,
thirty protons, Gladstone,
octane.
Hey. Something's wrong here. He said the bomb is nothing but a fire cracker. For smoking term termites out of wooden Indians.
It's a ru from Met Triple x,
who
now takes out her cameron takes a shot of him Don aldo and says I'll say something's wrong here, mister
Mystery Spy, Alias Don, El.
And the boys are now completely beef. The question marks are are shaking their heads they like, what is going on And then
Says you you're not one of B Spies y, and this is where the reveal. I love this reveal.
I miss Georgia Ka of the secret secret service and Don Nephew just ecstatic
Right. They realized that that she's one of theirs. And she's American
And now a side view, please as she's taking apparently mug shots
of of Don novo.
I'm on assignment to photograph the key men in B
spy system.
And
now she kind of throws donald the nephews down a little bit because of the be
spy hunters over there got on my trail. I almost did succeed in getting you. And here's that troublesome panel that we've been talking a little bit about in some of this. And this is
but you did, and that means that B will send me to the salt mines
and he holler goodbye cruel world and just leaps out of the glass window. I'm not so sure it it's a suicidal tendency, but I'm not so sure that that's what happened, but that's up to the reader. Right? Mean, it's pretty pretty unmistakable. Right? That's the that's the cliche.
It is. I guess there's is the plausible den ability you don't see it. But but that... That's how this reads to me. It's it's very striking and... It's consistent with the rest of the story and of the
the brutality of the spy world if you wanna call it that, it's an outcome of donald Ba gang like you said before, who sits Mit. A brave move by Barks, I think. Yeah. I mean, it's definitely memorable. I like this little visual where, you know, they're the ducks are blanc at their little up braid when she's chi them for having almost ruined it, and he draws a little narration box that says very small. They're that's right Very nice And nice and little psych gag. He doesn't do a lot of them in the story, but that's a nice one.
This is a satisfying
reveal. I think. Right? Because he's he's built this up with all this counter counter counter, never mind counter spy and and for her to be the ultimate counter spy. Is a great way I think. It's a good payoff. Satisfying payoff for sure. Barks to the topic of the brutality,
even though it says... And I know
that it's a false finger now, and it's a drawing. Right? Like, it's a drawing and she specifically says it's a false swing nail. The brutality of
peeling up that false nail. He's messing with us. He is he making us have some body horror, like, visceral
horror feelings
about
that finger now. Like, that is intentional and very skilled. Yeah. It looks did either. If you get grossed out by that.
I definitely did as a kid. You know, I had to... I had to kinda look at it and be like, okay. This is this is clearly a a very false snail, but but I I agree. It I i did find that a little disturbing. Yeah. You can feel it you I I agree sarah. You can feel it. She does go out of her way to say that it's my fa finger nail, but that doesn't take away the the pain of the situation
And then her knife, she's...
It's it's kinda due in its own thing. You know, she's holding it at the Ducktales,
and then
she's
And then, you know, I hope it choke you you ugly had.
You know, before she Al them, she's holding it not by the, like, handled but by the tip of the blade. Like, she's clearly, like,
laying with it and and messing with it. She it gets to ended up stabbed in the dresser,
and then she's
holding it in her, you know, between her teeth and her mouth at one point, she's comfortable with it. Yeah. Yeah. And she's very comfortable.
Like, she's just intentionally throwing that
authority
around that menace in their faces.
I I just... I like how she's totally in charge. She's just commanding this situation. Oh, yeah. And then, you know, I mentioned it, but this quick little reference to B.
This is meant to be
stalin and Soviet union pretty clearly. Right? The reference to the salt mine. He's not even a Chile Bulgarian. He He's from Iron He. Is that what he's called?
He's Al iron Huey,.
Yes. So behind the iron Curtain,
Yeah. Yeah. Here's a little outdated reference. Right? It's a fire for smoking termites out of wooden Indians. I guess that's those
old Cigar store indians that you almost never see around. Right. So after all those
shocking demise, Sarah, what how how does it close out? And so
you see the sign post...
You see the sign post that they had in the first few panels
that indicates that they're back in the riviera and
out in the background,
there's a figure in black taking pictures and the boys are noticing him. And
we don't dare tell on Donald. He'd chew our tails off. And you can see he's... Donald Duck is over there. He's still
reeling and and
remorse
and embarrassed.
Just leaning slumped against rock on the beach in the riviera.
I like your description. He has he's reeling. Right? He's mh he is shook. And he's not having a good time don't. I wonder if
George Ka
paid for him to go to the riviera to get him out of her hair the way uncle sc did.
That would not surprise me. This is a this a nice closing. I think
it's need how the story has come full circle.
It's neat how the docs are back to this situation and just all totally should end. That wow, you guys... We we had some really great stuff to say about this one. I I like how this worked out. You guys actually help me appreciate this one a little bit more because it's a very tight
story, and it has some some really neat twists.
Any thoughts
overall, May maybe we can start with you, sarah since you
since you enjoy this one so much relative to the others. Since I'm wiggling my fingers.
Yeah. In front of my face and excitement.
I
freaking
love
Madame
Triple x.
She is Georgia hard is
exactly
the kind of spy I wanna be. Right?
Like if women
have to be relegated
to
these
objects that men look at and don't take seriously,
I would leverage that to my benefit
or, you know, my country's benefit
and
let people underestimate me, and then I I would I would mess him up with my
my little s that I have absolute control over
and parachute out of planes to get onto trains.
And take naps because resting is important. I just I just love her so much. She's my hero
You know what
Sarah, I have to just jump on that and say you're absolutely right. She is in control of this story.
She is a character that Barks not only had fun writing her dialogue, but trying her and and and letting the viewer as well as the ducks get confused
by her her mission.
You know, it was she was devious.
She made them sandwiches
she uncovered the spy ring. I mean, she did everything.
She even put them down at the end.
She she really was a little bit of everything there. Yeah. There are so many,
like, especially with his handling of of the woman characters.
There's always just like an
that even if they're portrait portrayed in a positive light, I'm like, oh,
And this one, it's such it's so first
because she makes them sandwiches, what's what's the stereotype? I don't know if it was the serial back then. But, like, right women are, you know, go the kitchen make me a sandwich. Right? So she makes them a sandwich. She she gets back into this
traditional woman's role. And in doing so, she takes back control of the situation. Yeah. I there's
so many times where she just leveraged
the the the box she got put in as a woman and just
mess people up, and I love it. Yeah. I I appreciate that. That's great. She's she's awesome.
I found her totally commanding.
Right? Like, I read in the Thomas Andre book too warren. And he he referenced something. He referenced somewhere that, like, she wasn't
that she never really...
I don't remember what he said, but that that she didn't really stack up as a character. And I I strongly disagree. I think she's utterly commanding and very memorable. And and, yeah, some of it is that she looks like a pin up model of course. But but he's working in that spy
arena where your your kind of, quote, allowed to have a fe
character. So... Yeah, The this works really well as what it's trying to do as, you know, being a great spy adventure, but also sending them up with all this over the top. Counter counter counter spy. How about you?
How this one land for you? Well, you know, I again, I'm so appreciative to read these stories after so many years and get a new take on it especially with our commentary and our thoughts.
And when when they apply it to modern modern society and and the cultures that we've seen
I am gonna say,
I think it's a very good story.
I think for me, what's memorable about it is certainly the human characters and how Barks
kinda Al his editors
in his own
fight for freedom of expression, I would say.
So I gave him a lot of credit.
I I love the blending of humor and
intrigued.
I love the artwork. There are many good panels and I know on on your Facebook site, you're going to features many on this one I can guarantee.
I love commenting on those. But I will say it if the story unfolds well. Unlike a lot of the other stories mark when we've talked about them seemingly
rushed toward the end. This one glide nicely to the end. I I like the way this one wraps up in the last few pages.
And then leaves them on the beach without going back to Duck. We don't see uncle sc Al all in this story. The balance of everything is so wonderful. I love the break from the the funny animal characters.
And for that reason, it's a memorable story, but also for that reason, it's probably not one of my favorite in terms of pure Ducktales stories
because I'm a big fan of glad and sc and when when all that comes together, it's more of a fantasy. This had a real world feel in many ways. And that's why his editors didn't like it and cheating with death and hinting to get suicide and and
guns and violence and
even though it's part of the spy genre,
very different for
funny animal comics. And so he got away with a lot. And then I'll close by saying, we know this is the time when he was going through his messi divorce. He was I think
separated for sure from his second wife and it was a difficult time for him, but it's interesting how he created this female character of great power
and control as well. So boy, you had a great point there. Oh, that was a I didn't realize that. But your... The fact that they they never touched Duck,
makes this feel a bit notable too. Well, that's why my favorite panel if you're gonna ask me what my favorite was, it was the very first panel.
One of my favorite because I love the intro line that Donald and the nephews landed there because they he they got paid handsome by by Scrooge to get out of Duck. I just loved that. I
Huey,.
It's a good panel. Let's let's do
that... That's a great favorite panel. Any other panels you wanna highlight in this one?
I'll just...
We're on that
second to last page, and I i I think the
the federal Ducktales with all question Barks is a really unique panel. You don't see that a lot.
I love, of course, we we've talked about the
the six gangster all pointing guns to each other is probably
the most intriguing panel. That's it for me. I'll I'll let you and Sarah kinda talk about your panels. Sure. Any any that stand to you, Sarah?
I did wanna point out at the very beginning. One of my favorite panels is
two of the boys sing, there's a guy that looks like a spy, he could hide the plans of a battleship in those whisk
and the the guy is has a kind of a z top
type long long long long long beard that so long it's curling up and it just reminded me of mean girls when
when they say, that's why her hair is so big. It's full of secrets.
Nice.
I have to again come back to that big counter counter spy that
that one really stuck with me. I couldn't remember much of this story when I went back to read it. You know? Because this is one that I don't think I didn't reread this as often as I read some of my other favorites.
And I think that is because it's stood out to me as so different
and dark. And I can probably appreciate it more these days.
Yeah. This is a great story. It's it's not one of my favorites, but I definitely
recognize it's greatness for a lot of reasons and it is it is fun and delightful. The community, I did mention,
this is well regarded by the community. This is almost
talk to... As of right now, index has this one ranked eleven. Out of all, you know, forty one thousand some Disney stories good for an eight point four. So it does not get much better than this one as far as the community goes. I I think some of that reputation is just because of how it stands out in people's mind, but it is it is definitely a great, ina a great story. As far as other reflections go, you know, it...
I think it holds up pretty well. You were saying Sarah, there's not a whole lot here. Some of the, like, just the fe fatal patel idea feels kind of dated, but it also feels kind of timeless. It's too bad that there was never a lit graph for this one. Right? Warren?
There wasn't one for dangerous
disguise. I think, well, I i to imagine, I'm surprised when Carl Barks took control of his oil paintings and his his photographs that he didn't include this in that canon of work, but he didn't. I think it would have been wonderful
to see something like that. Did you ever see the Dawn Rosa poster
that he did as a tribute for this one? I didn't.
Okay. So you gotta look that one up. I'll definitely share that on the Facebook page when we released. See Don Rose, it didn't some poster for this one. And he even included
a cameo of himself as an audience member
in the bowl.
Let's see. You guys... We we've said a lot about this great story. I'm about ready to wrap it up, but do you guys have any final thoughts you wanted to mention?
Warren. Great story. Again, great great
plot twists and the whole genre
just really came alive with me with this story. And I'll just highlight again, the human characters were to me of great plus in the storytelling.
And I'm so glad Carl Barks got away with it.
Again, a plus for his bravery in doing this and I think his confidence is an artist and a storyteller
really peaked here. Well, sad, how about you, sarah? I mean I already said the thing that I I love Georgia corn.
I just wanna be her so bad. Yeah. She's great. Hey. I'm I'm really glad that we got to do one that you you got some real genuine enjoyment out of too. Oh Thank you.
I think this worked out great you guys. Thanks for bringing two different
perspectives in.
Had a lot of fun revisiting this one, I think it turned out great.
Thanks, Mark. I really appreciate it, Sarah was really fun to to share this story with with you and and having the three of us poke Al a little bit and find out a little bit more about it. Yeah. Warren it was so good to to have another...
Not just mark, but another
one of the expert on these comics. I love being info dumped on. Awesome. I'm so glad I totally agree. Well, hopefully,
hopefully, listeners enjoyed it as well. And hopefully, they'll come back next time to listen
to no such var. A very fun one. As always, reach out at Barks remarks at gmail mail dot com. We're on the Facebook page, and we'll talk to you next time.