Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of sc Mc and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge cl of all time, join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Hello, and welcome back to Barks remarks I'm Mark Sever. A grown man who enjoys du comics and who
still doesn't have an intro that he's totally happy with. But what are you gonna do?
I am here with a new guest c.
And we're gonna be talking
today about a very fun story. We're gonna be going over Barks
serpent tail, no such var. But first, let me have my guest introduce himself. Hi. I'm Austin and Kelly.
It's not much interesting about me. I guess I'm just like you and and everyone listening. I mean, I'm a big Barks fan. And you know, I've been talking to a mark for a while
about Barks comics, disney comics in general, and I'm very happy to be here to talk about you know, a very cool, very fun Barks story. Excellent. Yeah. Thanks for thanks for being here. It's it's one of the neat things about doing this project is that I'm finally getting to meet people who really enjoy these comics. So so it is fun. When people reach out. And I know that you've got your own
interests in in other non
comics and cartoons.
Right? Do you wanna give a quick plug to what you do? Sure. So for while I collaborated with Anthony Coat on his great Anthony's animation talk channel on Youtube,
We were doing a lot of stuff during the pandemic. Common live commentary over, great one of brothers cartoons
I was doing a series
called the magic of freeze framing highlighting
some of the great warner animators and their work.
But as the pandemic
sort of cool down. I sort of got busier and I haven't done a lot with Anthony in a while, but, you know, I've done dozens and dozens of videos and you can find them all up on his channel, and Anthony animation talk, And, you know, beyond that, that's pretty much it, but that was all very fun. And this is sort of the first comics related podcast,
video, any sort of thing I've, you know, ever really done. So this is Al like a new experience, but also sort of something that I'm familiar with at the same time. Excellent. Yeah. Some of that
classic loo
stuff. From about this same era is just wildly entertaining and and beautiful to watch. Oh, yeah. So Austin, you, you are pretty familiar with this issue with no such pharma. Mh. I... It's actually one of the first four colors I ever read that I had Barks embark adventure in it. So I read it a few times and you know, it's not the greatest Barks story, but that's only comparing it to his absolute masterpieces. It's a it's a great, you know, fun adventure. Yeah. I I'd agree. This is this is a lot of fun. This is
probably pretty mid considering it's in is what most people would call his golden age. But it is. It's it's a good time and and you have the fourth color.
Yeah. I collect the original dell books
so I have the original copy and a lot of other original copies for a lot of the original printing of the great Barks stories. So that's all fun. Nice. So we should you you mentioned that it was a dell
publication here in the Us. So let's let's talk about this actual
original issue. Oh, yeah. So I think this was originally published
you can correct me if I'm wrong, but there's... I think four color three eighteen,
so it was a one shot in a series of, you know, this this line of books that Dell would use for characters that, you know, they didn't think we're good enough for their own title yet. Put out in nineteen fifty one and usually Barks with your Al cover for the story. But the comma for this book was actually done by someone named. I don't know if I'm pronouncing is properly. Carl B,
something like that. He did a lot of great work with the ducks.
The big bad wolf and the other disney titles that Dell was doing. So Yeah. I I think it's Carl B. That's how I've always pronounced it in my mind. Although I realized now that I've never heard it said out loud. He was kinda the western like, in house artist. And yeah, You're right. He did this cover. He he got to do a lot of Barks covers for a while until they finally gave it to him for old Castle secret. It is nineteen fifty one, early fifty one, January is the publication date, and I I talk austin and usually about how many
reprint these have.
This one has kind of the average number in the Us. It's good for eight
printing counting this one. But I noticed something pretty interesting about one of the reprint. For this one. I don't know if you encountered this at all, but this is something that I learned about. And you heard of the Dino bright comments by chance Mh. The the late seventies Whitman line. Yeah. Have you ever seen one of those? Well, I buy a lot of the, like, the old dell Barks. So I actually see those like, i ton around. They're not, you know, particularly of interest to me. But I know that that printing
when they reprinted no such Barks, there's a covered that's the same one that B, you know, B whatever you wanna pronounce name as did, but it's sort of like traced over. It's sort of like a red wrong, I think. Right. So when I think of Whitman, there was kind of a dark era for the American Disney comics. There's a lot of... I would call junk stories. They were still doing a lot of the re reprint. The color was pretty ga that, like, late seventies.
They they really clogged the back issue bins. And I mean, this one still looks kind of ga, but I think the idea is that it was supposed to be much more premium.
Right? It had, like a a much nicer
cover I gather more like cardstock
with some gloss or pages
inside and it would be a lot longer. I think this one, they didn't do very many of these and about half of them were Disney comics. I think there were only like one to two dozen of them released though in, like nineteen seventy eight. So I I thought that was kinda neat. I I also
researching this, I I learned from reading my glad back issue that apparently Barks
had to kind of evade a dictate that Western Publishing had against
showing snakes in their comics.
And and that just cracked me up. The
letter or the the little paragraph basically
implied that the only way he got around it was that his snakes were just like so so dang cute looking that they didn't really trip the sensors. Yeah. Well, that actually is pretty interesting. I know in the mid fifties around around fifty five Dell crackdown on a lot of that stuff and they had they, you know, had a strict set of rules that know, their artist and writers had to follow. That affected Barks, it affected everyone that we're working with. But they didn't really strictly follow that stuff
before that point, but I guess the snake thing does sort of make sense. Yeah. Any any
interesting trivia or anything you came across that you wanna share at this point. I think there's something interesting is like, c serpents come up a lot in Barks work. I mean, not a whole ton, but
some like, somewhat often. This is the second of five times that he used, like a serpent creature like coming out of, like, a body of water. There was the famous terror of the river. Is this one,
there's a later day... Latter day ten page or called mystery of the log.
A gold key ten pager called Instant Hercules,
and then something that he only wrote didn't draw for gold key called a B lee of Lake Erie the junior wood shocks that was done in the early seventies. So... And and there's also... There was a cool... A bunch of cool covers done for this one. Probably most notably, the the Don rosa one. You showed merely on your Donald like adventures reprint. Yeah. I... I'm a big fan of that that rose one. I think it's a great attention get. I think I think you're right. I think it's fair to say that it's a lot of sea serpent. When you when you consider that I I remember I talked about this when I did the episode on terror of the river. It seems weird to me like c serpents are kind of a famous
you know, arch monster. And yet there's not a ton of like, pop culture famous
representations of that. Like Barks has his and, you know, he's not, like, super famous.
But you got the lock ness monster
but it gets pretty obscure pretty quick if you if you're really struggling. You're a fan of the old cartoons, Maybe you know Bin and Ce. Oh, yeah. Totally. Then that's an interesting one.
So you still the c six c serpent. But Yeah. Barks like sea serpents obviously. Because this was just five years
after terror of the river.
And
I... It's hard to, like, kind of escape the fact that the the creature design is very, very similar
for for the two of them. Mh.
Yeah. It's interesting in my mind, a terror of the river and no such var. When I was, like a very casual Barks fan. Like, they sort of blended together in my mind because his four color adventures with Donald from the forties have this all very unique flavor to them and, you know, in the mommy's he's ring you've got you know, this this mommy, you know,
in frozen gold, you've got this very distinct, like, art setting.
But like the c serpent that sort of serves as the major plot point in this one and tear the river. Like, they they kinda blend together in the minds in a way. Yeah. I agree. They they look so similar. But there's, like, a big difference in that. This one is so it's really goofy when it comes down to it. Mh. And of course and, of course, you know, spoiler, it is real. So anything else you wanted to share before I transition into our our titles from around the world. That should be it. I I do think it's cool looking on, like Ducktales and then seeing all the covers that have been done for this one around the world, you know, throughout, you know, the past seventy years whatever. So I would suggest the viewer to, you know, go on and check those out. Those pretty cool. Yeah. Absolutely, man. I'll I'll make sure to
share him on on the facebook a page as well. Yeah. I I definitely have some other stuff I wanna talk about, but I don't like to drag out the intro too long, because Boy, there's a lot to say about, like, snake charming and and some other
interesting subjects for this. But I I do like to pan Austin to my
international audience. And I imagine they get a kick out of me butchering
titles in different languages.
So I've I've given you a couple, and I've got a couple here. Why don't I start us off with
French? So in French, this one's called
So that's pretty straightforward, Donald Charms the
serpent of the c. That's that's actually a pretty cool one.
In Germany, they call this one and this is like like a crazy word I don't know if I'm gonna pronounce it right, but like, they call it
sc
well
or something like that, which roughly translates just a snake charm, which is, I guess, fairly straightforward.
Yep. Yep. It's one of those
big German
combined nouns.
Let's see. And then I'm gonna do
Norway and in Norwegian. It's no Ducktales
c... Okay. Donald Ducktales,
which is Donald Duck and the c worm. Got it... I gotta assume that's worm kinda like w
r m. Think a Norse word for Dragon or something. That's a cool one And then in Italy,
they call this one
of pent
dim
which is donald and the snake charm, which is you know, fairly bland, but
more descriptive than the German one, I guess. Yeah. And you know what? I am gonna throw in one other because I realized there is a weird one. In Spain, this was
and Donald has a flute, kind of kind random.
So
as we transition into discussing the the kind of story Arc here austin, I'm always kind of thinking
with these stories about what is the iteration, the the type that Donald and the Nephews are. Right? Because he he famously
makes Donald in every man. So, you know, sometimes his appearance is her heroic, sometimes it's coward
that's something that I like to think about. So I'm gonna kick it off by
talking about page one and the set up for no such var. This is really interesting to me. It's a neat little book end. Right? I guess, before we get to the book, we have this really quick drawing in the reader to a
a ship rack. There's a ship out at c and Barks
introduces it as being very mysterious.
Right? One of
sc Mc ships
that is full of gold from his last minds strikes a mysterious object and sinks And in just two panels, we've got the
crew escaping
and just kind of puzzling over how mysterious that is. And then we quickly trans addition to Duck where we've got the Nephews
and they are just pondering
sort of the the greatness of men. And how some men are great and some men are bumps.
And this is this is a really interesting
characterization I think of the nephews
because they're not usually
so like, high minded.
But but this is the story that Barb wants to tell. And so they're they're pointing out these
different great men who all happen to be walking by and they point them out by name and they point them out by eye q occupation, and they're all very, like, clever puns on their names. They they list off flynn hide, the banker,
who's rich and successful,
shy the lawyer,
famous for his wit or.
Go ahead on the next page Austin. Oh, yeah. On the next page, we have
grown bombs, the great doctor,
Barks up a millionaire merchant
This is a good one scribble the great writer. This one actually might be like one of my favorite Barks names ever.
Trial n error
the mighty chemist who walks by in crutches and, like, multiple bandages over his face.
Yeah. I really like this little opener. This this really
is memorable to me this, like, parade of great men. This this was one of the things I hadn't read this in well over a decade, and I remembered this vividly. Yeah. It's a it's a really nice opening And I have to say I i I think what's cool about Barks is work is that a lot of the characters aren't really portrayed is just, you know, like, dumb animals as a lot of people kinda made them. But I think there's like a real, like, bit of human nature and the fact that just randomly one day like, these nephews are just sitting around and thinking like, you know, there's so many great men and our uncle uncles a total failure. I think like random spurt of, like, that sort of thinking,
really reflects, like, how, like, you and I would think, Like someday, we would... You know, almost like a midlife crisis where you kind of get up and you're like you know, what do I amount to? Right. So go ahead and tell us about the contrast with the the great man on the rest of this page. Oh, yeah. This this great bit.
Donald shows up with a basket and a flute hand and one of the nephews goes and there comes
donald and they all turn
sad and grim, and they're all sitting on this brick wall. And Donald, you know, coming along, he's very happy and I've finding interesting because he's rarely this displeased and just immediately happy in the Barks stories. And in the ten pager
you know and he's got some sort of new profession. He's got this sort of optimism and positive
look to his like, new job, but you know, that all is shot down very quickly. But he starts out like, very happy here. So he's just walking along and his nephews he's just attack Al Donald, Aren't you ashamed your yourself. And what I really like is is the next panel is him just going... What have I done now? Like, he knows? They're just getting him for some, you know, something. Right. And I I think that's a great point. You know, we don't usually get to see him this, like, content
that on that next page, you know, they're just... They're roasting him basically for not amount to much.
And they're they're conveying to us that they they feel ashamed of him. And and this is pretty striking. Right? Because, like, the nephews not usually,
like I said, they're not usually this sort of like status conscious, I would say. And
they're they're really feeling
ashamed of their uncle.
It's also interesting that we don't usually get to, like,
talk overt
about his success. Right? I think it's just kind of a given that he's kind of a general failure. He has another job every week. But they don't usually like, highlight that fact. Like, what what should we tell our classmates? What do we tell our teacher
that you do? And and so by the end of this page, he's setting them up that he's saying finally found something that he can do really well. As
great. And then the next page, he shows up and he know go be seated gentlemen and I'll show he's all being very classy. And and nephew you start re,
he's got dignity. He's gonna be a great musician.
So he sets up and Donald just ends up being a snake charm. He plays a little something on his flute and the snake pops out of the basket,
and the nephews are immediately
ashamed.
Which I find interesting because,
you know, if we're supposed to assume that, like, everything that's happening in Barks stories before this one, is like something that happened in the past and this, like, individual universe. Like, you would think the nephews user are happy get Donald finally
grasp onto something, he can do well after so many failures is, you know, so many so many different occupations that, you know, he's taken up in the past. And I find there, like,
dissatisfaction
very, like, odd and out of character.
Right, especially since they're usually that sort of little boy mold of of thinking creepy crawl stuff is cool. But But again, this is the story that Barks wants to tell.
Austin,
do you like the ten pager that are they've been called before like, the brittle mastery of Donald Duck where he he masters an occupation and then it goes horribly wrong. Oh, yeah. Those they're good. I think the later ones can get a little,
you know, you get a little deja vu with them, especially if you, you know, red a lot of Barks work. But I think the ones done up to this point and fifty one, we're really good. The one that sticks out in my mind is
I think it's from nineteen forty eight. I don't know what people call it because, you know, these were all the ten are.
It's called wired where he's up against the Nephews uses as a telegram boy. I always thought that one was great. Yeah. I remember that vaguely.
I tend to love those stories. Like you said the earlier ones. It's interesting that this is almost like a an adventure length version of those.
I I love the snake so much. This this little snake that he says, you know,
don't don't smear at me this outfit, including the snake cost five bucks. I'll have, you know, and the snake looks all hot.
It's hilarious to me. It's one of my favorite parts of the story. And so on the next page,
you know, the nephews are despair that he's just gonna be a snake charm.
And he wants to prove himself you know, that he can't... He can do more than just
charm this train snake out of a basket.
And so he
he goes ahead and charms a bunch of wild snakes.
And again, it's it's very funny. They look weirdly adorable for snakes and the nephews are just totally revolt.
Yeah. I I think this is like all very appealing. I mean, like we said, he's Donald never really just this fully satisfied in any
point in any Barks story. So I really like the image in the bottom right where he's just kind of happily going along with the state the the snakes. So anyway, on on the next page,
we have, you know, him trying to sneak some more, and the nephews walk away and and, you know, discussed and whatever. And they find
newspaper with the want ads open. And they pick it up and they read the ad let professor and make dome, read your dome. He can tell you what you're good for. So they rush to get donald there so they can find out, you know, what he can finally do with him self. And I have to say I I like
having the nephews pick up the newspaper and the reader being able to see
the headline about Sp
sunk gold chip, you know, kind of tying it all back to, like, don't forget that bit at the beginning because we're about to go deeper into that in a few pages. I kinda like how Barks subtly does that there. Yeah. I agree. That wasn't... That was a nice little nudge.
And and this was such a a classic, like, plot device having someone spot something on a newspaper, which just feels hopeless outdated now.
So on the next page, we get this this experience in Mcdonald's office in this doctor or this professors office.
And, you know, the way they talk about
how he can tell what what someone should be by the feel of their head, it just instantly made me think of,
you know, the like debunked science where someone is supposed to be able to feel the contour and the shape of someone's head and
and know about their characters. So this is this is some great, like, quack
that that you kinda saw a lot in this era of storytelling.
And and the idea here is that the professor is gonna attach all these sensors and it's gonna display a number on
screen,
which corresponds to something that he's gonna look up in his book. And we get this great Barks gag where the professor adjusts his glasses, and he misses a little fly that lands on
the the number one hundred and fifteen
and appears to be a decimal point. And as I recall, this was a plot point in one of those brittle mastery
stories. The one where he was
the master wreck. There was, like a a little bug that totally messed him up by posing as
a decimal in a in an address or something.
So one of those elements he uses multiple times.
Interesting. Yeah. The master
one... Is that a... Like, is that a sixties ten pager? I think that's a way i I think it's definitely a later one. I think it's one of the better later ones. This the one with the wrecking ball where he's like an artistic building demolish.
Yeah. I've it's haven't things.
I I definitely wanna check that out. It's it's fantastic. It's a great one. Is a nice one. I do wanna bring up one thing before I move on to the next page. I I like the way Barks structures is stories, but I think just the convenience of the fly
landing on the the one hundred and fifteen is sort of like, oh,
lucky the fly was there that very moment. Like, almost a cool coincidence of sorts. I mean, he would take it's, like more of an extreme level and, like, I think the ending of the gil man comes to mind, that's it's sort of, like a weird one where it's like,
you know, how's... I I can't remember how that story goes, but, like, oh, how's Donald gonna, you know, get the money for this stamp that, you know, he just, like, traveled around the world for. There's a lot of that in the stories that have glad stone, right? A lot of a lot of massive coincidence.
Mh. But yeah. I forgot about those. Those are those are pretty good though. I think. I just like... I'm always like Glad Al a character especially.
I think he works great in, you know, the short ten pages.
On to the to the next page
where the professor looks up what eleven point five means.
And apparently means that Donald is this great detective. And
the nephews
immediately start re and and donald, you know, walking away and discussed. And what I find. Interesting is, like, I I feel like nephew is this point have been characterized is almost like, these
mature adult figures.
I feel like they should know at this point.
Knowing Donald, he's not gonna be able to latch onto any sort of profession no matter how easy are hard like right away.
But anyway, they walk away into the park and
you know, They asked donald what they're gonna do. You know, what you gonna do now? Are you're gonna rent an office? Start solving mysteries and then he just pulls down his flu it goes back to charming snakes, which I find really funny he he walks off into the distance. Yeah. I I really like that image of him.
You know, stubborn pulling the the little flute out. That's a great that's a great visual.
So we we transition now to
sc mc dot. And this is a pretty neat view of his office. You know, we're we're still transitioning into, like, Barks.
Figuring out how much he likes this character.
And kind of what are the rules of his his richness
And
at this point, he's got the huge vault behind him.
He's still in an office. We don't have a bin yet. I don't believe. But the office is just completely flooded with money. His his secretary is walking through it waiting through it. As he tells him about the the disappearance of the ship that the reader already knows about.
And
Sc is just, you know, demanding results he wants the secretary to hire the world's greatest
detective.
So very conveniently, the secretary is and find the want to add that the boys have
have put up in, you know, hyper
referring to Donald as the best detective in the world. And they've got the very cute, like,
kid setup
detective agency
that you know, you've seen in things like encyclopedia Brown and other kids books for years. And and they answer the phone and they
they
accept the job. Yeah. It's interesting. I I like this little detective setup, but, you know, I just mentioned how I I feel like q doing that we were supposed to be sort of like, mature and then smarter than even like the average all way. I like to think they could spell detective properly.
Al it
d e t e c k t i f on the sign here. But I I still think it's it's kind of funny how Barks through that in. I I I know what you mean. There's a little bit of whiplash there. Right? Because they've got this, like, really principled
sn attitude and then they're like, super excited and a detective,
which a kid would probably get excited about. And Al adult would probably know that
detectives are usually not talked about the same way that, like, judges
or bankers.
Are they're, you know, they're usually kind of on the outs. Definitely. I definitely agree with that. But anyway, on the next page, the Nephews
get all excited to just got the call and and, you know, they've got a mystery lineup up for Donald, then we cut back to Donald charming snakes in the park as he is.
And he's yelling at this tiny snake for
not being in step with whatever Marge donald on flee. And as he's yelling in the middle of yelling and nephew show up and start, you know, getting all excited about the detective job they found. And all the meanwhile, Donald to totally tuned down and he's just staring down like this tiny snake. Go go ahead and finish the the sequence onto the next page.
And, you know, they fit... The nephew finished talking and and Donald hasn't been listening a bit and he goes. I just figured out why that little snake never keeps in step with the others. He's nothing put a dog on to worm. I which I I kinda of find funny. I also have to say, I really, like the face Donald pools when he's
nothing but a dog on worm. I like that drawing.
I I love this sequence. I... This is one of my favorite parts. The... He's got the snakes like marching and formation
with the little worm looking all sheep.
And it's... They all they look so hilarious to me. It's it's such a ridiculous
this is like a this is a super high concept
story. Right? This is all about this is the snake charming story that he wanted to tell. And he really is milk it here. You know? What kind of, like,
ridiculous funny things can I do with snake charming?
I I love it. This part totally works for me. So so we transition just really quickly. But I like the b transition sometimes we're in barn Bay where the ship went down. We get this really cool half page panel of the scenery. It's very clearly like the Pacific Northwest somewhere probably between, you know, Oregon and Al alaska
somewhere on the Pacific coast there. It's it's just it's it's great art. It's definitely a contender for one of the best panels in this story.
It's funny you say between Oregon Alaska is in my mind, I was
saying this feels like something
between oregon and Alaska. So I I kind of find that funny.
You know, Barks was reading a lot of national geographic. So
Yeah. Probably thinking back to that when he was drawing that really cool panel at the bottom.
And and love the Pacific northwest, you know, we've got quite a few stories already at this point set there. Mh.
So you know, we're in B Bay and, you know, Donald
in the back and he's got flu hand. He's he's sort of looking out and looking away. And and the nephew already, you know, hard on the case and they're thinking about, you know, where the boat could have sunk or, you know, what happened to the boat. And then they realized that, you know, they've gone all this way into, you know, possibly discovering what happened and donald just totally disappeared. And then they find them in the back, just charming this really nice looking
pair of snakes. I really like this this character of of the, you know, the nephews already being like well underway with the mystery
and Donald just being in the back goof off. I find that really funny. Yeah. I agree. And and this is the dynamic that we're gonna get for most of the rest of the story. Right? The Nephews are gonna be focused
on solving the case and and trying to nudge Donald to approving his worth as a great detective. And Donald is is never gonna really
break his character for this issue of just being dedicated
to being a great snake charm. And so on the next page they're kinda checking out their supplies, they're figuring out, you know, that they seem to be pretty well provisioned
of note they have a glass bottom boat for looking for looking for clues
underwater, which I thought was pretty neat.
Radio to
to get support. And then we get this neat little bit where Donald
says that, you know, he needs to send us a fresh box of apples because this one has worms in it. And he... He charms them
all out of the apples and and we we see all these worms doing this little w
dance.
And and I like the loose snake charming rules.
Austin that that Barks has set up here that basically Donald charm anything that is snake shaped. Yeah. That's funny. I I was about to say like, I I kinda find interesting that... He's a snake charm, but he's also a worm charm because I guess, worms will look like tiny snakes.
Right.
Right. So they they go out to the bay to look for some clues and and, you know, Donald kinda silence them because he's getting inspiration. So, you know, they're out in the sea and then, you know, he's he's, like, you know, shu to the nephews because he's thinking and they all get excited.
And Donald, you know, has a spurt of genius seemingly and
You know, he pulls out his flu and he just starts playing and he goes a way to be a way to play Be and snake rhythm. And we, you know, just starts blowing off these notes and there's some nice, you know, expressions of the nephews just sitting there utterly disgusted.
So they're going along and they find a dent in the water, you know, they're looking through from the, you know, glass bottom boat. And they say it looks just as if a giant hand had picked up the ship and carried it away. Which is, you know, obviously weird because you can't just pick this thing up like it was a piece of paper.
And all the meanwhile tonal, this is still in the corner and and playing away on that flute. Right. Yeah. It's it's very ominous little panel where you see, you know, the disappeared
ship where it rested.
So so on the next page, this this is a great page. This is This is the serpents
reveal. This is what we've been waiting for since we saw one of the covers.
And and Donald is again getting inspiration
and he starts to practice a number
that is designed for charming big snakes. And we see a little quest and Barks rising from the depths.
And then the the absolutely
massive
serpent
appears.
Just looking kinda curiously
at the docs who who are, of course terrified.
And austin i I think that Barks
serpent designs. May maybe it's maybe it's because I love sea serpents.
But I I just I love the designs of his two big
adventure c serpents here. The
terror of the river fake serpent and and this real one. I think they're I just think they're great. Yeah. This... I mean, this one in particular, this is a great panel.
I I really do like also
and and not only Barks stories, but in general just like dell comics Al the time, there would usually be, like, a lot more for foreshadowing, like preceding the serpents appearance, you would see something like, you know, maybe, like, Al like a footprint or something or like, something that the serpent had left behind or they would be left thinking like, oh, what what could have left that? But I do like that it just shows up out of nowhere and we get this
really
great panel that people don't talk about when when they're highlighting
favorite Barks panels. This one doesn't come up as often as, like, this meeting octopus from ghosts of the g or
the dam breaking and only a poor man. But I think this is great. It's a really and nice drawing. Yeah. I I agree. Yeah. Sounds great. So on the next page,
I really like this first panel.
The nephews are screaming. It's a giant sea serpent and all the wild Donald is diving directly onto the boat just head first hiding away.
I found really funny. So they start to speed away and they say there's no such farm which, of course is a callback for the title. And the serpents in the distance and their getting away from it and they're looking back. And they're like, is that real and they're kind of debating amongst themselves? Like, did we really just see that And one the nephew you says, well, for something that isn't real, that imaginary serpent makes an awful solid splash, which is you know, sort of interesting because there's and in tear the river, the creatures
serpent whatever isn't real, but this one is... I'm sure they're pretty, like shocked by that. Al first, And then Donald shows up from the bottom and there's a little wise crack out of him and, you know, we segue to the next page with a nice transition. Yeah. You know it?
Now that you mentioned that about terror of the river, I think there's an almost identical line in that one about, you know, for something so imaginary.
It dripped real water or something. I've it's it's been recent enough that that I'm remembering that. So this isn't... This doesn't quite qualify as one of Barks like remakes of one of his stories, you know, that he likes to do sometimes, but it definitely has a few of the same beats.
So the next page is basically
an acknowledgment that, well, you know, we've solved the case. We figured out what happened. We just can't really do much about it. It's clear that the serpent is what sank the ship and that he must have taken it away. And so they're still wondering where it be. They they speculate that he's got a nest somewhere
and, you know, they they try again to get Donald, but Donald is is acting, like, he doesn't
doesn't quite hear them because he's clearly terrified
to get anywhere near and he's bus
charming
worms again out of logs for fish bait.
And so the nephew resolved that they're gonna wait until Donald is asleep and that they're gonna swipe his
the pic, I think they call it and so that they can charm it themselves. Yeah. And we get that really nice nice pair of images at the bottom with another nice donald charming worms or I guess, tiny snakes that.
Fall for the charming and then, like, the disgusted nephews, like soaking in the boat. So on the next to page,
they they take the pic flu whatever you wanna call it. And they go off into the water and they're looking for the serpent, and they don't really find anything and one of the nephews takes the pic.
And starts blowing into it and playing it tune. And I really like that drawing of of the the, like, the puff up cheeks. I thought that was cool. And this is a really cool panel too at the bottom. But they actually end up serena or just calling attention to electric eels
start zap them with, you know, classic cartoon comic logic of them, like,
shooting out physical thunderbolts and kind of like electro executing them.
Right really cool visual down there. Yeah. It is a neat visual. And and it's interesting to me for a few reasons, Like, first we don't often see the nephews getting, like, violence inflicted on them. Right? That's usually
more for donald. It... It's not that it never happens.
But that looks like it hurts.
And and then this is another example of eels are not snakes. Right? They're just they look like snakes, so they can be charmed.
And and I think they look... They actually look quite scary. Right? They're like, very, very sinister, very for ferocious just looking. And he's got the little... If you look closely he's got, like, actual, like, sharp teeth on them. Which is very scary actually.
And they're coming... Seeming like, the lightning bolts are seemingly coming directly out of that mouth, look with teeth. So it's all very creepy, very cool. Yeah. You know, i'm I'm kinda reminded to of the the Nephews,
like animal
call whistles
later on in
what is it the minds of King Solomon and
so far I know Safari, how they can summon they play different tunes to some in different animals. So this is kind of another
another play on that. So on the next page, you know, the nephews are
stuck speculating at where he could be supposing that you must be in the deep water. And then meanwhile, Donald is seeking out safe places to charm snakes. And I I really like this sequence.
Where he's imagining the kinds of snakes that he'd liked to charm, including a hoo snake for Va,
or some musical rattle for a rattle snake band.
Again, it's it's just Barks trying to think like what what kind of gag can you do with snake charming? Have you ever heard of a hoo snake? I actually haven't. Not that was like a little bit of a weird term when I when I was reread this one. Yeah. It's it's a mythical, like animal. It's it's a legendary thing. There aren't really hoop snakes but it was told and, like the the the my wild bill Pe
bill, wild bill...
One of those old like, Ducktales.
They they talked about them there and they're just kind of a generic legend of snakes that roll around and hoops. But they're it's not real. So it's just funny that it's presented like a real one. And and so Donald approaches is a crater that was highlighted. I I I didn't mention it earlier, but there's this, like, old volcanic crater on one of the sides of this bay. And the reader instantly
recognizes it as
probably where the serpent lives. But Donald just sees it as a good source of, like echoes and acoustics sticks to practice.
To practice his his charming. Yeah. And this is... I think this is a super cool page. I I like the idea of Donald just kind of wandering off and letting his mind roam like he's like a kid and you're thinking about these snakes like, perfectly shaking and rhythm and, like nice top pads.
I think it's all very cool. And I like that big fat smile he has when he's doing this Al.
Anyway,
we get to the bottom here, And I think something about, like this tin than the other panels in the bottom right corner
sort of four shadows this big build up on the next page where the water starts to trim and, you know, Donald blows it off and he goes back to playing. And then the serpent shows up. And Donald yells out not w, but walk, w u k. I like that because I I don't where that's coming from. And he he tries to run off and the serpent tail launches out of the water and pulls him back in
serpents eyeing him and Donald, you know, some nervous rack just starts you know, shooting out all these notes of the flu pic and... You know, I really like these drawings. I think all the panels with the serpent in them are like super cool looking visually. I I think this is a really nice story in that sense.
The these couple of pages are just bonkers. They're they're great this is the meat of the story.
When I think about Barks drying these, you know, some of these stories
have the moment. That I think he really
decided. I wanna draw this and I wanna make this
story
work. So I'm gonna lead up to this. And I I see this on on on the page that you talked about and on this next one, you know, we've got this serpent and con comp himself and sway doing a hula dance as Donald is is backing away ever so slowly while he still plays
and makes a break for it.
And and this imagery just this cracks me up. It's wonderful.
Don't think there's any question in my mind that the panel that has the serpent like looking gi
while
itself is is the winner for this
this particular story in in my book. It's just so over the top and hilarious. And And this is setting us up, right, for the next couple of pages where Donald.
Don wants to escape, but the the serpent is in love with just dance to his his charming and music, and he can't.
Yeah. I I agree on the, like the hula
dancing image. I I just think that is so cool. And it isn't that the panel that that rosa sort of to took as its inspiration for his cover for this one It it is. With good reason, I think he... Yeah.
You figure that out. Yeah. It looks
great. So we get to the next page and the serpent kind of snatch donald up and you get a really nice panel with him next to the serpent eye of clothes and
it's really creepy looking, and he plays stuff into the the eye and the serpent just drops him on the floor. So dawn one's got no choice, but, you know, just to keep playing and he's sitting there. It keeps playing them in meanwhile, then nephew are looking around and and they're trying to find out where the serpent is, and they come across the crater.
And they find the serpent dancing
in the water just to Donald playing.
And Donald just playing in the back and then he just randomly screams out help, which I I kind of found funny. I do want I would do wanna add on the previous page, I really like sort of the old school use of the word jerk as like, in the... A s for idiots.
I always kinda liked that Barks and others use that. I agree. I I like that. It's a nice touch.
So on on the following page, you know, the nephews figure out
what's going on pretty quickly.
And so they
they use that radio to communicate for some supplies that they need and they briefly debate telling
sc
about the situation, but they kinda decide that they'd like to kind of but they they decide to hold off on telling him
exactly what's going on so that they can hand him the serpent and the ship in in one
in one. And so we get this neat transition where Donald is stuck for for at least a couple of days,
just
tortured. And the nephews are like, building him little props to to hold up his
his instrument and fanning him and doing everything they can to keep him going
until finally, the the hell
helicopter
dumps the supplies they requested. I I think this is a really really powerful
few set of panels at the bottom
Like, the Barks is skill as Al as an artist really helps here where you really feel donald
pain and like, you can feel your mouth like, drawing up as you look at him blowing and, you know, all the detailing is eyelids. I find that really cool. And I don't know this turns out in the Gladstone reprint you have, but in the in the original one at the bottom, the helicopter Barks draws it is if it's just literally dropping the stuff out of the plane, which I would like to think is sort of damaging it all beyond for repair, whatever it is. Right. So I thought that was sort of interesting.
Yeah. Thanks for... Thanks for highlighting it. Because because you're absolutely
right. The those those panels are just painful to look at. And in in the kind of way that, you know, speaks to how effective it is. Oh, yeah. And and it's definitely largely because those the drawings are so powerful. I mean, that's kinda why Barks in particular stands out among his conte at Western because you know, a lot of people weren't drawing their own work that they were writing and and when you're
writing a script and giving it to somebody else, you know, you're not getting
someone who has your full vision in your mind when you can illustrate your own work, you can keep whatever thing you have in your mind. If you have the skill and just go, okay. I want this to look like this. You know, I want this to be exactly like this. And I think that was also a reason it's still like why Barks in general is was superior to
people work on the other material and the dell books Al the time. But anyway, on the next page,
she we doing in Louie are looking over the... What they got from the helicopter.
And they ordered blasting powder, but it ends up being barrels and barrels of pepper, which... I mean,
is interesting. And I guess it it sort of makes sense. But in a way, i'm I'm kind of left thinking like how in the world could they screwed up the order for
for, like, tap. I mean, it's another one of those, like, crazy coincidence so, lucky this happened here. But, you know, you go along with it because at this point, you're probably so enamored with the story, you wanna see what happens.
Yeah... This is definitely like our cartoon logic
segment of the of the comic.
Yeah.
So
what they do is they load a bunch of the barrels of pepper onto a log that's, you know, tilting towards the ground and they go up on a cliff and throw a big boulder down on it, and it shoots all of the barrels into the serpent mouth and you go ahead with the next page because this is absolutely. This is spectacular. Like, the the catapult
pepper into a creature mouth. Is a little bit hack meat but it's such a great outcome. The the serpent
swallows the barrels of pepper, and he has the kind of reaction you expect and you hope. And and that dead on perspective of the serpent kind of cotton on to what he's just eaten and and just feeling
horrible is is hilarious. I love that so much.
And And the serpent basically levi
out of his crater. In Agony and and the nephews
get off Al line that I think they say a few times brother,
that's action. And we get this little
panel
that interestingly Barks. He doesn't show the action. He has the nephew
describing
the serpent
drinking
water to put the fire out and and and he ends up nearly drinking the crater
dry.
Exposing the ship and leaving the serpent, just
w and agony
with a bloated
belly and torso so looking very funny. I I wonder if it was just too if Barks thought it would have been looked too ridiculous to show him drinking it all up or or maybe he was worried about his page count, but it was an interesting little gloss.
But it but it's it's a fantastic. It's definitely a standout page. And and and if this story, this story has to work for you, I guess, to appreciate these. Because it's just so ridiculous.
I I totally agree. It's it i... For me, it is the standout page.
You know, you got four of five panels that are just brim with action.
Well really full. You can feel the you know, the energy coming out of those, then.
What's interesting? I don't know if if... Because I figured you would've have mentioned it, but you didn't. I was immediately drawing comparisons to
dose of the g where the nephews are putting Chili pepper over the the, you know, the hun of meat and the octopus shoots out of the scene. We get another cool splash panel. I was thinking Barks to that one when they yeah. The pepper into the service mouth. Yeah. I'm I'm I'm ashamed of myself to
gloss over it, especially since ghost of the g is one of my all time favorites. So so, yeah, this is
another iteration of that gray bit. Yeah. I I would be hard pressed to choose which one's my favorite
version of the gag, but
this one's pretty cool, but I haven't read coast of the g in a long time. So I I remember vividly, I I would have read the two of them, you know, because they were in... They were both Donald Ducktales adventures
published within about a year and a half of each other. And I I read both of these over and over or I've got these dog ear copies. But I I'm not sure I've ever laughed as hard as I did the very first time I read the op... The that octopus sequence. But
that's a digress. Go ahead. Yeah. Yeah. Definitely great sequence. But anyway, on the next page,
then nephews run off, and they get all excited. They assume that the the the serpent either, you know, passed out or dead or led to bare minimum
unconscious. So one of them runs off gets excited, they're gonna go get uncle Scrooge and show them what happened. But the serpent gets up,
hiccup and and almost like drunk away.
So he runs off, trying to get more water and he grabs the boat with him. And he sinks back into the sea or the river or whatever you would wanna call it and I I do kinda like in the bottom. We we get donald in the background. Just kinda reminding you Donald is too. It's not just cool soap been drawing. What, I find interesting
is the ending where, you know, it it reminds me of
twenty four carrot moon, that story is ending. I think that's a great story. That's a later food adventure. But in that one, you know, I I don't wanna spoil anything, but obviously, there's a moon made of solid gold that Scrooge
trying to get to and, you know, he gets to it, but something happens where he's there and he kind of contemplate at the end like it worked really hard for this and I'm here and it's what I wanted, but is it what I wanted? And that's it's kind... It's not that deep here. But it's kind of in that case,
you know, Scrooge works very hard, like long endless days to get to the moon and at this point, the nephews have been working very hard long endless days to, you know, find out what happened to the ship and they have the ship there for evidence and this, you know, crazy,
you know, mythical creature And the ship and the creature, just both sink back into the sea where, you know, probably no one will ever
find out about them again. So I found that interesting and then on the next page, which you're gonna cover obviously, you kinda you're kind of return to the status quo. Yeah. I I like that comparison. It it strikes me that there... It feels like there's a lot of panels like that near the in the end of some of the stories with the Ducktales kind of looking
after something, you know, una.
What a great page that was too. I I love Donald like
sigh of relief at the end when the serpent is finally
finally left him in peace,
and he can be real. He can be, like human again.
And the and the drunk looking serpent, it that one cracks me up as well. So so you mentioned it. It's that's exactly right. We're going back to the status quo. And this is where we get the little book and.
No. I guess not yet. We don't see that great men. Yet. We get we get the Nephews
acknowledging again that, you know, we we can't even bother telling uncle Scrooge because we know what he'll say,
there's no such var
i I like that use of the word environment. And they go back to their rut. They kind of acknowledge for the reader, They voice out loud that, yeah, mcdonald's solved it, but he wasn't even trying to. And then we get this convenient moment where that
professor
runs up saying that he's been looking for them and that he needs to
fix the terrible mistake that he's made and take us home. Yeah. So the professor shows up, you know, seemingly out of nowhere, and
it's funny, and we get some good bits out of it, but even when I first read this story, At the beginning, when Donald brain is being examined in the one fifteen shows up, I immediately knew
what that one fifteen correspond with but it was still interesting Al the ending. The professor shows up and says Donald got a very rare Al that he should become the world's greatest snake charm, which I I think some people could have seen coming a million miles away like I did, But, you know,
still, I I I do think it's kinda funny, especially the panel that follows where Donald just totally shaken up. And we go back to the same park that hugh doing in Liu were in at the beginning, you know, Al,
great men of their time. There's gold, the great engineer rich and famous. One of them reiterate that yes, Rich and famous.
And then mick Owl, the great judge wise and respected. And another one reiterate yeah wise and respected.
I think that drawing is is a little weird looking. It's it's almost like a Huey, Al hybrid, more so then most of his owl judges that he had drawn at the past or in the future. So then one of the nephew he's sitting at the training goes, people are funny,
Some are great, and some of them are like donald and we end on a really nice visual of the donald.
Just picking up trash in the park, totally three of his flute and then not doing any sort of charming and, you know, just happily going along humming a tune.
Yeah. I look looking very content. And i I'm glad that you
I'm glad that you read what the Nephews were saying there because it's it's very poetic. Right? That, like, little colin or response, they have rich and famous? Yes, Rich and famous.
It's it's a really elegant way to have closed out the story and then in a neat book end and It's striking how happy he shows Donald just
picking up litter. I I do really like the payoff. You're right. It's it's we see it coming from a million miles away, but his little
panic
panel
at
at being told he should be a snake Charm. That definitely lands for me. That one is is really funny. Mh.
It's a great drawing.
Yeah. So So this one has a really cool structure, you know, the the book ending
with the fantastical
adventure in the middle. I
I really like this story. I I read this a ton as a kid. I think some of it was just my general
fascination with c serpents and how much I loved Barks
design for serpents.
It it kind of lands in an interesting place because I mentioned it is in his like, what what most people agree is his golden age of comics. And so you get these, like, pretty good comics mixed in with these just absolutely legendary ones. And I feel like maybe this one gets
gets a little bit less attention for that reason. I don't know. What what what are your impressions of this one Austin?
Yeah. I I sort of agree
I think in general,
the Barks fans are more attracted to
something that's like all around very, like, whim and and fan fantastic stick and where they go away off into some far land. But what I found interesting about this one is that I couldn't really get into the mindset of this being sort of faraway away land because for all we know, like, what was it called Barn Bay? I mean, that could've have just been a few miles, you know, north or south of wherever the Ducktales live. So you know,
in that sense, it it feels a little weird a little off, but
I think it's got some great visuals, some great art. I mean, obviously, the the panels with the serpent are all equally great, narrative wise, like story wise. It's not one of his greatest, but I mean, obviously, it's still a fantastic story. Right. I'll I I would probably put this one in in, like, my top fifteen or twelve Barks stories. I don't know if it would make the top ten, but it would definitely be up there somewhere. So that's that's pretty high praise. Right? Considering the number of them. That he's got.
This one obviously sticks with you. There's a lot about it. That's really interesting and I think generally
how weird it is
is what stands out to me. It's also interesting there's no human characters once they get to the that barn bay area. Right? It's just it's just them in the serpent. That's a big part of the dynamic of this one. Mh. Yeah. That's actually an interesting point. I can't think of many, you know, ten pager adventures Scrooge adventures whatever where they're they're totally on their own. I'm sure there's one or two, but, you know, even in the very eerie ominous and and fantastic ghost of the g,
you know, there's always some sort of creatures, some
or
something
that's kind of there beside them are in their midst. And in in this one,
I mean, they're totally alone. Minus serpent and themselves, of course, know, it's they're totally isolated from the rest of the world. And I find that really interesting. Right. And and he has such a parade of notable,
like,
drive by characters
at the beginning and end that maybe he was like, I don't need more humans
in this one. Because, like, they're really great character designs for all of those, like quote, great men that walk by the nephews. I think they're they're really memorable considering they each get one panel. Mh. And they all look pretty great. I already said Nick Al,
the great judge in particular, looks looks pretty funky but cool I have to say.
Right Yeah, they all look great. He he great at Al character designs, a unique character design with that. So you and I both both really enjoyed this one. I wouldn't i I'd would probably put this one kind of in my high middle
tier. I would say not like not like all time great, but but quite great or or at least very good.
As far as the community goes, I'm sure you know that I like to check on index and and how the community has rated
these
compared to the others. This one is pretty well regarded as you might expect. It's about a seven point seven out of ten, which is good for one hundred and fifty seven ranked out of all forty one thousand
etcetera.
Disney comics that have been ranked on index. So, you know, even for Barks, that's that's pretty high. Right? Because there's probably
there's probably a good seventy or eighty
stories in that top hundred and fifty that are not even Barks. So this one's probably somewhere in the top, like,
ten percent of Barks story by the community. Yeah. I was...
I was looking at Ducktales earlier and I was actually shocked to see
like, the majority of his four color mcdonald's are in the top a hundred. Yeah. And just... I mean, I I don't like to
solely judge a a story popularity or or people's preference based off of the index thing, especially because there are a lot of weird stories in the top one hundred. But... Yeah. No. It's weird because a lot of what I would consider to be his weakest stuff as far as the four Al on go,
are very high in the top one hundred. And, you know, I think this one definitely just deserves something in you know, maybe even just the bottom half of the hundreds, maybe something like seventy or seventy five. If I had to pick one, I guess it could swap places with. I would say, the insanely
overrated
adventure down under, which I think Actually talked to you about a while ago that we were both kind of shocked that that was as high as it was. Yeah. There are a few. I mean, I I've kind of said my theory before that some of them just stand out more in people's minds. Right? Like, that's that's his big Australia adventure, and it's definitely got its stuff to like, but But I agree. It's not a it's not a top ten story. Yeah. I mean... I mean, index is obviously not perfect, but it's the hand thing that I've got to get an idea
of what the community thinks. And they've generally got a pretty good number like statistically
of people voting for the stories
to to give you a good idea But there are definitely some some weird
anomalies
I think I remember from our our initial chat. I think you were rag a little bit on terror of the river. Right? Oh, yeah. It's
see it's interesting
with a lot of Barks is earliest stories or rather the the adventures
what I find is that
before what... I guess, the benchmark would be golden Christmas tree. That's the earliest one I can think of that's you know, sort of goof and and lighter than anything he had done before.
They're all very serious,
like seriously toned and you know, not to say that his fifties stories didn't have a genuine stakes in them. But here there are, like, genuine
stakes like you know, ghost of the g if, you know, if you don't find, you know, the the nephew that's disappeared, you know, he's
disappeared for good. Right You the old castle secret for all, you know, I mean, you know, those those ghosts and skeletons are real and they're out to get you. I mean... Yeah. We had actual actual skeleton in that one too. Mh.
Yeah. But I I
I've read a lot of those. And probably most of them But tariffs the river always felt like
a little too serious for me. It almost felt like
some of Barks is
later, not later work, but
we work, which is, I guess, is late fifty stuff. And almost like some of the worst Don Rosa stories where they're just pages and pages of Talk talkie.
Know, there's decent action in it. But all I remember from reading it is just... There's so much dialogue and and when Donald gets... I I... It's like kidnapped. Right? And he's underground with, like this crack in the submarine.
They're just pages and panels and panels that this guy talking and talking. I mean, obviously, you know, that's great potential with the c serpent as we saw with this story, but between the two, I would always choose this one, but I I I don't know I would be interested to hear what you have to say if you think that one's better than this one. See I I love this because these stories are like, almost
engineered to be compared. To each other. Right? There is is two big c serpent adventures.
And
the the design is so similar. So I was I was kind of
chomp at the bit did the opportunity to to
advocate more terror of the river. Because I do think terror of the river is much stronger and I do like that one better. I like them both for different reasons, of course, but that one just stands out in my mind even though the serpent in that one ends up not being real, there's like such a neat pal
terror and and fear in that one, you know? And then the serpent just looks so men. And I just love that bonkers villain. And I love the idea of a guy who's
kinda twisted in that he he just gets his jo by
by wanting to scare people.
So that one is one that I consider
wildly under underrated. So it's it's interesting. Everyone's got you know, that Barks had so many stories
that everyone's gonna have their own favorite.
Everyone's gonna have their their stories that they feel are under underrated or over overrated. And I love hearing what people think
is especially under underrated. That that really fascinating me me. It's
interesting though. I told you that this one gets a seven point seven good for a hundred and fifty seven. Terror of the river.
Seven point seven
hundred and thirty six. They're like,
clustered right there with each other and terror, the river just gets the slightest edge.
Oh interesting yourself. Yeah. Yeah. I I like that. I don't I don't like to pin stories against each other usually, but I Almost feel like you can't avoid it with with this pair of stories. Yeah.
I I I agree. I mean, they both have their merits. Right? Personally,
I might say I would prefer the visuals and tear of the river more. I mean, the style overall Barks is mid forty style, I think it's kind of cool.
Visually, I I think I would have to give it to no such farm
you know, they're both cool. But, you know, personally, I I I think no such farm cooler. Yeah. Excellent. So just to wrap things up, a few elections. I do like to mention how the story holds up in general. It's nice. This one doesn't have anything that's like really problematic to talk about I mean, other than the fact that snake charming is is now widely seen as
as cruel treatment. I I I looked a little bit into it, apparently, a a lot of snake charm
would do things to to the animals that resulted in, like, their early death to to make them safe to charm. But and it's worth mentioning too that snakes can't hear
the way
the way we do. So they're not like responding to music, the way that that it's poor trade. It's more like a a a reaction to the movement, I guess, of the instrument instruments itself. So so that's interesting. But in general, this one holds up, I think pretty well. Let's see. There are
there there's no oil paintings or lit graphs for this one as far as I'm aware. And and what a shame, wouldn't it have been great to see that
to see a lit though of the serpent swing? Yeah.
Wow that would have been really great. No. I I totally agree. I think when I was again, when I was, like it's like the, you know, the casual Barks fan that I once was
I would see the painting Barks did for terror of the river
which Gladstone used for the cover of their album with that one or like a version
by somebody
I always saw that and I thought that was four no such permanent.
But you know, they're both
great pieces. But
That he's interesting in this sense that I think in old California
also is is like another Barks adventure where, you know, he didn't do the cover
and then he didn't do any paintings or lit photographs. So he kinda did the story and and that was sort of it, which is interesting, I think. Yeah. That's true. And then I I mentioned, you know, sometimes the stories will have been adapted into
tails as far as I'm aware, you know, that that never happened for this one, although there were a few c serpents stories.
Any any
contenders for favorite panel that we didn't already
talk about or or one that you wanna give a little bit of love to again?
Okay. This is interesting. I would say it's a three way tie
between
maybe
the... When the serpent first emerges,
right? And he's looking over the boat from the right side. At the end when Donald shit shook,
shaken up whatever. You know, and he's got all those eye multiples. And the third one would probably be...
When he's wandering through the woods and he's thinking about the three snakes in the tele tat,
I think that's a really cool one too. Oh, yeah. Those those are all strong choices.
I'm a sucker for the, like stand out panels. So it's hard for me to resist.
Any of the really
spectacular shots of the serpent
itself. But if I force myself to talk about some non ones, I I do love the the panel where the little worm is looks so ashamed of himself. And I think Donald reaction shot that you pointed out when the nephews are just out of nowhere.
Telling him he should feel ashamed of himself. Anyway, there this one, more than many has just a a huge number of of great great panels in it. Any any additional thoughts any anything that you really wanted us to talk about that we didn't get to? There is there's one tiny point that I was kind of leaving in the back of my mind, but what I find, interesting is that Donald in a lot of like a Barks stories sort of is easily
influenced by, like, whatever fad going on or, you know, if he sees an ad for like, a job. He's very easily
his views will change the snap of a finger if, you know, you talked him about something.
But in this story, he
maintains this very strict uniqueness to his character. Right? Like, he's himself who is a, you know, a snake charm as weird as that is when he's supposed to be you know, for all he knows this great detective. But he just wants to be a snake charm, you know? And and I don't think Barks would have usually kept that like that. I think that's interesting.
Beyond that though, that that's sort of it, we've talked about the great panels a ton, you know, It's a great story visually.
Bit of a weaker story narrative wise, but I think overall, it's a really nice piece of work. Yeah. Those those are good thoughts. And I agree with you. It's interesting to see It's interesting to see him so content
sort of with his humble
here. Well, I think we had a really good conversation.
About this story Austin I really appreciate it. It it'll it'll be great to have you on for another the... It sounds like you're a big fan of the ten pager. Too. I and would be fun to have you on, I think from one of those.
Like. And you're you're coming up on... What would essentially be, I think the golden age of those ten pages. I mean, you had some great ones in in the late forties, some of which I you might, have actually covered Sunken yacht with this a great one. But, you know, the the the sc centric ones like, you know, tariff the Beagle boys. I mean, these are these are all really great on par with the best of the adventures. Oh, yeah. You're you're right. There's like
one to two dozen in a row coming up right around this time that are just spectacular. And and you mentioned
our our next
episode is gonna cover the story that you mentioned. We get to talk about Donald Duck in old California.
So I hope hope people will join us on the show for that one because that that is another very notable,
very memorable story. People are welcome to reach out if they have a comment, Barks
remarks at gmail dot com.
Mostly people reach out on the Face book page, which is fine. Still kinda kinda trying to think of a good way to end these gracefully.
But
no such environments
Flirt with greatness here and there. So thanks, Austin. Any time. Great story.