Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of sc Mc and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge cl of all time, join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context, and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks. Welcome back to Barks remarks. I'm Mark Sever marino, a grown man who still enjoys donald dot comics,
and I'm joined by a returning guest
returning guest and her cat. Why don't you introduce yourselves? Al is on my lap. I hope his prayers are not too overwhelming, and my name is Sarah, Santiago
Thanks so much, Sarah for coming back. We're gonna be talking about the landmark
story in old California
today. And and I'm very excited. This is a very famous
story among Carl Barks fans among fans dot comics. To me, it's it's reminiscent of the one that we
we recorded recently when we talked about dangerous
disguise in that it's a bit of a more mature story. And I'm excited to talk about this one because there is a lot to cover. There is a lot to cover. This is a story that stands out for a lot of people. I think a lot of people really remember it fondly. I feel like I should be
upfront about my own feelings
with this story, which is that I do really like this one. But I don't cherish it as much as a lot of duck fans do. I I I get... I think I
understand why this one Barks. So highly and is so well remembered, but much like dangerous
disguise. I'm wondering if I like read this one when I was a little bit too young. Because this one seems
geared
towards more of an older audience. Forming me. Nostalgia isn't something you can sell to children. That's for sure. And this was so full of nostalgia. Yeah. I'm I'm glad you said that because it's a great point. You know, this this is really a hugely nostalgic work for him. Is is very focused on the past and and dwelling on this sort of like, forgotten ideals. So let's talk about this story. This was published, cover date was March of nineteen fifty one, and it appeared in four color number three hundred and twenty eight. It has about the average number of reprint eight, including the original publication and it's a twenty eight pager. So on the longer side, and this story is basically
It's a sort of fever dream, right? Where
Sometimes Barks likes to do this thing where i'll have the ducks go back to a pass
without actually doing the trope of time travel. But there's a few stories in these works where he'll do this. In summer fact. They travel through a vision
or, you know, through psychedelics or hall
drugs in this one. Back to to the past and it's gonna be this like shared dream of theirs. So it's it's very weird. It's very unusual
very nostalgic,
quite lovely. I was surprised how similar it felt to nostalgia
for about that time period that appeared later on. But it's it's really interesting
how we're taught to view the past as children. You're you're the way these adults are experiencing
nostalgia amongst themselves. Yeah. And rep it for children. Like happy days. Right? Yeah. People people love to do this. They love to package nostalgia. It's always the past. It's always the good old days. It's always you know, in in the eighties, the fifties were the good old days. And in the fifties,
Gold Russia Era, California
was the good old days. Right? Yeah. And and for Carl Barks, right? You can tell that for him,
Nostalgia is before California.
Turned into what it what it was on its way to being in the fifties,
and that just accelerated.
It hugely. I'll take a moment here say that I'm a Californian.
I am perfect to to talk about this story. I was born in the eighties in the Bay Area.
So like, a lot of this story is really this digested version of the California
history
quote, that we got spoon fed to us in fourth grade history class. You know? That I was like, oh my gosh. This is beat for beach. So much of the stuff that I learned about in school. And
you get older and you start to learn that, you know, the the backbone bonus of some of that stuff is true, but of course, it's leaving a lot out history is written by winners. And and this is really Al and fetish us a kind of pass that probably was never really the case in California,
but you can tell that
Carl Barks is already
recognizing where California is heading with the the beginning of this story and and the congestion and the sp. And i I understand the instinct to pine for that sort of simpler time. Yeah. It... It's definitely a very human
instinct. I listened to a podcast
It's now called build for tomorrow, but it used to be called the Pe
archive and he started to kind of look into when was this
time period when America was great. And he traced back to the beginning of writing itself. The Romans
had their own version of all the good old days. Things now just aren't the way they used to be. I pine for these old days That kind of nostalgia is extremely Huey,. Right. Every generation likes to complain about the one that comes after it. So let me let me talk about a little bit of the background trivia because there's a there's a good amount of it. I did mention that this is one of the best reviewed best regarded of Barks stories. We'll we'll get to the actual ranking later, but I will note that if you kind pull out only the Donald duck stories as opposed to the uncle Sc ones, this is his third best
regarded or best remember Donald Duck story. The only ones that are ahead of it and the rankings are lost in the Andes and the golden helmet. It's just barely ahead of vacation time. And and there's a good few quotes about this one.
In a nineteen sixty two interview, we had one of those moments,
Sarah, where he
indicated that this was his favorite story. The one that he thought was his best and and I'm chuck a little bit because this is the third episode I've done now where he I have a quote revealing which story he thought was his favorite, which was his best one.
But it makes sense. You know, he had a very long career
in nineteen sixty two, he was I think still writing them. So we he had some of them still ahead of ahead of him, but he he had over five hundred stories if he count everything he did. So
it's natural that he might change his mind over the years. But he he's mentioned lost in the Andes being a favorite mentioned land of the tote poles and this one. So now now that I've got three of these down. I'm I'm gonna keep paying attention to these quotes.
But he said the one story I always liked best was in old California.
I created an atmosphere and then kept that fear through the whole story. Composing these stories is like writing music. You've got to have the beat and keep the whole thing going. I think that's fair. I think he did do a great job of maintaining a certain
dream like hyper realistic
pin
atmosphere in this one. And then you and I did dangerous to disguise a little while ago. We talked Al length about how that was the last story that he got away with using real humans on And I I bet you can guess that he wished he could done it for this one. Right? Because these the characters in this... They are
so
stunning
human, and I was just in awe...
We'll when we talk about our favorite panels, I'm gonna bring up panels where he depicted
these animal human,
but with
specifically human people features. Yeah. Absolutely.
I might say that these characters are more human than the humans in dangerous
disguise in some ways, because a lot of those were very care,
you know. Just just... We had some exaggerated figures
and some like, archetypes like the Fe fatal, but I I think he's going for a real, like, story book romance in this one. That's the other a fascinating thing to me that this is a romance.
This this is almost is could be a romance novel, Donald and the Ne user are at times kind of incidental to the story. It sometimes seems like they're only there to perpetuate the romance.
Instead of the other way around, the way
ancillary characters
serve the story of the ducks. Yeah. Yeah. Definitely. Let's see Barks was also known to talk about the setting. He did say for this one, no settings are taken from life, but the type of houses and terrain are recognized local. And then can we list a couple of the titles from around the world, Sarah? Or. If do you want me to start? Yeah. Why don't you go with the the, you know, location
specific titles?
Sure. In
Mexico and Spain had different...
The the Spanish and the Mexican,
even though they're, you know, ostensibly the same language, they've come out with different
titles where Mexico is in
California
and Spain's is
California.
And you and I had talked previously about the word Giga where it it it... The definition is more ancient, but in this
specific
meaning, it's more like antique
And whereas,
California is more old. Which is a direct translation. Right. Yeah. That's the connotation that I feel like they're going for there. And then we have a lot of most least straight up translations of in old California. This a pretty important title to keep consistent. So
we've got ones like then the danish is
e go ga, Californian.
French is rat on,
which is back to California,
Germany is a direct one, Emailed.
The only one that stuck out to me was just Italy is
Would be donald in the past kind of kind of weirdly emitting
California.
So we're we're almost
ready to start talking about the story itself. But
the thing that I haven't even mentioned yet is that this is kind of oddly
a literary
adaptation.
We've we've got Barks based adapting this really well known piece of literature, a story called Ra ramona that was written in the late nineteenth century tree by Helen Hunt Jackson.
So Helen hunt Jackson and wrote this historical
novel called Ramona. That was
that this is very loosely based on it. But you can I can see the bones of it. Right? So it's it's a story of this So so it's a story of of a half scott Irish half native American orphan and her lover, and it's basically like a a romeo and Juliet doomed love type of story. And and she had this mission
that was to get Americans to reconsider their treatment of native Americans.
She really wanted to, like, affect policy and and benefit welfare
for for native Americans. And and I think that's pretty awesome. You know, It's definitely gonna look pretty dated
based on, like our future version, but it was from a very progressed a very idealistic
mindset at the time. It was it was essentially supposed to be like a native equivalent of uncle Tom's cabin, which again was a very progressive minded work at the time. And so Ramona was very personal for Carl Barks. Right? Because they... The... His his community of San ja Sci would do this pageant every year that is locally famous and and is somewhat famous around the world because it's the
longest running outdoor pageant in the United States.
Next year is going to be its centennial
hundredth anniversary and the venue that it's at is actually called the ramona.
So i I thought that was pretty interesting. I didn't know anything about this Sarah when I went to do the episode. Yeah. I
It felt when I was reading it before I knew anything about Ramona, that the rodeo
felt different. It didn't feel like a rodeo in the way that we
understood it. So I was wondering maybe is this is this part of
you know, this the Spanish culture of the time, Mexican culture,
what was going on with that. But as an homage,
to a beloved childhood festival. Sure. That sounds right. Yeah. And and I think Barks talked about, you know, it was kinda like his little inside joke. He wanted these these stories, he didn't get credit for them. But I think he liked the idea that his neighbors could see this on the news stand and recognize
you know, local staff local elements. And he they did mention,
but it was just a quick throw away reference.
Right. Yeah. You're right. They mentioned that. So so there there's a lot to talk about. Why don't we go ahead and get into the meat of the story unless you had any other comments. Let's go. So in old California
opens up on that most Californian
of
occurrences, a terrible
traffic jam. This is something that we see in a few Barks stories. He complains a lot about progress
year about just turned fifty as he wrote this. Right? So this is very easy for me to picture. But but Don on the nephews user in that kind of traffic jam where you're like, risking life and limb and it feels very unpleasant to be in and they have to take a side road to a escape what they call the honking jam. And this gets the kids to talking
about what life was like in California
before before the automobile
took over. And it does specifically call out that their site seeing near Los Angeles.
So we don't have Duck like formally. I don't think it's established as their hometown at this point. Sarah. He's referenced like Burbank Barks a few times. But... But the docs have always basically been Californian
in his stories. I've gotten that feeling from the ones that I've read too. So Don is kind of... He's taken that on the next page down this, like, sleepy back road. And they're talking very... He's talking very wi fully and nostalgic
about what the land used to be like, and and he's he's really talking about the time before it was the United States. Right? They don't He doesn't ever explicitly say this other than to say that big Spanish ron chose covered thousands of acres.
They talk about all the
wildlife
and and game that we're there. They talk about the
Indians, the native Americans
that lived in the area. There is a panel where the boys one of the boys Barks weren't they savage
Indians, un donald, and and he
them that no, these guys were figured that having fun was more fun than fighting. And he characterize
them as being
smart.
I think he's talking about
everyone in this era, not explicitly the Indians because he talks about them building the missions that you've heard about and pointing out a mission here. And this is really complicated,
Sarah because
this is like a really interesting white wash
gloss over of California like like the rest of the United States had some very rough history
Right? And and some terrible
exploitation. But...
Sorry. I'm I'm getting stuck on this. Right? Because this is
this is such a gl of the past. But in some ways, the the area was more, I think, mixed
and integrated back when it was old Mexico.
What struck me about this section
was that Indians lived in villages along the streams and dance and made whoop be every few minutes. And what does that mean?
When you send me the article about Ramona, and about how it was meant to be, you know, the uncle Tom's cabin but for Native America of its time and and how it didn't actually catch on that way. It made me think of this
characterization of native Americans
as
him
trying.
He he doesn't have the level of
acceptance of
understanding what's the history
how the Us has
wrong
native Americans. But I get the feeling that he thinks he's doing a good job by saying, no, they're not savages,
they're this completely other
insert pate
description here. Yeah. I... This is very pate,
but it but it's very well intention
It shows I would say a little bit of growth from the story I did a few months ago land of the tote pulls,
This this is definitely a high point in his representation of native Americans.
It is it should be said it's totally in keeping
with the average like mindset of the time. Honestly, it's it's probably a little bit more positive than the average mindset.
Of its time because it doesn't. I mean, we'll we'll get to those characters soon. But you asked about making whoop be Miriam Webb says that informal old fashioned is to have noisy fun And I think that that's how I read it. It's it's like war whoop, you know, it's the cliche like
making making that kind of noise and just having a good time. So, you know, the this page ends with them
transitioning back So he kind of talks about what became of California
as they pass a bunch of noisy billboards Barks and he's like, well, you know, Gold was discovered in eighteen forty eight in California.
Barks is basically tracing that as the the time when California
took a turn for the worse. Right? Because it drew in all these people and all this development.
But the docs continue to drive deeper into the bat country and they're just sightseeing seeing and they pass one of these local references that we mentioned
where they they talk about seeing the town where Ramona once lived. Right? Clearly, she's not a fictional character in this. She's like a historical person.
They talk about how they would have loved to have met her they pass a sign that says there's the Ramona pageant bowl and they're distracted by a sign talking about an Indian reservation and the Ducktales
crash really brutally
into a large boulder.
So pretty violent looking crash. This would probably kill the sucks. So we got some cartoon logic here. But when the ducks come to they're at that reservation. And they've been taken
to see the medicine man and they're given
this like medicine
that has kind of a smoky look to it. The the Indians... Sarah, what what do you notice? Would you describe the native Americans for us? They're they're wearing
the quote unquote medicine man is wearing a vest. It has fringes. It appears to be leather, kind of a stereotypical
modern
depiction of
what white Americans think native Americans where
it appears to be leather, but then in the next panel, the medicine man or somebody else is handing over the herbs that the ducts are so supposed to drink. And do you see that native American
man from behind and it has an a one
flower
stitched on. I think it's supposed to have been made from a Al old sack. Right. Right. Which is just...
Can they just wear clothes? I mean, I think it's supposed to represent the the poverty that many of them are in.
But it's...
But without the context
to tell us this is poverty,
you know, we don't
understand, like, do they choose to live this way? Are they stuck in this way because of decades of policies,
of course, because they all assume context it was very frustrating for me as well as the way that they're depicted, their language is depicted. Right? It makes them
appear to be less fluent in English, we all know what less fluency means. It means less intelligent
to that kind of a an audience. It's just very frustrating
today. Yeah. I think that's understandable. You know, their their dialect is basically Hollywood Indian. Hollywood native and it was so expected that even in a story like land to the Tote poles were the Ducks encounter a group of natives that have never met
outsiders. He still has them speak in this kind of English which obviously doesn't make any sense. So this was like this deeply brain trope. But this is we're getting the stereotype of the happy Indian. They're all very, they're very simple. They're happy
they're very pleasant.
It's very pate.
Someone who's smarter than me can argue whether it's more or less harmful than the kind of stereotype that we usually were presented with. But the Ducktales basically start to feel the effects of these herbs
right away, as the natives are doing these like whoop
noises around them. And as they kind of fall into this fever dream, One of the Nephews.
They they're talking about how I feel sleepy. Like I'm sort of going into a dream
and one of the nephew says, I feel like we're living, you know time long long ago. Like, this is the part of the story that I had trouble getting past as a kid. Right? Because this is such a like fantastic thing to just kinda hand wave past. I thought it was a very weird
transition, and it really... It it pulls me out of this story a bit. Oh, card, it makes so much sense to me in cartoon logic. Right. At the time, you know, child me would have been going right along with it. Of course, that's what happens when you're about to fall into a drug sleep. Sure. Right. And and what I liked about these comics is that Barks doesn't usually do like the the true cartoon logic, you know, like animals and stuff. There's like a small degree
more realism than that. But anyway... The transition is really interesting
because he's got them
doing their weird dancing,
Hollywood Right. A native American dancing in silhouette in their
clothes that they have on in the modern day And then as they're falling asleep, they're still doing even more exaggerated into those shapes, those dancing shapes. But it's very clear that the silhouette people
are not wearing modern clothes. I... Right. As much as I hated it from a depiction of native Americans
standpoint it made sense
logically. In that that kind of logic. Right? Right. You see the transition happening. If it took me along with it. It wasn't just proof all of the sudden. It took me along with it. Nice. So that's interesting. This transition works a lot better for you than it does for me. It is it is drawn lovely. So as we transition with the du, you know, it's clear to the reader.
That they have gone back to long ago that we see now this this reservation is now a native village,
the Indians or dressed the way we might have stereotypical typically guessed they would
hundred years
before The architecture of their housing has changed
Yeah. I do. I do appreciate that it looks like it looks like the buildings, I didn't like research it or anything, but it looks more realistic than him just throwing up a bunch of t gps. You know, they're like, more permanent structures than that, which I think would have been the case around then. And so the Ducktales go back to look at their car. And they're basically wandering through what is now a wilderness. And they're puzzling over what has become of the car, Why do they see nothing, but cat and ante
know, it's taking them a long time to figure out what's happened. I did wanna go back to the the architecture. I don't think that it would have been
in this part of the country. That's a very specific
true right group of scribes. Yeah in a different part of the country. So I wonder if he you were telling me off my that it felt like even though it was kind of cringey and the depiction with the native Americans
in the other one, that you had read. It was still very clear he had done a lot of research
and and got some details
very right. So I wonder how much was
of this where he was like, okay. What kind of dwelling did the people of this time period in this part of the country,
and then, you know, he couldn't couldn't bother to, like, portray them with, like, any
intelligence,
but he could accurately
draw a round
with a fast roof for the. Yeah. I wanna I wanna
say that without doing the research, I suspect that he made sure to get these details right. That's just my read And I and I think he was very well intention with this one. I think like Helen Hunt Jackson story, who which is probably not aged well that he was really going for for what would pass for a respectful
kind
representation in a kid's comment. Right. It's a new tried.
Yeah.
He tried. So the Ducktales continue to walk through the wilderness,
and and they it takes I'm noticing, but the mountains that they saw before on their drive are now covered with Timber, in the manner that they must have been a hundred years before
They haven't quite connected the dots, but but they're gonna go back and see that medicine man and figure out why he's made their car disappear And and on the way, Donald encounters a g bear in a place where he said, oh, they've been extinct here for eighty years. And so, you know, they're hiding behind a rock from these g and they're just putting it together that they're seeing wild bears, ante, no roads, no towns.
They kind of figure out retroactively that the the natives look different.
They were wearing bucks
clothes. Oh they reference the house being Adobe hut. And when in the Nephews
establishes, and he he calls it out. We are dreaming
that we're in old California.
So this is this is pretty weird. Right? This is interesting. We've got this story now where we're we're given the setup that the ducks are having a dream and they know that they're in a dream, and
they're gonna go forward and basically
have the attitude of let's go ahead and enjoy this shared dream well we've got it. So Donald is reflecting. He's he's gonna agree with them. You know, This dream business does seem possible they that they've woken up a hundred years ago. One of the nephews calls out that now we're in the days of the missions and the ron shows and the the ranches and the pretty senior like Ramona. And so they decide to get into the spirit of old California.
This is kind of that tourism. Right? They're they're gonna go ahead and be tourists in the past. And Donald calls out, hey, the nice thing about a dream is that you can never get hurt, but that's immediately proven wrong as a bowl charges into him as these crossing the field. So they're they're like figuring out okay, This isn't like the regular kind of dream. We need to be we need to be careful And so they decide to make their way through the grass lands watching out for bulls, hiding and trees.
At some point, they need to, like, Maneuver past to field pull full of bowls, so Donald creates like a little straw dummy and all the bulls zero in on him and crash into each other
landing in a big old heap. That's a pretty funny little bit. Pretty clever too. Yeah. And after a while, you know, they're becoming really tired.
They're really yearning to see some some kind of a settlement.
And eventually, they come across the old run show that they passed that morning, but now it is in its full glory as it would have looked a century before. So Donald speculate that, you know, it's probably
occupied by an old Spanish, dawn and his family and their Indian service.
Oh
Right. Yeah. So I mean, we've got this
probably pretty accurate
representation of the politics, the culture of the area. Right? You've got this mix of people from
Spain. You've got people who are like my,
better what we would call Mexican.
You've got full natives. This is the dynamic that's presented in Ramona. I just I just hated that there was it's probably accurate, but I also just hated how presented without commentary
their quote unquote, Indian servant.
Yeah. It's it's not a great look. And and I guess this is kind of a part two where it it stray from the ethos of ramona itself. Right? Because
Ramona from what I I didn't read remote, but my cliffs notes
understanding of it is that it really does try the center
the story around a woman who has some native heritage.
And and comes to know that and accept that. And I don't think that's the case for the main one that we're gonna meet here. But the decks the docs decide that they can't approach this, just asking for the food that they're starving for. So Donald convince them that they've gotta make them think there were travelers dropping by in an old California
style. So they they go in dancing and singing, like, an old
Mexican
style,
yay.
It's very cringey. It's very awkward. I did not like this part as the kid like, it's so
true to Donald character
right where he just makes assumptions instead of asks questions.
Yeah. It feels like the kids are kind of on vacation from their critical thinking brain too because usually, they're the ones that are like I don't think that's how it goes uncle donald. But they just like, oh, sure, I'll believe anything. You're the expert on old California. Let's yay.
Right. And he did mention that he read a book about it at the beginning. So I guess that's why he's an expert.
And I'll note that despite how I how it struck me. I I think it's supposed to read as very charming. Like naive charming is how I think it's supposed to read And so now we're gonna come to a segment where we meet we meet the members of the Hacienda. We meet the people at this run show. And it is
everything to do with the Rancho show is just beautifully drawn. Right? Like, we've got some lavish lovely
detail
that interior, the exterior, the people, the fiesta that we're gonna get to meet. This is a real highlight of the story and I think it's a big part of what people love about this one, Sarah. It's so evo.
You and and comm. It if this is where he gets into that, like, just bark at his best and how he is just such a great communicator in the medium of of drawing. And it's it's so
simple and concise. And and I just I just loved it. I love the art in this part. Yeah. No no argument here. This art is gorgeous.
And this is kind of where we meet the main characters of the story in a way. And we're gonna get introduced to them very quickly and like you said, we're gonna just from looking at them. We're gonna know immediately what they're like. You know? We we see a young woman
talking to her mother
a lovely young woman. Talking to her mother, who's the don. She's very stern looking. Donald
approaches
port
native woman who must be one of these servants.
He greet her by saying high poc
oh
I'm just quoting this. Right? I'm gonna say, I'm gonna say his line, he says hi Poc tell the head man, we've come to dance the fan dang and his fiesta. This doesn't read the same way it does today after you know, we we had a couple years ago, Donald Trump using this as a slur. This this has always been used as little bit of a an insult or a casual, but it's it's meant to be like a casual
hiya here. They wouldn't read the today. Here. Right. And she is a no nonsense woman. She asked you know, fiesta.
And she asks him, why would he think that I'll read the dog's full name because it's great.
Fernando
gives... Why does he give a fiesta? And Sarah do you know what the joke here is with the name apart from it being one of those classically long
Spanish names?
I mean, no. That's the only one that I picked up on. I mean, that that part is great. But there are a couple of local...
There are a couple of local roads.
Embedded in that name. Paul Al a famous Southern California.
I think B and D as well, that's just something he threw in for locals I I lived most of my life in northern California, but I did spend a little bit of time. I I spent a summer in in Santa Barbara and tooling around down south. So And so he.
So, you know, Donald is kinda realizing he's gotten off on the wrong foot. He's just saying that you know, he really wanted one of their famous barbecue with free eats. He's like making all these assumptions about about how life works then. And and the Dawn has been listening from the other side of the door. He has realized that these are not dangerous people. They're just some be will boys, lost and hungry,
he puts away his shotgun which he is very reasonably
holding and he greet them warm saying that the table of Don gasp is always loaded for those who come in friendliness.
And and a lot of this story now is gonna be kind of about this like friendliness and
Al. Mh. Because
the members of the rancho are going to show them some
tremendous
hospitality, and you can see that Barks
loves this idea. Right? The the young woman calls out to bring them food and drink and to sit and the the dawn calls out for beds.
The dawn calls out for clean linen and hot tubs for that for the dusty travelers, which the Nephews are very
acutely gonna be dismay Al being vague to take a bath. And we get this really lovely little panel that's almost like Al almost like a movie post or the cover of a Romance novel on this page.
Where he highlights
Barks narration box
says,
do you do you wanna read the narration box for us Sarah? Just like that Donald did his nephews from the year nineteen fifty one become guests of people who lived in the romantic days of long ago, this channel It has
this is my favorite panels of of this comic. Oh, yeah. It has... It it and it feels very much like a d.
Right, of
spa. And he's he has, you know, a full head of hair like a human would and a little handlebar
mustache, a very long mute and kind of some floppy ears like a dog. But even
even that, you get the feeling that, like, this
man is considered
handsome. He is handsome,
and
he is... He has a presence to him. He is
very masculine,
but dog.
Right. And and... Yeah. He has that little, like, half warm smile and then
and she has
an old traditional
Spanish head covering
that you can tell is very old fashioned at that point, but that's who she is and then you have Tina, the quote unquote in and service. And I can I just say, I want Tina to give me a hug. I bet she gives the best
and then you have Pan
who is wearing a a big Spanish rose in her hair and and and her hair is long and and black with that little little line of blue that marks that it's shiny right how black hair shines in comments. And then in the background you have
and he's you see a silhouette of him on a horse,
lace wing of full with these really long dangerous ones.
This is art. This is a masterpiece,
and they're all animals
Yeah. I will never get over how good Karl Barks is giving human traits to animals and giving animal traits to humans and vice versa. Right? Like, both of these, he is an expert at. Yeah. Very well sad. This is a stunning panel at sets up so much. I only my only complain is that it's not bigger, you know? This should have been like a a half page or a full page panel. I can just see it as Al d
like, the credits, like, like, zooming in on each space as they travel across the screen. Yeah. It it looks like a play bill. You know. There's been a couple of nice covers adaptive out of this panel. And for the rest of for much of the rest of the story, you know, we just get to kind of live
alongside these people and we get to
learn about the dynamic
between them. And and we find out that, you know, the Ron show is in the process of the rodeo, which is the roundup up of the wild cattle. We we learn about the cattle trade, we learn we see that the la
are doing what they do rounding up stray.
We get to see Roland
finally, who who is arguably the hero. Right?
Right. And car... And Carl Barks trains like a hero's camera on him. Right? We we get to see him at his at his job just being
spectacular
And then the the Ducktales compare him to a famous modern day cowboy. Gene.
And so we're in the know that the Ducktales are thinking about all these to them modern western that now feel very antiquated. And then we get our little moment of peril where a bull heads straight for Pan.
And the Ducktales and pan to all have to flee.
And and Pan chi gets thrown from her horse when he when it steps in a go for hole.
And and we've got Donald trying to save the day. He gets it up to a little bit of buff getting pulled behind the bowl. But ultimately,
orlando ends up rescuing her and donald. And donald the yes.
And it's a great setup that we we can see that Pan
is
sm with Roland
and he's that sort of silent cowboy type. He clearly feels the same way about her. And and the nephews here, it's very cute. Tell me about the Nephews Sarah. They're often in the corner, The panel has
a a bowl with stars coming out of its its head. Like, it's, you know, ben subdued and
twenty.
Oh. No. I think you are wonderful. And he's just like, he's just got the little lines of emotion coming out. Like you said this strong silent type. And in the background, there's donald kind of knocked out but safe and the little boys are like
it's just like in the movies only nicer, and they a little Barks coming out of their head. They're so in love with the love that they're seeing in this scene. It's interesting for us to be the spectators
of something that the Ducktales spectators have too yeah. Yeah. Absolutely. And it's interesting to see them in this, like, romantic mold when he'll usually make them you know, little boys who think Love is ic.
Al well this is what we need. It's very cute. It's It's a romance. It's it's such a
such an odd. We've got this... We've got this little romance novel here. And so we transitioned that evening to kind of a typical night with the Vac volcanoes
singing
at the cam campfire. It's a very funny little song.
Total hugo.
And and we're made to know that Roland has the finest of all the singing voices
And the the worst of all the jaws. Oh yeah this. Again, he is... He immediately stands out as, like, movie star handsome despite being a dog, and Pan
is just stunning beautiful despite being a dog character.
She looks ninety nine percent human in this. He he made them as human as he possibly could. And we get this funny moment
and touching moment where Donald offers to teach him a new cowboy song and he kind of he kinda looks a little bit
shy and says, you know, maybe there's someone that would like to hear me sing them referring, of course to Pan.
And that look, is so
worthy. U.
If like, that's the kind of, like modern day, boy Barks. Like, Oh,
shy. I'm bash, but I'm also. Very hands and he was putting this look on dogs in the nineteen fifties. He was really ahead of his time. Right? Yeah. Because he's, like, he is that sort of boy or again, it's that like, back then this would have been the sensitive cowboy trope where he's he's tough and he can handle himself, he's sweet and shy, and has a lovely singing voice. Yeah
this this story more than most really feels like it is geared towards a more female readers to me. You know, it has... It has something for everybody. Right? It has. It has the... It has the nostalgia for the older man. It has the
the dreamy romance
and the the the bash
strong silent hero for the boy like, and it has the kids on Al adventure for the...
And and you're on the adventure with them. It just it has something for everybody. Right? And and we're about to get this scene where they are gonna have a big
to to finish the rodeo the Rodeo.
And
this is part of what makes me think that. Right? Because the the amount of detail that he pays with the the dresses and the suits is
something that you would
associate with, like a period piece that is stereo
more for women. Right? Like again, it's something anyone can enjoy. But the stereotype is that his boy readers probably wouldn't have been the the people who would have cared about him making these lovely dresses. And so forth. And and boy, the the banquet, the Fiesta is really something to see. He says guests come from leagues away. Fran shadows, vac volcanoes, Pad, Indians, cabal,
It's very poetic. We see all of these
people and we get introduced on the next page to the the pretty senior
coming and he tells us that Pan is the prettiest of all. And we get again the Nephews this audience surrogate. They're very excited to see her and they're looking around for long though because they wanna see him ask her to dance the And. And then
we meet the monkey ranch.
We
through the Nephews
are outraged to see a man who is named Dawn H,
a rich runs Run that the Sen order has chosen to be Pan
husband. And he is a pig. He
is
not conventionally
attractive. He looks older.
And she's bow her head because she is very clearly just not into him. To... She's she's sad about having to give the first dance to him. Right. And to be
engaged the truth to him. And then nephews are very upset as audience surrogate they they're thinking now things were too perfect
this dawn Barks del la, I believe this might be the first appearance of Carl Barks,
pig faced Villain. He will use this
archetype and a lot of comics spilling forward. He's like a tier two villain
going forward. He's he gets named at some point, I think Argus mixed swine and he never, like rises to the level of villain of, like, the beagle boys and Fun Long and Magic des spell who are Barks most famous villains, but when Barks doesn't wanna use someone else, and he just needs kind of a generic shifty person. He's gonna use this pig face to villain archetype. And so, you know, the nephews are of course outraged. They're talking to tina
about white roland can't marry Pan chi. And she says that, you know, daughters of the grand d's do not marry poor vac. So we've got this little class element here. This is this is set up as something that that that we can't
overcome it.
Without overcoming the class difference.
This next page is so lovely. It's more of this beautiful fiesta fiesta
Sarah, do you notice how little the ducks appear here?
On you're right. You're right, only in the very first and the very last panel does even Donald appear. Yeah. It's this is really all about On trying to get the nerve to ask Pan
or a dance
he even reaches for a spur as though he's gonna whack him with the spur.
And Pan
is grateful to don though for having given him
the the kick because of course, she feels the same way about him.
And we have this funny bit do you wanna tell us about the the funny little bit here with the music?
I don't know if this is a real song or not, but it has words that would not make sense at all. To anybody in the eighteen
forties, but it's you'd be a pip on my radar a while on the video we could sing beep up in a helicopter on our way to movie show, and he's singing this tour her
she says the words don't make any sense Orlando. But sleep are more
because she loves him. Obviously, this is a song that Donald taught him to sing to her. It's just such cute moment between... First before that, they are dancing and and you can see how beautifully the the layers of Pan
skirt are are kind of drifting up Al as she's being thrown around the dance floor. It's just... And their faces are turned to each other. They're looking at each other. They're both very engaged and happy and you could just feel the love between these two cartoon
human dogs.
Yeah.
Absolutely.
It's very romantic. Know. It's so cute. It's it's very surface level because we we have to use all this short hands to, like, make clear their feeling. So this has happened very quickly of course, but I do feel very very engaged and very invested in this romance.
I don't feel like this has happened very quickly. If you are familiar with the trope, didn't you
watch princess bride or these kinds of kinds of relationship
between the hired hand and the young daughter of the manor did fill up over months and sometimes years.
That's true. We're we're meant to
know that there's been a lot before this. It's it's very sweet. It's lovely. And again the detail in drawing her dress. And the artist three of her dress is very noteworthy for this boys comic. And this scars
as well. Yeah. And then we've got know, we've got this little moment where the Dawn is sc her for making eyes
roland orlando, but Dawn Port del lard is so confident of his station and the agreement that he he's not even bothered and he says to let the hired man sing his silly songs. He'll sing a different tune at my wedding.
And then, you know, we've got this moment at the end where we meet another gas to day. Which I think is a property owner who is on his way to monte and he mentions offhand that he room and his coach for four. And,
you know, Donald likes this idea because they really are just on vacation.
Why not. So the next morning, they get ready to hop in the coach.
I'll say, Sarah that does really sound lovely riding through Ancient California and an old stage coach. I'm I'm sure it would get tiring and my butt would get sore after a few hours. But I think that I would would agree with you on that. You know, my butt would hurt, but it would be lovely.
Right. And I'm sure the Al
has some pretty good upholstery.
And so, you know, the nephews are on board, but they they wanna see to roland orlando and Pan
before they leave.
They're just talking about how the situation it ain't right. And Donald like you habit, but that's none of our business, but then he has a thought. And he asked tina, what year they're in.
I love her response. She's like eighteen forty eight. My goodness, you're dumb. And you know, if you are a Californian and you know your history or you're familiar with the football team, the forty nine, you know what it means that they're in eighteen forty eight. The the ducks are so excited because they they know that they've got this solution to make orlando rich. And they convey the message that he should ride the hills beyond Sacramento with a gold pan, because he'll make it just before the gold rush.
The don, you know, she soften her heart a bit. She she agrees that yes if he's rich, he could marry her and gives him a kiss and Pan gives them a kiss and of course, the nephews lineup up to get a kiss from Pan.
Which feels kind of gross that one didn't sit well with me. Yeah. I I think I read that very.
I think it's like, you know, just
to me, it looks red very innocent cute, but I'm not gonna be grad or reading of it. Yeah.
And so we transitioned to the Al journey and they're talking about, you know, how rough the road is
I may approach the city of Los angeles Hi
soon, and the Ducktales are just
stunned to see the tiny little village this is this is a great little reference for the modern reader. And this is what any Californian who's been there long enough. My my dad loves to rem about the
peach orchard
that were one block away from his
my grandmother's house and down in Cup,
which is now like, a couple blocks away from the Apple, the giant Apple building. So change
in in in Phoenix. Right? Like, oh, this used to be orange groves. Oh, across the street, we used to have cotton fields, and I remember them. But now for miles, we have thing that suburbs.
Right. And it's en if you're not one of those people who who grew up there, and it's all you can think of if you did. Right. And this style called is a really nice man because as he gets to talking, he tells Don Donald that he really should be set up with some land he says he has a few small grants left and he just straight up offers Donald a few thousand acres of California
and Barks
narration box highlights this. He says just like that, Donald becomes owner of a huge chunk of California.
And
I mean, this this is what happened with a lot of California.
Right? Huge land grants given away to the right people and the wrong people quote unquote, and people would get chased off the land and and the land would get d up and marginalized people would get pushed to the outskirts
and
it's so it's a pretty astonishing little little bit of fantasy
and history. Yeah. And so, you know, the the Nephews, the Ducktales all celebrate that they're their big run now and they approach their giant tracts of land on foot. They hear some shooting and they encounter a very shifty looking man wrestling
their cows for their hides. And they very un wisely go up to the man and tell him that, you know, we're the owners, we've got the deeds here and this guy is he's that guy that you referenced that's very like hill billie ish very he does what he's gonna do. He immediately comment here the ducks property. He takes it over. And his name is Es,
and the Docs just they're disappointed that they've lost their land, but I think in the back of their mind, they're like, well, this is just a dream. So I guess it's not the end of the world. It's it's totally pretty weird. Right? Too have been given this this giant tract of land and then immediately lose it. Oh, I looked up where it was. I was like, okay. Where exactly is the and joaquin valley.
What have they done with it now? It
it didn't really look that developed from right now. Suburbs are around it. Yeah. That's that's like the interior that's like scrub, not so productive, California.
I mean, everything in Al gold plated these days but there are still parts of it that are less developed than others. And and so we've transitioned now. Right? We we headed from Southern California up to Northern California. So this is much more of a Southern California adventure,
but... But we do have this part again, California history,
all about the gold rush. And they head up to sutter fort, and I don't know if sutter that name means much to you, Sarah. But as someone who... Yeah. If you if you went through fourth grade California history, you learned all about sutter for and Sutter minds, so many of the names and the terms are so familiar to me and this. You think that I've been white would have been more interested in this story given that But
but this isn't one that I went back to all that often. Is there a modern day analog to sutter sport, does it still exist? What what's going on with Sutter fort? Oh, yeah. Like it's... you know, it's a big tourist desk nation, you can go and you can pan for gold. You can
see the sites
as kids, we did this big, like week long field trip called cross country, California where we stayed Al like a summer camp and one of the stops was to I believe we saw some of the sutter
stuff. There's a whole little tourist
industry with the gold rush stuff. And who was sutter? Sutter himself is the guy who, likes set off the gold rush by by being the person to to first discover gold in eighteen forty eight. So the mill been, like, reconstructed, you know? So we we've arrived at outside of the gold rush. And
they're very interested in this. They they've made plans to buy a gun to get their land back from.
And Donald leaves the kids so that he can go do that. And
pledges that he's not gonna be overwhelmed by gold fever. But of course, when he returns, he's got... He's got a prospect
pack and he has allowed
the gold fever to overtake him. Which I mean, of the two, I think that that's a better choice to be c obsessed with. Sure. Yeah. Especially given that this is all a fever dream.
So we transition to this being a gold rush tail and the the Ducktales have some pretty spectacular luck they got a a amount of nuggets that would be just worth a fantastic amount of money back then. This is more than any prospect through whatever hope to find. But we see another prospect
approach behind them, and he's gonna pull a con on them. He says you young dig that kind of stuff. You must be green. He characterize that as only eighteen carat gold. And he tells them where they can find some twenty two care gold
around the band. And when they when they foolishly run around the band, they realized that the the man has claim jumps them. Which like I you really get into these
details about the history. Right? Like, you don't just... Oh, and then people claim up each other. He
illustrates
how claim jumping works. Yeah. I didn't. I didn't know that. I I learned from this. I learned a lot from this one. Nice. And and then on the next page we learned that this man not only has this shift
claim jumper taken their gold but he is also
partnered with,
their old friend, who has heard claim jumping is richer than land jumping And and so, you know, the ducks are in a spot of trouble here because they're being menace by ezra with his gun, and then heroic just in the nick of time, and and we only see him by his silhouette first roland
comes to the Ducktales rescue. And he is just the the movie star hero
the nephew calls him just as big and rough as ever. It takes both men down ezra and the claim jumper and that's pretty tough. Yeah. And so the Ducktales continue now to work their Al claim and they've got the... They've got On to protect them, the quote best air in the hills i'm so they mine a fortune out of this claim, and it's very sweet. Right? It's a nice little ending, Donald says there's gold enough for us Al. And Roland orlando says for Pan, the finest ranch show in all of California
and they they warm part ways,
leaves, Laden with gold. And the story takes this with full turn as they watch him walk away, and they comment that Don Gasp and the Sen and Pan
they seems so far away now or something like people we read about in an old old book. And,
you know, they they decide that they need to take an nap. And we finally see the landscape
dissolve away, and and we finally see the the Ducktales coming to Do you wanna to tell us about
this seen here, sarah. The... It's clear that they... The four of them across three beds are stirring and there's a nurse in the typical
nineteen fifties
dress with a with the white nursing hat calling the dock
saying that they're coming to and the doctor explains to them what happened. You know, you're in a hospital. Don't you remember your your car struck or rock? And some indians trek to doctor you with dancing in herbs. And Donald like oh, you're not sure. The medicine man.
And then the doctor says, you must have given you some powerful stuff you've been in A coma six weeks. And, of course, Donald is just shocked at that news. Yeah. There there was no great way to transition out of this like, time travel tale that didn't involve time travel.
So Barks
told the story that he wanted to. He wanted this to be in a dream like state. So he did it. And and it doesn't
work perfectly for me, but it works alright. Because that's not the point of the story. Right? The point of the story is the west
and the nostalgia. I could done without the herbs causing
it. It could just been a headwind wound. Yeah.
I have that.
Once you bring in like, oh, it's been six weeks. Like, that makes it sounds like poisoning
and it... you know, even if their intentions were good, it still is pretty nefarious to put somebody in a coma for six weeks Yeah. I I agree. That part of the story is a little uncomfortable. I remember that it always kind of quiet me. I didn't read this one as as frequently as I did others as a kid and so my memory of it wasn't a sharp because it had been a good twenty years. Since I read this and I was like, oh, I think I remember, don't they like get into a horrible car accident and they go into a coma, and then some Indians bring them out of the coma
because I think my mind preferred that scenario or something.
And so, you know, the ducks are on their way. They recover quickly from their coma at this point, we've got it's lamps shaded by saying modern medicine and modern garages have their points and the ducks are soon on their way. And as they drive off, they pass the old rancho show in a very d
state And
the Ducktales very acutely decide to sing a serena
to them in the manner that they had originally greeted them that like little awkward cringey,
singing and dance seen that they did. And it's a very poetic ending. I'll just read the narrator box says so once again, Donald and the kids come up the path to the old ranch house. And as they sing,
we see a new panel with a couple of other Californian
and it says and behind them, new California goes by and the the two drivers are commenting on some some kids singing Spanish songs in front of the old shack and the man says you see the nut people in these sticks So what do you think of the ending there, Sarah? It felt
like it was very
abrupt. Mh.
I would liked to see a wedding.
That would have brought me the resolution that I needed.
Because as you said, it did become a story about
the rancher for a while Instead of a story about the ducks. Right. Yeah. That would have been neat. You know, his longest stories were thirty two pager. If he had had another another four pages or even just one page that just highlighted
Roland orlando as he arrived back to greet Pan.
But again, maybe that is an indication that ultimately this is a book for little boys
instead of four little boys and else. All stories are for everybody Barks. I fully agree. But
but I do you know
I do know what Barks was probably thinking when he wrote these. Right. I mean, there were points where they really did make an effort to to be expansive. But I think they did the thing that one usually does. By telling a story for boys, boys are considered the default and so you've just made a story for everyone. Right. Right. Right. I think it would been a really good way to end this story with some symmetry. If they did go back with Roland to the ranch. Have a wedding scene, go back and visit the Indians and then wake up in the hospital. Yeah. There'll be some nice symmetry there. I think it would have been neat to see some almost like spectral versions
of the
the people of the run shadow having the wedding.
As.
Oh, you just gave me goosebumps. Yeah.
Because you could've you coulda have done it both in one. Like, maybe we didn't need that little throw a panel of the
Goof ball Californian
maybe that could have been the wedding party. Oh, that would have been so good. So much better than my idea. Regardless, it's it's a lovely little story. I totally
understand why people love this one. You know, it's it stands out and people are gonna remember out of the, like scores and scores of stories he did. Some of them really stand out as distinct. Right? Dangerous
disguise is as unique for the reasons that it's unique. Voodoo hut was was unique,
say what you will, but it was a very horrific
unforgettable story. And this one just stands apart as like his most nostalgic and romantic
story. So I get like people love this one. What do you think? I always... When you tell me what ratings,
some of the stories have gotten. I'm always kind of shocked and a little bit dis dismay. Because you do tend to bring me on for the heavier more problematic
stuff. And I a lot of them
score so highly. And so the ones that that we read that are just just as fine today as they would have been, you know,
back then. Tend to not in my limited experience. Would you say that that's accurate? Yeah. I mean, you're getting such a like weird variety of them. Right? Because I've I've had on for a number of these. But but he has a ton of stories. So I might have to just pick a few like I might have to think about what is a good
representation of these overall? I'll think about like Right. Six or eight, you know, must reads to make sure that you've got a rounded picture.
I know I don't have a rounded picture. Yeah. But it also
does feel like so many of the ones that I've read
specifically so I can help process the problem like problematic elements
score dis dismay high.
But for this one, I can see how it's scored so high. Right? Like, the people that have read it very... you know, not everybody has my sensitivity,
so they're not gonna have the problems with it that I have. And I I understand that about humans, and I can see how this one would appeal to humans and, you know, I talk about them like they're separate species. Right. Right. Like, we're a robot study in. Like
like I'm a aroma studying them, exactly. What do you think? Does this one get... Do you think this one gets a little bit credit for trying hard or is that not enough? I think with
today's
sensibilities,
no. Absolutely not. And thought leaders will point to this is how this damaged
relationships
between Native America this specific thing it has caused this damage. And they can point to ways that even these
slightly
better
representations are still extremely harmful.
I think from well he was
trying and maybe doing the best he could at the time. I think it's better than
not
trying, but we can still see the effects of the harm that such per
has caused So I wouldn't credit him with being
progressive even for his time, but I can recognize that this was progressive his time. Recognize the effort. It doesn't mean it doesn't mean it worked. Right. Yeah. I... That's important to recognize Right? Because even even well meaning, quote, like positive stereotypes
can still be harmful. How about the story itself? You know we both had some really positive things to say about it. Right? What do you... What's your overall impression? I really liked it. I really thought it was cute. I really liked it. I was shipping
pan and.
Oh, yeah.
I I loved that the boys
just kinda got to go on Al adventure instead of be the adult in a situation.
True. I I did I did enjoy it aside from the. I think you could have taken out the native American people
completely.
That whole...
They they didn't even need to be there. You could have had the exact same story with head wounds. Yeah. I agree. It feels like he wanted to have them
because of the, like, the fact that Rum ramona is it's it's so central to Am ramona. But I I feel like we lose... You know, he never goes plays with Ramona
seat where Pan should have at some point been identified as having been part native I don't see her as being coded that way. At any point. Right? She... To me she was Spanish, not mexican... Especially because we see both of her parents. Right. And they're very clearly Spanish.
Right. I do read Roland,
though as Me.
I did see him as either a mexican
or a mixed character.
So... I could see that. That that was my reading of it. I don't think I'm stretching. I... Because, you know, we we have the, like, class element of it. And that that matches. Right? He's a.
And and I did like Tina, you know, she she can stay But the the tribe I think, you know, it's it's not great that she's quote just a servant, but it is true to life, unfortunately. Mh. But I liked her. I thought she was like.
I want her to give me hugs. Yeah. And I thought it was refreshing that, like, a fat character wasn't played for she wasn't she's very she's very large, but she's also not... It's not played for laughs. And she's she's so maternal. And she's allowed to have a sense of
control over the situation. Right? You get the feeling that she runs. The the show. Like, the inside of it. Yeah. So... yeah. I think... I think this a really lovely story. I've been pretty clear that it's like it's not one of my favorite. Like, I don't go back to this one all the time, but I do feel like it's one that I can appreciate much more as an adult. Than I can as a kid. Because I'm seeing... I'm seeing the detail that he... Yeah. I'm just I'm seeing the attention of detail that he paid with
elements that wouldn't have interested me as a kid. Like, how lovely everything at the Fiesta looked, the romance.
You know, it wasn't what I was about as a nine than ten year old. Right. Is there a practice of families reading these together? Like, a mother and a son maybe that maybe back then this would have been
geared toward
more of that than individual reading. I think that the expectation back then for comics is that they were just kids. Right. You you read him. You were a kid. He was writing them for kids. I I think he wrote and Drew what he thought he would enjoy. And he pointed tried never to talk down to kids. Like, that's something that really comes out and that he has said. A lot of fans, of course grew up reading these to their children. You know, I've read, I've read these to my own kids. I love reading them to my kids. No one ever read them too or with me,
but, you know, I just I've discovered them for myself at the news stand. But, yeah, this one seems like one that that parent could enjoy more than many reading to their kids. Yeah. It seems like it has several layers. It it seems like the first one that's written at that kind of a level two appeal to adele. Adults. Right? It has the romance. It has the nostalgia. And it's not just a history lesson. It is nostalgia. It is very nostalgic. It's very wi.
And I think what you're hitting on is that he really wrote it for himself. You know, this is obviously like a very personal one. You know? He likes to draw these more human characters in these more human
situations.
So everyone in while he steered that where he thought he could go with it. And yeah. I think he had a great time doing this. Any other thoughts or I can transition into talking about the consensus? Of course, the kind of Ana socialist
anti capitalist in the thought that the the class struggle being solved by just giving Al chance to make money was
hilarious
because it felt like he was able to buy Pan.
Obviously, she was a willing participant in this but because money was so central to it. My notes say,
everyone gets rich and Romano has enough to buy or afford to Mary, but
Yeah. It's true. And people who tell you money can't solve your problems are wrong. Right? Like, You're wrong. Ninety nine out of a hundred times. People's problems have to do with the lack of money. So this feels like a very good highlighting of that.
You know what I just remember. I didn't comment on how much I liked seeing Pan
out at the rodeo. You know? She was like dressed for it. She was obviously a very capable writer.
She looked awesome. Right? She she had multiple outfits throughout the course of this. But
she didn't do anything wrong.
It it was her horse that stumbled in a go for hole. You know. She... Like, she still needed to be saved. Yes. Because that's the old, like, hollywood
archetype. But I do like that she he really went out of his way to present her as very capable. She right. She's wearing a pants suit. She's wearing spur. And yeah,
she she didn't fall off her horse because she's
incapable.
It was just a an accident.
Yeah. And and again, she looks great. Almost as good as she does in her beautiful dress. I mean, chances are coming back around. So I would say that Yeah. She looks really great. And it's gorgeous. It's still very feminine, but also, you know, we have this stereotype
of you know, women could wet ride horses, but they had to ride side saddle she gets pants no problem. I know it. Look at her in the panel where her horse rear as the bowl coming. I mean, she's
steady as a rock. Oh, yeah. That's an excellent
thing to notice mark. Holding the horse with one rain pointing back over her shoulder. Yeah. I really like that. I really like I found Pan
and
Delightful.
Mh. So I've mentioned, you know, a few times that the community loves this one it is rated super high on index currently and likely forever. It has a rating of seven out of all forty thousand.
Some stories. That's good for eight point five out of ten. I like it. I think it's great. I guess it is like, if I think about what the all time classic Donald dot stories. This this has gotta be a top ten. Out of all the Donald Ducktales adventures.
Probably wouldn't... If I thought about the Donald man Scrooge stories. I don't think I'd have it in the overall top ten or twenty. But it is a great story. It holds up. I mean, as a story it holds up very well, there's obvious some very dated elements of it that that don't work
It it presents this weird, like, fantasy
utopian
version. Of old California
that was was not a thing. But it was a really interesting look back at the past. It it got some stuff right. And then some stuff it completely muddled up, of course. It is still a funny animal chronic.
Four children. Yeah. Yes. But a very ind one. I think we've covered a lot. So, you know, we can we can close out by by talking about if there are any any
panels
among the many wonderful panels in this story that do stand out as your favorites.
I already talked about the one introducing
the family.
Right. But I want to also draw attention to
the first introduction of the rodeo after the kids are being carried off into
a to a bath. It just makes me kind of, like, whisper fall for home. Right. There's a sag
so that's not quite geographically accurate, but back home, we had.
Oh, yes. So I'm nostalgic or for home because of this panel. And it's really great. It... You know, it has a rolling hills
donald writing a horse himself. I like that panel. And now I have to say that the panel with Pan
riding a horse that's rear that. That's now about my favorites now that you've pointed it out. Oh, I'm glad to hear it. Yeah. It is a good one. I have to echo what you said about the play bill, you know, the the poster for the Tele,
basically. That's so awesome. And there's so much
characterization there. And you could almost just pick any of the great panels from the the Rodeo
or the fiesta fiesta because they're all just so gorgeous.
I do like the pile of bowls.
And I do like the old the the introduction to the old on show, how we see it both in its new state and old and d.
And
just those piano panels that echo each other, you know, in the past and and in the present are really cool.
Let's see. And then, you know,
specifically, I love her ruffled dress during the fiesta. When you can see all that detail and and his his outfit as well. Looks awesome. So yeah, thank you so much for talking with me about old California.
We're gonna get to follow up our awesome podcast where we joined Warren Harmon and or you can't guess. We're gonna cover a Christmas for Shack,
next episode. So I'm very excited to hear what you have to say about about that one. And listeners can let us know what they thought of our remarks and reach out to us on the Facebook page. And we'll look forward
to will y up with a new episode soon.