Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks, the podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Mc Ducktales writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge con of all time. Join us as we have explore has longer adventure stories in their chronological publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical contacts. And how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Welcome back to Barks remarks, I'm Mark Sever, a Grown man who enjoys Inducks comics
and enjoys talking about them with friends and guest hosts.
We are back for another Landmark
holiday story. We're gonna be talking
today about Carl Barks classic
Christmas for Shack down and I'm very pleased to be joined by two returning guests gonna have them introduce themselves. Why don't we go with Warren first Hey, Mark. Hey Sarah. This is Warren Herman Rochester, Minnesota.
Glad to be back again.
Talking about another Christmas classic
related story from Carl Barks and looking forward to our discussion today. And Sarah. I'm Sarah Santiago.
Wearing my best Christmas pajamas for this very special Christmas in Shack sound okay That's right. We've got a Christmas in April here, which is our recording time. I like that doing these chronological,
just makes me aware of how many Christmas stories, Carl Barks had, but there's there's a lot to cover. It really stands out for a lot of fans.
A little bit of background
about the story at Christmas for Shack. We're still in Barks golden age This one was published
in November of nineteen fifty one. Unlike many of his Christmas stories. This one was released is one of the four color comments. You know, a lot of them were
put out in kind of limited
publications like Christmas
parade, but this one is four color three hundred and sixty seven. And this one's been reprinted just to ton. I counted thirteen,
including the original I think it's fair to say that this is this is his most famous Christmas story. Right. Christmas on Bear Mountain is very famous because it introduced screws mick dot, but I I think if you ask someone to name a Carl Barks Christmas themed story. This is probably the one that most fans would go to. This is a full length thirty two page story and
what really interests me about this one is is its focus on poverty.
It's it's gonna hit us right away with some really
start
images of really striking
poverty,
porn, in a way that I don't think you really see in a lot of pop culture from the era. I would hazard a guess that a lot of kids in the nineteen fifties, this might have been one of the one of the first times that, like, a middle class common with buying kid might have been confronted by this kind of poverty. Glad i do mention that because here we are post or America, and we've got Prosperous
advertising going on and everybody's moving to the suburbs and everybody's happy and the war over. We... And yeah Barks is brave here, I think and we'll talk a little bit about it. I I just think his his bravery and depicting property of the other side of America for everyone to see the kids grabbing these comics, was a really brave move and a bold move for him to pick this, and I'm not sure what the editors thought. Yeah. For sure. It was brave. Right? Because this this is a period where, like, he is getting some editorial push pushback from, like, using humans too much
You can tell that sometimes he wants to push the envelope a little bit here. And this is a big departure. Right? Because, like, it's it's a Christmas story. Christmas stories are generally meant to be uplifting happy go lucky. So
it's a bold move in some ways. And it's interesting too because it's very much at odds with like the ethos of one of the characters that's in this story. Right? We've got this really weird, like,
contradiction between this
emphasis on poverty.
In the story and, of course, the appearance of Scrooge Dot who is like a a major part of it and and who really represents wealth and the the Ty
ethos and that's something that that's
impossible not to about. Right, Sarah?
Yeah. That was definitely impossible for me to ignore and it it it actually
interfered with my enjoyment of the story. Right? Like, if it was just like, oh, a a Rag tag group does their best
to make Christmas
a little bit better for some poor people.
It would have been easier to stomach, I guess.
But this whole... Like, the... But every so often when they would go back Scrooge, just
refusing to let go of any of the money. It really made him out into
a fill in in my mind. And, like, you know, I know he is. But I'm from the era Ducktales.
And I grew up with the Scrooge Inducks that wasn't such a greedy
mean guy. Right? And I know he was... you know, he shares a name with the Scrooge from dickens. And so. And and living in Scotland, I also don't wanna hate in because I lost scotland. And I love.
So it was harder for me to enjoy this one. Well, it it might help contextualize
this, right, to know that this is literally one full length issue
before Barb is gonna get the the call, the request from his editors.
To
deliver them a thirty two page
Scrooge
story for the first time and Barb has been using Scrooge as a side character for the most part up till now. And it's kind of been like this varying level of almost villain
com foil or or a plot device when the docks needs someone to be able to flip the bill for something like a trip to to the riviera. But in in a few months after this is published, they're gonna ask him to deliver a a Scrooge story and he's gonna get this big offer opportunity to basically
spin off his own character into a featured
story which will be the very next for a caller publication, and Barb realizes he
understands that he's gonna have to soft the character. But he's really gonna expand the character. And there's already been some softening that's been going on You can tell because it's obvious he likes the carrot church, but you can tell that he wasn't really keeping this continuity
in mind and he hadn't yet flushed him out at this point. So I think in this story he really is supposed to be kind of a contrast with the poverty stricken and kids. Of s. I like in the story to a short film, all the twists and turns and plot twists and everything that happens in the story. I just see this as a and Al little feature film where the character of Uncle Scrooge is playing this greedy greedy person. It reminded me a lot of it's a wonderful life. If you think about it, that was produced five years earlier by Frank Ka. But Uncle Scrooge is the mister Potter where either is this this constant grade at the end, we see... I think we see the softening of Scrooge into Mark's point, the launching of Scrooge series only portal, man. I think this episode here features this villainous greedy Scrooge,
and we accepted it, it bothers us, but we accept it as a standalone alone, and I'm I'm glad that that he does actually become his own. Mh. Yeah. We're we're not gonna see his redemption in this story at all. No. And he's he's Severino gonna get, like a full redemption, but he... He is gonna soften after this. I do wanna point out that he is not as cake
or abusive for Donald in this one, and I did pick up on that and appreciate it. Yeah. Right. Good point There's there's definitely some like, nice family
sort of connection in this one I was talking to you guys beforehand. How, like, there are three Christmas stories that timmy really stand out and they stand apart. And it's because they're the the top rated Christmas stories, and they're the top ones that kind of take place in Duck
like Christmas in the city.
It's this one. Christmas for Shack, it's you can't guess that we got to get together for... And it's letter to Santa. Technically Christmas on Vera Mountain is ranked higher than them if you look on, like, the ups ranking, but that's such a difference story. It's a it's a more intimate one. To me, you know, these are a kind of the the tri
of that family
ones that bring in screws, they bring in sometimes Gladstone and grandma doc and daisy dot, and it's fun to me. To see the duct family come together because he he usually really only did that in these holiday stories. And I like to see them interacting with each other. Alright, You guys. So as always, I do like to pan herb to our international fans by going over some of the different
translations for the title that have been used around the world. I found this one really interesting because
Is such a a loaded
sort of term. Right? I think if you're in the states if you're not an English speaker, you may not get sort of the flavor of it. Right? But a Sc time really
implies a certain type of
temporary
sq that was not intended to be lived in forever, but might be home to
of people in some pretty extreme poverty kind of off the grid
disconnected from from the rest of society. And,
Sarah, do you want starting us off. Yeah. Sure. So in Spain, they called it Na In via,
which is Christmas in
Village. Yeah. And I when I looked this one up, I noted that in Spain every
publication translated Al something completely different. So I just picked one of the the Spanish ones. How about you were? Yeah. Italy,
the Italian title is papa
z
Al,
which is Uncle Scrooge and the faithful twenty.
And I got me thinking about what is the fatal twenty, you know, could it be the twenty l? Maybe that them they're translating into the value of the the burning dime, if you will. I I thought that was a little different from interpreting She tone Sure. Yeah. It's an interesting title. And I found it interesting that in the Scan
countries,
they went with a kind of an odd
translation that that's roughly christmas skin pen nonetheless and but it was like it's something like Al
pen
in Norway and You'll
Pen
in sweden and
and something very similar in Denmark. I Al thought I was interesting. One of the
on the Facebook page, urine a lobe Dial.
Getting his name wrong, but he had commented that in the Nordic countries for the first reprint, they took out nine pages of this story. Totally excise part about kids that lived in poverty not wanting to, you know, expose readers to that. So another interesting one, I I liked in France. It was all noel,
Christmas and P, and then Germany is buy not thin food cruiser store. Christmas for Grief village.
So I like I like all these names for Shutdown down. So
we're gonna go ahead and I... I'm gonna summarize this one and you guys are gonna let me know your thoughts as we go along. So Christmas for Sc town, you know, as I alluded, it opens very stark. It has the nephews
having taken a little shortcut.
Through what we are gonna learn is called shack town. And they're basically...
They're talking to each other
about Christmas. They're talking about Shaq town. They're talking about how guilty and terrible they feel walking through this Gu. Where
the people of Shack town
don't know anything about Christmas at all. And they find it as they leave Shack tone. They're finding out hard to be happy about prospect to Christmas coming up. They're really dwelling on this. It it it seems like one of those interesting kind of crystal moments that a lot of people have as a kid where if if you grow up well to do or or comfortable,
you're suddenly confronted with, like, stark poverty, and it really hits you, and you can you can really see this in the nephews. I think what adds to the the impact of that first panel is the the absence of a adult figures there. There's not one adult in there. They're all children so the children relate to the children, and the artwork stunning, of course, but what Caught was the the inking of the blackness in the streets, which only stays in She. And it doesn't go into Inducks work. So I wanted to point that out. So it's Al point. It is the students. And it's a good point about that lack of adults. Right? Because child poverty
hits us
way worse. Right, as absolutely.
Absolutely. And it's making a statement to the children who are buying these comments Yeah. And what do you think Sarah about some of the, like, visual
signals of poverty
that he's sending here? They're very striking. I mean, there are kids that there's a kid playing with cans when they're talking about when the boys are talking about whether or not
the kids in Shack town have toys and that kid's not even wearing gloves or pants. He's his knees are bare. Yeah. We've we've got kids like with patched thread Barks clothes, kids that are just hud
for warm. They're all so
They really look miserable. It's it's really it's not subtle, but I think it's very effective. In that first panel that there is what I read as a woman
carrying...
I don't know if that's wood or
not. Okay. And I actually read her as the only adult Yeah. In the area. But I could see an argument made for it to be maybe a kid who grew up too soon, and that has all this responsibility.
Yeah. The
expression on her face you know, once again, Bark is so good. Her face just is so evo
of the famous picture from the depression where the woman is just gazing off into the distance with her two kids hanging on her and just so worried about
everything, obviously.
And and it's not just
sad. It's worry.
Complete lack of security. Yeah. Very good Points. I
I did read her as an older child, maybe a teenager has had to grow up too fast and and been and then deprived. And and the reason is because I I think Barks is going out of his way to never
throughout the whole story to only dwell on the children. But I I could see because because yeah, she's got me sunken eyes that look like that look very grown up, unfortunately. So So as the children leave Shack down, they
they encountered Daisy.
And,
you know, she
reacts very
in a very expected way to their sad expression. She's like, you should be happy Christmas is coming up. And they explained
that, you know, they just walked through Shack down, and it is making them feel like fat pigs is the expression that they use again.
They feel like they They have too much, and it's interesting you guys to me how Daisy he refers to Shaft. She
to them, you know, is that's that awful place in the gu. Where people live that are down on their lot. It's such a optimistic way. You can tell that Daisy
doesn't think about Shack down if she can avoid it. Right. At all. And and that causes daisy to kind of dwell on the situation.
And she decides that, you know, hey, the women of her club had been looking for something to do. So she gets
she gets the bright idea
to do something about this.
And she tells the Nephews that, you know, she's gonna take care of it. I like the reflective nature of Daisy here. How she... First of all, look how we we introduced we're introduced to her. She looks absolutely beautiful. She's dressed better than we've ever seen her maybe in any story prior to this. And then and then her her comment Barks that you said about that awful place quickly
becomes... I think Gilbert she shook up. Yeah. And then then the immediate joy of realizing the she and her friends can do something to help. Do Sarah, is everyone in this story looking to abs resolve themselves?
It it's it felt
very...
How do I make these bad feelings go away I know. I'll do... I'll slap a band aid on it to me. Gotcha.
In terms of, like, when later on, we see so much of, like, the system as represented by Scrooge Inducks.
How easy it would be to red
wealth. But I do appreciate
that he does as as Warren said. Get more reflective about it and think like, okay. Here's what's within my means.
Here's what I can do. I will post this
to the women's group, and we'll get this sorted. Yeah. So we have this nice transition now to Donald, and Donald has his own problem.
This is a very, like, lower middle class
problem that a lot of people in in American
capitalist
consumers society you have every year. Right? It's the end of the year where a lot of bills come due and you were also expected to put on this great holiday.
And so he is stressing about giving his nephews a nice Christmas
while only having five bucks
to his name
Barks establishes, you know, there's no payday days coming up. No one's gonna loan him at dime, and there's a lot of stuff to buy and and to make matters worse, he is over overheard the nephew say that they're planning to spend five dollars for his present
So he's really feeling and insecure about his his ability to provide for his family.
At the end of the page, Daisy knocks on the door and she has this great line.
Sarah, what what's her line there? Donald.
I came to you with my problem because I know your Christmas worries are so small.
And Donald
responds to her and this just great so on
right way. This is like maybe my favorite a version of Donald here. Right? This, like knowing donald who's like, very, it's very witty to me. So he says they were. And when Daisy explains that her her club needs fifty dollars, he he goof asked her, you know, in pennies, nickel, or
want them. I don't think we would make that kind of joke today, but it it felt.
It it felt like a common trope then.
And and she
on to the next page that she's not asking him for the money but she explains that, you know, her club, her women's club is set in the process of setting up a really nice Christmas party for the poor children of Shaft, and and we see the boys in the background trimming the tree and their beam at this news.
And
she she lets him know that they're they're just a little bit short of their target.
And she's hoping that he might know someone who could donate the remaining fifty dollars that's necessary.
And she explains that the remaining money is to get turkey
and a toy
train for the children. And
she and the nephews
talk donald into approaching their uncle Scrooge
to ask for the remaining money. And this all happens in this, like, whirlwind of activity where Donald is just rope into this, what he knows is gonna be a terrible request to make Scrooge mick dot, because he'll help particularly
hate that toy train, which is gonna become a very key part of the story. Sarah. I did wanna point out for contacts.
That in fifty dollars
in the context of this chronic would be worth five hundred thirty eight dollars and sixty two cents
today. Wow.
So I mean, that's that's not a small amount of money that she is asking for. And even five dollars on get Christmas gifts, you know, that's... It it feels small to spread across three boys, but that's a lot of for them to have maybe saved or earned and then be willing to spend on on Uncle Donald. If fifty dollars was that much five dollars had to be worth almost fifty dollars. You know? I mean, Right. The the the inflation. But but we see donald in a good light, but I love those last two panels because Daisy is literally pushing him out the door and not not wanting to go along with them and the nephews usually later than the stories the He'll god the company Donald. To go see their uncle. But no, you're on your own buddy. Yeah. But I I love I love the gesture here. Yeah. These interactions are great.
So So the next sequence
has Donald approaching his uncle Scrooge.
And
and and we've got this great shot of Scrooge.
Everything is is getting established so quickly here in the beginning. He's literally shoveling money into his bin and he is pondering
about his problems.
Right? So we have all these problems
at the beginning. And they're all different degrees that we know that the kids... It's the kids of Shaft
who have the real problem. They're stuck in smaller and pom. Donald has a problem that ultimately is is not that big of a problem, but it feels very potent. Right because it cuts to his in security. For being able to provide a nice christmas. And Scrooge problem is that he can't fit his un
huge fortune
in its physical
space. He's trying to stuff it
in with all sorts of tools and implements into his vault into his massive money pit. He's annoyed to be interrupted by a knock at the door,
and he greet whoever it is with that old Scrooge standard
about to light his bower war canon. We saw that it pixelated parent. Every remember
at the door. Yeah that. I love the wealth of. It it is a classic Scrooge trope Sarah. I don't know if that's something that you're you associate with Scrooge, but but this is like,
This is a typical sp greeting. He got it as surplus after the Bo war. Oh, okay. No. I wasn't familiar with that, but they they do reuse it quite it gives a lot of mileage in this one. Yeah. And and as Donald,
as Donald opens the door, it's interest to me that both of them have these thoughts. Right? It's not an exchange Scrooge
screws is like just grumpy about almost wasting a shot. Donald realizes that he's particularly mean the today he's feeling or.
So he decides that his approach is gonna be to kinda strong Scrooge. She's... There's no point in, like, making up Polite Al request for fifty dollars. He grabs him
by the
broad cloth and tells him that he wants fifty dollars.
And Scrooge gives back, you know, he... He's not gonna be intimidated by someone asked came for money. And as Scrooge
continues to try to shove his fortune into its vault,
Donald explains what the ask is for and... He starts out by talking about the Turkeys,
you know, because that's the most reasonable thing. They wanna give the kids of shack town a ice Christmas.
That's what the first twenty five dollars is for. And then
Warren, what's the second twenty five dollars for and how how does he react? Well it's for the toy train for the kids. And Scrooge is not as
pleased with that because
as he says, great gus gold mines.
A useless toy trained. It he just goes off Donald and and can under stand why children would once that you useless lu toy. But he agrees to give them the twenty five dollars for the turkey. I mean, I actually question why they're buying one
two hundred fifty dollar train