We can have
Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer an artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comments of all time. Join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Welcome back to Barks remarks. I'm Mark Sever, a grown man who enjoys Donald Duck and Uncle Scrooge Comics.
And I'm very excited to finally finally
get to talk about the first legendary
appearance of uncle
in his own comic book in the legendary
story only a poor old man,
and I'm I'm also
excited and delighted to be joined by a return guest
who I I've had had a great time talking with him, and I'm gonna go ahead and let him introduce himself and mention who you are. Hi. Patrick Blocked.
Disney artist
over the last thirty years or so and various
comic stories for Gladstone
Gems and Big. And it's good to be Barks. Yeah. Thanks again, Patrick.
We got to talk
initially
about the trouble with Dimes.
Called times classic,
ten pager, and and, you know, that one really compliments this story
very well.
I thought so too. I thought it was... They're so different. You know it's that the dime story is so compact and pressed together and this story is much longer and kind of like the tell the car had time to like.
Develop the characters and do a lot of rambling along more more of than than the shortest history. So they are very complimentary.
Yeah. Definitely. They're they're complimentary in a lot of ways. They're both legendary stories.
I I gotta tell you. So when I started this podcast. Right,
I
I imagined myself
getting to talk about my favorite stories. I imagined myself getting to talk about milestone
stories like this one.
But and it was really important to me that the podcast have, like, a structure
and that I really explore the bark stories chronological
and that meant doing it the right way starting with Donald Inducks finds P gold and and
visiting some very nice, but but not maybe not as classic stories, you know, like frozen gold for example early on, which I hope I enjoyed. But it's it's just not in the same lead.
And
and eventually
getting to this one, but but I've had so much fun. And it's it's felt like such a nice build up. To get to to some of these legendary and interior ones
finally. They get much more legendary than this one.
No this is. This is the story
There's so much... And this packed into this story, there's so much well uncle discourage is about, like touches on almost all of is like nets and all the things that are important about Scrooge in this store won't way or another.
Yeah. Very well said this is like the essential Scrooge up. And when I went into preparing for this one, you know, there were a couple of things that I was really thinking carefully about. Right? Apart from apart from just the pressure of wanting to get it right.
But but I was thinking about that that moment
right when the editors
at Western publishing
must have approached Carl and and they must have asked him they they did. They asked him
specifically. This wasn't something that he submitted to them. They requested that he do a thirty two pager or
or the one shot series. And... Mh. And the four color one shots are really notable because they are like a a testing grounds for possible
spin off titles. And what a big deal that must have been? I imagine he was very excited, Carl at a time, and I would think that you he would feel like the accomplished something in fridge which is getting in walk. It was like, his own character that he actually created too... Was, like, the first time that carl being recognized is know, sort of having made that big step into, like, here's Scrooge I've created inventory getting
Yeah.
Exactly. That... That's what I was thinking right? Because that that's crucial that Uncle
Is holy his character. He's been... He's been working with Donald for years now at this point. Right? Hiring gold was back in was it? Was it forty three, I think. Yeah.
So he's been... He's been working with Donald. He's had screwed is this side character
in a number of stories
and then and and they must have been realizing that the stories that prominently feature sp had some really good sales. Yep. So yeah. And you can tell that that karl gonna Al out on this one. You know, He just threw her with Huey, head into it early insurance. Yeah. You you definitely can. You can tell that he wanted to get it right that he wanted to do something special.
And something really memorable.
And just boy did he succeed. He certainly did. It's this is the one book that I remember one story that I remember is kid exactly where I was at what I was doing when I read this tour because of the... Because if I remember specifically the client x story when the... And the damn this twelve termites verse, and you turn the page know that each page of the the damn I'm breaking. It was it was... I tried to remember, like, what issue when when we exactly what the been. I remember being a giant sized book, so almost has to been in nineteen sixty five, when I was seven years old. That was a giant type what that year came out with it. This story in it. I was at my grandmother's house. My parents were there so was probably on Sunday. Because we he dinner there every Sunday Sunday evening T was all the living room sitting on the couch. Breathing story. So it's like a very vivid... Not too many comments that I can say. But I remember where I was at, I was reading it. But this is like, you know, right up there with, like,
with I'm armstrong landing on the mood and getting yeah. Yeah. Just like I knew exactly where was at fit that day and in this particular instance, I remember exactly what I was doing over this which is something that's a great little remembrance. You know As you said that, I can probably figure out about where I was because this was in a collection for me the first time I read it. Mh. It was like a late seventies donald dot collection, and it was it was a four row the panels didn't match the the regular structure. You know, ten of the classic stories. And that was the only one the white hard Barks.
Yeah.
Yeah. I think of it is red carpet.
Yes. That's right. I lost the white white sleeve many years ago.
So I think of it as red covered. But... Yeah, that's the one. And and it has written inside Al My Angie. To to Mark for his eighth birthday, I believe. So... Oh, so we would about the same age. Yeah. Exactly. Was Severino it's definitely the one that, you know, stood out to me of those stories along with probably lost to the and. But yeah, it left
left this huge
impact and
you know, and my my other my other little personal connection to this one is that the the beautiful
reprint that I'm consulting right now from Uncle Scrooge Adventures
number thirty three. Actually, by half
was in the little letters column for that.
Great.
So I know that your work would have appeared probably just a few issues later. And and that makes practically
practically contemporary in that same common lot. Yes.
It's true. I guess there's a slight difference between being had a do teenager writing a letter to the editor asking a a random question about flint hard long gold and and actually having story running it pages. But... But I'll take it. So anyway,
I'm gonna dive in some of this background because we obviously have what cover here. We did big story. It is. So February of nineteen fifty two is the original
publication date, and it is in four color number three hundred and eighty six.
However, it is also
considered to be uncle Scrooge number one because officially, it's part of the four colors series. But I I guess that the convention must have been if they did choose to spin off the title that they started to give it, like, retroactive
number So I think that Scrooge gets
several
more more tries in the one shot series
with, like, back to the cl and a horse
story and and many hoo mystery. And I don't remember exactly where they started calling a numbering and uncle screws efficient. Couldn't tell you this one has been reprinted
so many times, Patrick.
I I saw fifteen
American ones including the original
for for obvious reasons. And and this is Al long one. It's a thirty two pager, which is why we do wanna hit the ground running but there's there's a lot of good background one of the things that is so fun bring you on this shows. I know that you got to talk to the man himself you got to meet me and even work with Carl Barks.
Did he ever mention anything
specific about this one? Did he Severino reference it that you're you remember? They particular particular story. Mh. I never asked him anything
specifically about the story. Right. No. I don't think that I actually talked to him about this particular story. Is know, it's like one of the stories that everybody knows a lot about it. Yeah. Like it's been covered so much. So I tended asking about all obscure things when I talked to it.
Right.
Exactly. It it would almost be a tell if you were asking him questions
about that that you're that you're maybe be not the world's biggest fan there's one thing I can tie into this story that that Carl... I didn't hear it from Carl but I knew about it. After it passed away It turned up that there was a... There was a screen play, like like something called
for a screen play based on Aqua Scrooge.
For Disney, was an animated film project that he had proposed to Disney. The day of said to go ahead and try and start developing and it was based on this story, basically, was basically a story Scrooge and about phone a lot of the plot. In this sorry. And this would have been, like
probably about nineteen sixty or that area somewhere. And at that time, the time that he developed it was at same exact time that Disney figured out that they can make a lot of money from move live action movies. So it got rejected because on the back to Mary Pop did so well, I think
I know that the... I I did on the... Whenever Carl passed away, and was an auction.
A lot of this material came up
through a collector that was buying but the bottom lot of the materials was auction on you ebay. And actually bit on the the screen play and it like drawings, all kinds of cool cool stuff and I was like one of the competitors. And I did and end up with them It's too bad because there been a wonderful thing to see publish, you know, because it was like, pretty extensive fluid the to to appeal in in print absolutely.
Maybe maybe it'll turn up one of these days as probably will inevitable probably
interesting to big that's definitely one of those what what could animated film. Yeah. You you might guess that there'd be a a decent number of quotes about this one. Right? Because this is one that he's so famous for and it comes up frequently. I won't share every quote that I've compiled but a couple of really interesting ones. You know, there was there was an interview where he talked about the process behind the Genesis behind the story and he said that they wrote a letter from the office. Asked if I would do a thirty two page screws comic book and I thought what little I had used screws up to that time. He didn't have any foundation Nobody knew where he came from? Although he had been Donald Uncle all these years. But what was his background? So I thought well I'll just work in a little bit about where he came from how he accumulated his well and how he's out to protect. I had already invented the beagle boys. At that time. And so I just turned loose on everything I could think of. That would help develop screws character. They really covered a lot of ground. You know, well you know this so much of about him leading claude make fortune but this story, he touches on all kinds of stuff the ways that he made money he made money on the sea, Huey, made money as a minor. He made money cat working cattle cattle wars and on the old Frontier and columbia. So it's like his fortune to very. Obviously, he really got around louisiana young. And he a young Inducks
Yeah. And everything that he mentions, you know, in that quote and and in that those little nuggets,
upon unintended of information that he drops through the story. It's all stuff that fires the imagination so much. Mh. And it's what is gonna make the screw story so exciting to the the reading And there's so much in here that he pulls later on in stories. You know, like, like the number one dime is mentioned here, but there is a reference to. Number one dollar is number one first fifty cent piece, like in order wall and space.
Already my.
The idea there'd being his dispersed dollars first half lower and that least was first time exact. There's so much foundation in this story and it's I'm so good and, you know, other creators are gonna mine
so much from this later. Like, like Don Rose and his life and times.
I mean, half of that seems like it's built from
off offhand references.
In this one. And and of course this was the foundation Scrooge.
Yeah. And and and it also strikes me how all of those ways that he made his money. You know, they're like so American, and they're so, like typical of kind of the American
immigrant story almost, you know,
arriving in a cattle boat and and
striking out for a gold rush and and it it is the story of America and is to think about it. Carl lived at that period of time it just after, you know, he was in the west and they just settled the west So he was right there at the end of, like, Al that exciting truth on. He was a kid that was Al still you know happening. But yeah. Pretty interesting. That's an important point because to me this this feels like such a West coast
store, you know, a Western United States or worry and I I think that's part of why like, as a as a kid growing up in California Bay area. That's also part of why Identified not that you have to be from from there to to get it, but I just... I saw so much of that around me. Yeah. The thing about carl stories is oh if you took all these stories, all Al of them together. They're really everywhere. They're like, nowhere and everywhere at the same time, and they can... I think that's one of the reasons is so popular over over the world like you go to Europe scan the may and everyone blows the stories because everything in the store could take place anywhere. You know what one one story will be snowing like four feet of snow. And the next story the same town. It's Al tropical palm trees. Right. It's like amazing. Know, and and Donald backyard, one and one
episode, it'll be like a big lake behind this house. Is the next one maybe be could cliff you could follow off of the next one will be like pine trees everywhere. And it's like it's like in each story, Bark just putting there whatever you felt did change. But at the same time, it feels like it all makes sense. And it's like an impossible sort of juggling thing the coral of Al this work, which is always amazing to me. The fact that he could keep it keep it so
in my creative and yet grounded somehow with the characters. And was this like, you know, very strange because most common were still do that. Yeah. Definitely. He had this sort of a about that. The other quote that I'll mentioned before we launch in is just one that he was quoted in an interview in the seventies,
guy named Malcolm Will. He asked Barks if the office had asked him to make Scrooge more lovable for this. For his. That's Al question. It is it's a great question. And he responded, he said no, I tried to do that myself. I kind of
anticipated it. They would tell me that. So you can tell in this story. I think it stands out that he is really trying to soften these edges, like he's definitely trying to keep what's made him interesting. And what's made him entertaining, but he also really wants to go out of his way to make him relatable. And he does such an amazing job of that that it's gonna help you very carry a comment but for decades. Mh. And and Scrooge
an amazing characters. Is it's like one carl created, the character metabolism was, like, much more friendly
situation this today, you know. Yeah. It's like million errors were looked upon in, like, more positive light than they are today. And things were were probably millionaires born as far away from public as they are today as far as, like, the difference in money between someone who is middle class and someone the Super rich. And somehow,
you managed to make Scrooge like, relatable and funny and and, yet, still super rich and and get away with it. Know if somehow was like oh know. It was like a friendly uncle, you know? Yeah.
You're right, it's a great trick making. If trick making a millionaire
so lovable and so relatable. And you're right about the difference in attitudes, but I also...
I think there were definitely times in the past where, you know, we've we've gone up and down with our attitude, that's like the Robert Barron, of the
beginning of the twentieth century weren't that far away. So No. With regardless, it's an amazing trick Huey, played. Yeah I'm gonna note that At this time, we have had twelve adventure length stories
that have featured Scrooge Inducks in some capacity and I'm including dangerous
disguise where he is only referenced in a text. Was this he.
Yeah. And by my account, and I don't know the ten pages quite as well, but but my rough count was that there have been eight ten pages
beforehand I. That featured him in some in some respect. And and that like, ranged
so wildly patrick. Right? Because we've had these, like, outright villainous
characterization,
like in Voodoo Hut
and
disposable appearance of Bail. He was pretty being. Right. He was at least antagonist.
And then we've had these more like comedic or or relatable ones like as early as the old ta secret
and letter to Santa,
you know, we've had these more family oriented ones like Christmas for Shack
and
pixelated parents.
So so it's just it's ranged so widely. And now he's gonna really hone in on what makes the character to work and he's never gonna straight too far from this. You know, screws is gonna be a little crust year if he needs him to be in some later stories. A little bit softer.
One thing I like and this one is how and Al. He is. And we're gonna get very very much very much. I'm gonna run very briefly through a couple of the titles from around the world. Because I like doing that. Sure. I found an interest in Patrick that in scanned.
These all seem to have
kind of a variation
on on the title, the cunning uncle sp where the quirky uncle bridge. Yeah. That that first one was in Denmark Finland and Norway. And then the quirky ample Scrooge in Sweden. And in Finland, that's Eve villa
Sat
in Denmark that's Dan sn on
in Norway. It was Dan
Scrooge.
And then for the most part, In other countries, they really did give it a pretty direct
translation. Which I I was glad to see because this title itself feel so icon to me and it's it's it's so poetic. That that little contradiction. Yep. So you've got, like in in French juice on
pullover, which is actually just a plural poor
and And then the the only one that varied that I noticed was in Italy. It was Papa,
d Do, uncle Sp, and the challenge of the dollars.
So any thoughts
before we actually dive into to the to the story itself, Patrick. Well, the story... It's a story where Carl has a lot of room, you know, the plot is fairly simple, but he like sort has time with the characters. He sort of develops characters more than he probably doesn't any other story. And I think that maybe that's one of the reasons I so loved it's because it's so much detail about Scrooge and so much there's so much going on it's like one character the other just, you know, you kinda of ones most about the characters with with them speaking in this store. So it's a loose story. It's a story where he had a lot of work and he he used it, you know, rather than have a lot of plot. He did a lot of talking with the characters. My thoughts on it. So the last the last story we did was very tau, you know, we didn't have much space and was like, very precise and most like you said, they're complimentary stories. Yeah. I think that's a good point. Right? This one seems like it has a lot of room to breathe.
And it's it's very much this, like journey. Right? It takes place over a span of time, really, really interesting
characterization about Scrooge and Donald,
even the beetle boys vehicle certain.
To express themselves in this one. And this is a real quantum leap for the beagle boys. Right? Because this is their first, like appearance as full fledged characters.
We even get the cedar folder. Yeah. That's right. Alright, Patrick. I I'm so excited for this. As as always, I'm gonna characterize the action on these stories and and we'll accelerate a little bit here and there because it's thirty two pager, but I sure you to give me some great insights.
At
as we
as we pause, man, you know, right off the bat on on page one, hughes this really cool device,
where he... He starts this out as like a conversation between him as the narrator and the leader, and it such a great way to draw in and engage us because he Barks us. He he says if you had a fortune of u centric julian dollars, what would you do with it, and we we just hit the ground running because he tells us and he shows us that uncle Scrooge
who has that much money chooses to do this. And we launch into that legendary
bit tell us Patrick, what it is that Scrooge does with his money. Well, he likes to dive around the, like a purpose see him doing it exactly that spring out of the money and heading back into it. And he also likes to borrow through, like, a go. And he likes to toss it up and let it get him on the head we seem doing that. Because nephew donald doc thinks the old boy is slightly money struck. You see Scrooge in the background glen. Blah blah blah. And I toss it up and let it hit me on the head. It's like, this most classic surge thing ever. And and that comes back to that over and over again in course of Scrooge.
You never forget it. And it's you see it from time to time. I'm doing. It's quite wonderful. It is wonderful. And it's so iconic. And and it's such a great thing to play towards kids. Right? Because money is so abstract for kids. What would you do with a lot of it? Well, you would buy a lot of fun things or you might play with it, I guess. Yeah. I guess it's a real kid thing to do. You know? It's like maybe if you were a kid, and you really didn't know too much about money something you would do with. And so as Scrooge
references that he's just invited donald over And the reason that he's invited his nephew over and what we're gonna see over the course of the next couple of pages is because he wants to install the Virtue.
Of having
this kind of fortune
and the joys and pleasures that it brings him. And this is such a great sequence Patrick because there are these two actions that are happening at the same time. Right? He is telling Donald about this. And he's being constantly
undermined
by essentially
the the things that can go wrong. With having this kind of fortune and the things that bring him stress. And so... Yeah. He keeps saying how wonderful is but the same time he's under all stressed we haven't name first Right. And he keeps getting interrupted first by a moth, which he he shoots out of the air with an old blender bus, and then by a rat, which distract him as it, you know, gets caught in the trap, and he's he's talking about how the moth could chew up a ton of his money in the rat could have done the same. He gets interrupted by having to spray a spider that might trip his burglar alarm. All problems we wish we had. Right. Right. Exactly. Before we leave this first page, look at how beautiful this page is laying out. Yeah the obviously, the first panel is wonderful with that circle. Simple circle title Away. Mh. And Scrooge and the money bend. The big seems wonderful. It looks the bottom the too black, the placement of the Barks in the bottom of the page. You only that page it'll be beautiful in the wall because this alex. It's just a wonderful draw page, one of its best opening pages, I think. And basically
the design is fairly simple, but it has a lot of detail, but it's like a very simple straightforward beautifully placed black and little. Yeah. Definitely. I I'm so glad to have you on to be able to talk about I love
the home. You know, if I could pick a page. Just would be tender for sure It's the two one, yeah. And thank you for talking about your ex expertise. And you're right. And listeners we are... We are a podcast. We're an auditory medium, and we're gonna commit the cardinal sin of just telling you about how beautiful this is be because it really is. And and if you love Carl Barks, you you know this story backwards and floor. They'll be following along with us with their for sure. I just love this accelerating action over these first three pages, you know, as he's talking to Donald and and having this be
undermined and eventually
And so as sc is really getting to his point in trying to hammer Al home, he's distracted by the sound of construct
going on on the vacant lot next door, and he's instantly
upset about this because he tells Donald this could be a blind for the biggest robbery in history. He points out that, you know, someone builds a building right up against his wall they could they the punch holes and and drain out his money. And we got a little call out to the title of the story as he starts to stop and say,
Oh wow is me? I'll be a poor old man. His expression there is priceless. Just some some great great express art in this. Yeah.
And so Donald Donald goes down because he wasn't.
Now he doesn't. He's gonna reassure his uncle through, but as soon as he gets to that construction, he knows, that Scrooge is right to worry because he sees the beagle boys busy at work building a a deep seller for their building. It's pretty well got them down now the bigger boys. He knows what they should look like, and bunch their numbers and they're different from each other and they're, you know, they're full fledged beagle just Yeah. Exactly. We've got got. Oh, It's thought the Bagels had, like a very nineteen fifth forties fifties kind feel about we don't see people dressed like this anymore. You'll don't see people wear these like sweatshirt like this. They're like you know, they're like, out of prison and how much money they're like, you know, always broke. They're to miss cigarettes.
Right. And and I talked some in the beginning how bark is like
his version of Scrooge as someone who made his well like on his own, and this is like the opposite. Right? Because the B boys are this name was face list. To me they're almost stand in for, like, Bureaucracy. Right? Because B Boys
Incorporated. And I think that's one of Barks this bias is.
Yeah. And so when Donald returns to the office.
He does alarm him by telling him it's the big boys. And and Scrooge just like at his breaking point the terrible big boys terrible beagle boys. Yeah. And when he goes
to to threaten the beagle boys with his blonde bus, you know, they're able to... One of them sees him coming and uses his construction equipment to clamp on his
shot by telling him basically
signaling that they are ahead of him. Right? They've they've got him they've got a great scheme going.
Like and then and this one panel here after it gets this done messed up. Oh, how much trouble can I make and half? Most of us have followed Barks as footsteps called and dot like. They refer them to themselves Ducktales. But Karl had this way calling him men, you,
He was a man who wasn't just Inducks. The world's witch as well that's right calling. And it's like Al really interesting thing then if you think about it, like... Not many not many artist writers call to do that. They've mostly called them Inducks. The karl thought them as people. We really just went ahead with that. Whole concept Absolutely. And we the readers were happy to go along with him. And so this really does trigger this spiral in him. Right? Because he's got this terrible
scheme going on next door, and there's a moth back, and he can't even shoot at it. And and he's just rand tick. To this.
Yeah. And man, it's such a great panel and it's so It's... It it's really effect to me because Donald has this conversation. After Scrooge has clearly
collapsed, out of, like exhaustion and stress and and his conversation basically goes like this. Come come over and help me take care of uncle Scrooge. He's caves in, and he asked them to bring the old Tight lot a sandwich because he probably hasn't had time to eat for a week. And there's such a great dynamic between Donald and Sp in this one Patrick. Right? Because because they're both basically, there's this argument in the background.
The whole story over who who's right. Mh. Right? Because Scrooge has his philosophy,
and and he thinks that what he's doing is the right way and is gonna bring him satisfaction.
Donald clearly doesn't think so. It's interesting to me to think about you know, which of those men is right. Yeah.
This, of course, leads us into the Scrooge telling you about his past because he's recovering, Yeah. And and he recovers...
He... He's recovering and the money then. Right? It that's Al shot.
Inside of the money ben. Yeah. And every shot and the band is just so so wonderfully drawn. And I just love I love seeing Kiwi doing Louie enter at this point, and they're sitting in his feet while he is kinda calm blessing, and it's it's that great opportunity for them to be the avatar for us, the reader and here uncle go Tell the story of how he made his money. And this must have just fired the imagination of the kids who were who were reading it. Oh, true.
And and Patrick, I'm gonna ask you to
summarize some of the ways that he tells them that that he made his money and can tell us about, you know, he... This is where he's gonna give us his philosophy as well. Sure. Well, the kids asked you if Huey, made his money the banking business. And he says banking sn, made it on the c's and in the minds and then the cattle Barks world Frontier. It's just I made that famous line and they had been by being tougher than the toppings, smarter than the parties and I made it square. And that expression face is extremely memorable. It's kind of, like firmly through these Gladstone. It looks very really knows what he's talking about. It I'm sorry I didn't interrupt you those. Those two those two speech balloons, they're almost poetry, you know, how he sums it out. And that.
He could really cut to the quick with with writing. You know. You had just how to do it. It was they would keep it simple, but the same point you would say in the way that no one else could say wonderful. Tell us about some of the great flashback panels where he talks where we we get these little tastes of of his in his empire building. Yep. Yep. We have we have this panel, first of all, we I froze my fingers to the bone, digging nuggets some of the creek. And I brought a fortune
instead of spending it in the home Barks. And this, of course is going to lead in the next day issue and into a much bigger bigger story about is time and the. We see Dawson gambling place. He's got a big bag of gold. He's not going into the casinos or anything like that. He's going to... They'll put in the bank. Huey, got pissed and it's looks very serious. Get it himself. So I kinda. And we've got you know, we've got little references to his copper days.
We've got
a russian calories in one more. Yeah. Al all of these great American
experiences where where people struck either did or didn't strike it rich, mh by their own hard work. Right. That's the contrast that he's set up. That's why he's sc said. Did he make his money banking? Right and he sums it up by saying, you know, you'd love your money to boys. If you got it the way I did by thinking a little harder than the other guy by jumping a little quicker and he's clearly feeling better. You know, he's refreshed because he's just recounted
how he made this money. So now now it's really
Al the Barks stories going forward are not about how he made his money. They're gonna be about how he kept his money. Yep. And so he is
set to take on the beagle boys. She's prepared but a great perspective shot of him standing tall And so Scrooge realizes is that he's gonna have to move his money. You know, I kinda gloss over the fact that we're not on Kill Motor Hill for this story for the purpose of this one. He needs to kinda be in that old Inducks office building with this vacant a lot. And and so he's gotta get his money away. From this situation. And he's clearly come up with a really great plan and he starts to recruit all of the ducks to do their part Oh, and he references that he's gonna fool the beagle boys the way he fooled the b of Mongolia
years ago. So
He's just tossing these little bread crumbs about about this incredible globe t but history standing adventure that Feel like my old self. Like the screws that gum up the James boys now dolphins.
Yes. Such a great taste around. Yeah yeah. And so the the nephews
track down that the b boys are dumping their dirt for their foundation in an older reservoir
and sc makes plans to buy that up. And at night, they Scrooge Donald take some time
chi it been and constructing a certain mechanism. And we're gonna learn on the next page what that mechanism is. And
how movies Scrooge too. It takes a lot of nerve to do what he's gonna do. It really does. It's such a great scheme what he does here. It it falls apart under a little bit of Scrutiny. But in the logic of the comment books, this works perfectly, I think, patrick. So tell us what what that scheme is. We build a shoot into the side of the money bed. He notices that the trucks the bigger boys are driving
stop before they come and get dirt put into them. And it puts the shoot right where the truck is. So that the shoot opens up and dumps a bunch of his money into the back of the truck and then they big boys is not seeing it. Is stump dirt on top of it, Take the dirt to the reservoir and dump so they're moving Scrooge money for him. I without know Absolutely. Pretty funny. It is. It's great, and and we accept it as readers because it's so poetic, and it's so perfect. You know. Yes they're. He's recruited the beagle boys to help him
save his damn money from How many times down the road will do something similar again. Like, the perhaps with the gold the gold corn in another story, and was like, a bunch of this is leads to, like, almost like a almost like a history of in various places hide it from in all these different sorts of places. So it's like a theme theme that continues on work through the run local Scrooge. Yeah. And and so we transitioned for a little while to the beagle boys perspective, which is perfect. You know, we see a funny reference to them boggling Al how long it's taking them to empty that little Severino pool of dirt. Dump it into the reservoir.
And then we see their a great moment where they're gonna
anticipate busting into the Bin and and and we get to see them get sku, you know, they they open it up and it's totally
back down the road in the future too. We get to say that again. Like, various ways that they're foil that get covered with, like, syrup and different things that. Again feature stories. That's right. Huey, been worse time. Yeah right happens to. And he's gonna have to raise the steaks. Like you said by coding them with castor oil or whatever.
Castor oil boys. Right.
Right. And so we transition now to the reservoir
which is where we're gonna spend
pretty much the rest of the story, which is which is interesting. And it's a cool setting. And I didn't know
until doing the some background research for this that Barks actually model this reservoir before and the damn
after
one that was built by a millionaire, a finance...
Yeah. It was a guy named William W, who founded the tell of I don't know if it's hem met or hem.
Right near hit Barks on San Ja sent where he lived. And so that... That's what he had in mind apparently. But anyway, the the docks... There's there's this great sort of building action where the Inducks were gonna
set up some defenses. You know, they've hook up some boo traps. And some land
around the... Around the lake, which is it works in cartoon logic. It's horrible if you think about it too hard. This Well, helps give them a way too. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. People this. And so Scrooge, you know, he initially is feeling pretty good about a sip situation. He's most money.
One little flies
his playing. Yeah.
There's definitely a few here, but So he goes to dr to screen some of his money out of the mud, and he had admire it for a little while. But then then he
syncs back into this turmoil of stress again
worrying about his money because he's like, well what what can I do with it now? Right, if I spread it on the banks, people are gonna see it. But I need to let it dry. I can't let the green box stay down there too long or they'll rot. And so we get this neat little solution where he again thinks back to his time as someone building is for... What what does he land at Patrick?
Yeah. The numbers that the Spanish put the their papers and things on ships like in bottles and when they got wet would stay dry. So it puts his green back and jars. To sync in into the reservoir. Right. And and this is something that he recollect from his time as a treasure hunter. Yeah. And we spoke Spanish
right. And we haven't gotten a lot of treasure hunting in the previous
po, you know, but that's gonna really accelerate going forward. And and so we transition, we do a little time jump to all of this activity, all of his money being safely sunk under the arrest.
And and again, he's initially satisfied,
but he size to his his nephews that there is something left
and he tells them that of course, he misses his daily money swim.
And and this ends up being that like, fatal.
Right? Yep Yep yeah bigger boys are sad not to give out they can't can't figure out what the heck happened to the money this disappeared far as agency can see. So one of them decides to go fishing is that things would have a justice and discourage is swimming it Al my dr up a power. So that's bad news.
Exactly.
So, yeah, he hasn't been able to resist it. And so he's slave to his his need to swim around
in the money. I love the little, like,
scene with the beagle boys. They're sad. Yeah. There's all mop around. And that b boy who who heads out to go fishing. For some reason reason I imagine that he's the same one that Loves p. Yes. That's think the same thing yeah. But but he his great expression when he sees that little amount of money that Scrooge has has dried up to swim on. I love it. Yeah. And he runs down the tree club. And so
while the b boy goes, presumably to tell his brothers about their great new opportunity.
Scrooge is again back to feeling feeling calm, and
he
he decides that, you know, the money is safe at this point, he can go ahead and settle up with his nephews. I think I mentioned I forgot to mention rather that he had put them on his payroll Al his...
One of his typical
me rates can't I don't think it was thirty cents. Was it... Do you remember how much number in this one? It must have been Al long time because he owes Al eighty bucks now. Yeah. The tax itself
Yeah. Eighty dollars and and screws just freaks out. Right? This is gonna be one of those common themes where Scrooge
is is too me to pay his nephews,
the the wages they deserve.
And he comes up with a funny little scheme here Patrick. You us tell us about his his scheme to delay the inevitable. Yes. He gives them little purses on hands of fishing rods and tells them they can keep whatever they hook on there on their lines. It doesn't tell them that they're penny and the the reservoir where the pennies are kept. Interestingly, this is a is Al these little fishing pause with persons? That was the subject of get to see that like on the cover and didn't have works as paintings. Particular scene of fishing for money. Yeah. Exactly. Yeah. This is gonna be part of that.
We and we didn't really mention that the how incredibly icon that the cover
the origin donald. No it's it's so very very best. As the Ducktales fishing for their wages, we hear from the tree line a chorus of beetle boys asking Can we go fishing two? And again, Uncle Scrooge Barks out in terra that the beagle boys have have tracked him down. I thought it was a little odd that, you know, the way they announced themselves, from a distance and how he can hear them. But
you know, it... It's it's necessary I guess, for the rhythm of the story. Yeah. I think it's kinda cool. And so Patrick, we're we're entering sort of the the new... A distinctly new part of the store. The bad.
Yeah. It is. It is a battle. It's gonna be this great rant
stress full and very exciting
sort of sort of war that's gonna happen in these phases. As screwed you know, immediately says, hold on nephews. I can't let you go now. Obviously, the beagle are gonna come after me a couple of the boys ironically Severino a little bit from the song once more around on the Merry go around. And they start to figure out, you know, there's this this kind of introductory seen where
the battle kinda takes shape.
The the boys
bring Scrooge the paper, which gives him the news that the beagle boys have bought all the lands down the Creek from him. Hard away we like Scrooge in this is that we... He's he's very sharp he knows what this means, they're gonna try to break his damn. And when you get this... You wanna tell us about that lovely panel that is establish is the
long panel at to bottom the page showing the damn,
upstream And then down below, we see the below them a little stream that goes. Blocked off in of lush bottom land. It now belongs to the bigger boys. So we know it nicely sets the same way. What's to come? It really does. Part of why this battle. I think we're up so well is because we have a really good idea of the little, like, majority geography.
Yeah. And and what Barks does here
in this next sequence
is something that he does and a lot of his best stories is he kinda gives you this outline. Right? Because he he says in a narrator box, what their first attack is gonna be. Mh And and he's gonna... He's gonna essentially label each one. Yes. Time, which gives it this really nice structure that I think is very comforting for the readers. You wanna tell us about that first
attack patrick. Each of the attacks... Like a acute kind of thing. It's it's unlikely thing to happen. And the big send
sort of a piece of glass up round glass with attached bite with two blooms and the sun basically goes through the glass and starts burning the whole
the damn. And we've got a great...
I imagine it's another of his bo war can't era surplus gan. He has Donald fire can through the lens to end that
Yeah. And on the next page, you know, we see the second scheme And this one's a little bit more bid.
One of the nephews was was fishing, and he caught a fish that was attempting to jump through the s, the water gate. And as Scrooge is chi him for fishing. He points out that this fish is a little different. This fish kit just looks like a car yeah. But my stores is the bigger boys uploaded them with a ball
that's right. Throw it just in time, and save the fish. Yeah. Narrowly saving the fish.
And this happens almost simultaneous.
With another
scheme
where they're sending trained cor
to dive down and steel bits of money Scrooge thinks they'll never get rich that way. There's a dirty year scheme a foot. Right. And this is so funny because
the the escalating big this
is is that some of them are carrying nap palm moms. Yeah.
And what is bridge do there respond. Naturally,
he... I know
language. I trained thousands of them when I was in the pro trade in Asia City. Says tweak, Jab black, well, call. He hasn't turned around and go back to it. It goes I've dropped them on them. There's Al these gag based on my jobs that he's had, like, ways where it places travel to things he nose, he so why his years of doing very nice.
Right. It's it's his Ex experience.
Yes. It's good. So
for him. And and we got a great little site of the Beagle
quote, rubbing their burnt spot
and and one of the b boys ounces they need to get going to plan for. So before, we can track these And again, Scrooge sharp is attached soon as he sees some gathering
clouds, he
instruct his nephews what to do and he He has them run Al lightning that place Al lightning rod and run a cable towards the beagle. And and as the beagle see the clouds and cause lightning to strike. He's able to divert the light.
So that it
eagles yeah.
That Barks he's out smart Severino turn, you say. Yeah. And then
this is a great part of the story. This is the part I remember when I was seven years old, for sure Yeah sort this point. Tell tell us about this this great sequence then is So they've perfect plan five, their secret rep the go little flag and there was a laboratory sing perfect in the lab. These are the new super species I developed. They look like beetles. Yes. They look like beetles but hot once we get them old, screws hands as damaged as doomed,
not really beetles at all. The beetles that look like termites are act termites that's right. Yeah And I like it when we get these...
I like these occasional smart vehicle boys. Mh. It's... Like a two and they whenever they have, like, clever plans that actually could work Right. And so they they managed to suck Scrooge. By planting a story in the paper all about the dangers that
exposed to wooden dams Any he falls for hook line and sink,
this. And as Donald walks off, you know, this this is one of those goofy
cartoon logic bits that it really works within the structure of the story. But we've got Al couple of beagle boys running essentially a stand in disguise.
Selling a great new bug that destroys
termites Well, this handy has done. Sure is. Yeah.
And so huge. It's Al huge bottle. Water of the the termites and is is like a huge like five court old fashioned like caring jar Al these packed fold these beetles. Because they buy the whole bunch. And so, you know, once he gets back, with that bottle. The the predictable thing happens. You know, they see them boring into the Timbers. I remember laughing like really enjoying the day Scrooge is looking closely at the bugs. Because it really word and he says, hey, very would. Are they supposed to do that and starting worried and think great fight again. And and the beatles have
acted like the beagle do. Right? They're they're sm about outs smart him because they've planned to the denote at the bottom. That's that laps that
makes fun of him for falling for it. He he gets off a great little. I've been sq I I think people need to use the words sw more. A great word. Almost never hear it without horn. Right? I've been horn sw. And and this is, you know, contrary to the earlier part of the story where it it takes place it's seems like over a couple of weeks. This is over the course of a day now this Al. It's like live time kind of
for the most.
And it goes into the night. Right? And and I think that adds to some of the ones... Should it to attention one. Yeah. Yeah. It's like it's like really build. You know, that the the big when they're they so evil the last couple pages and they're like really really bad. The vehicles And that might seem when they're bull dosing and spreading basins all through the slavs
below in their on their land and and and Scrooge and donald and the kids are trying to save somehow saved the damn, but it's like obviously hopeless you know, the timbers are like sips. Yeah. Spraying bug juice in there and it's a spring doll and the face because it's coming out the whole terrible situation. This was reasonable. It it is memorable because it is obviously
hopeless. Right? Yeah. And these two camps, these rival camps are are preparing for the inevitable basic this. Is one of my very favorite panels from the story is when screws, like, it's cutting logs and he's gonna try to replace the new with new braces and faster than the termite termites cut the old ones. They holds a brace up to the damn and they they're the bugs are eating it so fast but they just... No the end of this all going right there in nope. I guess it's only wish link Al. Yeah And termites are increasing the have families every four minutes. So it's like bad. Right. It feels so frantic And and it's It makes it understandable
why Scrooge essentially
gives up when the inevitable is about to have... This out He is. He's worn out he's lost and the page where the damn actually bursts. It's one that you really have to kinda stop and save because it's so It's so dramatic, and it's such a great payoff.
We know it's gonna happen. We know the dan's gonna break the Ducktales are forced to, like, flee for their lives. They
the.
And just before breaks, then there's like, a quiet moment is the big standard there and they're like, like, distant thunder isn't the for fire on the fourth of July, You're watching the damn the half them mile away watching from down below. And, yeah, this this particular panel that last panels the panel really stun me Al a kid I did. I stopped and red it. And I went and ate you got something. And left the book, and then I came back again. Started panel when They came back. I remember specifically that
It's almost like so much. And I remember, I remember the story really well as if, like, this seems so real.
The damn breaking up to panel. And if Ducktales, like, so simple and there's, like, snow obviously.
Somehow call hours great skills with being able to bridge that simple ducks the way they look, but we're using, like, more adult language and like know, like, more involved lots and being able to get away with the panel like this it's super a super complex realistic panel. And I remember I was reading like, god. That time was reading batman store or super superman stories that way boring stories from Dc, and I remember thinking, like, wow, this somehow, the duct Barks are more more feel more real than the Super superman stores yet the Superman stores are about like people that look like. And it was like one of the things about. But really I felt made the duct stuff so much more agreeable to me. Panels like this just like, bridge the gap between being a fan thing with dogs and being like super real. How can you pull that off? The bridge those two worlds? Pretty cool. Absolutely.
Very well said. This this scene is just so spectacular. Right? It is
as the... And that panel is is gorgeous. There's no characters in it do let think about how how long it took him to draw all those coins and all that missing water. The water is wonderfully doing. Wait it shoots off the the big. Braces that are left that are near you, like program, which just wonderful
wonderful sense of motion. And and great motion as we transition to the
the flood
spreading the beagle land.
Yep When dollars though and when the money settles. The beagle are making this reference to the flood
enriching their soil. And and that's gonna be really key. Right? Because it's it's a little
explanation that that Barks is gonna give for why this this worked.
Donald points out, you know, what's the problem we've still got laws.
And Scrooge reveals that, you know, according to the laws of floods and debris. That money now belongs to the b boys. They just have to go to court and claim the money as si.
Deposited on their land
by the flood
and I love that Because like good explanation. It's a great x place. And it's it's ridiculous. And yet, it seems so logical. But way finding a ship on the ocean that no Oh, dude took washed away and sure now. Right. And he's gonna use other
goofy he laws like this. He's gonna... He's gonna do such a great job in the future of justifying Mh. His plot. You know? And It just a couple of issues with the Golden helmet.
He's gonna create that that very realistic
interpretation of the charger.
Yep. Yep. Sure. And so screws is is sitting around
displaying the loss of is fortune while the b boys are are gl and celebrating, And we've got this really great
extended
kind of pacing
where he's just verbal
his frustrations.
He's just he... He's he's criticizing himself as an old man,
a plural man that just remembers the old tricks and we get this utterly master
panel where he transitions into a remembrance
of a of a time and bag dad and he trails off And suddenly, you sense a little bit of energy in his step.
And he tells the Ducktales we're gonna go down and congratulate
my new rich neighbors.
Mh. And I I love that that realization. You as the reader can see that little spark. Of something that he's thought of and and the nephews sensing it to where one of them kinda sort
Says, he's up to something. Yep pale they were so simple, you know, just this whenever screws say, yes, I remember the old tricks like the timing bag down. There's nothing but screws ten. And compare that to the, maybe back up of page, and look at the look at the damn breaking page. And that's in the same comic bookstore story. It's hard to believe that the two panels are so close together. And yet
and the reason that it works is because Scrooge is taken so seriously in my key his thought process and what he has to say is like, you know, it's like a real person saying. It's not like it's a call character. So you can get away with it somehow. You know? And it's a really tricky thing. To do that in order to me that much bigger of a change in the drawing from really simple style it's kinda to a really realistic town get little like. Just just amazing that he could pull. Definitely.
I'm I'm dwelling on these panels here for a long time because they're so affecting to me. There's so more in info so Al at.
About him be able to, like take time in this story because here he's doing. Like, take Al like character building kinds stuff. And start building for the future, not just for this story. It's like you can just feel that karl building this character for a future stuff. Yeah. Yeah. Absolutely.
And and every one of his expressions does such a great job. Yeah. Anyway, So for the big. Yeah. Right. So they do have
foul all that claim on the money? Yeah. But way. Here comes Al Scrooge. Just size mine. They won't rub it in. Yeah. Yeah. Boys, I have came to offer my best regard you y'all smart with me. And didn't fair. The main add us. Certainly not. I admire brains You boys have gone them. And
was set up. He's got something going on here. Right. It brain too in the old days but now I've got Al like soft tomatoes. The but you thinking he's saying that. Right. Right. This is a nice little
lead up.
And it's important that he says that. Right? It's important to set us up for the payoff and and this is all Scrooge
low the b boys, sweet talking them into granting him one little favor. He's so sad in the next bill. Could you find it in your heart's to?
Poor man one little favor in the his face. He said listen looking tears or poop off his big. Well, maybe. Just that I'd like to have one last swimming this money before you haul way You swim on that stuff, they don't even know about that. Every day for years, it's the only pleasure I ever had. Well, if that ain't anyone for the book... Go right ahead. Say he dives in he zips right into the money and they're, like, if I didn't see it, I wouldn't believe it. Watch shall I dive around it like a corpus? We're back to page one with this his diving thing. And see how I burrow through it like a girlfriend for and let toss it up about hit me on the head. Say, that looks like it be fun says to the vehicle.
Got of now. He's gonna... I love how I love how Scrooge lures the eagles in. I love how I love their reaction too to watching him and just initially
boggling at him and what he's able to do. And it's... He does such a great job of reeling them in
he tells them. It is. It's your money now. Why don't you dive into it and learn how to enjoy it? Your always got something there. Last one onions and honest man. We dive at the same time, smack their heads on the card money with a cracks sound. Look at Storage face on the next panel. How far the bigger boys bounce like his solid woman. Fuel of those heads like soft tomatoes back to the soft tomato thing. They'll be unconscious for weeks months and the think could happen before they could get their court and claim my money. Test disc so the kids ask him uncle Scrooge. How come you diagnosed all the way down and get get hurt? We never do figure. I'm Severino are told like, through the whole course of one of the things you never find out is how switch can do that. And says, well, I admit it's a trick. What kind of trick it possibly be So I wanna know
Right. What what do you think? Are you okay with that little bit a hand waving patrick. Yeah. I think that it doesn't matter at all. There isn't any answer. But, I think it's good that he didn't try to come up before. I
Know what the story is
whenever you're creating something Like guess you always wanna leave some things unanswered, that makes you think about it yourself that there must be more to to me know. You know, J talking with the lord the rings a lot of the background stuff was never told. He never learned about things. But yet, you felt like goodness was real and was more behind the world and than new this is the same kind of a deal. Right. Screws doesn't some trick. We don't know. I I think there's a little bit of danger in and going in and explaining too much. Right? Yeah. Sure. Because, like, some of the super superhero pre cool movies when they when they go in and they they
focus on some of these details, it it takes away a little bit of the mystery. And and you're not, like, I love Roses life and Time story. Like I really do. But Every now and then I'm like, oh maybe we didn't need every little detail.
Explained in this. Now, this is one thing we never find of
And please know never. He he talked a little bit about this. He said
he said that I don't it's explain how he does it because I don't understand it myself.
Perhaps husband. I never realized he said that.
I found this quote just today. Yeah. Perfect perhaps he said it has something to do with this character often he can do things which other people can't. He can go out in the desert and smell the presence of gold. So, you know, why why explain it? He can't.
It it's just Al ina bowl this.
Patrick this scene is so funny to me. The way that the beagle
get in and they dive off in any perfect unison And not one of them thinks that this might be a trick.
And then that callback to their heads feeling like soft tomatoes.
We never... You know, before, we've never seen anyone I was trying to do. But the before this happened, this the first time this has ever seen anyone else trying. It's like a surprise for the rate or too really I knew is gonna happen. Right. And it's important to establish that it's it's special to Scrooge that it's not just like a a cartoon thing that people in this world can do. So we transition, you know, pretty quickly. We don't need to see all the business of them hiring bull
and getting it back. Transition to the last page of the story where we wrap things up so beautifully.
And it's perfect because we we go right back into that interrupted
conversation the Donald and Scrooge we're having at the beginning. Bigger didn't where Scrooge is telling him, you know, I I still haven't found the time to tell you what a comfort Huge get out of a fortune like mine. And Donald is just finally had it up to Huey,. You know, he's he's he's kind of like been patient up till now. But he gets off what for me is a really memorable line. He says if you've got comfort I'll take Vanilla.
Shut up and pay off and he kicks him right and the yeah. And and that's when he delivers, you know, the the sting of Al line, he tells him you may not know it uncle Scrooge, but your billions are a pain in the neck. You're only a poor man. Good goodbye. Yep. Because the great expression was Scrooge just standing there You don't know exactly what he's thinking. You're wondering whether it's like, he's thinking like, maybe donald. Right? It's not explained to you. Just have to come to their own conclusion. Right and Barks talk. No, man is poor can do what likes to do once in a while. And then you get the back for the third time you get to save. You Like to dive around with my money like a purpose and burrow through it like a go for and tossed it up hit me on the hand. So D end happy, you know? Yeah. Because it they have be doing a thing. And and these last five panels are they really hit so hard. You know? That they're they're amazing. That first panel you mentioned that he looks haunted in a kind of up to the reader to to determine. I really do read it. As a little moment of self awareness. You know? Yeah. My I read My read is that for... For just a moment. He... He's thinking, maybe Donald right. Know, maybe.
Maybe this is more of a burden. But then he really does shake it off. Pretty quickly. It is. And there's a a, you know, a sort of truth that he's going at there that that no man is poor who can do what he likes to do once in a while.
And here he is he ends it enjoying his money on his own terms, not not for the richness.
The the riches that that they are, but but more about what they represent.
Yeah. And and so what what do you think? Do you think do you think Donald is is more right? Do you think Scrooge has it right? I think. But the moral of the story is. Would do whatever Severino you it takes to make yourself happy. That's might take on very simple. It's not little complicated.
So neither of them is right and they're gonna have a happy hour. Right. His Donald kinda follows his own philosophy. I mean, generally
doing nothing is what makes Donald be. And so this is the opposite.
And
gets into trouble a lot, just like screws is often to upset about things going after money. So both of them have times of happiness this in times of and about equal measure, I think. Yeah. I I think that that's a good way to to sum it up. You know? Neither is really right, but we're both are right. But
much. Yeah. I like that. It's such Al affecting ending because Scrooge looks so haunted to there for a moment. And then he really does look so content.
It's exactly. It's a surround story that comes back to the beginning now. Sort of thing where we start. Yeah. And the best of his stories, I think did that. A lot models a lot of things just in general. That's an ending
usually very satisfied. And I like that you mentioned that it's the third time that he references his famous
dive around in it like a purpose and burrows I like a go for and He
thing. A good thing going there. Know and
this was like perfect. He does that. He follows that rule of three. Usually it's.
Right. It's usually it's for the the comedy build. And and in this case, it's for the emotional
Who does Al lot of times just in general like like like, in the fire story with mcdonald's a fire. Yeah. There's Al business with lucky Lucky lack Lack Lack. Yeah. Yeah. Three is this a really good number to do things like that. Well, I have so many thoughts now that we've actually talked about the story. I I gotta size them all What what are you what are you thinking about reflect on this story right now. It's got a wonderful moment like the moment with Scrooge now the on this page, the the number our Scrooge I consider whether donald right So lot. That's what thing was on it. Know where screws is reflecting on his life reflecting on his past and my things that he's accomplished on on how he's
overcome things like through the story in the past, and he brings it to the and and applies them to, like, the present. So it's an older person's story. A person who's older who's like, thinking about the past and how it affects their wife today kind of a thing, I think. Know That's that's really good.
That's a really good point. Right? This is an older person's story. Right And and he's fifty two carl at this point. So he's, like, the peak of his career probably and, you know he's probably at least considering, like, the you know, like, he's Al. Like the pickup is correct, because he's guys booked now. He was, like successful and you said learned from his craft. And it's Printing things is learned in the past into this story comes. And and you wonder how much he identified like writing for an older character. Because Scrooge is clearly supposed to be older than him. But he's no spring chicken at this point. Right. Mh. Yeah. And his enterprise with but I agree. I think he really
identifies with sprint You talked about... You talked about the there's Al lot of fridge stuff being west. You know he's at that whole California go to California make your fortune by about and that's what Carlos from. So Carl could identify with that aspect of screws too and Karl
grew up working in various jobs, you know, like, hard, job. I'm sure that when carl was younger, you know, he wielded some pick pickaxe and some shovel and good things. Just like how Scrooge is portray is being a hardworking working person. So so crowded through that too. Think be later the why a lot those ways And, of course, carl was tight the box just like Scrooge. You know, Carl famously, because I would tell the story corolla when carl would actually take his pencils and you right C on a piece of tape tape it to his pencils because people would ran off with them So he would these tell another that he labels and stamp on on his comment but his personal file copies saying this belongs to Barks. So Carl is there was, like Scrooge a lot of ways. He really was. You know. He was like, make lists of everything. His list of all of the stories and all his account, everything was just so so. So Coral, he was like, he had very screws like, tricks about him. And he knew? But it great. That is great. That's awesome. Thanks for sharing that. I've done one was when number two pencils. And it's got an from is estate just a regular number two pencil it's a half now. Top your the raised it is a piece of piece of the masking tape. And the c. Kinda a great. What a great random little treasure.
Yeah.
So One of the things kicking around my head as I read this. You know, I I was thinking a lot about the age of of his protagonist and this one and now how he must have identified with it. I was also thinking una unavoidable almost about citizen kane. You know? Like it's it's it's kind of a cli.
Right? Like but it's impossible to avoid. And and to me these first two Scrooge stories. Both this one and back to the cl
together, they they almost feel like a certain version of citizen came. Because it's... This is Carl Barks mass for peace. Along with Barks to the c. There are a couple of his very best regarded stories. And they concern
the the story of this great man this great
fantastically wealthy man and him kind of reflecting on his life and where he where he came from. Mh. I don't necessarily have any great insight on that. I don't know that Barks was ever like specifically influenced by citizen kane, but it's so deeply in ingrained, I think, in in American pop culture that how could you the difference in the in citizen kane and then Scrooge and screws basically.
Yeah. Boy what he does, susan kane very miserable right his pain himself is like who's like very miserable to most life, most decisions even though he's Al this money among this power. Seems like the more money and the more has the more miserable is. He's happiest he use nothing with a slip and absolutely.
Sc somehow overcomes this. Eighth screws is very seldom and really miserable. Obviously he's got the money to dive in a purpose and birth like go for plus up and pay himself in the head with it he's pretty much happy. Right because he never really
gives away any of his rose bugs each of those coins is is a rose bud.
Yeah. Basically.
And I like I like how in these early stories he makes it clear that
I and I believe he does it in this one, You know, that he he goes out of his way to say that the the coins themselves are special because of the memories that he evo. Yeah. He knows each one apparently like pretty much. Right. Which is, you know, a crazy ability. It's it's a little bit nice. Role, but that's that's how he is. Knows the exactly where that big giant jar of dimes is at the bone this money that's right. I also... I I don't wanna overlook how great it was story this is Donald too. And and the fact that while this is a showcase for screws, it's not called sp mick dot. Right? Mh. This is called uncle Scrooge. This is still
very much around Donald. And Donald is always part of this, like
conversation and and the debate. Even though it is definitely a Scrooge story. Yeah. We sort of get a further development of dogs in the story. Like his perspective is being the nephew of this sky and get to see him. Usually, you see Donald disorder of getting the caretaker qa doing really And this one, you get to see another facet of his personal and I think that the the little scenes with him at the beginning and and also in the beginning of the next issue, where he's just kind of looking at his uncle and, like, been used
rye,
acknowledgment of what a character. He is. It's it's just about donald at his best. I like the blow hard Donald. I like the angry Flu Donald, but there is something about a donald that is just kind of like you see that little gl in his eye at the beginning.
He he he really knows he's really kinda got his
number
in a certain way here. And and he he doesn't really wanna be in the position his in know not built for it, I guess. He doesn't have that hard working mentality. You would rather just like sit sit back with a couple of iced tea and enjoy the day. Yeah. That's right.
But a great... Yeah. I definitely think that this is a mass piece. You know, this is university.
It's it's a universal claim. Right? I don't.
I don't think
anyone would say, there are a lot of people who argue this is is best of all time. It's definitely out there. It's always gotta be in the conversations. Certainly could be business the story
reduce. Right. And if you take a look Inducks, you know, that is where it lands. It's not quite voted the number one story of all time.
This one generally ranks at number four. Really. Mh. It usually falls
and index is like, it's it's It's open to voting all the time. Right? So these three do change but there been enough votes that over the years, I haven't seen those really the top top tier, they don't move around as much. So it's generally back to the.
T la. Mh.
Oh, what start? Oh Golden Helmet and then this one is generally the the sequence, but they're all grouped close enough together kind of all these...
A difference between liking
story the mask and thinking it's this best story too. Like, I think craft wise, this could be his bad story. No. The all wouldn't pick it as my favorite stories, which is the different thing like travel lost my personal payment. But I might think this as being as best crafted story because it really is very originally, you know, because of the fact that he created Scrooge and his story. It's not him taking the donald and doing something different with the created character during it's all his own and, you know, the whole whole business Scrooge. Just have closest to that. Yeah. Yeah. And it's hard to argue with the results. Too because you know, he's gonna spend dozens more stories out of this. Scrooge just gonna be featured in a lot of other media. He's gonna become a very recognized character. He's gonna become a beloved Disney characters.
There's a limited number of people who can say that they've created an iconic Disney care. That's true. It's gonna get him into the Disney hall fame. I think maybe in one of its in inaugural years, if I remember right, Mh. Yeah. And also, also the story has the benefit of coming in early fifty two whereas later on, he's just or it starts to get stiff like a thinking? Like, just another year. It's noticeably different. Yeah this is still point where I would say it's like in that period... The ten page like dozen ten pages. This is right at the end it's follows the period. The one of Christmas for she. There's it right beautifully drawn stories. This is a key part of of his golden.
Yeah.
So, yeah, the community Loves it. I I mentioned that it's ranked number four, the the actual vote is eight point eight out of ten on Inducks. So almost everyone is is giving either a nine or a ten. Yeah.
It's it's so timeless too, and there's very little that doesn't work in a contemporary
context, which is nice. There's not And definitely see big fashioned at Al. Doesn't have a moment and it's it's not relatable and just wonderfully. You can understand that it gets to a point. It's like universal
universal story. Right. And and I do like to talk about appearances and other media. You mentioned that there have been some wonderful
with the graphs. Made of this one. I think he did three in total.
Wheels. Like yeah know...
Excuse me. Yeah. He did he did one that is a version of the cover. He did
a gray one with the the evo titled damn disaster at Money lake with the devs looking on. And then
a recreation of that great scene Al he walks through
old da and... Oh, and then one of the... I think there might be three oils of the cover. Just about, I think. There's more than one. Yeah. Yeah. I think you're right addition
different
and everybody else wanted too.
Right.
Several times. Yeah. He was high and high demand for those permission sign now. And then one of his great diving through money
poses, I guess that is I'm I've totally separate forth, you know, Yeah.
So those I would think Ryan. I think one of them is based on that great burst panel.
You mentioned that, you know, never never gotten off the ground animated movie. That would have been something to see. You know yeah The the Ducktales shows did cover this this one, not in a way that I really find satisfying.
There was like a five part
kind of mini movie that the first one did call liquid assets.
U. Which had
it was kind of a tape on this. And it had, like, gizmo
and infant fe and crack shell gizmo up and protecting it and his money and, like, inadvertently dumping it in the lake.
I enjoy the duck
episodes, but I don't think I feel like if you're gonna cover a story like this, you gotta really try and do it better justice.
Yeah he I would imagine that the animated phone would've have been wonderful, you know, because he written the whole thing and through the price story board for him too because it was. He did at one point. Know this was his job and like thirties, sir, so he could've done that justice. And I always feel like Disney missed out on a real opportunity when you consider how popular the stories are outside of America. You know, I I feel like if they had done something like that, that that it could have been massive, and it could have been really enjoying. Sure. Could've have been but there's a lot of could've have been. Right? If they had done that they
done that
If you had written the screen plate pitch it to them three years earlier, private got. That's right. Or or epic Donald if that had ever gotten off the ground. Right? Yeah.
And and the second duck tales covered covered his line, his iconic line in one of the first couple of apps so although they didn't do, like, a a story on this. But
but, yeah, this is this one this this has just inspired so many dock artists
Do you do you feel like this one would directly inspired you or is it just kinda you? No. This is a story that inspire everyone that's it's probably doing square. Point up but I think, you know, it's like a... It's got so much stuff in it. Is... I think virtual everything is Scrooge
whatever these in the story. Basically. Yes. That that is the the line of the podcast. Right? Everything that. I read that. Just now. Go ahead. The store I had it my head nice.
It's true though everything that we know about Scrooge
is right here in this story. He he's gonna be telling this story
and he's gonna be telling the stories that come out of this story. Yeah the next dash
ideas are pulled from the story by Karl just like, probably probably easily a dozen strange stories that are here. Re told, you know, like, various ways to full the bagels by moving his money and I'm opening up an empty ban or been with other stuff and. He did Al several times. And various ways try to disguise this money from the big like coming in into to is gold into corn, different items like that. Too that two stems back to the story. And the biggest various ways of being inventor and trying to come up with ways of capturing the money the way they do here with the termite termites team.
Something. You know what it's like. It's it's like a a touring
musician doing the greatest hits. Right? You gotta. Yeah. It's like it's like he... Yeah. It's like that got a good idea and then they turned in into other songs. You know, it's like yeah. And they're different enough. Know the amazing thing is that they're different enough to do excellent story down the road. You don't feel like he's repeating it. You have to look for the... Look for the story to find it Right. For sure. Because, you know
unless your hands be copied won't be boring the later stories are not... If they come across as fresh because he just took the see of the idea on this story and turned it into something more something more, I guess.
Yeah. I think
I I like to think that we've done this story some justice here. Do you... It's big shoes to fill to to the really account you know how good this story is into this describing. And we did we good shot. Like Right. Any any other thoughts about this classic?
Oh, you know what? I I don't wanna miss. I I do. There's there's a ton of them to consider, but are there any panels that you'd really like to highlight as far as favorite. Well by far my favorite panel, as I mentioned before is one one three damn break. It's all obvious. Know it's an obvious thing, but it was such an impact for panel for is probably the most impactful single panel of any Barks story that I can remember is a kid being impacted by, and I can remember that moment, which is amazing thing to remember where you were at what was happening, you know what? I'm remember coming back to this. You know, stopping reading it right here going to get somebody
it coming back and staring at this this giant panel with the Damn breaking, you know for like, a long time, probably like, fifteen minutes.
Twenty minutes, just looking at space. It's like, wow. I'm not returning back page. And reading again the the business with the termite termites the brace and coming back to the again. It's like amazing because the revelation... No doubt it affected my work.
Because it is. It have be Barks affected by something and they'll have it that come back. It it is a gorgeous panel, and it's the obvious choice that I've gotta make too. I I really like all of the little kind of haunted
Scrooge. Huge group there's a lot of single panels of screws reacting to things here. But I just one two. And and then all of those little flash Barks panels. That show classic like.
Mh. They're they're so great because they tell it's such spa story because I I could imagine so much out of each one of those
past. The panel from Dawson, you know, where he's got the bag on his how many Barks
visited that?
Almost most of us who
it's at some point on something like that Scrooge with short visual
and during the bag of money and the, you know, just how tough he was and how just a wonderful. It's all one panel, know. Oh himself. Probably was inspired by his panel for next story. Yeah. Don't you think that he he saw this panel he looked at it again as well, I could write a whole story about this time. Probably we will.
Absolutely.
I've I've gotta imagine that as he was writing this story, you know, his synapse we're fired to just I know that story is going to be.
Yeah. All of those possibilities.
And and I I love how sentimental and nostalgic these couple of early
Stories are gonna be
excellent.
Well, at once again, Patrick, thank you so much for joining me I
Grateful. Off give I have a great time. Thank you. I hope listeners enjoyed it, and I hope they'll come back to listen to the next episode, which will cover another Al I'm classic, the Golden Helmet. But, you know, these days, these episodes are covering his golden period. So
you pretty saved Yeah. It's it's an embarrassment of Riches right now. It is.
Thanks again, Patrick. Yep. Thanks for having me.