We can have
Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer an artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comments of all time. Join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Welcome back to Bark remarks. I'm Mark Sever, a grown man who enjoys the comics,
and I am joined by two other very rugged grown men. I'm gonna introduce them and then ask them to just maybe talk about when they first read our
story that we're gonna be covering today, which is the all time great the golden helmet.
So first, I've got Warren Harmon. Warren. Tell us when did you read this? They Barks. Good to be back. I read this probably about forty years ago when I landed into the one of the many reprint? Was kind of an enough state when I was my twenties and I was just starting to really avid consider collecting Carl Barks stuff really stuck out for me, but I I reread it the story today is Al lot more meaning than it did four years ago. I will tell you that. Nice. Yeah. And we're like likewise is joined by Austin Kelly. Austin, when did you read this one? First, of course, it's it's great to be back for think the third time, which is pretty cool.
Yeah. Embarrassing, it was...
I think it was back in January.
Was my first read through. When I first discovered Disney comics, there was so much. It's that's a great thing. There's so much dense material and all just of such high quality. There's so much Barks, rosa,
Italian stuff. So I had to just go through whatever I could whenever I could get it. And Golden Helmet was just at the back of the line for no particular reason. But, I got to. And I'm just... I mean, it blew my mind because it I think it's a great story. Yeah. Absolutely.
I don't think there's any reason to be embarrassed. Right? Yeah. You you've gotta read it for the first time sometime, and it's a real treat. I don't thing. I'm assuming
everyone on this call feels
largely the same about this one. Probably the way that most of the duct community does. This is an all time classic. This is one of the most famous bark stories I don't know about you guys, but I am just
so excited. To talk about this one. Yeah. To have all three of us talk about this classic and to really dig deep into the to the story structure to the artwork but, yeah, this is gonna be great. Yeah. And we were joking around a moment ago that we've got kind of like gold error reader.
Yes.
And and I'd be like a Gladstone error reader and and Austin what would you be like Gems stone or graphics? Yeah. Kind of more graphics but gems also Barks. So like, this is an evergreen story. It holds up. It is a must read for comic book fan is a great one to if you wanna introduce someone to karl Barks, I I didn't mention myself. I first read this one I'm I thinking I must have been eight or nine. It was in Gladstone big album, which, you know, the those album covers, those giant sized ones they Al stood out so vividly and seeing that that great famous cover donald holding the helmet Al lot, it's so enticing and I was just so excited to read it not. I I know I went back to this one over and over. It almost felt pointless to reread it again. But I had such a good time revisiting it this week. It was great for me to also to pick it up after so many years, and I have the
very fortunate to have the Del four color issue.
I'm reading with the Graphics one here and I read it three times just in the last few days. And we'll talk about it. I read some kinda of critical reviews of it as well which you're which were helpful, but it'll be interesting to to dive into this. Yeah. Sure. Everyone can't feel the same way about every story. Alright. So just just a little bit of the numbers a little bit of the background. This the Golden Helmet was published
in May of nineteen fifty two. It was created at the very end of December and
four color four zero eight. This one has just a boat load of reprint. As as you would expect, including the original, it's it's seen fifteen
printing in various forms and formats
in in the states It is one of his long thirty two pager.
You know, I'm... I'm just gonna kinda open with this. Right? I usually... I usually save Inducks stuff for the end. But like, I think it's important to ask for ourselves
at the outset of this episode. Does does the golden helmet live up to its reputation. Does it live up to the heights of of how the community views? Because this one is the the highest rated donald duck story. The community ranking is number three Inducks. And and that places it only below back to the cl deck and charlotte a lot. Which of course surf screwed stories. That's great So as a solo donald Inducks story, there is Scrooge. There is no Gladstone. There's no daisy. The net are in but they're secondary. I think this is really a key story that explores donald
humanity. Does it deserve that rating? I don't know. I think it deserves to be way up there because of its reputation because of what Politics Barks donald growth. Yeah. And and we'll check in kind of at the end and, you know, I don't know that anyone can answer that question because it's it's criticism.
Right? It's...
But But, you know, your vanilla is is my hot fudge Sunday or whatever. But it I think it's definitely worth kinda keeping that In the back of our mind, this is... This is considered by many people the all time greatest Carl Barks Donald Inducks venture. So the the other through line to this one.
As we go through this, Barb definitely has a theme here. Something that he ties everything
back to. This is a story that is all about masculinity,
rugged
as he calls it for for better for worse. That's the thru line. Mh. So we're we're gonna be thinking we're gonna keep keeping that in mind. And it... It's not necessarily something that that has to age very well too. Right? Like, Austin, what you what do you think about that element of it? Does this does that How many the store you feel kinda dated to you? I don't think that
particularly...
I don't think there's actually a ton now that you mentioned it that makes this field dated.
There is just like a bit of a novel element to it that I guess, like, by fifty
standards was like, crazy. I mean, not to say that in today... If, like, someone was declared is the owner of North America, that wouldn't be insane. But there's just something about it, like thinking about it from a nineteen fifties mindset
that sort of shocks you a little bit more. So I guess he's not really dated or anything about the story as much as it all it just feels like it might have worked a tiny bit better during the period, you know, which isn't a bad thing. Of course, this Barks is timeless, but, you know, but but some of them do feel a little bit like a time capsule away. Oh, yeah. So let's kinda talk about some of the background
I think it's well known.
That this was a a very at least it's well known among Barks fans. This was a really turbulent time
a very sad time. Personally.
Warren I know you you know a a pretty good amount about that.
Kinda kinda refresh. We don't need to go into, like, the super gory details. But Oh no But he was he was ending his marriage with his second
wife he was
up to his eyeballs in lawyers. He was dealing with alimony
commands demands rather, and he was
at the end of November, December nineteen fifty one when he was writing the story, many of the critics and authors that I read read pointed this at his probably one of his two lloyd low points in his career, and this was his mid midlife. His other low point came at the end of his life in some legal battles. With his artwork, but this one happened when he was really productive, and he was in those gloria years that nineteen forty eight forty nine two fifty three, kinda of that wonderful golden age of Barks So if I believe he used that low point to work very very hard at coming up with more creative stories. This particular story strikes me as one of his more adult stories, and that might be another reason it it Scrooge high. I I'd read it described as, like, very cynical. Right? It's It's a it's a pretty dark somewhat mean story or or mean spirited in some respects. Here here is a quote that that I saw it you sure you've seen about it too. He said that it was done at a time when my fortunes were at a very low. I had just given everything I owned to my alcoholic x y phoenix changed for my freedom.
Yeah. He continues broke and in debt and facing years of stiff alimony at the age of fifth feet. I chose to keep working, and I can recall one day when all the bad news struck me, and I should have been heading for a bar, and instead I sat down like a zombie with a pad of paper and jot it down gigs and plots and situations that seem to port into me from somewhere. The Golden helmet must have been one of those situations. Yeah. So that's that's pretty start. You know, it it came out of that low point as you said, there's a lot of great a lot of his greatest stories are from this period where he seems to have really poured himself into his work. Yeah. I I I find it interesting because it it does make sense now that I think about it that it came out of, like a dark period because, like, something that people are always instructed to, like, tell like, people who are going through bad times is like writing helps. And that's one of those pieces of advice you always hear and people just blow it off. But like to think about it, you know, the fact that golden helmet, and I guess only a poor man if we're talking the same period, came out of this period of Barks life than, like, There's there's a lot of truth to that, you know, in a weird way. I mean, people say it all the time. But, I mean, I know when I'm, like, at a low point, I just start scrubbing ideas in writing. I mean, I'm a filmmaker and I write stories and everything. So And that usually ends up being my best stuff. So... Yeah. Right. Yeah. It was probably very very therapeutic.
So you guys before we get into the story, I I do wanna I haven't really mentioned the fact that this that this this comment feeds into the the the history and kind of the mythology of the viking.
In a really in
intriguing way. Viking are kind of all the age right now. There's couple of big viking... There's there's at least one big viking show. Current film out there called the North.
Right. North man and there's, like, the viking or something. It's interesting like the viking are such a cool historical
archetype. There there's not as much viking in pop culture, I think Al you might
expect. Well, the only viking that we're familiar with here in Minnesota the losing viking and they thought of the Super bowl a few times times and never has ones. But there's no question Al this these viking are are the motivation for donald wanting to be to man up if you will. Yes it's an interesting way for him to play around with that theme of mass.
So you guys before we get into it, I did share a couple of the... A couple of the titles from around the world.
I chose to keep in Scandinavia.
Perfect. Yeah yeah
Out with Norway. Oh.
Yeah. Norway,
translation for the Golden Helmet is donald Inducks old
Helmet, pretty much a straightforward
translation to gold helmet. Right. Austin. Sure. In Sweden, I'm gonna try my best on this.
Then Gi he,
I guess. I don't know,
which is another direct translation donald duck in the Golden Helmet. Right. And and then for Denmark, I'm gonna do Denmark Dan
and
And again, it's a straight up translation. This is like a perfect title, I think. Wi mess with it? That cover are is so interesting. And and I guess it's worth mentioning that the the helmet itself doesn't look like a real viking helmet, not even the, like, plus shade horn viking helmets. To me, it looks more like roman almost Yeah. It's but you're right. It does not strike me as the classic viking helmet that we grew up with. No. But it looks let's just say it. It looks rad. Yeah. It it looks awesome. Can little kid me. Just thought that that helmet was the coolest looking thing. And and then speaking of Denmark, you know, I I held on to the Danish title because they they love this story so much. I almost feel guilty not having a dane on here to talk about this. But they're like
ministry of culture
adopted this as part of the Danish Canon in two thousand six. They published this work. This canon of work significant to Danish culture. And this was the only item of course, the classic lego brick made it. But but this is the only
item that wasn't danish. Oh, wow. Well, they really adored Carl Barks as well. Correct? Yeah. I've.
I thought that was fine. So the last quote before we get into the story itself is is a letter that Barks route with him revisiting.
The story years later. He said I'd I've just read the Golden helmet story for the first time in many years. The amount of plotting and the script is amazing. And every device in situation seems to develop easily from what has gone before. I can offer no extra explanation of how I did it other than to say that I wrote and re reroute and we polished and double checked backward forward and counted syllables in the dot log. Read the stuff dozens of times for effectiveness and flow. The bogus latin legal phrases are really meaningless other than as points of reference and a running gag.
So, you know, he he has some appreciation of how the story is. I... It's kind of... If I do say so myself quote, I I think he's right to take the victory lap with this one. I'm really glad you shared that because listening to bark himself, comment on how he created the stories years later reflecting on them is really great for storyteller tellers and story maker like, like, Austin myself who who do that for a hobby or for a profession. It's that's part of the art of crafting. I think.
I I I thought that was super cool. Hearing him talk back about what he thought about as crop. Process. I mean, obviously, that just gave me, like, major anxiety listening to how much work keep and it. But I mean, it totally paid off. And and this is like an interesting comparison I don't wanna draw.
As far as, like the the comic
animation, large, medium, car Barks is is definitely a genius, but I would also call Texas avery
Who did, you know, Red Hot Riding hood and and all the Droop cartoons at Mgm. And he had a very similar process where he would inspect his films
I mean, like Barks was counting the syllables and everything. Text would inspect his films by frame. Right? Every single one this films frame by frame and he would change every error, and it cause this major nervous breakdown where he actually left for years at a time, and then he had to come back because he was just such a perfection. So I find it interesting that that never affected Barks or at least to my knowledge. If anyone listening knows otherwise, I mean, let us know because I would think after twenty five years of being so perfect if that was what he did with every story,
I would think he would have had to cracks at some point. That that well said to me what comes to mind is the fact that, like, this isn't what he really like wants it to do. Right? It's it's interesting to me. He obviously came up through the Disney system doing shorts and stuff, but he didn't
love doing the dot. Right? He wanted to be doing prints val.
And and so it's it's especially impressive, I think that he put so much effort and heart and perfectionism
into these comments that were... I have no doubt that he enjoyed doing these that some of them he did. He did something just because it cracked. Him up were or because it was a story he wanted to tell. But even in this one, right, there... This literal story was kind of him wanting to tell
Prince Val type tail or or at least to draw something that looked like it could have been sat there. Yeah. He was so...
Influenced by Health foster and the Prince Al stories and it evident as we see and hit the high seas here, but...
I think he absolutely
thoroughly enjoyed that Considering the time in his life and was a great way to cope with all the reality what he was dealing with. And warren you mentioned hitting the high seas, he loves his sea fe stories. There's only many great ones I can't begin to name them all. Probably the best when it comes to on the water and among the rocks. Well, yeah. As far as as far as just pure, like sea fair and navigation itself. This is the one that is most, like pre op preoccupied, It does such a great job of giving you an nine idea of what it meant to navigate
the the north c's
before
before digital compass
and satellite
navigation and and everything like that. Yeah. And and you and I Warren had mentioned when that way back when I had you on the first time with of the north, we we mentioned that Al like kind of a dry run almost. I think it going for gold helmet. Yeah. And do you think about it in in Barks time frame. That was just about two years from like of the north to Golden Helmet creation and and look at the maturity because all the work he did Al spend time. So prolific. Let's let's...
Let's do this guys. We are going to talk the Golden helmet. We're gonna go through this this story I'm I'm gonna do the main kind of summarizing, but I I wanna hear you guys kinda page by page, and and then I'm gonna have you guys do certain sequences. So you guys the the Golden Helmet
opens
it opens up in a museum with Donald being in a a an assistant guard. Of course, he's an assistant.
And
this is just such a master
opening to the story. I see that a lot, but it does such a great job of setting this up. First off, we we get this, like, taste of donald
looking at extremely bored literally saying h home. And he's kind of plotting
sleep
through the exhibit and and you guys the exhibits are wild.
Barb had
so much fun.
That there's there's this goofy looking sculpture called the God of ga
these sculptures, they they look like I don't know. They have, like a mad magazine vibe to me or,
I don't know. Sur pcr Al bonus or there's that they're not very typical
Barks.
Right? There they're a little bit realistic. It looks like something that that Van Horn who came along later, frankly, would have drawn. But he's just pacing through the museum
and he's pondering and how he's been working here for three months and nothing has happened, and the reader is treated to this great view of this this beautiful viking longs ship that has a a caption
pla indicating that was dug up and herring Norway, buried by the viking about nine twenty a d and this seems like a good job for Donald, but he is talking about how he's the rugged type and he crave it adventure. You know, I... On that last panel of the first page
and threw throughout well, he's bored. His comment about being the rugged type. He doesn't do it with a lot of flare. It's just sorta of mentioned, but the visual in the museum that he stares at Severino day is that viking ship. And I think that just takes him back. I also wanna to call out the the similarities a little bit to lost in the End opening when donald again is one of his
occupations is that of a museum jan. And I think there... He's like third assistant to the the second assistant or something, but B Barks his his sense of humor in there was more in the writing because Don was enthusiastic about being the guard in the news see. And here, Our as humor is all in the visual. And it's just like you said this the sore surreal pieces of art, these salvador dolly like images and these great me. My favorite is the the dive laundry bag But what about you austin? What... What do he think of these museum pieces? Yeah. You run up the mad magazine comparison. You also mentioned William Van Horn, who I definitely think of by contrast. I I don't think anything like this would have ever been done by Don Rosa. My favorite is in the bottom left corner this horribly wrinkled
sad frown face is just labeled
joy
Would it just feels like Barks is happening just a total field day this absolute
garbage in the background. I just love it so much. Yeah. But it's amazing. I I love the one that's labeled the fight. It it looks like barb goof thing on like,
surreal.
Right? That that's that's how I take it. I guess, what what's our overall vibe? What does Barks think of the the nineteen fifties Era museum. Right? It doesn't to me this this viking boat is is an incredible thing to go visit. But
But this doesn't speak very well of of the modern museum. Oh, I think he's he's really critically
kinda tearing that apart while he's focusing in this great and I should say probably only splash panel of the size in the entire comic that central
viking ship is where he wants to take us. These other things are throw away gigs. But and I really don't think he was a fan of the modern art era. Right. Yeah. Yeah. He's really doing a good job focusing our attention on that ship. And and on to the next page, you know, he gives us some great perspective.
Over the course of the next few all all around the ship. The next page is really devoted to just seeing Donald at work
His his day dreaming about being rugged being like the old time v kings and then contrasting it with the kinds of directions that he has to give to to some really goofy looking people who
who want directions to the Butterfly
collection
and the lace padding collection.
It's it's a really
striking
contrast, and I'll I'll throw it over to you guys but before before I do, can I point out that Donald appears to be really, really good at this job? Like, he's casually he's been working for three months, and he he just... He knows everything.
He doesn't care. I I totally agree. I wanted to point out that I thought it was very interesting.
When you were talking about this page, Mark and I was just scanning through it. I was thinking, you know, Donald hit like this really low point in his life and then I read the panel on the right side where he's thinking to himself that he's sunk so low. You don't even have to be able to read the text to tell just he's just got these total morons coming to him for these just goofy sounding exhibits like Barks conveys that point and like Donald has really hit rock bottom before his create my overseas adventure, you know, which I really like. That's great storytelling. Yeah. He awesome. Would you mind reading the the panel right before that. It's a great kind of sum of his
situation. I actually really like this now that you mentioned Donald is Google eyes staring at the viking ship and says those old viking fought walrus and whales and savage tribes and I tell dog I nature boys wanted to find
butterflies. And what I find interesting is that, like, this is almost... I mean, not this particular situation, of course. But it's almost relatable in a sense where like, we've all been through that point in our lives where we stand around, and we compare ourselves to others, and we just think, I mean, I've sunk so low. And I think that's like a cool thing about Barks is that he makes this, you know, doc that in the cartoons just throws around stuff and Scrooge everyone, like such a human character, which I always very intriguing.
Yeah. Yeah. That's a great point. And and a warren it strikes me here kinda reminiscent
about luck of the north. Right? The through line and that one was Donald
gil. His extreme sense of of guilt and the through line and this one is his like in insecurity. Oh, Absolutely. That's greatly put Barks And this particular one,
you're absolutely right,
especially in that last panel of the second page because he says I just want to pretend. To be a human man that says it all.
A few minutes on top of this ship, I'll be one. And and think about this, the museum is a lonely place.
Lot lot of time to do in your thoughts. You guys before before the next page is is the... Is the second go live nature voice that? Is that Far
first reference to... I'm reading that man like a game. Am I off am I off track there? He ask he looks very like Al a dane
call them both the
men. The the critics say right, both them he is this one the skinny one is more
than the other one. Yeah. Yeah. That's what interesting
take on it. Yeah. I... The the first guy looks to me more just like kind of a man child. Me that's kind of a book worn man.
But neither of them are, like hurting anyone. Right? They're they're both totally harmless. They'll be interesting to revisit, you know, at the end. So on the third page, you know, as you mentioned, he's up on that ship pretending to be a human man. I don't think the
insurance would like that. But it does give him the moments to to over here who is going to turn out to be the villain of this
story.
Rum around the old ship looking for something in its hold. And Donald directs him away. And and you guys this he's he's quite the villain. Right? This is Azure blue. Mh. And I I'm of two minds. Right? Like it's It's it's a shame that he didn't use him again. But this also makes him very a very singular presence. We we just get a quick little taste of him, but we we know that he is big trouble. Right? Just from the sn on his face. Yeah. I love that about his character the way, like, Barks almost built his face, so it's naturally
sc with the skin coming down on the eyebrows and they're sticking up and all the wrinkles on the muzzle Yeah. I think the first pay... But the first panel here says it all He's got this little crow Barks and this tiny flashlight he's poking it in. And it's like what kind of a man is on an old viking doing this stuff? You know? It's a it's a perfect character be sets it up really nice for the whole story. Right. And and so he he makes up some excuse donald direct him weight to the charts. And and this on the next page. This is naturally pete Donald interest. So he goes down to investigate in the ship and and he ends up finding
in an old knot hole,
there's a loose peg
that reveals
a a role of deer skin that he identifies Al a map. It's a really cool moment of discovery. You know, like, to me as a kid, it seemed very plausible even if it's a little bit far fetched. I remember this point as a kid enjoying that sort of self discovery very resourceful he's he's pretty smart here about knowing what to do to find it and the way he finds it This is a very memorable moment for me Yeah. And you're right. It's kind of a quiet moment I I do find it very memorable.
So he takes the chart, and we're gonna meet one of the the other
small handful of new characters.
He passes by this, like, mysterious
sc stranger.
We get a taste of his thought balloon. Austin I really liked your reading of Donald. Do you mind reading
Azure blues thoughts for us?
So Donald runs by with the map and Blue says by the ninety curse of the Northern Lights, that stupid guard found what I was looking for. You know, I mean, which is funny. I wanted to bring this up really. Think like Barks as world is based off a tiny bit too much of, like coincidence is. I always found it interesting that Donald just found like the right pillar that has the right not hole with the right map that we was looking for, you know? Right. Yeah. He's he's got... He's definitely got that heroes lock. That sort of heroes
heat seeking.
For sure. But man, Blues dialogue in this or monologue in this
case, I guess is great. So Donald does take that role of your to the cure and and the cure is a really interesting guy, Right? Because he is this old book
academic looking
But we're gonna see that he's really
resourceful.
He is is really, like, great in in a moment of crisis.
I just I really like him. It's quiet little supporting role, but I've got a great deal of a
refrigerator. Yeah. And I and I will say looking when we first meet the,
he occupy such a great part of the first third of the story.
And whereas no other regular character has and such a a partner with Donald in plotting and in in discovering one of the critical essay I read about this story was there's a lot of similarities
similarities here between Indiana Jones going into the academics in the museum and into the college,
very some parallels and so Al we know George Lucas and and
silver. Spielberg Stevens Spielberg were influenced by Carl Barks greatly. Yeah. That's a great point. Warren Tell us, tell us about the curator
interpretation of the deer skin. Oh, well, the curator is he says that this map is a log of the old viking ship. It tells the tail of its voyages, and the king was commanded by a viking named o off the blue. And and it's it's pretty funny if you know your your viking history. Right? Everyone knows Eric, the red. That's it's just a good a great goof on on that name. Oh, I love it. Yeah. In fact, I really thought pull off the blue was real, so I started looking it up and every reference went right back to Carl Barnes. That's right. But, yeah, yours before Eric the red, and in nine zero one, he landed on the coast of North America. They're all important to discovery here that we're talking about the fate of North America, the entire continent. Yeah. And and he finishes by you know, giving our little artifacts the yeah its introduction. He mentions that
he buried a golden helmet and he gives the latitude to fifty nine degrees on the coast of Labrador. So Barks sue he's laying out, you know, our destination. And the... This illness
sc man has been listening in, and he's kind of music about how all of the
information that he had translated
previously in Norway or fitting together and he gets ready to act. You guys wanna eat tour for a moment. I feel like Barks
was ahead of the curve. I'm I have no doubt he got this from National Geographic. Right? But, like, if you look up articles about when you know, America was quote discovered. But and we know there are lots of issues with, like, discovery is silly for a Al land that was already populated. But you'll you'll see references
from like into the twenty first century about new evidence suggests that the vikings were the first and I I felt like because I read this story as a kid. I knew better than most people that the vikings had been here longer longer than
Columbus. For example, and growing up here in Minnesota part of the north land and in viking lo and Norwegian
immigrants came over
very big part of our history here in the state and and to to kinda see this come come about and Barks
educating the reader about this from his time with national geographic, but also with his love for history. I think this is one of the most compelling moments. Of any of his stories. Right? And he and he's definitely gonna stretch historical facts to its breaking point, but... But he does it in such a great entertaining way. And and so on to the next page, Donald and the are consulting
at his discovery.
And
before the curator is able to send an expedition
to Labrador,
they get interrupted by that man. Austin, do do you wanna tell us about the the pair of people that interrupt? So as your blue walks back in with a new character,
who kind of has, like, the same facial structure going on
who introduces himself Al lawyer shark. Who's here to demand possession of that map for my client here, azure blue. Eldest descendant of Al the blue. Really funky
bark Al looking characters here We already talked about how bright blue design was.
Yeah. All awesome is the lawyers Barks
draws funny also. It's like another thing he has going for. Yeah. Shark is hilarious. Right? He's got like this permanent
sn
sn, and we talked about how this is This is Barks hate letter towards lawyers. Right? He felt like he just got... He he just finished getting screwed over. By Al lawyer and his divorce proceedings, and he like poured some of that venom into this depiction.
I love Barks. He cracks me up. I do find that like hook knows, just a little bit uncomfortable
It it is is viewed by some people as a bit of an anti Medic trope. I'm not suggesting that, like, he was purposely
depicting him that way, but, like, I do think that's something that kinda got absorbed into the pop culture. So that that part of him, I find a little bit
but
shark is is is hilarious.
His, like, sort of venom
legal realistic
interpretation is one of the better running gigs, I think.
Interesting. I never... I never saw that myself. But, again, you know, you're right. Al it he appears more h and upper scale. I mean, he's got the bow ties he's got the tuxedo, I mean, the long tails. Right. So I just wanted just say, like, that was what came to mind for me too. But you took the words right down of my mouth. I mean, it was just like, in the pop culture, almost, which sounds like horrible to say, but like, it, it it's what came to my mind at first, but just like a hook knows just something that a lot of people were putting on a lot of different characters at the time. Right. It's it's not an indictment of work specifically. It's an indictment of of the country
of of pop culture. So... Yeah. You guys this the the this code of discovery, and one of his longer narrator boxes
it is it's a work of genius, I think. Because, like, it is at the same time,
completely over the top and ridiculous.
And yet, for for like, the young readers reading it, It just... It felt so iron glad. I don't know.
As as a nine year old reading this, I bought it. It it felt like it invoked almost the magnet Carta. To me. Right like, oh, yeah. Yeah. It feels like something that must have happened
at the time. But but this idea that, you know, it it says that the the nation... The rules of all the nations gathered rome and draft to the law which read any man who discovers a new land beyond beyond the c's, shall be the owner of that land unless he claims that for his king. And so Barks tells us directly the steaks here. Since all of the blue claims North America for his own, it now belongs to his nearest of kin.
And has there ever been a higher stake?
Outside of maybe Al ancient persia. This has to be this the Barks story with like the very highest of snakes.
I think it is. I I... Oh my goodness. You mean the whole fate of North America is at stake here. And so the curator of course of jet Right. He says
horse and Pure Barks, how can that man prove his ola offs
nearest of Kin.
Warren, I'll let you do the first of Shark legal east dog Latin.
Flag is from died dumb, which is legal language for. How can you prove that? It isn't? Love it. And. And then of course, Al you blue,
snatch they map away from a very distressed curator. And so they leave... And and Shark gets the last word. They they imply that, you know, they're gonna slave them once they get the gold helmet, which is what they need to prove
his ownership.
Austin, what's the next bit of dog latin?
Locust
Joke,
which means I no idea. What to the landlord
belong the doorknob knobs.
It's such a great turn phrase. It it doesn't even make sense, like, the more you think about it. It's just so bizarre, but it's just so awesome.
I love those. I been drawing your parallels between owning an entire content to owning a a a piece of property, like Al like tenant classic bark here work. And so on the next page, you know, we've got the curator and he's days and and what what Barks is doing here is that the curator is like our voice of authority. Right? He he is taking it seriously
for us. So that we will because Donald is like this this sounds like preposterous
and he's he's saying I'm I'm just gonna go bash him on the head. A great shot of him getting ready to peg him with his his baton. But then the curator is setting up the states. Like, we have to stop him and we have to be the ones he can legally do this and if he is able to get the helmet, then it it's true. The inter... The law is sound. And so what the curator does is he
he reproduce the map and he is gonna... That they're gonna set out separately.
They're gonna head to Labrador as Donald says among the icebergs and polar pairs.
And when the curator points out, pull off the blue did it, are we less of men than he was?
And so we've we've got the steaks. They're set up the curator and Donald are gonna head out and separate paths. Donald will sail up the coast. The... The curator will head
an overland route And so he gives him, you know, enough money to make an expedition. And as Donald leaves pondering
wow. I was just thinking, you know, nothing exciting happens anymore. It's it's thing I'm the rugged type, but the curator
instruct him make sure you chuck that golden helmet into the ocean. It is dangerous.
I love that discovery for the reader seeing that in that last panel, Al the shots beautiful with the of the background. I totally agree, I was about to say warn. The the composition is great. And the statement is foreshadowing for what I always thought was the stronger half of the story.
Yes. Austin. Who I like that. You you have got a
statements. You think that the second a half is the stronger half? I really like the drawing in the first half with all the the scenes and the storm, but I think there's some really cool, like, commentary on humanity almost, like, Al the end with what we don't wanna spoil it. But what happens is the helmet and all, you know everyone. Yeah. As if anyone listening me to this is
it's not read this one. Alright. So
Warren, why don't you tell us about why don't tell us about the sequence where they prepare. Sure. So Donald race is home to let the boys know that they're off to Labrador.
And the kids are just sitting in the living room floor playing marble and kind of dis interested in anything.
And Donald just has, again a classic fit and and explains to the boys. We're going to Lab, and is that a movie and he gets so frustrated one of my favorite panels and he throws himself head first into the wall.
Just out of sheer frustration over the oddly enough, the the the roles have been reversed here for a few panels because it would be typically the Nephews who would know all this. And Donald is just frustrated. They don't have any idea what's going on. So then he they skip to the where on the plane heading toward the diaper. Well, if this amazed me too that they're on this great airplane flying over night shot of the plane and that's an overnight trip. But then in this beautiful bed we're donald on one side and the nephews are on the other side and a plain in the passenger by, well, that's pretty luxury travel
for nineteen fifty. Donald is now kinda re in his found adventure here. No more old must museums for me, just the northern c's. Out there and let the soft east study their butterfly butterflies and chatting and as they kind of land in New newfoundland,
the Inducks Discover there at the docks they see Azure blue loading boat full of everything
and everybody including paper reporters. Yeah. This reminded me of, like, Gladstone and Donald,
getting ready to take off in the race to the south c's. Yeah. Very similar.
Yeah. We've got this, like, pursuit I, he's even got a worship.
Azure blue. Yeah. Out there.
His worship again the world. Clearly a big deal. I'm gonna ask Austin to to kinda tell us some of the their voyage. Sure. I wanna comment first though, I think it's super cool. The way Barks keeps bringing up, I mean and that. The panel with the plane shot erase will decide the fate of the people of North America. And then again, when the Ducktales are looking at blue loading up the ship, we just have these people on the side going this helmet that will make him the owner of North America, you know, he just keeps re emphasizing those steaks because it's So
that's just... It speaks volumes about how powerful the stories, which I just think is so cool. Mh. I'm glad you brought that up austin and be... It looks like a worldwide event. This is a big deal. Nasa lost and tell us about their voyage. Sure. So Donald sets off after blue, and
it's a pretty rough day out on the c's.
A bunch of water hitting donald in the face. He's got a very
unusually
determined character.
Let them sc. It isn't in speed that's gonna win this race. It's a rugged,
you know, back to that key plot element of the rugged, I guess. So they keep going and there's some arguing between Donald and the nephews about where they are and the the compass. And I mean, in reality, none of them know what they're doing because they don't this stuff very often, but so they're all in the same boat for one stone on the Nephews, which I find kind of interesting. So again on the next page, there's some more rough weather on the c's and Donald and a rain raincoat this time with the Nephews all beaten up hanging on to this the base of the flagpole pull. And
anyway, we cut ahead to blue in the war. And what I find very interesting is that, you know, this crazy weather
where even the nephews that are, you know, usually the
the determined type in these stories have almost totally given up when they're hanging on for deer life. Donald is determined he's equal with blue who is you know, the war leaving, search, shall we turned back to, which is what someone's saying to a blue on the ship and he goes, hold your course. I'm giving orders here, which sounds so stupid. You know? It's so much at risk, but... I mean, he's such a crazy character blue, just It's interesting to see blue comfortable in like, a cabin, right while the Ducktales are exposed to the elements and their smaller ship.
And it it's wonderful to see him in that in that environment holding a gun on the captain of the ship and also his lawyer in until I mean, this wire is going everywhere with you. That, that struck me funny. The first time is... Oh, yeah. You guys the see the storm, all of these panels were just drawn so beautifully here. Could. This is the part in the podcast where I commit that cardinal in of, you know, verbally describing some great visuals. But but they're they're just stunning. Well, second that on the standing artwork work. Those first two think is when he sets off are just
unbelievable in
execution, and it really does rival health are from Prince Al.
He wanted to do this. He...
Shame he couldn't have given himself more excuses to do that kind of art. So basically, this storm the purpose of the storm is to
equal.
Donald and blue. He holds...
He he points a gun at the captain. I like... I like how we up the steaks here. Like, he's he's a bad villain. We've got some gun play in our in our Disney comic here, and he he just you know, Al allude to I'm gonna be the first to that golden helmet. I'll I'll take Shark dog latin here. He says y
k
focus.
Which means the boss speak jaw.
And just at that moment, of course, they crash between two a couple of ice Barks.
And they get ship wrecked.
So he gets a little bit of come up and there briefly. And and the Ducktales state
see that they've managed to pass them. They see the lifeboats, and they celebrate.
But
Azure blue,
Donald does not actually see Azure blue in those boats. So he's not ready to celebrate it right. And we do...
We do flash forward. Barks and blue are in a robot
very risk.
Growing towards their destination and
blue, you know, thinks that, you know, we're we're bound to have something
break far way. And... Boy, I guess warren we've got another parallel that I didn't think about with lost in the Andy where we've got a a a bit of an extended fog sequence ones. We do. And
close. Maybe Barks needed a little break after
after Labor the painstakingly drawing all his crashing way. That's really a good point because he the
drawing each of those panels in the... In the previous three or four pages had to be labor intensive. Let's just throw in a few horizontal lines and some some gray paint and let's call it fog. So I think I eat... But he does a nice job of that. And then Al to the story
of how close these boats are really becoming to the ice version into the danger out here and the nephews of there, of course, Al asking donald dot donald to look out. It's it's a really neat sequence here what they figure out. You want... You wanna tell us how they head off, you know, how they keep safe and the fog. Yeah. So the
so, I discovered something. If we yell, we can see the berg see them by Al listening to the echoes as they bounce off of the large
icebergs. And so they start yelling to gauge their closeness
to the Barks. I think that's just brilliant. It it's really clever. It's... It feels like if you're a kid, it feels really clever. But, of course, it it leads to
Azure blue.
Also
local positioning them and and boarding their boat at gun gunpoint, leaving damage drift and just a robot. Mh. I I I I I thought this earlier when Al blue pulled the gun on the captain,
But I think here really, and I think we might be at the halfway point in the story
is where stuff gets serious, you know, where they run into azure blue and lawyer shark on the Robo robot, and he pulls that done on Donald, you know,
where it's like the states are really high as we're about to see, I mean, Donald is really America's only hope here. So I think this is what to become like a real nail bite I think is like the best part. Yeah. That's a really good point. Right? Because
what Barks is doing is is these two competing parties are getting, like, whittled down. Right. Each of them gets left, high and dry
more and more. And and Austin, you alluded to Donald being the only hope. Why is that. Well, we check it on the curator who's taking the land route, and it looks like the helicopter the he was in has broken down the motor burned out and it's gonna take three days to hike back for repairs. And, you know, he can yell all you want. But, you know, it's three days and he better start walking because
is it latitude or long fifty nine over off the course to lab
coastal labrador is a hundred miles away. So there go secure and he's hiking and he says, again, just sparks nailing in those states. Donald is America's only hope. Yeah. It it really you really feel for the curator because he definitely does not look like a young man. No. He's not. He's a seasoned
c of the museum. And by the way, he has an no name. He's just known as the cure, which I thought was interesting. Yeah. And he's... But he's also as determined is donald to make the trip and so he starts a one hundred mile track. Yeah in pretty dangerous country,
Right. Yeah. You you feel for him. My my feet have like sympathy blisters for now. And and we get another of those like
blue alluded to his luck turning around. That's what happens next for the docks Al they encounter some of the records of his ship, and they're able to fasten and fashion of sale. And,
boy, everyone of Barks little narrator panels.
I feel like his narrator panels are more interesting. Than in the average
story. They're like cheering him on. Right? The wreckage is a price find out of it, they fashion a mask and mount a sail made from the Kansas the anchor.
And
gonna have used point out in an annoyed way that Donald is getting to getting to live just like the viking did. A thousand years ago. We see this really cool. I... I love the panel where he does, like, the manual
siding of the stars. It really fires the imagine issue light. But also sharing his expertise in navigation, which we didn't know we had. Of course he's a sailor doc I guess, you could save. Or I I imagine that he got it in his, like, three months in the museum.
You know just yeah. Yeah. But I love that pose. That's a very very unusual angle it we see Donald. He does it with such. I just just great flair. I just love this the silhouette use here. And and so finally, they do reach that latitude.
The latitude fifty nine, the head west, and they
I didn't mention that they're supposed to be looking for a head that shaped like a cross is where blue is buried has hidden the helmet. That's correct. And guys...
What do we think about that, that lower splash panel. Austin, do you wanna read
when they see they finally site land, what what does...
When I think one of the next you say. So they get to these this great pile of rocks this gray Barks splash panel and they say oh off the blue must felt the same way. And that's the
view of America
I've ever seen. I mean, I agree with them. Oh my god. It is. Just drop dead gorgeous though. I mean, it is a very un welcoming site. I mean, you buy it. Shadows over the rocks and the Rocky tide, but And I actually never noticed like, the little penguin
in the bottom left corner. Yeah. I love. I love the little bit of puff that are featured in this. But I love the introduction and and Austin, you nailed it. I I I agree with you. The sheer scale of this panel, and I wish it was the larger. U you know, here it's it's only one of the two two two frame or two panel squares that it takes up on the lower part of the page. Again, they're very few splash panels of any in the story. But it is probably my favorite bigger panel and the scale with it that sailboat. Yeah. It's it's stunning. It's such a great panel. This is a really cool sequence. Here. The Inducks, now they have to just basically
scan the coast They have to hope that the curator map has led them roughly in the right direction. And and and they're
they're... They don't know it, but they're competing with Azure and shark who are doing the same thing on there old boat at this moment. But neither of them are having any luck And and we see them on kind of the opposite
sides of a little Rock island. And as they round it and spotty each other. We get this great taste of Azure glues t
as soon as he sees the docks, he yells at shark to ram their boat and sink it. That miserable museum guard is not going to be neither of the golden Helmet mass. That that's that's that's a great a confrontation there, but I'm gonna go back just a frame two there, Mark and comment about another another characteristic
trait of that lawyer who's oh yeah. Thank anything
because I think this is where we start talking about. Well, I suggest that you sue somebody,
Anybody from millions of dollars of damages This is Carl Barks is disdain for lawyers right here. He was living at in his real life. They were suing him for divorce. They were... I don't wanna get into all that, but this is a clearly
completely different thought at the time when... And, of course, Al your blue agrees with him, then the confrontation. Yeah. I'm glad I'm glad you pointed out. It's the other great running gag with Cherokee besides the ridiculous Dog latin
where he's he's constantly
suggesting suing for damages and an over the top way. What what do you think of his like? T here austin. Just just ram there about. God. I I... He is just so
ill. You know? I I think it really just
solidifies, like, the states and the point. I mean,
America's only hope has just been
sunk in the, oh my god. He's climbing up the rocks on the side with his nephews.
He's thankful that he wasn't shot at. I mean, it's a really well structured
story at this point. I mean, this why I was saying earlier, like, the second half is my favorite of the two, just because It gets really suspense at this point. And he's Donald to hit a high where he's at that adventure that he wanted at the beginning. And now he's back at Al low that he started at, you know, which I find very interesting. It's definitely the the, like, more exciting half, but I think Think they work together so well. But man, every Write austin every panel in this sequence
is just Al another work of art.
The Ducktales like scrambling,
helpless the drag gold onto these cold rocks.
Azure blues great pose Al he's like men them, talking about taking care of rugged runs like you and rugged ways. And then lady luck take a a turn against blue as his motor comes out, I suspect because he just ram another That's. And in turn, it's gonna smile. Lady lock for is gonna smile on the dots who are hud
at like a a little camp campfire they've made in a puff and nest. You guys this is such a wonderful sequence. This is like, such a thrilling bit of discovery.
It fired my imagination so much as a kid. We've got... We've got three of the dots huddled for warmth, while one of the Ducktales
is kind of at the edge of the water
overlooking the island that they had just kind of met and encountered Azure blue around And he asks Donald how long ago Al off withdrew the map. And and Donald is like,
and discussed and he says a thousand years, what difference does it make? And and a camera pulls to the space between the island
and that little point that they're hud for worm on and Hue says nothing
except that in a thousand years, the waves could have cut through the neck of that head.
And it's just such a thrilling moment It it really sends like a little chill
up my fine. The throwing moment, you're right, and it it's is moment of discovery when you are discovering the eroded rock that once was the cross that made that He a thousand years ago and you can see the remnants of it there. That's where your imagination kicks in and I think this is great for that young reader, the old reader. For any reader because this is truly... This is in the adventure story in the vein of Al Indiana Jones And now we're seeing the Nephews and donald work together really well. The resourceful of doing and and and donald now getting it So probably one of my favorite sequences in the whole story. It's gotta be one of the best sequences
in in any of Barks adventures. It's... Because because you... You're filled with such a sensitive of excitement. Right? You're like you know that they're are close. You know it's about to happen. I was just gonna throw in, like,
I think it's really cool the way that Barks structures
the Nephews and Donald, like dynamic, like donald is good at sort of in this case, determination also sort of aggressive and fighting back because he's so dead set on finding this helmet. And the nephews, you know, their junior year wood shots and they've got the guide, but they don't have it on them, but I'm sure they're well read into it and they're able to look over this cliff and go well, wait a minute if it's been, you know, a millennium worth of time, this
Could have worn down and we might be standing right on top of the helmet. So you know what I just find it interesting the way that Barks even it out so the different plot can be hit by different characters
for different reasons, just speaking to their different strengths. Right? Yeah. Very well said. And so Donald pulls out that copy of the the... The carriers copy of the map. And you... And he looks to where he thinks it should be. I'm sure enough they see a really suggestive care of rocks. Doesn't line where no natural, no man made formation
should be with a grumpy looking puff.
Nested it. I talk. And I I love... I love the bit where donald gets, like
crown by the helmet.
A couple of and eggs break on and Barks really likes to do that. Right? He likes to take Donald down a pin right at those moments of Triumph.
That's a good good point And and to, like, really
add some punch to their almost discovery. We transition back over to Shark and to to Azure and Shark have just gotten the motor working again. And Azure is gonna just take a scan for the docks. And and we get this really cool perspective shot through his bin.
And and in the narrator box,
Austin, can you tell us what Azure
screams?
Another
bit of classic Barks riding classic blue line by the seventeenth of the c which screams as your blue, they found the Golden helmet and we have this off some image just like the cover of Donald Triumph holding this,
awesome looking helmet in his arms and the nephew are all happy. I didn't notice to it has it been up to this point where the narrator rate box are reading off, like, almost like a kid's book, you know, with that line, like Scrooge as your blue like, they're being told from, like, the third person Yeah. It's it's interesting that sometimes he like sometimes he feels like he's almost having a combat station with the reader and those narrator boxes. In a way that I find really enduring. I like it. It's it's really striking too.
I I think I'd never remember when I... As much as I've read this, I never remember that that great cover shot is really like a shocking lease. Small bit of a regular panel because it fills your imagination. So well. Well, it shows that downloaded in greatest triumph of his whole career. And in now, he's he's suggesting that he's saved North America in this little, you know, through the a vernacular shot, but Al Austin, and and all of us agree, it just made... It made for one of the most iconic covers ever. Yeah. Absolutely.
And and so
blue, of course, is enraged, and he wants to immediately go come near the helmet, but char key is like, let's let's be sneaky and smart about this. And so they make their way to ambush the Ducktales from behind. And we see the doctor kind of basking in their discovery. We hit at this great shot of Donald holding the helmet Al lot. It's a beauty.
It is really icon to me. He's... He's going out of his way to draw our eyes to the helmet. And then all of a sudden, of course, it gets snatched away by Azure blue who introduces himself Al the emperor of North America to you
slate.
And and and he he's triumph now. He gives this really creepy lee grand
and he's talking about how the dear skin map and the golden helmet or his deed
to North America.
Next bit of Dog Latin, Warren, His lawyers lawn lawyer shark then says,
meaning, that's telling boss.
But this is this is absolutely...
Again, I he's smiling here too.
Task.
Test, please. Yes. And and then they are claiming that they are the slaves and you'll work for me Severino day with no Sundays off. He's holding out of the map and the helmet with such greed. It's it's amazing. Right. And and the, you know, the Ducktales are outraged.
And as they're just triumph fence the the nephews very acutely say, you won't take our junior wood check trophies,
Donald, new television set, and they don't care about this stuff, but they wanna drive the point home. So another bit of dog Latin and Shark says oh yes, he will. P
stun.
It is the law, and he is holding them at point telling them to get on and be my crew. So that I can head back to New
and be crowned. And of course, that's our Huey,
for him to get...
To get a big stone landing right on his head. Tell Austin about who saves the day. So the
back in play. Who I guess the readers all forgot about he's looking worried and
destroyed as usual. It throws the rock on blue head buying that fee boys to helmet us not be allowed to fall into his hands again. It's best that we sail at once and dump these things far see. So, you know, he's like he's almost stepping in as like, the practical one where he just knows it's gonna be taken a bit too fun I mean, of course, it has been already. But, I mean, it's almost necessary for the story for him to be here just to be like we have to get rid of this. You know? It's just powerful tool, which leaves us the climb
the best part here. Yeah and the indicator is horribly tired here. He just walked a hundred miles. So hearing him say this, You believe in him and you say, okay. Well, this is gonna be the end, but yeah you're right. This is the climax. Right. And and he's
he's gonna be the only one sitting. On the boat as they're sailing out to dump it. And the this is such your right austin and this is such a great seat. We get shark
whispering as, like the devil on his shoulder
Shark is just a greedy
k.
Of of the lawyer.
He is trying to convince the curator that these are your deeds
to North America now. You've got it. And, you know, the curator kind of asks him, what what payment
we we're not meant to
to think he's taking it seriously.
He's just kind of asking. What payment would you expect for being my lawyer shark?
This is gonna be another great gag near the end where his fee is always something
exorbitant, like say Canada.
And this is really cool. We
We've gotten kind of some hints of this before. But now the the helmet itself is kind of taking on
this like, power. And whether you think there's some supernatural element or it's just the promise of all that power, which is like too much for one human to literally hold in their hands. Right? It is... It is this corrupting
thing,
like the one ring and the lord of the ring right.
But it it's doing it. To the curator.
And
the nephew,
one of the nephews,
Eyeball eyeballs the curator
and notices
that the old chance getting a strange
glean
in his eye. Mh. And that gl is gonna be our warning.
That a character been up it. And and suddenly, the curator gets over his exhaust and tells Donald to turn south where because he has decided that he'll be the owner of North America.
Warren, how how does he deal with the fact that he's not ola ups next to Kin? Well, now the curator wakes up He's holding the deed. He's holding the helmet and donald Claims where you you're not the next Kin because you're not a akin of off the blue. Barks clearly says it again? Al
fun
dumb. How can you prove that he isn't? The second time he's used Al line, and he'll continue to use that.
Line, and the gl
curator is just holding out of that helmet with with dear life and then he says claim that Shark is absolutely right. I can own North America. This map in the helmet are my deed to the continent. Yeah. Al austin any comments. And and if no, can you tell us about the caretaker of plans?
Yes.
I'm I'm just shaking my head over here, Like, it just gets so ridiculous
I
so much. I mean, on my first read, right holding the Gladstone print in my hands. At the end, they've got the helmet the cure stepped in and I'm feeling the pages and I'm like, wait a minute. There's too much to go. It's not over yet. So, like, this is this is just a seriously
bizarre turn. But we return the page and the curator is just so excited. I'll run the country for the benefit of the
Everybody will love to go to a museum
twice a day. And, oh my god. He is just going to z over
museums. Every Sunday, there's gonna be a museum party. People will bring their lunches and study ancient Breaker rock. I love that mind.
You know, he just don't forget he just want a hundred miles. So while he's he's rambling on it on, he just totally does off, and Donald picks up down and tries to throw it away. Oh, it's great. I loved
I love the Nephews reaction. Yeah. To
what the curator has in mind one I'm like, ugh I think I liked Azure still better where he was gonna be slave.
Yeah But what a great moment here. It's so rapid fire. Right? As soon as the curator falls, Donald picks it up. And he winds
way back and any kind of phrases in place, and button and an nephew and my print Hue, he yelled at him throw it. Don't you go getting a gl in your eyes What do you think warren about Donald vision? Well Donald vision is
interestingly,
his the cloud of of this king of North America holding the throne wearing a... I mean, sitting on a throwing, holding the helmet wearing a crown grasping the deed He looks all powerful yet the image of his
wide eyed stare, you almost wonder if he's in that same kind of transit to point. But, yeah. I think it's I think it's so funny. It just the vision of him as king over it is. And it adds to the slaps stick of the sequence. I mean, the trade off back and forth from crashing boats to who's got the helmet, and and now we're back in Donald hands.
Yeah. He's definitely
seen this vision of Grandeur jury for himself but there is again shark with Whispering and Donald here, tempting spot you're in, I'll gladly the year lawyer for a fee of course. And then, of course, visit Huey,, who says Uncle donald throw that dog gone helmet in the ocean.
Yeah. He just pro claims no I see no reason why I shouldn't be king of North America. I can be king Donald the Viking kid.
Yeah. Nephew who's taking over the Latin.
Al is fun dumb meaning, We're back on the hook again and they just looked like they've had it. What do you guys think about Donald grand scheme here? Oh, it's scary.
It's it's pretty gruesome. Right? Like really gruesome. It's preview. What is what does he wanna do Austin? He wants to just let people go on just as they are. I won't take a thing away from them. Let them have all the land and oil wells and minds they want, which is just it's creepy because, like, if you think about society functioning like that, it's like,
what that is in saying, that is not how anything were so I like I like shark egg donald on over his
air metering
scheme here that a side could cost a nickel a gas a dime But but a creepy concepts
right over air to own the and layer reads is charging people
to take a breath. It it really
me as a kid that, like Donald was suggesting this. And, like, at this point, the reader is just on the edge of their seat, like, imagine life with Donald as your ruler. I mean you couldn't manage with that, man. Yeah. And and Barks does a great job of making Donald look like really un hinge it's it's great. Every expression here is awesome.
We get... We had our dog Latin where the Nephew comment, G graft is gasp bus on the next page. Donald turned out to be a dirty
snake To donald, I agree with you and I think Donald would not have had this without the influence whatever you wanna call it call it the curse of the helmet, but there is something
otherworldly about this help with. What do you guys think? Do you guys think it's got a super supernatural power? It's just like you know, classic power crops.
I think it's just like power corrupt. You know, there's a different
character
having a different reason each time it's picked up and it works like perfectly well with who they are just like Donald is so non nonsensical. He has no clue what is talking thinking about it in way, like, going back to what I was saying about, like Barks is commentary almost on, like, society and, like, how people function it's just people get these crazy ideas when they're in, like, a situation of power. You just read this stuff, like
a gasp is a dime, I mean... What are you talking about? You know? Yeah. It's just... It's just beyond. Oh, it's great. What what do you think lauren?
Supernatural... Well well, I wanted to think it was.
However,
listening to Austin and and and thinking again about this time in Barks his life when he must have felt that everything he did was like every little innocent move was being taken away from him. To me,
I'm thinking this this thing does hold some sort of power, not not maybe within the metal of the helmet, but maybe just within the idea of having it and, of course, it doesn't help at all to have shark over everyone's sort wanting a piece of this action. I I think it's just I think it's just the power corrupting personally, but it it's funny either way.
So, you know, but it really does number on Donald. Right? Because he
literally
maroon.
His own nephews. This Al not heartbreaking moment. Right? This is some terrible villain,
and you can only excuse it because of the steaks and and the corrupting influence of the helmet. He he drops them off at least with some supplies on an iceberg
intending to send a ship back to rescue and once rescue them once he's king. One of the nephews though has swiped the compass,
which is a great move. Right? It's a great bit of sabotage, but it's also a bit of sell
sacrifice because, you know, one of the others points out how how anyone come back and rescue us.
Alright. So we're we're coming on to the the the closing
out of the story we're Donald is like,
lost in in northern oceans the the kids and the curator and shark. I'm sorry. Azure are just drifting on the iceberg there on. There there's the weather against them. While they're maroon on the iceberg, the kids
are kinda talking about what they know. They realize hey, ice icebergs
drift south.
So if we can shape the iceberg using the axis
that their uncle call left, they can get the bird to move even faster.
And
as we transition back to Donald and shark,
they're drifting in some fog.
Austin, can you tell us I really like this sequence. Tell us about what happens.
Yeah. I I I really like what's coming out. So Shark and Donald, they're just going along
and Shark keeps trying to tell him he should shut off the engine and save the guys, put as usable donald thinks he knows better and he goes, look, I see a pair of lights. Two of them winking right up head.
They crash into something, and it ends up being Al iceberg.
And the two lights being a polar Barks eyes so the polar bear comes on, and he chases shark and donna and love the flag. Poly comes on heats all the supplies, and then he leaves them both stranded with nothing left, but the helmet on the boat alone.
Isn't it isn't it kinda funny how we get this big peril of a polar bear, and we never really get a good look at it? No. We really don't get that I just... I it reminded me that there's such a quick like image of a polar bearing left the north too. Yes. Yes. It is.
But but every... The whole interaction with polar bear is like almost more comic than threatening because, like, Donald
shark like, I don't know what we're gonna do Ask the bay. He's new captain.
And then and then he leaves, like, just absolutely
huge with his mil food. And this leads us into a a classic like
starving to death
a adrift
in the ocean
where donald and shark are music about what they would give away. For just for a Hamburger.
Well, he would give away the state of California because he owns North America. So he would give away California for him... But Barks says you wouldn't get it from me that cheap.
And and Donald starts to wall you know, wondering if this isn't his punishment
Yeah. For his behavior and and trying to get something
from nothing.
And shark definitely won't hear of that because Huey, a tiny lawyer. That's right. And this is really time so well. Right? Donald this stew and he sees a silhouette in the distance
that that he believes to be Al off the blue and his old viking ship take revenge. It's a wonderful ghostly image too. I really.
And I think that's exactly what scares him enough to maybe even convince him that he shouldn't have had this. Yeah. And and it turns out austin, what does it turn out to me? It ends up up just being the nephews
on an iceberg
viking
hot rod iceberg as they call it just out trying to look around. So Donald thrilled to see them. Shark grabs him by the back. Don't be rash sir. Grab their compass and some food. You can still be king donald the viking kit. And Donald thinks a few things over and He decides he doesn't want to because I think he had that little
existential crisis almost like, almost
lost
philosophical moment where he's like, I wonder if this is punishment trying to get something taking what wasn't mine, like, I think that's very interesting. Barks doesn't go into, like, philosophy territory very often. I think that makes... Gives a story, like, more of a series five. Yeah. I think that's a great point. Right? Because I think he has a moment where he's like, wow. I've... I've been given the second chance. I can take some redemption here.
And if I don't, I'm I'm lost. Right? So so he's gonna do the right thing. And and then the inevitable thing happened What what we knew might as well happened all the time, The true, the true villain of the story,
boy Barks
grabs the helmet
demands that he'll become lawyer of
owner of North America and of everything
and you guys I love how the nephews are just... They're just gonna wrap this up Yeah with no snow fuss, be had. They've had enough enough no more.
Don't you think this real estate trading has gone on long enough? What what a great wise guy way of putting it? What what's warren What's the nephew response?
Y, you bet, Meaning,
yes. We are gone on too far and then, of course, they grab a macro or a fish and they slap it. They throw it across the ball of the boat. It hitch shark in the face And finally, the helmet and the map land in the ocean. Yeah. Pretty un.
Right. Yeah. And how we get this great like parting
view of one of the nephews
kind of afford alarm looking
using how now no one will own North America If A one of his brother says, get that look off your face.
Darned if you weren't getting a gl in your eye. Just gives him a a swift kick in the butt. Yeah. Yep. But it's a perfect... It's a perfect ending,
and then it's tapped with with another
great ending.
The it's such a nice book weekend. Right? Donald, he goes back to the museum. He was really good at doing that. And he needs to... I think he kinda needs to process.
Everything that's happened. Right? And what better place to process it? And right in front of that ship. And so in his museum, ga, he's gazing at the ship and thinking about how... Yeah, the rugged life had its points, but I don't know. And this time, one of those kind of, like if feminine faye nature loving dandy boys. Ham and Barks him, you know, where where can I find the embroidered lamps shades and
Donald is about to direct him? And he says, you know, on second bottle, I'll take you there. Darn define ain't getting interested in embroidered lamps shades myself
It's such a fascinating.
Ending you guys. What do you make? Warren, what do you make or the ending? What is that? What is B telling us? I think Barks is stating that everyday
simplicity of living is just fine.
Oftentimes g can take over if you reach for too much, and I think that's the more moral of the story. I think it's a morality tail told very very well. This story has really gone up in my, I guess, my collection Inducks stories is one of the top. For sure, based on just the whole hotel of it, but the simple four panel ending it kinda just goes there. Yeah I think that's right. What what do you think cost? What's he saying with that ending? I agree a lot with what you said warren, but I almost think it might be looking a little bit too much into it. I like the message so no doubt Barks had something like that in mind when he was writing it. But I just always find it very nice that this Story in particular,
come full circle. Right? Everything is exactly as it was at the beginning you could insert these four panels into the front of the story and it would have been, like, the same scene. Right? So all that chaos went on and yet, is back to normal. And donald had this little taste of the high that he wanted, but he didn't really want it as much as he thought. Right? And he's back and he's looking at that same viking shift and he's going No that rugged life had its points, but, I mean, I think he's saying in a way with this embroidered lamps shade stuff he's taking up an interest in, like, I'm happy with what I have. So I know
a bunch of people hate it when
you look too deep into Barks, but I guess, like, what's nice is that there is a single message. It's just Be happy with the what you have because you wish for too much, and it's never what you think it is. And yeah your life is probably a lot cooler than you think it maybe. That's really well put Austin that...
I'm wondering is this is this a rep
of, like, uber mass?
Is he... Is he saying? Like, it's not all it's cracked up to be. I think so. The myth and the legend of masculinity
isn't all that great. I mean, I guess, in this masculinity and rugged or not like,
exact synonyms, and maybe I should be talking about rugged
I don't know. I I can't help but think about where the the country is in this time. Right? We've just like it hasn't been that long since world war too ended with was like this really upsetting.
I I think there must have been this kind of, like, almost crisis of masculinity
after the war. And and all that loss. But
I don't know. I I I'm not wholly sure what to make of it because, like this is a very gentle
This is kind of like an endorsements
of gen utility at the end. Right? Like, and it's... If you think about, like Donald Duck worst nightmare,
where Donald just had this, like, freak cow that he could be associated with tat
Say, and now he's like, eagerly going off to learn about embroidered lamps shades it. It it's it's a really interesting closer to me. But but I I think you guys have great points about kind of that like emphasis on on the simple life. And it is okay to just be a very good museum.
Guard. So so you guys we we did it. We've talked about this legendary
story
Al at least we've talked about the action of it. I feel like we could go on and on about this, but we've... I wanna kinda kinda limit ourselves to, you know, what are your overall closing thoughts
about the story. Austin and you wanna start off? Sure. I didn't think a ton of it on First read, which was a couple months ago. Like I said, it was after a bunch of other Barks stories, dozens of the adventures and
couple hundred of the ten pages. So I mean, I consumed so much of the genius at that point. But, I mean, certainly after discussing it tonight, like you said, weren't, it would it would probably be higher on my personal favorites list also. You know, it's it's less more because the drawing style is so simple yet so detailed
Barks was counting the syllables on each page. I mean, this last page alone is easily
fifty, sixty words maybe even less than that. I think it's a great story from any angle and a in a really meaningful one. Think we a nice discussion with the the ending and it's overall meaning also. Excellent. What what do you think Were? And how does this one how does this one leave you? Think there there is there a moments of humor, which we want in a Barks story, but humor doesn't dominate. I think there's this all these wonderful Gladstone of mythology of ancient
history, all these wonderful
glimpse of incredible artwork.
But for me, it was this trading off of of power and agreed that whether you look at the helmet is with mysterious powers or just the symbol of whoever holds it
becomes powerful at least in their mind, to me is one of the biggest Al details that he's told and so for me, that exchange... Can I go back to breaking the story up into the the parts? It this last third of the story was so critical to tell, and it... To me it just got me thinking about how perhaps we all live our lives and finding that, again, the last four panels. There's nothing wrong with just the simple life. Thanks for that. I I love this story. This is this is an all time favorite. This is certainly a top five story for me. In in the case of, like, the index ranking, you know, I we're not covering that because here because I already mentioned it like, number three,
that's pretty much right on the my. This is a top five top ten.
It is such a wildly
invent
adventure story. And and that's kinda what I come to. It's got some great things. Don't get me wrong. I love the themes. I love the idea of the corruption.
I love the kind of the the the
that, like,
vein of of...
What is it? What is it to be a man in nineteen fifty two and this like weird time and history? All of that stuff is great.
But like the bones of it is this
incredible
race
for a a token. Right. A a an artifact. And we've got this great, like a a mystery
where we don't even expect there to be a mystery.
It is an incredible treasure hunt
with not a trace of Scrooge dot. In sight.
It is just filled to the brim with some of Barks absolute
best art. You know, he was doing exactly what he wants. To do apart from, like Donald Du,
California. I don't think there's a time that he's felt, like, better about what he's trying.
When he's when done Inducks story then this one. We we have these wildly
invent terms of phrases and this just bonkers,
lawyer character, this amazing
life snake
dis just
The the villain I love to Huey,, more than almost any other... I I I could wax on and on.
About what a great old fashioned
rip roaring
story the Golden Helmet it is. I I I I can't say enough kind things about it. I I think it's one of his utter masterpieces
You you cannot go wrong if you wanna introduce someone to Carl Barks.
Give them this store. Right. I mean, the only the only way it could go wrong is because they might expect all of them to live up to the greatness of this. But Al mark. Yeah. And and you mentioned about Scrooge Mc dot, not even appearing in here or being mentioned and and
while the growth of donald and the the execution of the storytelling this rip yarn,
it had a lot of that that
adventure that I discovered when I first locked razors so the lost start. It was a movie when I saw nineteen seventy nine when it came out. I was just over twenty years old, and it blew me away. Yeah. But I just wanna throw him before we wrap it up. You know, before we record it, I look Inducks and it's greatest donald
marquis story of all timing. What are you talking about? I guess, from an objective point of view, it... I mean, it it honestly might be it's got so much so much depth to it so many overlapping.
I mean, there's a lot to like about it. It really is. Yeah. I mean, I don't beg reg anyone. If you don't think it's the greatest of all time that's fine. I'm I'm not even sure I'd call it the best donald duck adventure. But it's it's way up there it's gotta be in the conversation. So you guys just just a few more reflections before we line things down, you know, at as be fitting, one of the greatest
stories that Barks ever did. He of course, he, of course, did a a a pretty awesome oil painting for this one. Right? It, of course has to adapt that great panel. Did you guys come across I guess started another oil painting? That was Donald siding the star. He only got up to doing a sketch for it. But but that could have been pretty cool too. Yeah. That was one of my favorite drawings in in the I'm looking at it right now. And and Mark, I was not aware that that Barks started that Al an oil. But no. It it that little panel became the cover, which we came the oil painting is probably one of the finest depictions of Donald Inducks and the nephews. I still think Sheriff bullet Valley is the best cover. But that's just.
Oh. It's this ones. This one's up there and my top five covers. I will send right now. So you guys... I'm I'm gonna talk about some sql
kinda mall over the the last thing to do is just favorite panels, of course, which I know is a is a big order
So there there have been a couple of of sql.
Don Rosa did a really cool follow
called the last charts of Columbus. I really like that one as far as his
as far as his sequel go, kind of the evo guardians of the lost library to me, which is like one of my all time favorites. So
I think that's a very successful sequel. I know that that for some people, your mileage may vary with rose, but I I love that. One. There's another one by famous Italian. Austin
you're more... I think you're more versed in the Italian dot artist and I am. Do you know mass Da?
The story I I don't know if I know the story. Yeah. So it's it's a Mickey mouse story actually. It's
mickey Mouse in the Of America, but I think it must be a Mickey and donald story. I would be really interesting to read that. I know I know that a lot of people really like human. I don't think I've read single one of it. Wow. Yeah. He he does great stuff. We don't have that one in America yet though. So Dave Ge Fan graphics thinks if you're listening. Yeah there you go. Yeah.
Yeah.
To localize. Sure. I guess it is worth mentioning on the topic of Italian stories and sort of sequel
Romano Sk did a story called z papa e
costco the auto, which is uncle in the Golden Helmet.
It has no relation to this story but just when you directly translate it's the exact same title. So when we work. Okay.
They changed it to captured in Banana and, which is a great story. So you guys should check that one out. But nice. Yeah. I'll make a point of it. There was also
an Italian pre just a couple of years ago. That kind of hide.
I guess, it tied Golden helmet and with Land the hi Inducks a little bit. It had... It actually featured Al off the blue.
In in his day and encountering the Huey, guys. So another one that I'll have to check out, not aware of those. That's great. Thank you for sharing this. Yeah.
Reflections on how this holds up. I I think there are certain elements where it's kind of got a time capsule quality, but on the whole, I think this one just holds up incredibly well. Doesn't feel modern, but it does feel time to me. I mean, it's it's certainly a timeless
Plotted, it's core, you know, who's gonna be the leader of North America. That's definitely something we can still connect with seventy years later. And and those state just just states.
And you know, I didn't dwell on the fact it is weird that it's just North America and not South America when they are connected, but that's not what Barks wanted to it to do. And, of course, you know,
it it... It, of course, ignores the people that were already there. But again, not the store looking tell. I did find this very edge occasional one, I learned about what a sex was from this. I learned about puff and the word Karen.
This one really fired my imagination in a way that I like it informed me about kind of viking and the north, the northern oceans. The one thing that I learned was the the term He. I had not heard of that. So I went and I went and Googled it and and and I read all about the he of continents and an off sure and the rocky, you know, structures that were there. I mean, he he uses these incredibly
accurate terms to build on the the lord. Oh, I learned so many little geographical terms. From from reading Barks stories. As far as I known either of the Ducktales.
Series
ever adapt or featured this. Well, you guys the the last thing to cover unless someone has another thought. This is a hard hard thing. Favorite panel. This is just
crawling with amazing panel.
So
Warren, what what do you got? Well, I I have I have four favorite panels, and I'll just quickly go over them. Mh the first panel get of the story is one of my favorite panels because it sets it up. It shows the board
with the background of the viking ship in the museum, and there's humor in it, there's
anticipation, and there's Donald as we know Donald. It's Al largest panel in the whole story. I like the
when he comes home and meets nephews and gets them one to go to Labrador, when he do and they say what is that a movie? He just slams his head and wall. I mean, how many times do you feel like doing that? And he did it I love that. And the the other two panels are on the same page. It's where he's he's positioning at the sex. I love that angle of of where he's actually
showing more about how to find the nor star or whatever he's doing there. And then, of course, the bottom panel that we talked about it a lot in that that is my favorite of dark and light and color and rugged and it's just wonderful. So those are my four panels. Those are all excellent choice is that I would be happy to echo any of those. What about you, Austin? Okay. So I'm gonna cheat a little and say that I think all the panels are awesome. And I
Wanna pick one. So I just wanna give another shout out to the cover, which I just think is so wonderfully rendered and just so awesome and appealing. Just to me it's such a nicely drawn image It's
I just have... I've had it at my side for the entire two hours, and I've just been doing nothing but staring at it if you see me looking off to the right size It's just it's so awesome. On the cover. I think that's very fair. Like of all the stories, this is a good one to say they're all great because they are
I really do echo all of those excellent choices warren. I I'd love to kinda highlight a couple of quieter ones like him wrapping on the peg is really great as he finds the the deer skin The... There's Al amazing
spec dev on the the second page
of the viking ship at kind of an angle that that is just a wonderful shot.
Anytime someone is holding up the viking the the Golden helmet, especially donald with the helmet in one hand and the parchment and the other pro proclaiming he'll be king donald with viking kid.
Anytime someone gets a gl in their eye, donald siding, it really is a great obviously that amazing panel where they find the helmet. The the ic view of America is such a good panel.
I've I've looked that for longer than I cared in there. And just the karen
of rocks with that sc puff. I love to.
I'm sorry guys. I I could I could on not I'll I'll save it for a facebook. Just the last one, I guess is the nephews
hugging on to that mass
schultz of the bone. With it with Icc
water. While Donald
is,
you know, dogg
sailing on let I put a great a great piece of art and care characterization and and dialogue this story is. Alright. Thank you guys for me. Thank you for all your time. This has been a a pretty extended episode. I really appreciate. This was an awesome
conversation.
Like big thanks. Yeah. I think we had a great discussion about this one. Any any closures, any final thoughts here? It's a great story. So I mean, I don't know. If you haven't read it, and you listening to this. I don't know what you're doing. Go find a copy. I'm gonna echo Austin and and Mark and say that if you haven't really
read and looked at and admired a Barks story. I give if it's a ten pager or a thirty two pager
you've got to experience it. This is the one to launch you into that addiction to the duck man. Again, I'll say at one last time
often from the depths of spare as Barks was experiencing come great work. This really at the age of fifty. He was halfway through his life and there were a lot more excellent things to come. Yeah. Absolutely.
Well, you guys thank you again. We did it. I'm I'm so thrilled.
I
invite listeners to to come back next week when I get to feature
the great story, the gil man. Please reach out on the Facebook page,
Barks remarks Facebook page, We... We've got an Instant now. I'm I'm on Instagram as well. Our extra Barks on Instagram and Twitter and
thank you guys again. Don't don't go getting any glean in your eyes.