We can have
Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer an artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comments of all time. Join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks. Welcome back to Barks remarks. I'm mark Sever a grown man who enjoys Inducks comics and enjoys talking about them with guest hosts.
May I ask my guest host for today's episode to please introduce himself. Hi. I'm Fay Cam res. I'm a lifetime
Carl Barks.
And I've also done a lot of professional Disney comics work as far as commentary and translation and localization. Apps. Thank you so much for coming back that. I had had a lot of fun on our hours of the... That was a blast.
Yeah. That was a said. A letter on last.
Yes. That's right. Good old Borrower war, Canon. I really like having people
join me for to talk about stories that are personal or special,
to them. And we've got one that is is
today. We're we're gonna journey to British Kia
and talk about the guild man, and I gather that's a personal favorite of yours. Right? Yes. It actually is.
Interestingly,
it was the first one of Barks of stories
the long adventures anyway that I read, the first time I read it, it was in the original
publication from nineteen fifty two.
Because
our friend David Ge picked me up a copy at one of the... I think it was the Baltimore comic gum. He said like, oh, no. I got this really cheap. It's a good copy. It's one of our is best, and he sent it to me. And
Interestingly,
that grace the first Gladstone issue of Donald Duck. Yeah. That's right. They picked it for their... Their return to... For were their there beginning the publication just like we got... I think Tara the B boys was another of their first. Mh. So just... We're just checking those off If I ever branch out into
a Floyd Gottfredson some podcast, I'll have you on for seven ghost? Oh that's one of the best Yeah. That really is. And and it's true That is this is a classic. This is one of the all time great I would say, I really like this one as well. How know that I'd call it like an all time favorite, but it's it's way up there. I've read this one. So many times, I think I first read it in their giant album
where where it was... It was paired with a couple of Barks other South American team stories.
What to talk about little little bit of the background for this one, you know, you mentioned that four color publication it was originally in four color four hundred and twenty two and
so so you've got an actual copy of that one which is pretty neat. It's always thought the cover was the cover art was interesting and a little bit misleading. Right?
A little bit as,
you know, El dorado himself is depicted like as as just a giant
So I I imagine that some people might have been left down by that original one but
Al any rate, July of nineteen fifty two is the publication date. Had a good number of reprint in the Us as most of these all times have. Nine counting the original And this is a thirty two page. So there's there's a lot to cover here. It's it's among his longer stories.
I'm very interested that when I when I think about these stories, kind of the thesis of these episodes is, what is special about the guild man? Right? What makes this one notable, what makes it unique among Barks stories
right away, we've got a we've got a somewhat rare Gladstone
adventure story. Do you think about Glad in the adventure length once? Oh, he is always a great prank. I I love him and these stories. He's always the ins of the trouble and some capacity when he... And whenever he shows up It's just always, you know, you're you're guaranteed to have an irritable good time. I'm not sure if you mentioned it on the
shell before, but, of course, Carl wife, hated Gladstone with a passion. But, you know, I I I just always loved them. It because he's the guy everyone loves to hate. So... Yeah.
In addition to Bark wife, which I actually didn't know. So thanks for sharing that.
But you you can tell that Barks
himself. Hates Gladstone. Do would. Yeah. Yeah. I mean, he he he created ham right, so I'm sure he has a certain infection form him, but he's really a character
of the type of like flight coming easily to success
that that you you can tell really annoys him. So I always thought that was an interesting dynamic. Yeah. And he always...
At every opportunity, he gets him pom by and a fight with Donald that it's not something you see a lot of actual physical combat and these stories. So
that aggression somewhere. Yeah. You probably get more of it with Gladstone than just about anyone. Yeah. And and you know, it's interesting to me how Gladstone kinda he doesn't go along for the adventure. No
one. Unlike some of the other ones. Mh. So I really like
There's there's a lot I have to say I have a lot of thoughts about this one, but I kinda wanna integrate it into our conversation about the story itself, but but that is what I wanna come back to. You know what What is special about this one? What is unique about this story?
There there are a couple of cool elements to this though. Were you ever a stamp collector? Were you ever a fan of phil? I I assume how accent.
I only had a couple of the cartoon character stamps.
My father would always buy me those when they came out. They had a couple with the warner characters
when I was kid. But beyond that,
they're collecting dust somewhere in frames. So. Yeah. It feels very old, fashioned, but this that's a good hook for this one. Right? I don't think spam collecting is nearly as popular
as it was.
Went when this was published. And there's some interesting, like, real world connections with the the famed
Magenta stamp. Right? I I think that Without question that's one of the most interesting aspects of this story because
the the like Mc, the treasure that they're hunting after is not this legend
artifact or anything. It's like this real piece of a thumb that was published
put out by by the British post office
a hundred years before and in researching this, like, that... There's only one actual magenta stamp out there. Right? And I I came to learn about this, like, ra
scheme
that the, like stamp
slash venture capitalist Barks who have acquired it Have now.
So you can if you are so inclined become a fractional
owner of the actual
Magenta stan. My. Have you ever heard of this that fracture I? I've
probably heard of that concept that expressed another way but this does sound a little out there. Yeah. Yeah I mean, it's kinda to me, it's kinda random reminiscent of an N f t.
Basically,
they'll sell you a a steak in the actual
one penny magenta stamp for a hundred and transferable bucks.
You can you can buy a tiny little piece of it. So
Stanley Gibbons is the... Is the collection house. You cannot you can Google it. And, you know, if it was like twenty or thirty bucks I might have gone for it, but
I I don't think I'm gonna blow a hundred and thirty bucks on it. Let's see. We're we're gonna get into the story in due time. I do want pan a little bit to the international
the international crowd by sharing a couple of the titles from reprint from around the world.
Just in brief I will mention a couple that I really like. I like just the straight up
Which is just donald versus the man of gold and Italian very straightforward.
And then I think I need some French
speaker to clue in because there's there's a title... The French title, it seems like it's a pun. It's
tame
du,
the stamps of the stamp but I'm I'm guessing there's, like, some kind of pun that I'm missing Hopefully, someone can fill me in on that. That'll do it for the international titles.
That there's some pretty cool, like,
historical
mythology
built into this one too. Right? What do you think that? Do you... Do you know much about the Legend of Al auto, the guild man. I just know what the movies told me. I've have never
pursued that. Yeah. So I mean, I I try to research these pretty well.
I don't wanna go
too deep into it, but
this is like, Al an a legend that's based on some fat right there there really was this gil man who was the chief of the the tribe in this area.
Barb apparently got the, like, the place a little bit wrong. It's actually like a thousand or so miles to the west in Columbia where
where there was this coronation ritual
among the the cheap shop people
and and between six hundred and sixteen hundred,
They had this ritual where the new king would be covered with gold dust before he lap into this, like, crater lake called Lake Al.
So well... And I didn't see it in your notes there, Barks, but this story actually got remade a couple of years later. I believe it was in nineteen sixty.
Palm Murray drew it with Mickey and Al nephews.
It's a pretty shock for shot remake but Yeah. Yeah. You're right. I didn't mention that I I I figured you might share. They're... I think there's been a couple of mouse
remake, because I remember reading one in glad that I don't think was the one with with More and Fe, but but maybe maybe my memory is playing with me because... Yeah. That it was like beat for be almost exactly the same.
Well, well, in this case, it was not a flattering
comparison
because, you know, people probably know it. I am not a fan of pulmonary work. Now and it's actually good a little more jade over time because Palmer Murray was not a fan of Carl Barks.
Yeah. He he was very critical of him, and I kinda think he was jealous of his popularity. I was gonna ask, do you think that's a jealous thing? I mean, You would think he'd be make taking shots at Got and more than Barks or something. But... Well, God was in a different
he was in the newspaper era. Yeah. Yeah. But
no. But he was rare among... He was rare among the contemporary is a lot anyone else just had good things to say about them. People like Tony str and a couple others. Yeah.
But,
we're not talking about that story. We're talking about the original. That's right.
Yeah. You know, I I could probably name a couple of Murray stories that I remember fondly and enjoy, but I I wouldn't call myself a a big fan. Right. Yeah. And
let's let's go ahead and get into it. There is a lot say because, again, this is a thirty two pager. So That you and I are gonna
describe the story in turn
and
share are cutting
insights.
And I'm gonna go ahead and open this, start us off with the intro page. Alright. So the gil man has an opening that sees Donald
Basically,
we we were introduced to Donald in his new hobby of stamp collecting, and he is in front of a large prominent map of South America. We're getting a lot of information. Right? Barks telling us a lot about the story in that opening panel
we're we're getting our destination. We're getting what it's gonna be all about. He's listing off some various stamps and their values.
As the nephews enter asking him to take them
to a movie. And so the Nephews basically in short they accuse him of wasting his time.
And he expresses his annoyed and that he's annoyed, and he
educate them about stamp collecting being a quote big business.
Need tells us, he tells them and us the reader
about a particular
stamp that is worth more than fifty thousand dollars.
And I guess we're talking about a half a million Barks or so in in contemporary money. Yes. And the nephews have have a little quit, but why don't you buy one of them and spend the rest of your life paying for it.
And Donald,
she back. He's not gonna buy one. He's gonna sell one. And this is another one of Donald fo,
you know, one of these brilliant plants. He wants to raise enough money so he can go hunting for it. And
it's not it it's the making of good comic book,
but this is
a sensible idea. It's just as much of a gamble as anything else he's done. And quite around, he's gonna encounter Gladstone and this has.
So donald goes dumpster diving, literally looking for rare stamps. And Gladstone catches them. Just have his what he thinks is down Al low as grounding around in waste bins. Yeah. That's right. He's gonna encounter him. We get... We get the impression that Donald has been going to the railroad station a lot. To look through these waste baskets, and we get... We get these lists and he's... He is unable bragging to Glad stone about how much
money or value he's made in finding these
stamps in short
and very predictably, we know it's gonna happen Donald
he's gonna... He's gonna light a fire under Al Gladstone
who is going to use the old Gladstone stonewall what, he... He himself says it, u. Me and my big mouth, I've got glad done
started on
camps, and we hit this narrator box that informs us ten seconds pass
before the past
kicks in and and he comes back calling an entire album and and that really quick before you go to the next page, I love the book.
In in this story. Right? I I love how we start with this Donald than Gladstone
almost like a ten pager.
Mh. And then we get adventure, and then it's like we're we're back to to finish off the ten page or almost. Or it's almost like two different ten pages book ending adventures.
It's an interesting structure for this one. Well this is more of Carl Barks is careful planning. This is he's introducing this element because it's going to eventually pay off later in the story. He's not gonna be Gladstone in the first couple of pages. And as we see, donald calls Gladstone a jug had because Glad don't think she's gotten himself an instant stamp collection, but what he's really gotten is somebody else's
it which just happens to beneath the railroad station and he goes to see final Al there we go. Tell us about the name that. Yeah. No. It's on. A Al is a stamp collector.
So that's just
more more of that clever word play Carlos known for I love it. So clever went over my head just there. Well Well, I think I can't imagine how many times I read this as like a nine year old before I before I picked up on what it actually meant Right. And Gladstone is of course being his usual self. He wants to keep them waiting because the reward will be bigger. But Donald
is a firm conscience,
and he
being a fellow stamp collector, he does not want to see
that kind of exploitation So they go to one hundred twenty week board Drive, We get we get Donald being guided by his conscience quite a bit in this one Or or at least, like, kind of battling with his conscience. It comes into to play. It tends to more in these glad
stories. So so we head to millionaire row I like Barks ridiculous address is this This time we're on swan more drive and we get to meet this f t Al and I find him super memorable. He is hilarious. He's one of my favorite parts of this story here Al that. Well, he's so.
You can't you can't white them. Right. Right. He's he's rich. Obviously, he lives on millionaire air row. He's a lot more c than say uncle screwed. For example. Right.
And he's a total debts. His his whole thing is that he he has a terrible memory.
Right. This is gonna be the running gag throughout the story.
I'm here for it. I love I love f.
Yeah. And and he realizes that
Gladstone has returned his famous orient
collection.
And and we get this little bit where he's like, considering how did I how did I lose it and he realizes, you know, we're gonna get we're gonna get these comic
inter lives where he's he's leaving things behind. Very valuable things behind
and
in absent mind, And so key
rewards Gladstone.
But we get we get the first
instance of one of Barks, I think one of his all time best running gag that. Yes. We're gonna get a different name. He's gonna miss remember Gladstone name every time and he's gonna refer to him as mister Garfield this first time. Well he keeps forgetting who Gladstone actually is too. Yeah.
Yeah. It's great.
So he rewards him with a thousand
dollars.
And and just leaves Donald
stew. Yes. Because it was just enough to get him down to South America as well. And Donald literally just sits there to salt. And
it's one of the more brilliantly paced pages and Barks stuff because it it it just plays out. Like, so file Al can logically
forget what had just happened because Donald been sitting there so long. But, of course, that only happens the passage of two handles.
Right. And, you know, he calls a mister Al Gin.
He thinks donald this Gladstone
and that he hasn't given him the reward money yet. And donald wig out. He's telling him no. No. No No. Don't don't give me this. And this is this is why I love file
because these pushy like, seeing too it that he keeps the money. See him out. It's like, Imagine mister Garland Goose pimples didn't Water Reward how confounded noble can a person get. And Donald is thrown out with a thousand bucks
I love that line. I'm so glad that you read it. Yeah. I love that that next name of his
And I I like his outrage, like, he he the only time he becomes heated and not Al is because he really wants to make make things right. He wants reward him. So this is this is great. This next page Donald is walking out with a thousand bucks in hand, and he's got this like, internal battle that he's got here. Mh
Because he he knows, you know, it's not ethical to take it. It's not his. But but he does this thing that, like, a human being would definitely
do. Well, like say you can easily... He rationalize
it... He as he's walking away, You know, he doesn't even stop. He just... Mh he walks out, he thinks I don't wanna make him feel silly by returning it, and he I don't want him. Bear with him. He's such a nice guy. And then kind of the the the final blow is that he talks himself into... I'll give him first crap at buying the magenta stamp. Mh.
And just like that, he's rationalize
it. You know?
Mister Alex not gonna miss, I guess. So... Right. Yes. This this page is very reminiscent of the luck of the North page, which I'm sure you discussed
With this conscience. That quite as good, but it... This is what separates Carl Barks from the other creators. They never had
the other guys never had their characters have this kind of internal time. Right? And make you... And make you really feel Al. Not someone else. There's no parallel
Yeah. You you're absolutely right. This this is brilliant this internal battle. The steaks aren't as high as luck of the north, but it's still the equivalent of ten thousand bucks.
So...
Yeah. I I won't criticize Donald too hard because whatever, it gets us it gets us to the next part of the story. This this is a great way to to launch the story. It's a little less pat than say, uncle Scrooge ping to get them out of town at the beginning of dangerous to disguise.
Right. Yes. It's a nice little setup of them. We're arriving, and
we see that the local
are kept to this stamped collecting business and Derek splitting and for all it's worth. They meet a woman, and she says c
I have trump big trunk attic. You pay one dollar you can see, and
This is five stamp collectors. We got from this week Pedro. You know, they they literally keep it it seems like everybody in the whole that whole part of South America is keeping a trunk of old letters just to exploit the Magenta app people. Yeah. That's right. I I like the sequence it feels very Barks to me. Right. The like, the people in the quote
sophisticated
country are getting a leg up. Oh, yeah.
Yeah. That's generally...
Yes. For the time period that's generally what the smarter writers tended to do. The so called ignorant foreigner are actually smarter than the Americans.
Know, Right. And we've definitely got a little bit of the stereotype or the true
of the like lazy
latin Americans,
but
but but in general, you know, the this This will be one of the kind depictions.
Part the story. No Al.
Right.
Yeah. I I like this sequence here in Gi. It... At the time, this was British Kia is now it is now heavily independent for for the these folks.
They have an encounter on the next page with a... What turns out to be a stamp collector from Boston.
They they mistake it for a potential bo constrict ripple through this trunk of old letters This is the part that I remember the most from that Murray story you remembered. I think they were doing the same behind for be. Yeah. Yeah. The same kind of tour of people's attic And after,
you know, many houses of this, we... Barks gives us the idea that the docks are getting very weary and the Nephews have a great way of summing it up. They say, yeah, we're quote taking a sort of Cook tour of the Georgetown
attic.
At one dollar per attic. That's a great turn of phrase. To mean.
And this page closes out with Donald getting a a supposed bright idea saying that he wants to look at the
the mail records for eighteen fifty six. You're right. We we did get into the year of the the stamp. Yeah. I never actually said the full title of the stamp did. No. It is the the British kia
one cent
Shen,
which is which is of course, officially the world's rarest
stamp take us to that next page and his visit to the post office. Yes. Visit to the post office is quite cynical. We're tipped off
by the signer there. Yes, we have no magenta stamps. A little turn on yes, we have no banana hand. Yeah. Yes. And there's already seventeen stamp collectors ahead of Donald request. And he just leaves and discussed. And this the story takes another turn when they see when the nephews, see old man and get hit by his speed mode and fall to pi water, and there's more of that junior wood check ingenuity that can't go in to get save of them. So they throw castor oil. Well that just happens to be there to make the old man on the Applicants and Ast oil, what a great old time trope? Your you're a fan of the the classic
animated cartoons.
Yeah. This this isn't in like in seems like it's in every fifth cartoon of a certain of a certain time. Yeah. Any anything involving small children, it'll will be there. Especially and especially with some of the r game two realtors to. Yes. This is it's a nice supposed segue that actually is moving the story forward because this old man is gonna give them the tip they need. Yeah. That's right. And and so they do save him by giving him the castor oil, make him una
to the per brianna.
Per of course. I hate to disappoint people who imagine that per brianna, like, quick and are an actual
danger but but, apparently, it's it's a bit of an urban myth. They're not really gonna gonna, like, eat you down to the bone in in moments. Like they might bite you, but that this old man would survived. Mh. And so, you know, he asks them. He tells them how grateful he is, ask if there's anything he can do for them and and the nephews... One of the nephews kind flip says, hey, maybe you can help us. We're looking for a one cent magenta stamp of eighteen fifty six, and
we get this nice little po moment with him where he is like, reflecting how that... That's kind of a running joke around here, but but in my case, I actually
do know I don't know where one is, but I do know who has one.
And and he tells them that it's in the hands of El dorado, the guild man. And I think we kinda gloss over that On on the way over, the Inducks were reading like a travel log that explained a little bit about the legend.
Of El dorado, but this is widely known. Right? Like... Yeah. This is this is Al legend that even today, a lot of people are still familiar with. Yes. It's a little bit of Carl for foreshadowing there.
When they're reading about it in passing. And we get the explanation from the old man that it was his father
who who originally had the letter with the stamp. He was a male carrier, and he got robbed to by a band of strange indians and carried and he was carried away to the jungle. He managed to get away but El dorado kept it. And nobody... And nobody believes him, unfortunately.
Just seems to be another tall tell, but the Ducktales this as an upper community, know, Yeah. This the this is their reality at play. They're gonna help this old man
prove his prove his father was telling the truth and they're also gonna get rich. Too. Yeah. That's right. It's very convenient. This this old man this old river man is is like a a very sad part of the story. Right? Because he's been, like, spent his whole life basically trying to prove his father's story. I like that element sad where, like you said, you know, Bark keeps, like, four foreshadowing things. We get this reference to the silver Ducktales
and the mail tab. Yes. It's the silver Ducktales. Yep. Yeah. That fascinated El dorado. So as you said, you know, they cut a deal with him and
they go off in his instead. A charter a helicopter.
Where were to assume that they're gonna use his tips
to to kinda locate the last
spot. The little the last known siding. And I like fat that on this couple of pages
over the helicopter with with the helicopter, ride, we get this kind of, like theme of development
that Barb likes to touch on talking about how much the area been developed. Yeah.
Because at this point, they're in like the Savannah, which is which would have been jungle Barks when his...
The river man had his one and only siding of.
Yeah. These are just more dicks of how pushy things have gotten, but the world still has uncharted territory,
The Inducks are going back into danger
once again, the dangerous jungle where it's so fit where it's so thick. Even dinosaur could live here and Severino seen Donald says. It's kind of funny this on the... And the last two panels of this page is almost something... It should be terrifying, but it's almost comic cold but too
because then nephews user saying, well, you you don't notice the jaguar that's about to jump up
it's...
But the boat constrict got him first. Our old. There's a there's always a bigger fish that. I I like that you you highlighted what Donald says how there could be, you know, something that that's a common theme of Barks. Right? I and that's something that always fired my imagination as I was a kid, the idea that, like, there were still things to discover. Mh.
Even in the modern era of the nineteen fifties.
Yeah. You know, there were still these really thick junk.
Tell us just take us through the rest of this jungle sequence because it's kinda of brief and bliss surprisingly. It is brief and brisk, and I think it's because
Bark new and his head that he had visited territory like this before. And he has more interesting stuff to get into. So he just wants to establish
the kind of danger the Ducktales going through.
Donald thinks his skin is wiggling from the cr, but it's actually Al Ant,
and they still haven't reached anything for days. And
all of a sudden,
it's kind of... It's a bit of an adult reference
Dewey we got a monkey on us back, literally.
And do it just does not seem prepared by it at all because it's just Like he says it's tame as a kitten because compared Al the other danger they've been through who cares if this monkey sitting on me. But donald on wig out
a came monk you mean somebody
lives around there. So he gets the bright idea to shoot the monkey off and they're gonna follow them wherever he goes. Yeah. It's interesting that Barks gave Donald
that, you know,
realization. Yes. He would normally do that for the Nephews, but they're kind of just exhausted.
Yeah. He's not really interested in this... It's a cool sequence.
I like it. But it's it's not like you said it's not the story that he wants to tell. So, yeah. Go go ahead. Can take us take us up to the temple. Yes. So the... So they show the monkey away and they follow them. All of a sudden it's a quick journey because they're able to they have a lead finally. And, yeah, they get to the temple and if they think it's a deserted mining room and they don't see anything but monkeys the the the inhabitants aren't actually there yet. And they take a look inside and that one says it's kind of a museum
and they see all sorts of things that Al dorado and his men have taken from various explorers over the centuries
And
we get into one of the more well known sequences of Medic Huey, and Barks stuff. Oh, yeah. This didn't happen very often.
One of the nephews gets terrified
by something and yeah. Stuff docks.
This is pretty weird. Right? It's it's a little off putting. It's a little off porting. If you immediately reminds me of a cartoon that Jack Hannah Carl Barks old collaborator Al the Disney Studio had done...
They've been in theaters maybe a year or so before Barks wrote the stories the lying around. And Donald said his... And Donald Ga is getting pursued by a lying and he poses as a Ducktales,
to right. I don't wonder if Carl, you know, he he didn't go to the movies a lot, but I he saw that I think he saw ja and he said hey that's a good gag jack came up with and... Yeah. You gotta assume he'd keep tabs on what they were up to a little bit, little old studio. Little ben. He was pretty isolated as a creator, but I I don't think he was above that, especially with people you worked with before. Helena? I want a backtrack just a bit to their arrival at that temple. I I love the pacing.
Yeah. So much. On on that one that rhythm of donald like emerging through the jungle growth and seeing u
a paved path then he just looks up slightly and they see a o again
temple. It's really fore bow. It's really imposing looking. It's very
spooky. Yes. And this... Yes. The staging is some of his best. It's very for forgotten. It's like this is empty.
This doesn't feel right. We better do what we came here to do right away. Yeah. It really feels very. I remember this feeling very un unsettling.
He really shifts gears masterfully to make this whole
sequence
very creepy. I feel like he's there than anything in the jungle. Yeah. It's true. I'd like the the camera has this... The the camera. That we know.
Yeah. Yeah. The the purse effective through most of it is so low to the ground.
And it's just... It's gonna pay off when we get to.
To the big payoff.
Here, I'll I'll let you do that pay. I'll just... I'll just mention that, you know, they they do continue
to look for for what they're pursuing. And then they find it. They find the mail sack. It's got its own room
which they kind of ascertain retain it. It It's because it's it's it's in a place of honor because it's the only silver item. Mh. And and so tell us about the sequence where he opens it. Yes. The... Yeah. Donald this two Craze to realize what his nephews do that this has been too easy. Found the stamp Al last yelling and, the fifty thousand dollar beauty and they're not... They have no reaction other than other horror something above donald and, hey, the scams here, what the dickens are you kids staring at? And
big reveal that takes up about three eighths of the page, El dorado himself. Yeah. It's it's a great reveal. It's it's gotta be one of Barks best, like, page.
In in any of his stories, The way that the like you mentioned it, the way that that panel
stages is the reveal makes him so imposing. El silverado himself looks spectacular Right? Like, he's this weird
mismatch of of native
tropes with the bone through his nose and and,
you know, I don't think it looks like any Indian in that area would have. So
Like that's a criticism you could level. But I don't think there's any denying that he looks in imposing. He looks
terrifying on his very detailed and art drawn. I guess he's human is need that. Yes.
Yeah. So we don't get We don't get an explanation how he's existed this long. Yeah. It's weird. Bark is totally interested. Like we never really question as he like, long lived is he immortal. Is there like a a chain of Dorado and it's hereditary?
Right.
He's not interested in that. He is interested in having him be this totally imposing.
Terrifying figure. Right. So So on the next page, you know, Donald been caught he has this, like, half hard attempt to... She says pardon. We we thought you were out of town. Tremble. Yeah And we get... So El dorado
commands
that his, like men sees him. We get this, like, kinda trope that bark really light. Right? This, like, native lingo
that sounds
quote native, but also has like an English pun. I don't think it's aged that well, but it's not probably not the biggest sin of of these stories. It's it's It is what it is. It was it was a it was a common trope of the day. Right. And they sort of go... Do away with that a lot... If he does away with the elect with what he likes What he really likes to do is show what the translation really is and have them talk
Right. The basic English and sometimes
distorted English too, you know, just as any
street wise tough would. Tomorrow these runs would dare touch my price silver metals. Al get the royal works.
Right. So we we get some motivation for El dorado. We don't get to know him very well or or very long, but we do know what this character is all about. So so the docks get tossed down into this like dungeon that crucially is is below ground. Right? And they're just left to kind of faster and talk about the situation what happened. And they're are kind of
recollection what the old river man told them how El dorado is nutty about silver. Mh. And that's that's gonna segue way into the Inducks Brainstorm.
Yes. And that's why the Nephews hit the force site. It gets a bottle of silver pain at a dine store because they they predicted that
this might be able to help them at some point if if Al dorado was that nutty about silver.
I've gotta say I I respect sparks that sometimes he's like I don't need to do the building block for this. I don't need to have two panels that shows the kids. At the Die store. Right? He can... He... He's in a a good enough story. We know that they're resourceful.
So he can just allude to it. It works for me. Right. And it works because the nephews only had the idea to bring it. They have no idea how it's gonna get them out of trump.
Just have this option, and now they have to really say Of course, Donald is the big one who gets punished first.
Right he's hold out of the dungeon.
And the nephews figure out that El must weigh a ton if he's covered in gold dust. And of course,
being junior wood shots, they know that something's gotta be holding them up and they see that the pillar is what's exactly holding them up. Right.
So we we get this nice sequence on that next page where they're pondering what what was that we thought he'd weigh two tons.
I love the Nephews really determined look. Let's see as they start shipping away with their trust junior with Chuck and knives, I assume And the predictable happens, you know,
El dorado is in the middle of some sort of punishment
ceremony.
Right. He pave in through the floor the... We we get a little a little bit where the other natives are concern that the gods must be angry. It's a little eye and it's not it's not a big deal. Right.
And so he lands in a days sheep. I love a.
That's a great expression like he's all of a sudden, this guy is no longer here. He's a typical Goo, you know, not cool. Yeah. I like that because he, like, starts out so
imposing. Mh. And then Barks really inflate him. Right. And and so they get the great idea the natural idea the thing to do with the man who's a the golden man who's obsessed with silver is of course to paint him. And
eventually, he's gonna.
Yes and he emerges
and
everyone is beside themselves. You no longer gold, you silver, Inducks what Great magic. And I I think this is where I I think this sort of reveals that Barks didn't really take these tropes to seriously
because now he's making my typical American fashion obsessed first and by going. Oh,
brother
Yeah. Looking at his new silver look, and the duct hike got out of there,
And
one of the nephews has four... More foresight sight, and they need something to help their case.
I I like this reveal too. They found the mail sick and they meet the old man who's
ecstatic and they reveal. Yep. And if anybody still got your father's story, here's a spare pair of Al dorado pants to help you win the hassle.
And
I like that. And it's right. Well, what's great is is that this story is nowhere near over. I mean, they've they're promised the stamp. But there's still... There's still what like, another nine pages left of the story. Right. There's essentially a ten pager worth of material left.
Exactly. This is this is what makes this one stand out to me is that the climax acts is not where you think it is. This is nowhere near over
but it it doesn't feel short at all. It's very brisk, you know, and you said Barks had other places you wanted to take docs.
And this is exactly where he is is taking them.
That's this it's kind of con try, but it also isn't, but it's also logical.
Donald taking this nail set and he gets are acc by a dart, and you can't leave the country with the sec of his majesty mail.
And it's like, no. It's still has to be delivered even if it is ninety six years late. This this next sequence is is great. How is it that that this
sequence
feels
more suspense. Right? Sure I mess mail sack back to
back to the Us is gonna feel more successful than tray
more suspense than tracing through the jungle
and entering that forbid temple.
I don't know how he does it, but but it's it's fantastic. And again, that's what makes this one unique.
The the real danger and interior is not where you think it's gonna be. Right. Absolutely.
So I love... I like that that kinda little bit of conscience comes into play again here where, like, these
these her majesty
mail folks have to do their duty, but they... They're like
understanding when they realize the Donald
is tracking this magenta to stamps so like, oh man, we gotta cut this guy a break after what he seems to have been through. And so they they at least give him the last known
address or the the next
address and it's destined
to miss Susie Bell swan,
sixty Hon Street in Mud,
Ohio
in the Usa.
Mh. And thus
starts this great sequence where they're gonna trace through some of these, like, very Barks
locals towels.
Why don't you tell us about
the that first stop? Yes. They go and no. No miss Susie Ba one lives at that address. She left in eighteen eighty. Gave a forwarding address of ten q Road web foot oregon,
and of course Barks was born and oregon gone, so that's a little out of a thing. Yeah.
You as the distance status? Like, what what was she do that you moved
completely across the country, almost from Coast to coast?
Especially.
Actually that exactly. And this way, this is this becomes a domestic suspense story. Plus this is also showing that Donald actually is a good person. He... He doesn't have to do any of this. I mean, he could just skip with it, but
Just try him.
But, yes. See we've established that donald as an outstanding character in the story. Right for this one. At least for this one, I I love the webb foot. Yeah. The the... I love the Barks lu his, like, weather afflicted
towns. Right? Whether it's like, flood out Ohio
and tear of the river that's in perpetual flood or what is it point marrow and frozen gold that's always being covered by snow. This is And so eventually, they are able to track it to to her where she floated away in nineteen o one, Her forwarding
address is forty five Mall Avenue Inducks
bird,
Al.
So this is pretty significant. Right? That. You wanna tell us about it? Yes. Isn't this the first time, they actually named the state, quote unquote state that duck berg
Yeah. And and I believe that it's the first and only time that Barks uses the the, like, a ama of California
and Minnesota.
To to refer to this fictional Al
stay. I'll defer to what... I'll defer to what you say there because it's so ingrained into my head as Right because so many Yeah. So many Disney comics creators have used it it just... It just feels right. Right. And and and it kinda matches, you know, where Barks sets these stories so many of his stories are gonna be are gonna take place at a California Beach.
But then he's gonna have his winter, Minnesota like stories. So it works. So when they track when they continue to track the story, the trail runs cold because there is now a factory of the tool factory in it's place. And so they have to go back to the post office.
And
this is a great sequence. This is one of the ultimate you love to hate him
moments in in Glad gander history because the duck arrive at the post office at the same moment that their cousin Gladstone does. Right. And tell us about what happens. Well, this is a beautifully stage sequence.
No for you today, Gladstone, but there's a letter here. See you're late this it rather of miss Susie Belt swan. I believe she made you her so air.
And there's a brilliant it's the fourth panel on this page. No. No. No. He dials
faint thing. Donald is just he's just
destroyed by wes. He... He's been able to see this. As soon as he saw Gladstone,
you sense that he knows
what about to happen.
Mh. And
nephew you shoot them away with violence.
I'll wrap this waste basket around your ears.
A great turn phrase.
Barks did that kind of thing like every issue.
Right. And he... And Donald still holding up hope that Gladstone too stupid bed, he'll just think it's old and toss away because he doesn't know anything really about the stamps. But that's
That's counting... That's not counting on the Gladstone look like he should. Yeah. I know. This seems like the triumph of hope over experience.
Mh.
Because
Glad stone does kind of notice that stamp seems a little bit odd.
Yeah. And
and the docks follow him into a very familiar house on millionaire row. Yeah yep. And Donald knows the deal. He's like, we can finally rest because
I Haven't really highlighted this, but, like... This has been such a great journey. Right? They the deduct have been in motion.
So much that we sense that they're just utterly
exhausted physically and mentally.
Yes. And Gladstone
bursts out two minutes later with a lot of cash
telling them that
he just sold a stamp for fifty thousand dollars
and as an aside, hey, didn't you just go to South America to find a stamp? Did you have he luck and the the look of murder that the four du give him, Definitely a stand panel for me in this one. Yes. And the very next one is too it's just like, ink talking and hey. Jealous and my fifty grand.
Did they're holding back everything to not kill him.
Yeah. It's like, come around sometime because and I'll tell you how to make money from the stick bracket. And balance You Donald tell them. Alright. Come on. We can stand anything, but I'm gonna walk home alone. And every ten feet, I'm gonna stop and have a tantrum because, you know, that's the you know, the bait and switch. You think he's over it. But no. He's... No. He's not. He's donald Ducktales gonna flip out. I I love love love love that panel that how he just launched
himself and first into a brick wall, I think that might be my favorite panel of the story. It might be mike too. I I I I kinda I quote... I actually quote that quite a bit. I'm gonna go through. I'm got every ten.
It's so evo. Yes. And like like you said, it's... He does such a great job. He has such a level demeanor until that moment. Right. Ahead. And feel caleb
is... He's in a super.
You know, he's going to... He's going to go to San Francisco code and exhibit this stamp bought for mister Gold.
He's running off and, you know, as he's running, this is more of Barks as brilliant pace taste, and it's hilarious to forgetting as he's going along which city he's actually going to? Right. By the end of the page, he's going to Boston this time. Yeah. He's he's forgotten his hat. But he says, oh, it's fine. I'll put a new one in boston.
He's like, forgetting in real time. Alright. And
just happens to Past Donald who's just shedding his bitter tears over a dark river
and he
F is right behind him.
Mean you thinks he's gonna take a train to Saint Louis or fly and no. It's a trade. And why am I running? That's it's this... You can't help and love this guy. Oh, I do. And he has a taxi but. This is one time where his forgetful is really gonna do him in. He forgets the stamp Al with the Magenta stamp. And who happens to find it donald. That's right. Yeah. He is right next to it. This is a bit of the Gladstone luck somehow. Yeah transferring to him but
but it's like noble. Right? Because I I sense that Donald would have like, really appreciate selling that magenta to stamp to him. For what it was. And and he he is... He instantly
realizes is it's it's violet Al
and he wants to get it back to him. You don't hear him. His internal monologue is not recognizing for a reward even in this one. So really what he just went through to get that stamp. He's not looking it get lost.
Yeah.
Exactly.
And and he so determines to do it. He he arrives at the train station. Thinking I'm gonna take a chance He's probably going to exhibit it in some city. So he hawk his wrist watch, which gets him a ticket on the trade to Chicago but only as far as the Duck City limits.
Right. And then we transition
back to F who is Barks skiing in his recent
acquisition.
I I gotta read his dialogue here because that's just so it's such a perfect gag He says, I'm aboard the train on my way to San francisco.
It's a wonder. I didn't become excited and forget something. But My magenta stamp here would make anyone excited.
And he and he realizes, of course that he has forgotten it. Yes. And this is the one thing he does remember Bur he remembers exactly where he left it. Right. This train won't stop reaches San Francisco. And donald forbes...
This is the strangest of chicago. And I I love that panel where he he Gladstone
my old friend grind
gimmick.
It's just it's just such a great little
character be because you know, got donald done the right thing. And he said, he's about to get like, he should have had coming down. But I don't actually see it. It's just little it's just little ending with the Nephews on the phone. You know, donald... That's not down on these out Al the city limits. You have you got money for carb you got money for camp home. Oh, I'm got fifty grand, I guess I can make it.
I I think I think we sort of summed up going through a page by page market. It's mainly me realize what makes this one so special because it really takes the deduct and places.
You're not predicting where the story is going at any point. It's... You know, there's little past issues, you know, we mentioned it's a little similar to luck of the north where Gladstone stones driven the whole adventure in some way. Yeah. And we've we've seen, you know, the jungle journeys before many times.
But we you've got this wrap. And you also mentioned that it has a bit of a ten page flavor story.
I think in this case, unlike with big t top bed, what you just did, which is just a ten page story and the thirty two pages is This one just has more of the intricacies of a ten pager which wide... Which is why it has that flavor. I mean, big top is just Carl Barks having fun going nuts with how long. Can I make this go? But
this one,
no. He knows how long he wants it and where he wants to take these docks. Yeah. There's a lot of confidence in his storytelling with this one. Right? Because, like, in this thirty two page comic, we
We spend a lot of time in in many different places.
Always on the move always in motion. I think that's why this one might get brushed off a little.
It doesn't have
one it doesn't have one journey in mind. You know, like the golden helmet has that one goal in mind throughout the whole thing. Right. But
I've I've always loved this. I love it ever since I first read it.
I don't... I I don't know if it's my time favorite, but it's like, you don't wanna spare because it's really really, really great. Oh, yeah. It might not just be as famous as as some of the other stories. Yeah. I I feel like this is in kind of the the very top of the second tier if that makes sense. Maybe
maybe it's
You know, I've sometimes, like, will sum up different films and directors, etcetera. You know, that there... There is some overlap in the first to your territory. But for some reason, it... I can't articulate why though because there's nothing wrong with this story. There's nothing that feels bed or con t or holt,
you know, or, you know, well Carl was just filling in this, you know, Carlos was just filling in pages here. This... No it It's
atmospheric, it moves brisk.
It's really funny. And oh... Yeah. It has suspense where you don't expect systems?
I I think we covered it pretty well. Yeah. I agree. I I think this one's extremely suspense.
Very funny like you said, one thing that stands out to me on this, like, as we've gone through it this time, it has some of the best
expressive.
I think of any...
Any of Barks stories, the Ducktales
expressions, glad stones expressions
everyone's face is such a treat to look at. And I I would encourage people to really pay attention
on their,
you know, read through listening to the podcast. To to look at look at those faces, and look at the expressive in this one. Well, this is about where he peek because
as an artist because I haven't listened to your recent episodes, but this was around the time when Carl second marriage went south and he was doing out of his work out of a hotel room. And, you know, I think that fuel him
you know, sometimes angry, can be a
a great vehicle,
and he did he drew and wrote some of his strongest new material ever,
and unlike, as you'll get in into next episodes,
where, you know, something like the western office censorship,
beat them down,
this sort of had a negative impact on his work
This
had had really
good effect on his work. I mean, this stuff is untouchable,
really, as far as the long adventures go. Yeah. And and it's such a unique structure. That that to me is part of what makes it special. That book str.
Yes. So, you know, we've been talking about it, but let's let's
see where the community chimes in. This one is very well like by the community. It's not quite in the conversation
for, like, the all time great But if you take a look on
index, you know, which is Of course, it's not the end all, but it's as good of a measure of the community sentiment we've got. It does generally
make the top twenty. Oh, no. That's pretty good. Yeah. Yeah. I was. That's why better than what I was thinking. No. When I when I looked and, of course, this is subject to change. It'll probably float here and there. Yeah. But never that much. When I looked, it was Al number nineteen.
U.
With an eight point two rating out of ten. So so very good. I I was curious too, and it it is... It is the highest rated story that features Gladstone gander.
Even even out pace is luck of the north, which I think is about ten or so slots down. I I think I might like luck of the north a little bit more. It's it's definitely one of I'm more pivotal and important stories and Barks career. Yeah. Yeah. That that guilt sequence.
Very little in his career Barks quite the punch. Mh. That that does. But but this, you know, it it definitely chimes in with that great suspense.
I remember being genuinely creeped out the kid the first time. I read this one.
So, yeah, Very well regarded as you mentioned, it's been rei imagined by other Disney artists, maybe not as successfully. Right. Don Rosa did do a follow to this one. He did a sql story called the last lord of El dorado. Haven't read that one in in years. There There's a there's a big gap in my
rose memory for various reasons, but
I I just don't remember that one being particularly
unique but maybe like this one, it's...
An un gem to extend. Who knows. Yeah. I'll I'll have to revisit it.
But but... You know, most of the roses is stories I can remember very, very well. That one I get I've read. I don't I don't remember that. And and then, you know, this one, he had had a pretty great oil for this one. A great painting that had the title stamp collectors bad moment and you know that one? Oh, yeah. The the the Barks being. Yes. Yeah. That's the great one. It's one of his best ones. Yeah. Yeah. I agree. It really has that. It really captures that eerie creepy sense. Right. That they got. I I saw it two that that painter
John Ga has done an a neat version of an un finished, like, concept he did for for the painting called Flynn guild Man which I think this worth taking a look at. And then that, are you a fan of the either a Ducktales series? I can't remember if we talked about this. I believe the fifth on that one.
So
definitely...
I definitely have a soft spot for the original. You know, I was a bartender fan, but four. I... My my
appreciation of the Barks comics dates Ducktales by roughly a year. So you know, as an eight year old nine year old, whatever. Oh, of course. Yeah that it did its job then. Yeah. That's what it did. And and I I think it's a lot of fun.
They never adopted this story specifically. But the
the recent one
which I have kinda mixed feelings. Yes. So that's the I believe the fifth time completely. Got the eighty seven Ducktales guess is good for whatever. Yeah. I I mean, I think that the recent one did some good stuff. There there are some aspects of it, I really like. But then there are some aspects of it that really
puzzled me.
And and the weird little, like, homage that they did in this one.
From an episode called nothing can stop del doc. They have, like, El dorado appear, but as like a mecca as like a robot.
And it's weird. It doesn't bear much but I I don't I don't wanna gloss it. So duck
covered the guild man.
Yeah. So as far as what's dated or our K the magenta stamp is now worth... Let's see. I think I put this down somewhere. I hope I didn't
excluded it. I wanna say it was like it's sold recently for, like, ten million dollars or something like that. But while I Google that, let me ask you that if if you have any favorite panels that come to mind that we didn't already cover, Gosh. I I can't think of it any we didn't cover already. But this it has so many that are burned in my brain that that kinda sending Al a of Gladstone,
donald, stopping every ten feet tantrum. It's really the end of the story that I actually is standing at the most to me because it's just... You, it's just this incredible journey that's now ended,
you know, Yeah. Supposedly so def.
Which is why I I I guess it it I guess is why those panels are burnt into my add so much. Because this is where I it's like, well, wait. This isn't how it's gonna end. Is we make they just lose and this... Oh, I ironic a isn't it ending. No. These Barks is gonna make it the double I. Yeah. You didn't you didn't remember that
Donald ended up with the money lights got the first time. He's gonna get it again. It actually fa me how memorable the parts that are not. The big jungle
temple adventure are in this story.
Like, they really stand out to me. And that there a ton of great panels. You know, the one where they enter the temple at first.
And it looks off forbid. That that one stands out to me, but but like I said, a lot of the just reaction shots
are are really cool the Ducktales expressive
really is what stands out to me in this one. Yeah. Any any other closing thoughts, anything that we didn't mention that you wanted to say about this one. Honestly, if you don't regard this as one of your favorites,
reread it, I I I think you'll be surprised. It's... Like we've said, it's one that, you know, it's just an accepted classic, but
you don't hear talk the lot or dissect a lot about. I guess because it has a lot more famous material surrounding it. You know, it was done in nineteen fifty two when Barks was doing a lot of his best work. But yes. Just... I I have nothing else to say about the guild man other than I don't think it's my fit... It's definitely not my Al time favorite story, but it would be in the top five of the long ventures for sure for me.
That... That's fair. I I think it's very memorable.
And
I think you made some great points. You summed it up nicely. The only thing I'll add is this is up. Awesome story if you wanna introduce someone. Yeah. That's... Yes. And that's why Gladstone don't pick, but I story to print and the their first issue of donald doc. I'd right exactly why they picked it. Because because you're getting it all, you're getting his great art. You're getting his great adventure his a humor. You're getting everything with this story. And I don't think they wanted to pick this one too because they wanted to differentiate the characters
you know, for the new audience that's getting introduced to these characters
because Scrooge plays no part in the story at all. And it's a story around
money and greed a little bit, which is kind of surprising that Karl didn't include him. Room. But I you know, I think it's all the better for that because
Scrooge might have taken it into some predictable territory,
but
That's one thing you can put in this story favor. You do not see where it's going. Where hit. Oh, and I'm so glad we got to meet f t Al Yeah for this one. Yeah. I I would have welcomed having him. You know, I don't know how he could shoe horn another stamped story again, but it would have been great to see him. Coming back. Alright. Excellent. Well, thank you so much, dad for joining me to talk about this classic. Listeners feel free to reach out if you have your own thoughts about this. We we love to to mix it up on the Facebook page.
Both the Barks page and the Barks remarks has its Facebook page.
And please join us next time. Our next episode will cover
the very interesting trick or treat.