Wanna keep
Al.
Welcome to Barks remarks, where we discuss the adventure length stories of Carl Barks. The legendary comic artist and writer of the Greatest Donald Duck and uncle Scrooge comic stories of all times. As you can tell from our a typical opener, we get to talk about a very unique story today. The Donald Inducks
Comedic Adventure Trick Treat. I'm I'm very excited to do so. I being Barks Severino a grown man who enjoys Inducks comics.
I'm gonna introduce my guests and ask them if they've still got the
opening feed to the cartoon in their head.
Warren. How about you? Doing surgery. Can. Yes. I can't get it out of my head. If it were October, I feel a little better about having it in my head, but Yeah. That... I watched the cartoon, the nineteen fifty two. Jack hannah, Cartoon,
several times in preparation for this. Yeah. It's it's not as bad as it's a small world, but it's close. Good to be here that's. Again, I'm a longtime time Barks collector and
always happy to be on the on this this podcast. Pads definitely a catch Al little did. How about you Sarah?
You know, I don't, but I can't sing you the song
that I have in my head
because you don't...
You wanna keep your, like, not explicit rating
It's from Tiktok, but it's, you know, a double on top. I maybe maybe Tiktok will
discover trucker treat at some point. We are your things. Oh,
that would be great. Yeah. They could have fun with it. You guys I'm I'm so excited to do this episode.
Because this is such a unique
and and weird and and strange story and situation
in kind of Carl Barks
history and and his works.
And we don't get to talk enough, I think about the the short cartoons.
Like you, I rewatch this one, but it's on Disney Plus. And so
because I re rewatch it on Disney plus with my kids around. I ended up re rewatch it. Many many many times
because I nearly three year old, every time it finished with would jump up and say, again, I get yeah. I know.
But I love that. Short cartoon. I really do. I think that I may have even watched it
before I read the comment and I've I've try to watch it every Halloween or so, and it's it's nice that it's just widely available on both Disney Plus and Youtube
So
listener, it is required
homework for this episode. We we are gonna be talking a lot. About the animated short that Carl Barks
adapted
this story from in a in a pretty strange round process.
So if you haven't recently seen it or never seen it, do yourself a favor, pause it, take the, like... I don't think it's even seven minutes along. Right, because it's about... It actually is about eight minutes. So it's something seven to eight minute short cartoon.
It's a classic I I too Mark saw the cartoon before I read the comment. So
that... That's my memory of it as a child is to see this cartoon.
Sarah had you seen the car tim beforehand I hand, and I think you watched a lot of the Disney shorts.
No.
I was a
garfield and Charlie Brown Halloween girl.
I watched that very many times,
I can probably, like, talk along with it.
I just... Those are stuck in my brain.
Somehow I missed this one. I don't how did it work originally? Well, it it would have been
warren you wanna tell us how it would have air? Why it would have actually been the theatrical short and in the movie theaters prior prior to the feature film
being
screened in late nineteen fifty two because the the story board was written in February at fifty two, and that's when Barks was sent the the story Barks, he had no film to watch to be inspired him. He was in process while the film was being made. He was in process,
adapting his version of it Yeah. Those those shorts, the cartoon shorts were were big business. They were theatrical It seems weird to think of them now. Right? Because like, I would encountered this on V dhs.
I remember, like, literally the video store that I rented it at the first time, but
the these were theatrical. They were projected
they film on on a movie screen just just like the Loo ones were originally before they kinda got their second life of being
rerun and aired
on Tv,
But know, this was never like a halloween special that would have added on one of the big networks. Right? Right.
Yeah. So this this is a really interesting
situation. Right? And warren you you alluded
to it a little bit. Tell us about how this
economic came about. Most my understanding that as the story board was being developed in the Disney world in the Disney
Studios.
It became apparent that Jack Hannah who, by the way teamed up with Carl Barks ten years earlier for finds pirate gold.
So they... The editors at Western
along with Disney, kinda collaborated and said let's let's just do this grand halloween
celebration with the short feature at Trick treat.
And let's have a comma come out at the same time.
So the story Barks were packaged up and sent over to Western and the editors there.
Alice Cobb was a senior editor, and and I gave those to Carl Barks sit here. Here's a story.
Produce a... I believe, intentionally
I think the originally rather, they had originally intended to do a thirty two page comic, but there just wasn't enough material in the in the cartoon to do it. And we'll get into that as we go through the, but... Yeah. It was one of those like early examples of synergy
cross promotion. Cross promotion. Correct? Yep. And and it's kinda weird that Barks wasn't,
you know, referencing a finished product.
Or anything like that. So you you can kinda tell when you consume both of them that it's almost like, he was listening to someone
around the corner.
Talking
about
something that they were watch I think so. I think it was that experience.
And his own experience with the way he crafted the comic book was in his story board format he had story from another source that he had to adapt. And I think that was the challenge for him was to make it make it interesting but keep the idea alive. And that's where the tension started coming in between the editors and and again as we look through this story and walk through it, we'll point out those glaring differences between the automated feature and know the story. Right. Yeah. And that's gonna be an interesting thing to talk about.
And if anyone was up to the challenge of doing this, it's Carl Barks. Right? Because Right. He... He's at Po genius.
But he also had this very long animation background working with story Barks,
writing gigs. As you mentioned, he worked with Jack Hannah. So this is like,
almost a reunion.
Although, obviously, they didn't actually get to, like, meet with each other over work with each other again. And right.
But, yeah, it would have been great in a way if they had collaborated on this. That would have been school. And I when I was a little disappointed. I'll just say right now, and now I understand the sequence of events. It would have been great to have Barks get a credit on the film, but he had nothing to do with the film, so I get it. Right.
So was Jack hannah like, Hannah Barks
like that same hannah or...
I know the name Jack hannah from something else too. Didn't he do like a name of a wildlife.
Yeah.
Right. No, I... It's not it's a can. Huey, stayed with Disney for quite a while. Right. William Han. His Hannah and Joseph.
Those there's a few famous hannah and animation clearly.
So you guys as we go through, there's there's a quite a few things to think about. Right? We can kind of talk about which
what whether the comic
or the
animated short is more success full.
We can talk about...
We are, you know, mostly interested in the comic today, but I'm I'm very interested in this as, like a comparison
between the two of them and I love the animated short. I think it's just... I think it's a delight, I think it too incredibly watch.
It's brisk. I don't love it the way, like, I don't feel the same relationship between the shorts that I do the comics. But I I find them very enjoyable and especially, like, classic, you know, traditional animation is is
like, a thing of the past these days, it's either done very cheap Or very rarely in favor of C I.
So I just... I love seeing these wonderfully painted hand and hand drawn backgrounds and genuine like
animation like,
animation
that
uses
cells
and the the kind of real hands on craft some shit that, you know, I'm just... You just don't see that much anymore. I think the biggest
the biggest
pleasure for me and in watching the film and then reading the comic several times was how
the Brilliance of Carl Barks was able to add
important dialogue in the comic that the film couldn't and were the film moved so much in terms of action and sequence and gag That was brilliant. You're right mark, yeah. The colors,
the music the, you know, But but with Clarence invoicing donald Ducktales, there wasn't a lot of dialogue in the cartoons.
But Carl Barks had that because he could write all that dialogue. So you didn't have to worry about the... What did that dot say?
Problem. So I I kinda like that comparison between the book and the movie because I think it they compliment each other and, you know, kudos to Carl Barks are taking the source material, which is already fun and I think making it a little bit different if not better. I was a big fan of the witches character
development. Maybe not development, but just poor portray we we... You know, I love a a strong female character
and
to
really have a lot more substance. And in the way that Barks can give substance
to a two dimensional drawing
with
three lines of words. Right? He can just... He is just amazing at that, and and the witch was a really great example of that between the
cartoon and the book. Yeah. I think that's a good point. Sarah. She feels much more like realized in in the comic. I mean, everyone feels a bit more realized because it has more room. To breathe. But
she just... She feels kinda like a force of nature
in the cartoon.
And in this one, she's like she's the main character. Which is pretty interesting. So she is almost certainly Bark
strongest
female.
That might be a
controversial thing to say and some
well for for donald duck. No question about it. And and I love it that she's Al advocate for the kids and, you know, and typically, the kids are clever enough to get get to donald, but they need a little help this time, and she's very happy to help them out in that way. So yeah. That was... She's a she's a fun foil. Yeah. Cartoon nephews are much like they're they're a little bit more simplistic. They're not Al clever.
And and they're also usually brat here. So Barks has to kind of lower them in terms of, like, their involvement,
but
but I think he he balances it pretty nicely. That this seems like the good moment to talk about which Hazel I love which Hazel. I think she's just such a fun character. I always think of her like mentally as a Barks character even though technically
you know, she was created for the short. But I I love his version of her in this. And it's really interesting what happened later. Did warren
Did you happen to, like, read about kind of the Loo connection there? That character
it which Hazel who who I associate with Trick treat. It also shows up in some bugs bunny cartoons or at least a version of her And so I don't know the background on that. If that was just and animators
over drinks Al a Barks saying, hey, I'm gonna borrow which, said the word brothers
animators did. They they did. They they just... They just grabbed her. They snatched her from the short. That love. I was wondering how that happened. You know, basically, they felt they could get away with it because, like, which hazel is is a Inducks name or it's it's a plant name, I guess, and everyone associates the... The the thing that's in your Medicine cabinet.
And and they were like, well, you can't copy that and so they they went and got her and they went and got her
her voice after as well. June four eight. Yeah. So June four didn't do her
in the very first bugs bunny cartoon.
Okay. But but didn't get trick treat certainly. Right. She did. The great June four. Are you familiar sarah with June four? I'm no. She is he's legend.
She did rocky the squirrel and
a number of walk on Loo Tunes voices and other voice. But she... She's, like animation voice act loyalty. I... My dad always talks about. Like, a family friend of ours was very bitter that she got...
He was on taps to do the voice for Rocky the squirrel and June four Al, like, audition after her and, you know, snatched the roll up. But so. I do. But, yeah. He he he randomly
made friends with this old like silver screen voice after named Lucille Bliss. Who did like Sm fat and one of the sis first from Cinderella.
So she she would kinda hang around our house, once it's in a while.
That is very, very cool. Yeah. It was fun. But but admittedly, June four is is amazing. And
eventually would would
which Hazel from Mu tunes is more famous. I'd say just because she appeared in multiple Barks did And I actually like the way she's animated with the warner brothers style. I think she's... I... Again, the foil for donald is a little different than the foil for bugs bunny or daphne Inducks, and I just thought it was I just love that version, the warner brothers version. But they are... They are a akin. Yeah. That's interesting. Yeah.
So the story it self. Right? We've mentioned that it was in nineteen fifty two. This is considered bark golden age so it's interesting that, like let's acknowledge this is not as strong. By by quite a bit as most of his stories from around this year. It... It's not a typical story. This is not something that he sat down and used his own creative Juice to come up with. This was an... This was an editor assignment, and he... I think he definitely made at work. But it's it's a comedy really. It's not an adventure. You now most of these thirty two pager are much more exciting much more adventurous.
This was published in Donald Du number twenty six. And that that's notable because this is our first
So it's not a four color story that Donald that's been spun off into his own title And
wherein you were asking me about the number Yeah. I was confused. I I I I go wrong my room in my my Ducktales room here that I have, I count up all my four colors. I get to the Gil Man and account number twenty four And then there's no number twenty five. I know there's not a donald doc number twenty five. It's so So I don't know what happened.
Mark, do you have anything on that? And my understanding is it's just one of those whoops. I don't remember where I read it, but I think I think they just missed counted, you know, and and they just got the numbering off. So I'll buy that. I think that's where they go. And that... Not well that's so much. But I think it's it's great that as he started up the uncle Scrooge series,
where he really put all these efforts after the four color his contribution to the Donald x stories was kinda winding down and this is one of those last ones before other, I just went in there. Yeah. I guess there's just gonna be a couple more stories that may make it for Donald... Donald Ducktales long form. Mh. Sarah, did you did you reflect a little bit on the golden Christmas tree at all? It did. I have such a poor memory
that I didn't make the kind of like, detailed connections
But I did kind of get, like, a general vibe of, like, oh, there's a witch in this one, and it different than the one in the golden Christmas tree and Donald is different.
You know, the the ones that you've given me, is been kind of hard to develop, like, except for, like, the consistency of Carl Barks being amazing. It's been hard for me to develop a sense of, like, how Donald is supposed to act, how which is exists this universe, you know Yeah. I just think about the fact that oh, this is another editor assignment and this is another story that kinda shoe horns a which in his universe doesn't really
it's gonna have a witch,
We're gonna have an awesome which introduced in a in a couple of years in the un Scrooge series, but she is gonna be dramatically diff from the kinda of classic witch of the tropes.
I'm talking about magic the spell by the way here. You you might know her from doctor. I remember that.
She's she's a Barks creation. And it's interesting that, like, He was made to use the witch from Snow white. It felt very shoe orange to me in golden Christmas tree. And and here he's made to use which hazel and and it also feels shoe, but she's such a, like
sort of daphne character
She has kinda of this like, energy that I think fits better with Barks vibe. How do you guys think about with Hazel? I'm a fan. See she takes on o all of the traits that I'm usually, like, shaking my fist,
and
she meets them in this really interesting way. And she's like, I'm not gonna let you get away with that. Also, be nice to these kids, I'm their protector. Yeah. Yeah. I like Even know you're you're her guardian. I'm there protector.
Okay And I and I and I will say I... As as much as... You know, if you look at the whole canon of which in the Disney vault, there's no question that which Hazel
is that incredible foil for donald, almost on that energy level. I love to what you said about energy. As it and artistic drawn. She's just a care of every which that you would be that of. But
she certainly is is in a league of her own when it comes to comparing her to the other which is that we see in snow white and some other classic rims brothers fairy tales. I I think that it's interesting again, the story Barks from the Disney studios provided Barks with the arc that he was going to adapt. It would have been interesting to see what Barks would have done on his own if he would've done that. And
I'm glad you mentioned magic had spell she's one of my favorite characters. The so and she's known. I I just love. But I like with Hazel, but I think what Hazel is is this chaotic
smart as a whip. I mean, look Al. Look at her her potions and her Shakespeare ex
education and...
At least... And you said lot of fun. So much much speaking after the boys. What do you guys think, where does she rank kind of in the pant of Disney witches? Right? Does anyone have a favorite which they wanna go to that for? I'm a classic animation fan. My my... I you can't beat the the coming in the the witch ins snow light. So which Hazel is is really more of a character of which and and really
Barks had very little to do with the creation of which Hazel What, what do you think, Sarah? You know, I don't think I could answer that question
without about three days to prepare so that I could research all the various switches. And then consult some of my friends who are actual, which is or, like how good is this
representation?
Well, we we got what, like Warren mentioned the evil queen from snow white, you got efs,
of course. The the big one boy. Who else was there? Well, there's ursula so to see which in... Oh, yeah. So the c which. And little.
But I'll I'll hit you guys with my three. I'm gonna say... Okay go. I actually do put her I do put which Hazel in my top three. I am a big fan. You called her chaotic one and that's Kinda perfect. I love her chaotic energy.
And and she does get used a lot in later comics by, like, some of the Italian creators, and I know that pat Block who is on here a few episodes go. He got to do a couple of stories featuring her
I really like with Hazel. Do you love me some magic to spell, you know? She's she's great. One of my favorite villains But my all time favorite Disney which is a little bit of a wild card choice. I love Mad mad Mi from.
Oh my goodness. There's a reference. Y yeah.
Yeah. She she is a hoo. Do you can you remember her Sarah? That is a deep cut, but I do remember of just a... An energy. Yeah. I don't remember specifics, but I have an impression
that she's made in my mind. She's great. She's right too. Wow. Right. So let's see a little bit more.
This one's been printed
reprinted quite a few times.
It's county the original printing, there have been eleven of them. They're just briefly pan some international listeners we've got of fun title from Brazil. It was originally called No das Blue pass a night of the night of witches.
And
in in most of the languages, it does seem like they kept kind of the trick treat title. You know, in in German. It's
Severino
or
chic,
which is Donate
or boy. Which I guess must be there they're equivalent of trick tree. So that that is definitely fun. Donate or bully? Oh I love that. That's fantastic. Oh.
Don't see or I'll bull you. And I like in
Spain.
I've got
Or.
Have you heard that trick treat term before Sarah through.
No. I mean, that makes sense.
Not
Yeah. What does that mean? A nightmare which.
That's that's great. I really like that one. I think that one's fine.
Alright. You guys... Let's let's get into it. Let's talk about the story itself. The the only people I would say Barks good as you as you start out with the comic is that the opening title of the the opening sequence
of the animated card to compared to the original
page and half if you want me to talk about that appeared in Donald number twenty six, compared to The department's original version, there's three to very distinct different openings to the comment and the story that might Barks mentioning yeah rights.
Thanks for mentioning. Like, before we actually jump in, We can't really talk about how this got, like butcher.
This
So we should mention right now, you know, the the original Warren tell us a little bit about the original
presentation of of the story. Sure. The like, the cartoon again, which was the
inspiration for Barks the story opened with this a shot of which Hazel and the sky on her broom and the the in the foreground,
it was more fence posts and darkness. You could maybe make out a a head stone on a graveyard, but you had to really look fast if you were gonna find that. But when Barks got the story board that he said no, I'm gonna make my opening page more I think it needs to be a bigger splash panel and the graveyard
in his original art was extremely prominent in the foreground, well that troubled the editor greatly. And and you've got this switch, and it's two ominous and it's... And the and the typing even trick treat was in red, it could be mis misinterpreted as blood, and it was just two gruesome. It's creepy. It's.
It's it's a cool opening. So that's what happened and so then Alice cobb said you're gonna have to cut that panel, and we want you to create another opening which features the Nephew painting trigger treat, the title on the window of donald house. Then then, of course, it's all fun, because you see Donald and enjoying himself and that page and a half, which originally appeared in in Diamond number twenty six. Was finally eventually replaced with the Barks as original work. So you've got this controversy right off the bat about how we're going to introduce the Halloween store. Well and that editor didn't just cut that out. So Sarah, what what happened is I've sent you the the, like, full can. You you get to read the story in its original glory, and that's pretty much how people view it as it's supposed to be. But technically
when it was originally published,
it was hacked down to one was it twenty three pages? Yeah. It was twenty three, and then they added
a twenty fourth page later. Yeah. It was it was a mess. Cut a lot of of the, like, fun stuff that Barks added to kinda stretch out the story. Right? So Right. She didn't like a lot of it, including my buddy,
sm the bad, which
I think is crime. Right? Yeah. So let let's do it. We're gonna talk about the story. Warren you've you've already
introduced it really nice sleep. Just just that the story opens just like the cartoon,
the... With this switch that we're gonna learn is which hazel lying around us spooky halloween night
s
and generally
scaring
animals, even ina object objects seemingly,
and and we get introduced to her as well as her broom b l's above. And in the comic, you know, she's revel in her ability to scare things,
She scares a black cat. And then and then she attempts to even scare a pumpkin.
But the pumpkin turns around, and it it turns out to be a Jack
on a post that's being held by one of the nephews
Sarah, do you wanna tell us about how the boys are dressed?
Sure. Although I did have a question, I could recognize the pi
and the little devil with the, the pitch fork and the horns.
But one of them is dressed in, like, some kind of yellow
that third nephew is in a ghost or a goblin.
I I take that as a kind of a sheet that they're wearing to look like a ghost.
Okay. See how much of a... It's a great pumpkin Charlie brown girl I am. I thought that I that thought wouldn't have never played to me as a ghost because I'm so stuck in the ghosts from the Charlie Brown halloween special. But and and you mentioned pi, but I always read that as a witch. Well, I think I think Sarah looking at the hat, and I think it's it looks like your traditional pi hat. So when she said that, it's funny. I never really really called out the characters
I I I do see the resemblance to one of the Nephews Being which. Well, you know, and that was kind something I wanted to bring up was how are like, which man really started with the pilgrims rooms and tying back to James the six, the slash first of the united kingdom and how he set the country off for running witches and blah blah blah. And and why clothing from that era is used to depict which in our modern times.
He has a call
though, and that's why it reads as pi to me instead of as which... I mean, I I think it's definitely supposed to look like a sort of salem.
Which. Right? So I I think I think that sort of pill over tone is delivered. But that's my thought. I think it's supposed to look like one of the which that was you know, accused
of which witchcraft Al sail. Right. But but that's interesting that you read it that way. And and anyhow, the ghost to me is kinda s like the ghost
Disney shorts like like lone and ghosts. So that's why I read it immediately like that. And I should mention too that Hazel references
briefly that she hears that earth folks don't believe in us switches.
Anymore that she wants to do something about that. And and it's also notable the kids are singing the tune the that incredibly catch to from the cart. And then I as I read the about this Barks, and sarah, I noticed that this is where Carl Barks felt to talk a little bit about what the cartoon didn't do have that narrative from which Hazel. So he added that so we would get a little background. But he also knew that that catchy tone would make make great little appearances throughout the book as well. Right. So so it's it's cute little interaction. Right? The the trick treat. We only get one trick treat interaction before they're gonna encounter donald Right? She calls them goblins, which I guess is kind of the stand in for for scary
creatures that you know on the fifties. And it it... It's... Do you guys find it pretty weird that they're treating Donald house as though it's not their home in this short. I could not figure this out at all. I was really puzzled by that because they're going to donald Du house, but it should be here. So, yeah.
Taken buy that. I I think that both the cartoon
and the comic they just... They want to tell this story and so both of them
Carl didn't have any choice I'm guessing because of the structure of the cartoon.
But it's weird and it's a little bit distracting,
and it doesn't work. Right? Because like, as a kid, one of the first things I did when I got home after trick treating was dumped the rest of the remaining candy. That my parents had into my own hotel Barks.
So
quick but he needs... This is a donald versus.
The Nephew
story. And so he needs them to be at logger.
How often did those happen? I was shocked as a kind of, you know you know, I'm the newbie, you know, this is my first time reading these. And I was like the why is he being a sure. I didn't understand his motivation...
I thought he was acting
more kind of like arbitrarily, like, Scrooge than like, himself. It didn't fit with this anything I'd seen before, like you know, and and then as more mentioned, it appeared as if he didn't live with them. Yeah. It's it's it's weird you asked about that. There's a lot of donald versus the Nephew stories. I think it's mostly a hold over. From the cartoons.
Right? Because that was the premise for a lot of these. But I would say it's probably a good, like, twenty percent of his stories. Have them just outright Al odds with each other. I think you're absolutely right. The duck and the iron pants comes to mind as probably the greatest one. I know it's one of your favorites Barks. Just to see them see them go ahead of with each other. But what I like about what Barks did is, this is really true to the film right now the story Barks are really following these opening pages very, very closely.
But not only is Barks adding his own narrative to give the reader a little bit more context but he also created the these extra panels of a typical trick treat relationship with one of the neighbors. As you said, Sarah, it was cute. It was just like
a traditional Halloween wing would have been Barks in the early fifties.
And this is where which Hazel has an opportunity to say, oh, look at that, She says, how long is this rack been going on? You know? So she she gets to see what she is kind of fascinated by. Until they go to the next house. Now in the automated feature, it starts out with Darn I believe. So it goes right there, and that's where the action starts. And stops. Yeah. So one, why don't you go ahead and tell us about the interaction with Donald there. Yeah. So so as the boys leave and and they they kindly tip their hat and thank the the neighbor.
They venture to uncle Donald house the next one. Doesn't say our house, but Uncle that house. Yeah. Let's go there. He's got lots of candy. And so there's where they're singing the theme on. I I love that And Donald was reading a book, and he looks Annoyed, but he's prepared. This is another thing that is... Said you brought it up is what is... I just mind here, does he just want to abuse kids weight? I mean, what's going on here? But he says I've been
also set for such visitors and that evil look on his face when he's lighting the fire crackers and hiding him behind us back. And as they still innocently say Trick treat, I've got a surprise for you and just like in the cartoon,
he pops them in each bag, and they all explode. This takes which Hazel by complete surprise but he's not done. He continues with the water gag over the head where he pulls the the string on the pale of water wrench all three of the nephews. He's having a blast at this kinda sad situation. I mean what what is going on here, and this is where they eventually
meet with Hazel?
Mark. I know that you'll... You'll take it from here, but I I just thought it was an interesting sequence.
Troubling donald come.
Yeah. Donald don't stun on the jerk and this one. Yeah. It's definitely a little bit of a of a sour note. What jerk he is, I think. Well just
Sarah. Or and used the word that was rolling around in the back of my head. Abuse. Like, this he up abusing these children and in my head, I was thinking if he... It doesn't seem like he has custody of them right now, and he absolutely doesn't deserve it.
Yeah. That this really is born out of the animated shorts. Yeah. Right. Like
this this was kind of the the style. This was kind of what what they did. It was broad slap stick. And and if you take it literally, that's that... It's definitely abusive take how you... Take how you want. The fact that this was viewed as high comedy.
Transitioning to Hazel meeting the kids, I find it a little bit awkward
they just kinda point Al her and say, look, a real witch, and and that's kind of enough for her. Oh, joy. You know, thou I do believe it in which.
And and so just for that, she's gonna help them get candy. Right? And we're just into this little slaps stick comedic story. And the next the next few segments of the story are really gonna be all... It's a cartoon
printed on age.
And that
may not work that well for you. You know? Like, It's a fun story, but it it can only be as good as the cartoon and it can only be as good as a cartoon on paper Barks.
So I think I think the parts were Barks diver a bit are actually gonna be the most entertaining
going forward and I don't need to go into, like, gruesome some detail about everything that she he does, you know? He like, he pulls the water trick on her he pulls her supposed rubber nose, he knocks her down the steps.
And she just gets really mad, and we we go into this cute sequence.
Where she's gonna do the thing that which is do, right? Which is do best. Day
they bubble up a cauldron
of magic post I I love this sequence in the cartoon.
I really like this sequence
in the story. I love...
I love the little rhyme, you know, it's starts out Al the shakespeare ex, Rhyme but then... But then he extends it past... That's Mc. Right? It's
coming yes. So he extends the the Mac bath
double double toy and trouble or the animators do.
It's it's such a fun little. Do you wanna read us the...
Do you wanna read us the intonation sarah? Double Double.
Toilet and trouble,
fire and Cauldron bubble. I have needle ton of shoe, hand of clock, that points to two,
neck of bottle, tail of coat and whisk from y ubi go and I I I love how he transitions that. I I like this silly little segment where he's like, okay. I'm gonna pat it out. I'm gonna explain how they get the whisk whispers from the billy up?
Good. This is the best part with the nephews. Right? This Barks part where the nephews are, like, kinda low key arguing with each other over over who has to sacrifice their one shirt tail to give them to their country street. That's that's a funny line.
One nephew paints glue onto the other nephews, rear end and and let's the go do a ghost do best
ram him by him in the butt.
And and, you know, get some of the... Get some of his list that way. His the difference Time Barks is art and storytelling comes in on his own. You're right. I mean, this is the the first of three huge examples in the story that he was able to employ his own brand of humor and writing and it's Brilliant with the three boys. Yeah. It's it's very strong. It's it's a fun part of this lightweight
goofy a typical story. And and I love how hazel stairs with the whisk and says
repulsive. I believe she does that.
I like the in the car too too. Right? Yeah. That's the tip of the iceberg for the... When she drops it gently into the colder and then, of course.
Oh, yeah. We get a great animated
explosion and a great drawn explosion in the climate.
And and just her look of delight Oh, I love the panel that he he translated the line of dialogue
directly where she says kids this stuff loaded. But on the com, she just has this, like,
static wild look. That... That's one of my favorite panels right there. Yeah. And the color colorful background with the bubbles in the in the bottom and... Yeah. It's just it's brilliant. And and so the next sequence is fun. Right? She sucks up a little
dispenser one of those old
style.
One of those old spray things and she scoops up the kids on her broom, so they they nervous get a ride. And
and the next few sequences are gonna be about for different ways that she uses the witches bro to try to get to get the candy from Donald. Donald is gonna take some time to away his hard earned
selfish Leonard earned candy. Well, this is where Barks
again wanted to
basically let the waiters know that through Donald dialogue is that he's now settling in and he he has peace and quiet and his life. The motivation for possibly the motivation for his wanting to get rid of the trick treat the way he did was so that he could just have a peaceful evening.
Instead of just turning all the lights and going to the basement. Yeah. And and this next part of the story it it should be really cool. Right? Because We've got all these, like, halloween creatures coming to life. But I can't help but think about how much better this works in the cartoon.
Oh, yeah. Yeah. This is this is the highlight of the cartoon
I would say, right? Where the witch is flying around,
we've got that great catch Al little your room of the theme playing. She's spraying different things with
her bruised, they're coming to life, doing supernatural stuff. Sarah what's your favorite of the little, you know, which is room moments here. I like the the ghost
that
played a a gate
like a liar. Mh. I thought that was that was cute and clever. What about you orange? Did do you have a favorite Al these little moments? But I I agree that the animated sequence
tied to the songs so well. So when the word ghost re rhymes with post, you could see that
transformation take place. The magical
brush,
even calling out the color green was very clear in the saw Lyrics, and I think just the the the part in the animated feature, what I love is when the pampers just went by Diamond face. So I I would say those two. I don't agree with Sarah. I like the... I like the introduction of those ghosts. They're very
reminiscent and of lone some ghosts in a way. Yeah. And This sequence like, it's very... I I can't help but compare it to the cartoon just because the the words get the song stuck in my head. And it it looks great on animated page, and it just looks bland and static. As as nice as his some of his drawings are of, like, the jack lantern bleep wildly at him. But yeah, Hazel is going around singing the song itself.
I'm gonna plop some of the song in right here because it needs to be hurt.
Take
Al
if you want your through surgery lane, oh, we can do that
I do love the absolutely
wild panel.
Onto the next page of, like, all of the different ghosts and goblins lining up to
donald. That wild
one that has send nose
with a a finger that can ring the door Al pretty cool. Yeah. That's pure Barks, isn't it at Mark? I mean, that was the automated cartoon doing. That's believe that's right. And, you know, when Donald finally dare to open the door for whatever reason, he instead greeted by Hazel who, you know, has successfully
kind of pushed... Terrorized him into giving up the candy
until he references
until she references him being a push over. And he he just takes... Yeah. He takes such u at that that he gives her the bum rush. And and you know, we get... We get this escalation here. Where they've gotta keep trying, they've gotta keep using the witch bro. You wanna tell us about the pretty girl sequence Sarah?
Okay. So the the which uses is some of that all purpose spray and turns herself into
like a you know, the nineteen fifties children's comic version of a sexy woman duck. U.
And goes in to
ring the doorbell and get his attention. And and so it works on him because he's kind of a poor to this in this episode, and my notes were you donald.
Pretty dusty old Cli.
What I thought was interesting in this sequence was that she uses the spray on herself. So his reactions are all his. Right? He's yeah he's given all of that to her
himself with no magical assistance or or.
And
she gets all him to give her all of the candy Yep. How about that little flirt fictitious nickname cuddles of? Is that what you wrote you about
No. Just the voodoo blue
with the little Barks.
The little hard coming out from him and his cross side leaning over off balance
I like the kinda era
specific list of candies. Right? Bond bonds and caramel and gum drops and candy almonds.
What do you think of this one? Well, what she
into this Ducktales. Female Ducktales
first thing I thought of was, oh, she's turning into Daisy. Well, it's not quite daisy. There's actually
a a bit of magic at the spell than face if you take a look at the eyes and even the codes in that first panel. So what we have here is a so of which.
Who's becoming kind of a beautiful witch if you wanna use that term. Right. And so this is where Barks I think is being Barks and he's starting to say, if I were to do this, this is what I would. And so this again, is is second of the three introductions of these and... Oh I agree with you, Sarah. I think this is Donald just being a
donald. You got a girlfriend named daisy. What are you doing? Yeah. I didn't I never really thought of it, but that's a good point. It's kinda magic at one point now. It is As as H and, like dusty and a sample of Cli is this is, I do
love the moment where she just like
transforms. He asks her what's your phone number cut does. And she can just sensor her s at which craft thirteen thirteen.
Give me a buzz sometimes sucker.
I love. I love that. She's just she's delightful right there. I been switched.
Yeah. And and so, you know, Donald, she almost gets away, but Donald catches him with the last. So
and they all fall off the broom. And I I do love that panel with l's above how he
just kinda looks on at them helpless
and and so, gently. To see them all fall. I love how Barks personalize fe the room here. Yeah. P up has a lot of personality. Mh. Yeah. Oh, and I I also love her her line
he triumphant takes it back if she says that laugh, that nearing laugh, I'll change it to a thousand tears.
And we get... We get this great upgrade now of the... Which is bro. They're adding... What are what are we adding to it, Lauren? While, they're adding, they're adding a very unique item. She wants more feathers
and a derby hat. What what's the Derby have four one.
Oh, that's for style boys style.
That's great
that's so far. To me, that is like... Yeah, especially the way she says it to the boys. And they're so Inducks. Like, and they got one right away, which is interesting. Yeah.
But I I love that line. That's probably one of my favorite panels too. It's it's a style boys. It's awesome. And then the last ingredient Sarah the yep Oh bet. Port poor b that yeah contributes the last ingredient. The final ingredient, unfortunately,
is
one of these straws from
above from his broom. I love I love poor bills of bugs like x expression. He doesn't eyes or a face, but just with a couple little sweat drops and a little e. Huey, really feel for for poor portal room there. Like I've talked so much about how good how just
magnificent
Carl Barks is at making these animals in emo. In such human ways.
He even did it to Al bloom.
U.
Yeah. You can... You you see that he sends his what's coming, and he's like, oh, no. I'm gonna mad in here. Warren you wanna finish off the invitation for us? Sure. Focus Poc.
Eyes, try this derby on for size. Oh, it's great. It's it's it's he has a lot of fun. With the invitation there, I think. And and she ref, she tells them to stand back because he may be in evil mood and
and the reader learns that she talking about her pet
sm board. Better known as sm the bad. You guys what you think? Of sm the bad here. He's got some good piercing.
He does.
I absolutely love everything about Sm the bad. Is his such a Carl Barks creation, and the derby had just adds the final touch. Oh my god. I'm.
Balancing on top of one of the horns.
Yeah. This this is one of those situations where it's it's almost pointless to try to describe over an auditory medium, but like he... He's an older. He's got these oversized face. He's a cy clock sober. He has one eye, two bull,
excuse me. Has one eye in the front and one eye in the packet of his head. And he has these wild
six arms
And he he's just
so over the top, and I can't believe that they made him cut. Sm from the original comment. Sporty is part of that original nine page sequence that Barks was told to cut. He was the second half including the the transition to the girl.
Because the editors thought it was unnecessary and too scary. But these
again with how expressive he makes all of his characters.
This is such a
non scary
to me. Even his one eye, community in his and his, like, one tooth that comes up out of above his lip from an under bite. It's he's just he's not scary. He's a pet. Yeah. Is a bet over. He he's he's not men Al all in my opinion. I and I don't know why. But then the other little note about this is that did not only yank these nine pages out and they printed the the shorter story, but they didn't pay Barks for this either. He says many times she's quarters say, they didn't even pay me for these pages. Right. Yeah. And and they they made him draw a new story. When we did
Donald Duck Worse Nightmare, we were also gonna do one called H God.
But you are on such a care with Donald Duck Worse Nightmare that I was like, that's this is enough for one.
Which was great. I love that episode.
Well, you have be Barks even though I go on such stairs that we can't even get all up in?
But but you guys, I love mortgage ford. I did find him a little bit scary when I when I saw this Al page nine. Not like I was gonna have nightmares, but at least in his introduction and the way he was introduced. But then by the end, you know, he departs in such a goofy way connecting think Barks does a good job of
him. But he
he greet Donald in the house and, you know, Donald is, like, initially thinks he's like a fraud that he's hollow or something.
But but then he realizes is that he's real. And Hazel eggs him on to, like, at this point, Donald has locked away the candy in a closet
and has the key. So she's egg him on to get the key. And more of his for is
Warren tell us about how sm he is trying to get it. Well, mortgage board is trying to get into the house any way he can. I mean,
He's got what, how many Barks? Six eight hundred that's six. But might as well be
might as small be more than bad. Yeah. Yeah got six Barks and he's reaching and they they extend too. Now I can see that he's trying to get into the house anyway he can't to get that that key that's hidden in the book that that that put in there. And everywhere he goes, the arm comes out of the most unlikely placed in the home, the fireplace,
to reach up. And then eventually, which is probably a pretty terrifying panel. I I will say all these Barks appear at once and you here donald
grabbing the jar with the key and saying help. Yeah
And the next panel was almost Al frightening. You see this long shot of Hazel saying
that's it sm. Thou has cornered the rogue
interesting form there, and the arms are just stretching all over the place and until he grabs out by the neck, which is pretty scary. It is a little disturbing. I can I guess I get where the editors were coming from, but this is like, this is the wildest, like, most bonkers part of this story? So... Yeah. It such a shame to lose it out, and I'm so glad that it was restored. And we've definitely got a pretty disturbing bit here you know, Al sm leaves with the candy.
Donald has this idea. He he eyes one of the fire
from his original praying. Any paints sit with jam to look like, you know, a candy Cane or play handy or whatever. And lights the fuse
and tell Sm. Here's a great big stick of Candy just for you and
which Hazel tries to warn him away from it, but it's no good. He He says one of his only lines of dialogue
he says
good.
Oh it just
disappears in this violent
explosion and
editors probably had a detrimental trouble with that as well. Yeah. And and I love... I love when Hazel covers her ears.
Sarah, do you wanna tell us her bit of dialogue there?
Okay. Yeah. To which says
that's why he's called Sm the bad. Val know not what he's going to do.
I love that sort of resigned Well you know, he's keys isn't an over.
What are you gonna do? And so Hazel
gets pretty mad at this point. And she decides to take the direct approach.
She
barge into the house just as Donald
locks the candy again and in front of their eyes, he Swallow the key, and she's delighted because this gives her the excuse that she needs to spray the spray directly
on
him,
specifically on his feet. Warren you wanna tell us about the sequence? Well, very... Again, this this echo echoes is the the the car too and very well.
Spraying with the the bugs spray the prayer. He just starts can't control his feet, the which is brew, and Donald feed is allowing him to
do whatever what Hazel tells it to do. So kick out that key, so he starts taking himself and starts dancing wildly if you want to. To actually try to live dis launch the key from inside donald, flipping them around, like a flat jack and a pan. And then you get these funny sequences of Barks his head on the pans on the wall. Yeah. Until he's absolutely
coughs up the key. Yeah. You know, this is this is a pretty fun sequence in the, but it's another example where it just pale to the cartoon. Right? This is like this is meant to be animated.
And it's meant to be tied to the music. Like, all the animation is is absolutely
perfectly
cute.
To the like full music or squared dance type music that's going on. And Barks really does is best here. Barks also knew one to stop. He had a three sequence gag that he was following on the story Barks because in the cartoon, he sw the key three times. Here, here, he says... There's only room for one gag here. Yeah. And like, it it does drag on a little bit in the cartoon even the the feet right. Maybe that's just because I'm queued by the chronic not to think it I think it doesn't last this long.
Eventually,
he kicks it out a couple of times. Kicking himself bumping into a cactus you dragged towards the fire, which is the little intense, and they keep almost getting the key and then finally, Huey, slides under the closet, and it's the old saw. I can't have it no one can have this handy. And so the final sequence
has her. She's realizing that she's gotta get home pretty soon.
What do you think Sarah or her Al little reference
there. If I'm not back on the which is moon. And may me wonder if he lives on the moon or if there's, like, a specific other moon
Do we know about this moon? Like the plan is here anesthesiologist in me like, picked up and was like
just shoot... Where is this moon? Is it in the belt? That's not a moon. Do we have a moon that we just don't know about? Did the... The witches keep it secret?
What's going on
Sorry.
It it wouldn't be Barks first secret moon. But, yeah. I I... That stood out to me. It really implies a little bit more back story. It's ethan through that end. Yeah. But but, yeah. She's got time for one more try. Do you wanna tell us Sarah about her her last attempt here from somewhere she pulls out some iron pant
to give him enough weight to knock down the door. Which is just like I... I I don't know why they're called iron pant.
It's like a full, like, suit of armor. Like, Yeah. I think it's just bart being Barks using a acute nickname for
for a suit of armor. Oh, okay. I I like in the
in the cartoon. This has such a nice sense of rhythm, right? Where she's like not take Al long,
start about a mile or two. It's very it's it's music alright?
And it's very catchy. And it's a pretty thick. It's this works pretty well in both of them for me, I think. I like
after he does the expected thing and crashes from a great distance into the into the closet that destroying the closet door and probably some of the wall around it. You know, he
raises the white flag of surrender.
Do you wanna read her dialogue there Warren that starts with down early orders? Yes. Yes. Yes. So she points a donald and he says, thou my early hoard must learn and on Halloween,
the goodies belong to ghost. And
I'll have to treat. I love what Donald says after that, though. Was this still played robbery, you know? Yeah. Then bills above has the final word if you wanna call it that and taps him on the head, and he just bleep falls over. I love it economic violence to close it out. And and we've got one more page in the story itself, and it's It's a little bit discord. Right? It's a little weird because we've got the boys
celebrating and
hazel
last thing, you know, that Donald better of Learned lesson.
And Sarah, why don't close this out. So the the kids are so excited because their Loot socks are filled with candy
and hazel promises
with her, you know, thumb and her pointing or thumb over to Donald that from every halloween
that he has learned his lesson and he will fill their sa. Force with and
a kind of bruised stuff batter Donald does Allstate
next year, I'm gonna be a goblin too so they fully converted him He's not just going to pass out candy. He's going to get into the halloween spirit and dress up as a goblin. Right. And then the which, you know, calls it a day and flies off it, you know, in into the moon.
I don't know if that's for secret moon or if it's just like, really nice image with the witch
silhouette in front of the moon.
And
morning comes, and it's always is right with the world. That's the way Barks wanted it. I mean, if you read... I've read some of the criticism on this and at that last page was all Barks
I don't know what he looked at and referred to from the story board from the car was very different from the cartoon. Because in the car too and donald out cold and which just takes off. And here, Donald has a little hint of humanity here. I'm gonna be a better person next year. In that little narrative panel on the last splash panel. That's all Barks is writing. I I I love with the story. Talking about how the post go back to being regular posts and all the goblins become boys and girls again.
Nice little poetic cap. I do find it a little bit odd how Donald is just totally converted and he's all, like,
Joe v now and fond waving her off. I I guess, I guess Donald loves a good fight so maybe he's like, that was that was a good fight, you know? Was a good one. I I'm ready to move on. Yeah. But it's it's it's an odd
a strangely paced story that it's easy to explain the pacing and the structure by the fact that it's Al an eight minute cartoons
stretched out to thirty two pages
of it's not Barks best work, but I think when you consider the limitations that he was working with, he handed in something that was quite entertaining and and,
you know, his own. But what do you think warren. How did this kinda this stack up for you? Yeah. It's interesting. Because here he was interested in in launching his own doc... Scrooge series, and he had already had this thing credible
experience creating and building Daniel's character, and then he was handed this story board and said, you we don't... Here's not a story idea. I don't know if you really wanted to do this. It's hard to say, but he wanted to make it his own, and I think he did. I am I'm impressed with the the additions that he did up. I love Sm.
Without that, I don't think it would have been the story that I remember. So, yeah. I I think
not his strongest, but it wasn't his story in the beginning. And I have to think those little sq or verbal battles he had with his editor would have been I would love to been Al fly in the wall. To hear him try to defend what he was doing. He never... Eventually, those lost pages were restored and we're able to see the original version. I'm very, very about that. Yeah. Absolutely. What do you think Sarah? I, of course, as a so, love for this.
Because Halloween
is like a social paradise and you get to see
everybody's little, like especially in the Us you get to see like, a bunch of people with their, like, little, like, libertarian. Well, they don't deserve the candy, so I'm not gonna get it, but I think I've... No. I personally think everybody forget Candy.
And I'm glad that that which finally
convinced him
convinced Donald to participate
because it's worth fit, and it makes everybody happy and everybody deserves candy and I have taken some notes
from this witch playbook. So watch out for me. If you complain about people coming to your door, and you don't wanna give them candy that's how me. You better not be sting or... Or I'll be there with my all purpose with juice. I already know the taste. That's right. Gotta work on those whisk of a billy billy, though.
I live him neighbors. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. This is a fun story. Like, let's let's talk about the community. Right? The it's easy to imagine this one being a divisive one in the community. And,
you know, when we consider the era that it came out in, like, right at the height of Barks absolute
best cluster of stories. It's definitely...
It's definitely ranked
lower than most of the stories that it came out in the mid stuff. But it's still Prime arrow Barks. So it's good for a seven point five on induction. Which is good for two hundred and fifty eight out of all forty one, nearly forty two thousand comments. So so that's that's good. I I a lot of people. I think a lot of people probably remember this fondly. All bet the italians that read a lot more with Hazel stories then we did
especially like this one. And let's see. So as far as other reference
which hazel turns up in a little bit of other Disney stuff. You know, she's my my kids like Mickey Mouse club house.
And I believe she was featured in that or the house of mouse or something. You know, every once in a while, they'll make her... They'll highlight her and some of their like halloween specials and stuff. Warren, do you have the lit though for this one? I got it last year. I was I was was really wanting that lit graph. It's it's quite remarkable.
It is almost a combination of donald answering the door.
And be amazed by all of those wonderful creatures that he created the top of that page. It's a it's a beautiful
large lit.
And, yeah, I'm I'm very fortunate to have a copy of that. I don't have that one framed it's in my... It's it's a great lit graph. It's great painting.
It it makes me think, you know, he must have, like, enjoyed this story enough. To
you do two versions out he did a couple versions of the painting didn't. I believe he did. And again, it it was one of the few that ended up as a lit graph as well at a large one too, which means it was one of is favorites. Right.
So I... Do you know if it was one that someone commissioned or that he chose to paint? I don't know that. Because, I mean, my read from... Yeah. And then there was this other random painting that had smartest board in it but last
This was his non Ducktales painting that he did of just dark creatures and he did a few of these as well. Right. So I love to see sm in there.
He he clearly had a blast creating smart support. Oh, I love mortgage a lot. And and then when I watch
the
Ducktales series last year. The the new one You know, I thought it was pretty uneven. You know, it had a few inspired moments I thought I watched it all, but I realized that there was an episode that actually referenced the old Hazel house and that has, like, a version. It's not it's definitely not adaptation of this story. It's more like referencing
characters in it. But Ducktales does reference
does reference this story, the the more recent of the series.
So... Yeah, you know, this is not the greatest Barks story, but it's definitely fun and it's neat to see everyone while what he can do with someone else's idea. What
what other thoughts Did you guys have anything else you wanted share about this one anything we didn't really cover? Now that you kind of... Now that we've talked this out a little bit more I do see what you mean about the parallels
between this and the golden Christmas tree. Mh. And and I I feel like there are some people who, you know, when given constraints can
knock a project out of the park. And I feel like Carl Bark is and isn't one of them. In that this is a fantastic
story, you know, Al just without the reference of the cartoon,
it was, you know, cute and interesting, but it was also,
like, now I can see how clearly it wasn't his own voice and how heavily
editorial edited,
how heavily edited he was. And and that's
unfortunate because it makes it not as enjoyable. Also, I just I wish they would just like, let him do his thing so he could be fantastic. Yeah. Yeah. We don't really get to see him. Kind of unleashed very often.
Dangerous
disguised was probably
the, like,
most free to write his version of a donald Inducks story that we ever get to see. Golden helmet came close there, I think as well. But
this is definitely one of his more limited ones because he's operating off of a off of a story board. How about you, Warren? I think the Cartoon
stands on its own, and I think the comic stands on it so I think they're great individually. It was wonderful to watch the card to and read the comic several times. In preparation for this episode and and because of that, I have a great appreciation for Carl Barks knowledge of storytelling and his love for adding what he believes the reader should see and in witness. And I really believe the added sequences
that he put in were absolutely necessary to keep the story moving. It was extremely unfortunate that those were eliminated by the editor. Because they were playing it safe, which makes me like Pearl Barks even more because he didn't believe in playing it safe. And and I really that's that's why I I enjoyed this comic, probably more than the film
because it was... It has the call Barks.
Touch and that that was important to me. But it was a great unique
experience bike watching the cartoon and then reading the comic and discussing both of them. I really enjoyed this very much. Yeah. Well, thanks for for answering the question that I forgot to return to.
What do you think Sarah? Call or Cartoon?
You know, I think comic for a lot of the reasons
that warren
brought up, which is so funny for me to say because,
you know, before you started this project mark, I, you know, hardly ever read comics, I had never read a Carl Barks comic, and now I'm I'm such a fan that I prefer his take on things rather than a little animated short. That's awesome. Yeah. I mean, I I think I'd so neat to hear you say that. Right? Once you see Donald, like, acting more, like a human and and less of a sq it
controlled, you know, cartoon duck. I I think it's hard to go back. Right? Yeah. Yeah. So that's cool. I am gonna land on the other side. I do like this story. I love with hazel
the Barks version of which Hazel, I love sm board, as I mentioned But this this cartoon too is is... It's it's It's a masterpiece piece. Like this is a great cartoon and just it's got some amazing artist.
It does that thing that golden cartoons did so well which is tied and music
to the animation in this same incredible way that just gets totally lost in the cartoon, which in the comic, which I think is a bit of a pale echo of the Cartoon.
I kinda disagree with you warren that I don't think the chronic does stand by its own. I think I did read the comment
before I saw the cartoon. Now that I reflect. Because I remember I remember
seeing the cartoon tuned that the comic made more sense.
At that point. Right? Because like the kids are randomly singing this song.
There are all these sequences that clearly work better in animation. I get what you... I I think it's totally
enjoyable. Right? And I I think you're right that it stands out as, like, something that you can still enjoy. Of its own a accord.
I do think that it really benefits
from from viewing the cartoon.
In a way that the cartoon doesn't benefit
from reading the khan, if that makes sense. It does. And I think the the animated sequences we talked about the the room coming back with the duct and and and hazel on it.
Wreak havoc it on the house and bringing up the Gladstone. Only works really well in the cartoon. What I liked about the comic was was the humanity and a little bit more of the Barks as touch. That gave it more of a of a of a donald backstory story I like to experience.
So they were both brilliant. Certainly the animated cartoon and is like the Disney cartoons of the time. Beautifully done. And and you said about the music and the in the the reliance on music animation. Keep in mind, this is when he was making movies like make my music and feature films like Melody time, where they were all driven by the musical scores and animation. Yeah. For sure. There's there's a couple of deep cuts. Make my music Melody time. Yeah. Awesome.
Well, you guys let's let's wrap it up by reflecting on favorite panels.
And unfortunately, this is one where I think this favors
This compares very favorably.
Right? Because I think there are some wildly great panels. In this one. Do you guys mind if I start though, please. Go ahead. Actually... I actually wanna call out this this is... This might be a little mean, but there's one panel that I noticed on this most recent re reread where I was like, oh. That's some of the worst are I've I'm answering.
Really like most of these tell me about this one. The
page where it starts where she's talking near the end
calling him kids, this pigeon bush over, Am I wrong or is that the very bottom left panel? Looks like a really
lazy,
not up to Bark
golden age standards,
where he's kind of standing at the top of the stairs looking down at him. Look at the feet look in his face maybe it's just the weird hose that we don't usually see him at that angle.
Dead on. Yeah. That's Al that's a it's a it's an interesting
have really cool you brought that up because every other panel leading up to that frame shows a pretty traditional angry or
revenge donald. When we get to that panel. There's something about the shape of his eyes and the pose that so different. Yeah. Maybe
my finger on it. The rest of the page looks great. So maybe he would just wanted to finish that page up. He happened and he looks, like, like, there's a dutch angle there because she's... We're we're looking for her point of view and she's got pushed the stairs. So she's gonna be seeing him really wonky look at her her hat is even pushed over her eyes.
Yeah. That's true. That's that's a fair point. So again, not to be like mean because there's some amazing art in this. The the opening slash panel hit that that half page channel is an easy choice, you know, with the graveyard. Really, all of the extended size panels are really cool. But I do...
I I mentioned
how much I loved her wild
expression. I've gotta come back to that one where she is just so delighted by that which is true.
I think I think kids this stuff loaded. His is my favorite. What about you
warren you wanna go next? I will echo your...
About the larger panels. The opening panel is beautifully drawn. I I've mentioned this earlier, I do like the sequence with the... Which is brew
and this one panel which shows... It's almost orange and color in my print here, and it shows her up above the pot and then a shadow of her. It's very medicine, but it's also just wonderful because she begins for invitation. I love that. I love that panel. But
the panels is the transition from her to the to the woman the duck that I said kinda reminded me of magic good to spell like I love... I love that that whole look. And then when she creates
sm, that one. Those are my those are my too but it just sort of these new creations these new characters that appear for the first time so much fun. Those are totally right about that. Sm panel. That first appearance is great. How about you sarah? I can't believe nobody has said
the panel
whether she creates all of the goblins
and they're just Al and the ghosts...
I thought that that's why Mark was gonna... Was like, oh, I need to go first because everybody else is gonna choose this one. Why I figured it was kind of a. I figured someone who's gonna say it. Because because it really As much as it doesn't hold up to the animated short, that that finished where he has that whole parade of them, that is delayed. They're also
different
and
recognizable and un unrecognizable at the same time. And then the little detail of, like, the one
pink monster with the roller skate. Yeah. The... That's just that just makes me so happy. Yeah. Al like he had a lot of fun. Excellent. Any any closing thoughts, guys. I think I think we took this really nice. Like, go for. There was one more
with sm
in the shot where he has all of his various arms in various windows and they're all coming at Donald.
We we talked about how scary Sm kind of ended up being even as, like, the cutest pet over ever. Right. And that was for me that was evo
of
formative horror shows was I had Severino watched, which was the thriller music...
The full length one. Where they're... You know, they run and they're trying to hide in the house. And then, like, and arm comes through a wall and, like, Barks grabbing them. Obviously, this was made thirty years before. But in my head, it evo that terrifying moment. Yeah. Totally. I could see that. And and to tag on too, I do love the moment where sm eats the fire
and
good. I will finally say by one of my closing comments here Market Sara would be the as much as I enjoy the cartoon and this comic, I'm still gonna try to figure out why the nephews don't seem to be living with don so that's gonna bug me for Al long and long times.
Send me the what So that's something I have to live with. Yeah. It's a that weird are little cartoon logic there. Awesome. Well, you guys enjoy your Halloween
in summer. Thank you for
unpacking trick treat with me boy? Next episode is gonna be a
because we get to cover back to the juan.
Mh
arguably,
Carl Barks most legendary
story ever by some accounts.
So
that should be a great one, but people can reach out to us on the Facebook page. We now have an Insta.
So check in and
we'll we'll be back soon. Thank you.