We can have
Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer an artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comments of all time. Join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Welcome back to Barks remarks. I'm Mark Sever, a grown man who enjoys dot com, you can probably tell from our different opening that we've got a pretty significant story. We get to talk today about the legendary
story back to the cl dyke, and I have two special returning guests
here joining me to talk about this story. So I'm gonna ask for them to introduce themselves
and talk a little bit about your work with the comics.
Henri Go. Why don't you go first? Thank you.
Yeah. I'm monica
a comic Barks
illustrated from the allowance. Also
lifelong
deck obsessed Yeah. I... One of the things I do is
try this new comments. I'm currently
drawing the backside of the dutch Donald magazine or at least I'm drawing about a quarter of them they are by different dim autumn.
And and how about You York? I work as an
a artist and also an editor for eggplant where I edit a comic called Ka and get
that means donald doc classics where we use usually
present a long call story and some other goodies. Awesome. So I... I'm very pleased to be joined by a couple of super knowledgeable
fans and artist.
In their own right. And,
you know, that's that's appropriate
because this is such a famous story And, you know, off the bat. I... I've got acknowledged. This is a legendary one. I definitely feel the pressure
to get it right I also really just wanna have fun talking about a great classic story. Back to the quan is really interesting you guys
because there is
so much that we could talk about and that we could just go into the weeds about. There's the angle of this being widely acknowledged as one of the the best
stories, it it's responsible for a lot of the mythology
around Scrooge dot and it introduced, of course,
a character glittering gold who is
despite only appearing in one of his stories, you know, one of his most memorable
creations
So that's like, right off the bat. There's also all this, like, complicated
behind the scenes stuff with the making
of the comment book itself because, you know, it's widely known by fans that a lot of the art for the original printing was
this was subject to some censorship.
There were some missing pages originally,
and it's taken like it's been a a a process.
Over many years to, like, kind of recon the majority of that art. And so that's that's a lot. To get into. My mission
today is to to really focus
on what is significant.
And and what is great and what works and what maybe doesn't work about the comment. And and I Al interested
guys in some of the details about the lost art and the and the recon reconciliation. I just... I wanna acknowledge that we could spend a whole up as so talking about that. I'm I'm not interested in going that deep into the weeds. But Y can, you must have encountered, you know, as an editor
and just a long time fan, you must be aware of this. Would you mind giving us just a little bit of kind of right off the bat background on on the backstory of this comment and and what happened with the lost art. Oh, yeah. Call,
he usually
wrote and and three stories at home. Just took them to the office
before anyone else so them. And this time, he clearly went too far because hitting some scenes that were not appropriate for this economics. And since western Publishing were responsible, they had a responsibility
that all the the comics
would fit into these sort of guidelines. And this case, there were some real violent panels
Barks steps over the lines. So they had cut it because he had some...
There was a Barks scene with the big fight. And screws was dragged and other things.
Even if the might have liked it and enjoyed it, they couldn't publish it. Because this might fire back towards then. So well what happened was that the edit had a cut a lot of pages to make me work. Yeah. That's exactly right. And and we will while I don't wanna dwell on it, we will get a little deeper into what do you think You are chemo? Do you feel, you know, as as an editor with E? Do you feel a bit of sympathy you feel sympathetic to that editor with less?
Sure, I probably would have done the same thing because
this is not a fan application. This is a mass market allocations that selling hundreds of thousands of of copies probably. And so this couldn't do that. But back in the seventies when these pages start to turn up and in published in,
etcetera, and then in some comic books inc had changed. So well, different times... Yeah. The world was ready for it. So so you wouldn't have published it either, but yeah. I imagine you wouldn't have felt great about it, but that that is your obligation as you as you said, the editor has like, a a responsibility.
Exactly and the edit to saved the pages that might tell us something
that the edge failed it were worth saving at least. Right? Yeah. I thought about that. Too because a lot of time the the pages wouldn't have been It's unusual.
Yeah. We're we're very fortunate. So I guess that might be part of why this story stands out to so many fans. Right? Because of that, like,
history and and just the nature of the pages that were cut out as you mentioned, it's got some very mature themes
bar
brawl, obviously, drinking is implied, a drug, a kidnapping, even,
potentially,
some like
suggestive
perhaps
romance that was a little bit here than what they were accustomed to seeing in dot com.
So stuff stuff to get into.
So do did you both do both of you have, like, a lot of experience with this? I I know for my part, I went back and I read this one. Over and over and over, my my original copy is pretty beaten up. Henri, What about you? Yeah. So the funny thing is that this is not one of the I red charles, and I don't own in dutch. I was honestly surprised because I feel like I know going very well, but I I...
So I've been reading. It comes from a very early age, but this is one I must have read
online later and then got English copies of it when I was maybe fifteen. And I think I also... I did know the character from the
in the netherlands ones. So I don't actually remember it could very be that I read them the the other way around You were referring, of course, to glittering gold. Right? You know her from the Don Rose the comics. Yeah. That's right. And I'm yeah we'll get into that later. I'm actually you're curious how significant character to felt before those stone economics. Yeah.
But... Yeah. So I have not read that austin. I
Coincidence pretty recent that I
visited this, and I actually only just got my my book Barks. How about York? Does do you have a like a long history with this story? Oh, I we do. This story was published in Sweden back in nineteen sixty for the first time. So wait Al where do wait a few years for it. And over here, some of the longer Barks stories were cut up and published in the weekly as a three part story. So this was part of the Call that my father bought as a kid and the I got later on, and
I must have read this story over and over no service I love it. Yeah. The funny thing that's... The story is so the the setting that's in the store is so significant that I felt, like I always knew it because It's it's referred to so often in so many European economics as well. So I'm still surprised that I apparently don't own it in dutch. I always felt like I always knew to on, but I think I just knew it through all the ways it gets referred to. Yeah. Yeah. That's a great point. Because this is like a huge part of the mythology of Scrooge and and part of his appeal. You know, the idea that he made his fortune through hard work in some really iconic
situations like the... He he wasn't old enough to have been in the San Francisco gold rush, you know, through Barks lake timeline, he was just right. For the for the gold rush, which really fires the imagination, and you can tell that the story really friday and drawing the story obvious they really fired the imagination for Carl Barks too. So let me go ahead and talk about a little bit more of the background.
This story was published in very early nineteen fifty three cover date... Cover day at least since January nineteen fifty three, and it's in four color four hundred and fifty six. It has been reprinted many many times, thirteen of them in in the Us including the original. And as we mentioned famously, this was a thirty two pager
but
for the... Original printing, it was short
twenty seven and of those
lost pages.
Y came? Am I am I right that only
half page at this point is like,
still missing
of the original that that all of it has been recon. Should except a half page. I think that three panels are still missing. Oh, that's right. Because there was very very recently.
Yeah. One more just got discovered. Right? Like just a year ago or so? Yeah. Did you have something...
Did you have some involvement
in in that y?
Well, no but friend of mine, who is looking for the undiscovered Barks are found it. He's been turning up lots of nutritious, these past tears. Yeah. There I seen it also who is it? So
and and didn't denmark. Right. So let let me run through a little bit of the background trivia. So first off, I do have a couple of quotes like, from Barks that I like to read. When whenever, you know, there was something
controversial about one of his stories. He was quoted as saying that
it was, as you mentioned Y came that cut out. The the section was cut out at the at editorial office and Beverly Hills in nineteen fifty two. He said that he was originally a little skeptical of weather I could get by with such a bar room atmosphere. But I did it any anyway for a fun. I love that. And he goes on to say such pages when cut from stories were were never returned to me the sequence was cut because of violence and dance hall
atmosphere. That feels like such a Carl Barks thing to say I because this is like really
detailed artwork. You guys both are artists and Henri, you're specifically a Disney artist that must have taken... The the page is cut must have been even for someone like as talented as Barks that must have been like a a real effort. Yeah. I think I think it took about two days per. I mean, I know we've drew fast, but still that's some significant effort. I'm sorry it was sad about the ballroom panel because it really looks like yeah. And all of that one Yeah. Yeah. Absolutely. That's like about a week's worth of pay. But I one you was even if he was even aware at the time if he would actually go to the new send and and see how his on comments has published.
Yeah, That's a good question. I don't know that one. But he did know that he wasn't gonna be paid for it because he said, evidently, I wasn't I think they figured I should have had sense enough to know. You couldn't get involved the fights in a Barks. It was quite a while afterwards. Before I found out why they cut it. I got a letter from the office or was told on my next visit that I had violated a lot of their taboo and should have had sense enough know it wouldn't work. It... That's that's awesome. Right? Like the... What... It's almost perfect the way he did this. He he couldn't have had any way of knowing that it would have been
regarded as such a great work that it would have been saved for prosperity, but that's what happened.
I love that. And and so this is someone else's.
Quote. But I really like this. I think it's too perfect.
Gary Brown wants described the Barks seen as like jack Kirby with du
which Of course, Jack Kirby is is a famous superhero writer.
What do you think Can re that wanna mention some of the
donnie
Involvement with Re, do you think this is a good time mention or kinda talk about it and during... When we get to that. See exactly I'm not sure because I mean, well eventually also get to the panels that are not in the original printing, but it would be interesting if if there's people that always owned the old version and somehow of missed out the version Yeah. That would be fascinating if there's someone who has read it. Yeah. I'm I'm curious to hear from people who are old enough to have grown up with the the other version and I can imagine that maybe this story feels lot less significant without this sequences.
Got glad. Yeah. I grew up to that old version and when I saw this bar room Severino. I think it was Barks And company. Danish
is... Wow, I'm missing something here. I think it bad. Few years before I found the the complete version. Yeah. Actually, I'm just realizing because the the most red dutch version mean got published and announced in the nineteen sixty two in the magazine. But also we have those best off stories we know... Those Al series of all the
covers. Mh And they publish this one in in, like, the best of Scrooge store's number two. So it's obviously a significant story, but I'm actually wondering that the what version of the comment that would be because Was that. I'm I'm guessing. Because it was in nineteen seventy eight, and I think I'm not sure when done edit that... I I think it was first published and it's like, most,
you know, complete at the time form in the book Scrooge with Ducktales life and times. That was in the late seventies.
If I remember right? I've never seen that one myself.
Eight one. Oh eighty one.
Yeah
Sorry
that would still have the the
incomplete version and?
And, of course, back on four color four fifty sips came out, you know, it it had a
print printing of something like a million copies.
So I guess, technically, I had looked that up for only a plural. I guess, technically, there must be a lot of people who never really saw it. It wasn't
until the, like, late eighties, I think, in the Us that it had, like, a a mass market
publication that that restored most of it. Yeah. So I'm curious if this story is
was considered as
significant or as well remember
before the reap publications didn't included those flash vaccines.
Yeah
is just because of all the fan in, you know, the just just the fans that the true fans who kinda shared things around Yeah. I'm so I'm I'm curious how at what point this this story became considered so significant than one of the very best stories because it does read very differently without those without those missing parts. I guess it also depends on
the edge of the reader then. I do think the time you go up and and make you look differently at stories. So Sure. By the way, I'm just checking index here, and it seems
as if the ink version of those four panels first appeared in nineteen eighty Severino that Glad come miguel that you have Barks. Yeah. That's what I thought. I thought that this this one I know is very significant and there's a lot of really good commentary, and I think that it was probably the one the first of these albums that I actually bothered to read the read the commentary for. Because Al a kid, I was just wasn't interested in that stuff. And then at some point, I went through and I realized oh, this background stuff is actually really fun. Alright. So I I do wanna cover a little bit of kind of the cultural background, and I don't wanna forest Al the comic itself too much. But this is a really fascinating
setting. Right? As I already mentioned, we've got the cl gold rush Barks
himself seems to have been inspired by a specific book by photographer for Ethel under in baker in nineteen forty nine, which was all about the Yukon gold rush of eighteen ninety eight. And so, you know, he
was kind of interested. He found himself interested in what was left behind.
After the the gold rush. After the gold dried up. And so he model gold Al a very sympathetic kind of representation of those characters.
You know, and that book actually had a pitch sure of a goose egg nugget or egg shape gold nugget that inspired the goose sag nuggets. So I love that Barks has clearly taken this idea of, like, the the forgotten
towns and tied it in with, you know, the the device of Scrooge
himself
struggling with his memories. I feel... It's very po.
And I I think it's a huge part of why this does work so well.
We're gonna we're gonna hand briefly to our international
listeners
just as I am with my you know, European guests. I always... I always say in this podcast, you guys kinda have partial ownership of Barks because you're so much more into it. Hand and we are. No the the Dutch one...
The funny thing is actually just remembering this the... Because the dutch one is called to us.
Actually, Al like, I remember now it doesn't kid even though I somehow did not read the story as I get that name was mentioned after Al hours thought it was K, which how you would literally pronounce it in touch. I hadn't already added this for some actual place in the Us. Oh, yeah. Nice. And the Swedish one was till dock clone like that means back to the clone bank. Yeah. Those are both correct translations. Right? Mh. Yeah. I think it's an easy to translate title it looks like a lot of stuff.
Most of them are direct translations, which you like to see when a really iconic title. But I did notice that a couple of countries had something that translates
to something like and the pool or the polo.
Star. I'm wondering if that, like, kinda references the North star, the polar star. Like in Italy, it's Severino
del
So it could paid that's the make nickname for the goose nuggets or maybe it's gold nickname? I'm not sure actually. Yeah. Oh, you know what? That means Our stars off the north in star of the north. That is right. And then I saw in French, there was one wee reprint that titled it and the dyke bride.
Said.
So that was kinda interesting. But, yeah for the most part, they did what they should have, and they stuck with the the appropriate name. As far as notable appearances, of course, you know, glittering gold, gold o guilt. As Don Rosa would later, you know, give her... That that seems to be her real name that has stuck for other comments. Creators and in the Ducktales. Signing. It's fair to call her that. Alright, you guys. I'm ready. I know that's been a lot of pro log and anything before we launch in. Let's do it.
Alright. I'm I'm so excited hear what both of you have to say. And and so excited to talk about this. Back to the lawn dyke, as with most of these like golden age stories, it has a great opening that really
draws the leader in immediately.
We we focus on Scrooge pacing around in his money bin and he is
despair about the fact that he's just finished counting his money, and he can't remember how much there is. He talks about the time that he spent thirteen years ways did. I think that's an exaggeration. He's been doing other stuff in that span. But and by the end, he has talked himself out loud into calling his nephew
over there to help him do it because he's worried he won't live long enough to counted again. And the reader of course knows his Nephew is Donald Duck, and we've seen Donald in the last two panels here. So we're already primed to, you know, find... It's it's a very good gag, the fact that he's completely over overlooked donald in there. But you guys this is a great opening. Yeah. Know how it starts. It actually just looks like it's going to be just not... It doesn't big splash panel, but it other than that it looks like it's just going to be another funny
ten pedro just from the way Scrooge is acting really silly right from the start. No wouldn't buying and sitting on a desk. Yeah. This was just it's just starting out like any money then story. I love this because I I think it's doing a a an excellent
job of drawing us in. And and then, you know, seeing on to the next page seeing donald kind of like sm at fresh and really keeps our interest because he is... Again, he's still talking out out loud pondering the fact that, you know, he's forgotten his Nephew name, and Donald helps him out. He says behind and donald du and then Scrooge,
rate fully asked for his phone number too, and he tells him me, yeah, I know that. But but why phone, I'm him.
And and I I love Scrooge panel where he's
realizing that it is donald old and and Donald pointing out. You know, I just I walked right in here when he asked when Scrooge Barks, how he got in because, of course, it was unlocked. So the point is he's establishing
right off the bat that Scrooge is having
memory problems. It's it's Comedic and slaps stick, like, with with older people, this this can be something that's kind of tragic of course.
But... But it's pretty far on this Barks story. What do you think like? Oh, this is a great and super funny.
Into the story. But
to me as an editor, it drives me completely crazy.
Oh
it look the depend three behind Groups is interested in money. In front of the disk, there's the door. And in the final panel, you see that the phone is on a high table And then turn the page, and the cable is not as high and independent for, it's a really, really small table. It's it's like if this was a crazy cat economic where the and elements change in every panel. Because if you started the sequence everything
in the room is moving around changing places. The doors, the the tables, the desk, everything.
But it works because it's funny you don't think about it Al the reader. Yeah. That's exactly the thing I sweat over entirely when I draw panel, and I I spend so much time trying to rotate the room in my head, so it's
consistent, but nobody... If your writing is good, nobody is going to care or no this except some crazy fans make.
You exact people listening to this point podcast most likely
That's awesome. Yeah. Because I'm I'm just the lay person, you know, just a reader and and I definitely didn't notice.
And
doesn't. The things I do notice just... And that you... You sometimes take it for granted but how funny almost every
detail justine in opening pages, the defect that Scrooge sitting on the desk and how is crying when when climbing out the letter affected there's a gosh meter in the Money bin, which is ridiculous of course. It is all these all these little things he adds in the panels just in the way the characters acted already It's just the conversation in our office, but he manage to make it really fun interesting. Yeah. That's absolutely right. There's some amazing site gag, some amazing
expressive art... No. I noticed the little background detail with the framed... My first dollar locked to the wall. I... I'm glad you pointed out that post where he sitting on the desk fret because that is very funny. And and so the doctor are talking Scrooge and Donald pushes him that he needs to see a dock. Right? Because, like, memory problems could be a screw loose quote. And and we get one of those very typical
Scrooge
beats. Right? That's this is his character.
He won't do something even if it would be better in the long run because it's gonna cost money, even though obviously, this should save him a lot in the long firm and So he he talks about using one of those, like, strategies, people use to remember things. Henri, do you wanna tell us about his strategy here? Yeah. So he wants to tie string around his finger, and there's some random string hanging from the doing and as he pulls it, well donald looks on a gigantic
boxing and glove plus down from the ceiling.
And which just honestly to me also one of the most significant panels
Because of classic classic. Really is. His his burglar batter,
it feels
super
iconic to me. And that panel where he just w
himself is a masterpiece.
And and so when he does that, you know, that does convince him. Maybe he does need the see a doctor.
Know I can you wanna tell us about his visit to the doctor and and the diagnosis.
Sure. The doctor
diagnosis in with pointers of the thing which is a mild form of an issue. And I love that blink of the thing.
And of course, screws asking if this
were to be cured and the doctor brings up this huge meal and of course, Scrooge is afraid of that and rather.
The thing is that the big needle is not intended for him but for the small capsules
that he needs to take every twelve hours to keep remembering things. Right.
So
with that said, they are leading the doctor's office
and now, Scrooge
begins to remember some things from the post. I I love this next sequence.
So much. It's one of my favorites I will note really quickly this, you know, the the needle not being the the real needle is that's a classic trope. It's it's a cli, but Barks does it pretty well. It's also funny to see that this doctor is also clearly a pharmacist to
And and I actually... I mean, outside of the the this page that the Ducktales, one of the... It's so full of stupid little ge in the background.
Wish I had a dutch version because I'm really curious had translate all these final things the parents signs in the background. A funny price list, for different medical procedures and and his
diploma dick quack because, of course, quack medicine is is a term. But there's also something interesting in this in the sequence to me, which is... Because this... Especially is one of those those comments versus Scrooge is being remembered as being really rugged and
and
and not afraid of anything. But then there's several parts in this stomach, especially this page where it's being quite windy and he's running away from from the needle. Yeah. That's a great point.
Chicken the nineteen sixty swedish prints and the background science on the same panel one and four, but in panel five, instead of shell pills and meat,
we have one box of viruses and one box of. How nice.
That's that sounds on it is. Alright. So I... What... I gotta handle this next sequence
carefully
because
It it feels really impactful to me. Right? You've got Donald is casually
asking Scrooge on the walk Barks if he notices his memory
improving. And Scrooge has this great far away look throughout their and he's just kind of mu to himself and it's very clear that something is coming back to him. And the words that he is
saying.
They are they're really magical. Right? Because we can tell that they reference something from his past. We can tell that it's something really siding and impactful
And long buried
in his memory.
Y joaquin, what are the first the words in that bottom left panel? Gold
sk dawson.
Yeah. And and then when Donald asks him about it, you guys I'm just gonna I'm gonna go with it. I'm gonna do my my bad Scottish accent
sure sure. This is.
Better than mine.
Yeah. And and then Donald asks about what he's mumbling and he says clifford and gold. White a Creek four rocks in a square. At N then Henri eureka, What does he go on to say? At least five hundred pounds of pure nuggets and and and the new doll just trying to snap and out of it, but
let's see what he says. The old blood ball, the trail two white horse
mosquitoes, but I...
Goose
then school turns around and I'll all to go on a trip with the nephews right now because he needs him. That's because
I'm not sure what the first time is Scrooge does that when he basically just expects donald to drop his whole life. Yeah. Yeah, it's definitely something... It's it's definitely a Scrooge tray. Barks spins eight panels on this sequence. An writer what
had Scrooge
remembering things in one panel. And in the second panel, it will say Let's go to Inducks, and that will be over but the set of works is working here giving us glimpse of Scrooge memory
that's just great storytelling. But of course, you had many pages to spend
so we could let base sequences
for
page. Yeah. It's so
tantalizing. You're you're absolutely right. He does such a good job of, like, laying out the rest of the story with these little bread crumbs.
Yeah. Yep And regards to the drawing...
What I... Because parts drawing stars often so simple, the background are it's there's only the information you need really, but I love how just applies slightly
making scooters people smaller or pointing slightly differently. He manages to really
this far away expression and half file... We've just... He just draws two little lines in the in the fourth panel screwed somewhere turns around just by drawing these two little movement lines you get this idea that is solid snaps turns around towards the and Al external Yeah. That amazing
start tuning with good tuning out with just two lines you can convey all this this acting and timing right. And and so,
you know, twenty minutes passed, we had some snappy writing where Donald tells the nephews who who have to come, of course. Don't ask me where we're going this is uncle Scrooge party and we get... We get something we don't always get. We get the title call out. Where where Screws tells them, you know, it's it is my party. You're going with me back to the cloth deck. And so on the voyage
to to Al alaska, you know, we get Scrooge
reminiscent, and he's he's finally, he's got time to kinda leisure tell the docks and by extension us. About what he's remembered and what's so urgent. And he rem to the docs
about his time and the Al dyke where he made his first strike as a sourdough.
I I love the... I love the terms that Barks uses. I felt like I learned so much about it. And he he talks about, you know, the hoard of nuggets that he buried on a place called White Agony, Creek that he walked away and forgot about and he goes on to rem
about
a girl. Henri Enrique, do you mind telling us a little bit about his reminiscent
Scrooge screw starts talking about how remember that buried is sort if not said the creek, but then he says, no. I remember the nuggets and more much more He remembers
a girl.
And his nephews look just the surprise as we as the readers are. Of course glittering goal the star of the north. She was span and flashy, and her heart was as hard as the eyes on the tundra. The only live one I Severino knew.
And all just says golly.
That's some really nice writing, you know? Like Barks wasn't just so just just an artist. You could really write when he when he had to, some some really poetic lines. Yeah. And that's Scrooge says that. He he looks down at a sunset in the background. Mh. Claire to be.
It it is. He's he's rem reminiscent very sweet.
And when the when his grand asked if she was his sweetheart. You know, his his his
Premier, his tone changes.
And he says bye. But then Donald points out that he gets a a far away look in his eyes whenever he thinks about her is is a little different too from his remembering what we can, you know, distinguish that. But the thing is here that the eyes are different.
It will look close at the eyes in panel two, the circles with small jonathan.
In implying that Scrooge is actually lying in the next panel because we... The readers know what is money I looks like. We see on on on on the previous page, that the dollar screens. So there's a clue. We know the Scrooge is loading. Absolutely.
And and so Scrooge covers for himself by telling Donald that far up far away look is my
well. The old girl owes me a thousand dollars. And he goes on to say that at compound interest, that would be a billion dollars.
And and he gets this just like delightful money hungry look. It's it's really like it's a pretty evil
expression. And Donald has a walk away one liner, where he says let's go eat kids. For just a moment there, I thought Uncle Scrooge was human. And no
right. Right. He's he's definitely talking about a human but I love this you guys because this is a gag bit, but it's also like the thesis for the whole rest of the story. Right? We're supposed to learn by the end. Whether he is, which of these panels that almost alternate back and forth is is true. Is he... Is he a human
with, like, some human feelings and and a loss to love or is he just a money hungry,
you know, older? And he apparently cares about how is nephew see him
you're not be seen Al somebody with feelings.
Oh, yeah. Alright. Really smart economic drawing here. I mean, the first panel in this sequence, it shows us the boat and the seat. And the rest is most the characters
background. Just a hint that
that... We understand that we're ownership. Yeah. Exactly. Yeah. And of how he uses that sunset to set to mood, but then also in the way the panel is... It's a beautiful panel, but it's also funny anyway because the docs are also small. So Scrooge just leaning with his Al goes on the railing, but because he's so short, it's actually one of the lowest part... It's it's like a brand multiple lower parts. And And actually looks quite quite funny. I love that's the thing that keeps coming back in the Barks, stories and I love putting that in my comic subaru where you make use fact that the Ducktales really would be almost toddler size if they were if they were human one Yeah. That's great. So the docs do arrive Scrooge kind of lays out for the readers. He says now for the truck to White horse, then down the Yukon to Dawson.
So I I love the know, the sense of place here. And and the docks, you know, they wanna know why are they coming along. And he explains to them that, you know,
is a pretty fear place So he's gonna need their help with some of the un
people that they might encounter
kim, do you wanna tell us about their this outfit sequence?
Sure. But the thing is that in,
screws decides that you need to be equipped. And because they need to take the
trail over to the shield could pause and condolences
walking and spirit else. And of course, Mcdonald's points out that there's an airline go there.
But, of course, skirt says my, how this country come soft when it sees that their are airplane going. So he decides they Al work there because
Why by a ticket, we can work for free. So
then make this track through the shield could pause
How seemingly within minutes. I mean, I don't know how much time is possible. Seemingly within minutes, Scrooge is so set on being rugged and that the country is ons
sitting on the donald Barks mister carrie. And then I love how both... The the story continues, but it's also a pretty funny joke Al the same time, I like the sequence, right? Where they're walking up the choke group pass because it's meant to kind of def deflate Scrooge a little bit. Right? He's it's supposed to show him that he's not the young man that he wants was. We're supposed to see that he's a lot more vulnerable than when he is a sourdough though. And and Barks accomplishes this with a very funny narrator box. That chill hasn't changed. Since the days of of the sourdough dose, but the sour
have. And so he's he's forced to ask Donald to carry him on his back If we get a great... A great exchange between them, Henri enrique, do you wanna tell us read us the exchange Stop great When I was your age, across this past with two hundred pounds on my back. Dollars says. If you were Al full of hot air, then as you now, you probably float over like balloon.
And and I love that it's followed up by, you know, the nephews having to support Louis carrying most of the rest of their out fit. Do you guys know about the chill pass? I don't. No so this is a real and very famous
geographic feature sure. The only difference that Barks has done is is he spelled it with a a second c instead of a k. It's Chill cooked.
Yeah. So he's get getting one of his great bird puns on there. But but this is a very famous. It was the only accessible part of of the mountain pass between Alaska and B c to get to the the lawn Gold fields. And so during the rush, you would have this really
po line of prospect factors basically waiting in single file. Don Rosa, you know, he depicted this in a pretty cool way in the life and time stories. Barks doesn't really show it because, you know, this is after the gold rush. So you can't show that single file line. But it's a very famous
seat. You want to tell us you I came what happens when they finally make it to White horse a few days
it's it several days later...
This part.
Well, they just barely made it there. And then the first thing to see is an airport. And if we clone, we have been here a week ago donald says our
grant Scrooge this. And then a carp pulls up and there's a guy in there from
ran point service saying that this school
employee and Scrooge is of course, the surprised to learn that it owes the entire find service. So the could've have found there for free instead of walking
for days and days.
Alright?
Because it did not take his memory medicine And why didn't you take his medicine?
Because it costs ten cents a piece.
Of course. I'm sorry to be cracking out through this. The... This... I've always found this to be one of his funniest gag here in one of his greatest stories because it's it's is funny, but it's so based on this
characterization of sp that we understand. I I love it. So, you know, the core six
for the ron.
And I missing seeing the reader because he's reminding the readers about these memory pills. Yeah. It's a great story device. It's fantastic because he keeps it fresh in our mind without making us like well
unnecessarily on it. It's it's a very Barks at his best. So Yeah. It's a character driven bag, but then it also still keeps the whole story.
Reminds you story as a whole, so it's all together so well. And I also get to year Molly and embarrassed Scrooge, which is not something that we used to. That's true. And it's a great... It's a it's a great drawing of him So the the the Inducks do arrive at dawson. And and we get to see the Al dyke River. And Sp clearly remembers
he's explaining that the gold claim is farther to the north and he says we have to walk to get there. So we're establishing that the next segment really does have to be on like. But they... The Ducktales do take a little bit of time to site see an old dawson. And this is a really neat sequence for a lot of reasons. Partially because it just gives Barks an opportunity to draw these scenes that we know he wanted to of of an old boom boom hometown past its glory days.
And and... But it gives us an opportunity to see screws looking
nostalgic, and it also kind of focuses
us on this element of, you know, the past and memories.
And and we get some good storytelling
accomplished by Scrooge
reminiscent. He
he actually gets to go inside the old black jack ball, which Bark and rows and other creators are gonna end up making my Con. And he walks in. He's talking about where he saw glittering and gold, the star of the north. She was singing after the ball and a she was singing after the ball and a voice is pretty is the crackle of new bills.
And then he immediately
transitions back into his, you know, money hungry lost one thousand dollars that compound interest. Wait till I get my hands on that old gal. That of course is a real song, either of you guys familiar with that song? Nope. I not So I had to
about every detail of this for the podcast. And and I'm glad I did because that song is very significant and very famous and I'm really glad to know it. It it is a song from the very first
broadway musical that was considered to be long run it. It was by Charles k Harris in eighteen ninety two from a trip to China. So, you know, the timeline matches and
And and there are some themes in that because it it shares
in that musical,
a man
misunderstand
and ends up walking away from his long lost love and only learning about her years later. So... And it was a huge hit song at the time. So it a very good very appropriate reference. Frame him to make and I'll probably insert just a little bit of it right here.
This is this is one of those sequences
now where are we Al one of the omitted.
Broken greeting is a cup
right.
So we've just... We've just flipped basically listeners to a page that doesn't exist in four color four fifty six. And Scrooge is accounting and we get something really special. We get a flash to Young.
It's it's a great, like, Hollywood k
of a of a man entering a sal salon. Right? Scrooge young screw enters, the salute to some sn.
And and he
demonstrates that he should be taken seriously by empty his poke onto the sal.
And and in addition to some gold dust, he empty the goose egg nuggets. And he has the whole bar
just a go. And and then suddenly,
glittering gold makes a dive and she grabs the nugget and she's
it in a way that suggests, we know that she's up to no good right away. What what do you guys think about this,
you know, the... This entrance
that he makes and and this scene. It's it's great to get to c Scrooge at a different part of his life. I'm not Sure if we've ever seen it before in any of the other Barks coming yet at this point? Yeah. I know. I think just a couple like a a brief panel in in the previous four and only a plural man, but nothing is detailed. Yeah. So we we transition to another cut page and this is... You know, there's some real stakes here. He explains that he had coffee with gold, and she's probing him for details about his claim. And he he w says, you know, that the claim jumpers that have tried to find it are pile... I'll I'll spare you guys my Scott. Scottish. I have fun with it, but they're piled
so high around there that I have trouble finding Al my self. And in the panel where he near, I don't know what gold put in my coffee.
She just looks so like it's it's a really chilling panel. She looks really Devious
in a way that's not sympathetic to our character at this point. And he wakes up. It it clearly he's been dropped. He wakes up in a snow drift miles from town. He takes stock of the fact that his pope and his nugget are gone. And he heads back to the black ballroom
ready to go on a ramp page. Well, you can tell the Barks had fun with be sequence. I mean, showing this dual rush sal,
the drug of Scrooge the looked on
her face, everything
about these sequence screens. I'm just having a ball. Let's just draw the stuff lot of this time error, but I didn't know it was going to be become. Right. Or maybe he was crossing his fingers that it wasn't yep. Also love that they're getting coffee.
But...
Yeah. I do think with the way Barks, like, drying women himself, I think all these look where he asks more coffee
She's supposed to look very pretty Ducktales. Yeah. It's not not sure if it's my taste.
And hence some looking at docks. Yeah.
Yeah. And you're right. She's supposed to look very su
but also,
like Devious. And and I think as far as, you know, a female
doc it works. Boy She she is icon to me. And the issue that I'm looking at has her just colored all in gold as any color
should good color should have made the decision to do. But but she looks great It it's very iconic. That old dance haul look. And this next sequence is also gonna be super high Khan. You know, he barge into the sal into the ballroom in the manner of an old western, and he's sn, weak wings and coward have ten seconds to clear out. And Gold is kinda waiting for him giggling
with likely some thugs. Obviously, the implication is that she does this frequently. Right? She rolls minors
for for their post. And she's gotten away with it before. And
on the next page, we get this half page slash panel that is really unlike anything else that bark ever did and that his editors wanted him to never do again. Two bad, two n's.
I mean, he shows the guys calling that with access and knives.
And stuff and this is just a big fight
he's asking for that sequence to be cut. And then of course, screws twins, and as you said, set on the previous page that
ground is cleaning, there are people pile to high around there trouble finding it.
He else go through that... It didn't just say that. He's actually piling the bag guys up. Now he's using a pile of of toss
guys as a staircase case to get too gold. So we could wonder if this whole sequence is
just some strong story dialing on Scrooge part. Or if this actually happens...
Yeah. That's a great point, where I think we're definitely meant to wonder. Right? Is this just one of screws just tall? Details or or did this actually happen? And I know that, like Don Rosa will play with that idea later.
He'll of course, do a couple of homage
to this Barks room fight. I'm glad he could get away with it by the by the late nineties. And I I like this sort of push pull, like, oh, no. This didn't really happen
quite that way, and then and then other writers will give him that, yes, This is exactly what it But I I like
when it's left in the middle a little bit. And it's funny this this this great fights now is I can absolutely
understand why it got cut, but being
European and having grown up as every European reading asterisk as well. I would think absolutely nothing of this battle, actually.
Oh, you're right. This is... My
now is more violence than
And this is totally
reminiscent of one of the asterisk
massive fight. I mean, I mean, Barks
and Walt Kelly
were very influential to the best european economic artist. I think Right like one of them was inspired by better work probably. So I would not be surprised. No That then again, they couldn't definitely... It would I've seen
high.
Boston and
I don't know if I'm saying their name right? Wouldn't have gotten to have seen this great him. Yeah. Because our is from the nineteen sixty. So... Yeah.
But it it's it's amazing. It's both violent and slab stick at the same time. The the narrator box is great. It was a fight to be proud of. I was like a buzz,
men fell rose like Domino's.
And and by the end of it, you know, he's covered his goose na, but the other gold in the pope was stolen. So he makes her right a faithful
I you. And he tells her one thousand dollars, ma'am, at
compound interest where I tear this dive apart splinter by splinter. And he's just gotta look of furious. So it's a very... You know, this is definitely something to talk about. Right? He is he's righteous
upset, but he is basically taking the law into his own hands here. And he... The the thing that he's about to do he about to kid map her. Exactly but at the same time, I do under stand why he's doing this because he's been working so hard for this gold. Digging out there out in nowhere and she has kelsey, drugs in Ducktales Al Barks gold without even working for it. So it's about to show her how work is done out in the wilderness. How hard it is. Yeah. So on the next page, she's working for it. She's digging for gold or a Scrooge says keep digging that, you don't get in the supper. So she learns the hard way. Riots? You you you say you understand it. And I understand it too, but it's still. It's a moment. You know? I think it's in keeping with kind of the, like, classic hollywood vibes where this was, like, a convention, you know, the the woman is kinda taken forcibly
I find it pretty uncomfortable.
To to read these days. In this story that I love. And and I... I've got a note that, like when Dawn Rosa went to revisit this scene and when Ducktales.
Went to revisit this story. They both took some pretty
clear hands
to
soften.
What happens here to give her a little bit more agency.
Mh. I guess we can talk about how successful that is. But it's it's interesting. Yeah. That... What I also find interesting is that she looks angry throughout and she does not look scared, which makes... Which make it feel very different. And she's calling him a roof, but she
misunderstanding what he wants to do, which is, of course It's it's interesting that he suggest her thinking that... Yeah. A wolf because the wolf is definitely someone who has
intentions in in the language. Of that day.
But but as you say, Scrooge only wants to demonstrate,
you know, the hard work that he goes. Real. And
and that second panel which shows
Scrooge carrying gold. That might just be also something that Scrooge tells is nephews.
And... But ultimately, I think that was way of Barks showing that sequence in sort of plenty way, quotation mark. And yes instead of dragging her along, he carries, her. I do feel like that whole sequence everything that you see is the way Scrooge is talking in figure speech and you see everything literally early, which is also kind of meant Al as a joke. But, yeah, I do agree that it's it's... I can actually understand why this would not have been now. Published at the time. But yeah, I do feel the way came across to me, but then again, I I I grew up reading a lot of old school comments that are a lot worse in my opinion. So because she doesn't look scared, it never really came across that way to me, but I mean, of course, it's it's Scrooge is way out of bounds, but he's also not meant to be in my... At least that's how I see it Scrooge is not really same as with mcdonald's. He's not supposed to be a character
who sets an example. Definitely not in the Barks only. So Sure. Yeah. And and it definitely helps that by the end, you know, she is very pride full. And when he pays her for her month were, you know, fifty cents a day, all you earned and it's all you'll get. She throws the money in his face and s off protesting. I dug more gold than you did. You tight wide. So, you know, she's she's got her own form of pride here. I didn't read it as a kid. You know, I think I I've consumed a lot of old media too. So I do think it's just meant to be kind of in that old hollywood
style of storytelling.
And it's is it fair to look back on it with today's?
Of course not. But, like, we have today add a is. So It's it's it's one of those cases where I kinda read it with two brains. Yeah. That's right. But but... Yeah, her saying her calling in wolf makes you clear that parks was aware what it what it would imply. Yeah. Absolutely.
And then I think this is really key too that he says that a month past. That's a really long span of time for these two to be together. You know? I don't mean to jump ahead, but, like, I've seen people very critical of the idea that, like, they had any kind of a romantic flame here, I think I think that this one month passage I don't see how it could imply anything else. With the combination of, you know, his, like far away
remembering and this one month passage and this like old Hollywood
print. I think it's iron cloud, and I I honestly think it's a bit silly to not
acknowledged. The way that Barks has set this up. This is absolutely in another universe like basically a classic.
So...
So I do... I do really like how almost nothing
Al implied, so it's really up to interpretation. Absolutely.
You could you could drive a semi truck through that one month. There's there's no end of the stories that you could tell if you were so find about what happened there, but I know what the convention that he was going by.
To me it's iron. But I understand that other people might have other ideas. Henri, do you wanna tell us about the next page this this is comp duplicate.
Yeah. So if we if we have any more recent printing of this comic when we go to the next page, there's
four panels in the middle. And if you look very closely and you look at that's for too often, he'll be able to tell that they're not drawn by Barks. But
there were panels that were evident by
I think they were based on a sketch that Barks through up trying to remember what sequence is missing there. So... Yeah. So we have I'm trying to see what it looks like in the original printing again. Yeah. I'll I'll kinda summarize it while you look at that. But he's basically Donald checked in on, you know, what's happened Scrooge
left. And he's established that Gold left years ago. And so Scrooge is upset that, you know, she skipped down.
And then that sequence that you referenced that's been recon
by Y is basically him talking about, you know, and they're establishing that he hasn't skipped his memory medicine and they count the capsules
to make sure, which is very important to the rest of the story it it should be noted. Yeah. So when you read the story and the way it was originally published,
so the that version. This whole sequence... The entire flashback is is completely missing and donald kind of comes back seemingly me out of I was nowhere because he hasn't really been gone mentioning that he found out gold skipped down. But, yeah, what's interesting is that the many of the person were got that it really makes makes sense that they're missing because for obvious censorship reasons. But then, I guess this this part that's missing is missing to make up for the page counts. Yeah. I think they just needed to make it fit in a certain number of pages that that But yeah. But this sequence that is missing these four panels there very... Once again, an important reminder to the the fact that the the
isn't skipping his his medicine. Right. So, you know, yep was trying to really... He was going for a style match. What do you think? Did he pull it off? Is that
But do I think I you're.
I'm curious what you what you guys think? Well, I'll tell you that as a kid, I never noticed anything off whatsoever.
Now so I don't think I would've have... I don't think I would've have noticed doesn't a given. So I don't remember when I was about fifteen. I for right this. I don't remember because I was reading a
a scan of an old call, so I don't remember if I read this version or the old version. But I did So I got this photographic print
while ago and I did notice that it was... It did stand out to me it's being by,
but to be honest, I've been spending... I spent a lot of time with my life looking at dance art, so it's stuck out to me as being his but. He did a really excellent job next human install. I don't think any
unsuspecting reader would Severino know is it's also... If you know that their sequence is missing and your go looks for it, you can probably away... You could probably tell, but... Right. Yeah What what do you think you are Well, I do have the nine eighty one Barks pencils. Next two year not the original, but the the printer versions, I Barks did the detox the way you drew them in the eighties, of course, So Ji
just ink it, he had to withdraw it, and make it more fifty style. Yeah. I think makes work Al diego assist you can tell if you know Don't need the style but for the cache reader, it works nice. Right. I think that's just right. I I think it's a great great job. All things can etcetera. And and I by to instance because you
you asked me if I could ask him about it, but I said didn't get the same anymore, but I did happen to ask it very recently, but, yeah, I would like to ask what it was like to add this panels through such a significant story, but... Yeah. What he mentioned was that he really really tried his best to make the installment, which I think he did a good job with... Can imagine must be very hard to match the inks especially that. I agree. I think he was very successful. So it definitely helps it transition better to because I feel like it would have been very jarring We we get to the arrival at wide creek where his claim is and his cabin is, and we see that someone's living in it. There's evidence, you know, of smoke. And so when the do approach, to investigate things. Scrooge seems to trigger some kind of alarm, a rock falling and he gets some some shot fire shot at him some butt shots.
And so the Ducktales are clearly being viewed as trash pastors.
And they need to lay low until
time when they
go to look for the place marked by four rocks. In a square. And
and the next sequence
is a nighttime sequence. We don't get see a ton of Barks nighttime sequences. I don't think. But it's it's basically all about blackjack.
It it is... It features
the bark silhouette where Scrooge poke a boulder that he doesn't remember, and it turns out to be a g y Barks. This is a very wild bear that chases the Ducktales.
There's a great funny gag where Donald gets chased up a tree It does the little catapult or
thing and it playing him.
It's it's exciting. It's funny. And just when Donald seems like he's in danger.
We see the Barks called off, its name is black jack. It is a team Barks
and the Inducks all see a little old lady holding a shotgun gun, walking away with the bear. And we've got this little moment to end the sequence of of... I mean, it's kind of like a toxic masculinity
thing, to be honest Right? Screws has just been very effectively chased off. But once he sees that this is a little old lady, he
he gets angry and he demands that they come back and fights and so they comply and fire off another round of a bucks shot and that Barks chase again and And so the Ducktales have to kind of recon around their camp campfire and figure out what is their next step right very lovely panel what fired. Yeah.
Yeah. So yours also a little bit I was curious. So I've just been reading the old version alongside them somewhat restored version mostly restored version. And
one thing
because the way the page is flow, it's interesting that's for a few pages here, the the ending of the page is halfway
where to you see the page and at a different point. And where you write the common pages you usually tend to end on something that makes you want to turn the page. Yeah. And case. What what the original layout was? Right. And
good at that, usually. Yeah. And another sequence
that's missing here, there's another half page that is not not in the original printing apparently. But it does look like it was this is drawing my Barks for sure. But it's where
Scrooge
sc talks about how he does not want to send the police after gold because he he would like to keep Al lot out of it because he does not really have any legal ride to the claim anymore. Right? I think this results got just sort of making it fit with the pages. Mh. The wonder what the would have thought of Scrooge also wanting to keep the lot of it. Maybe that's also not something that you're you're
just saying it disney.
You're you're right to guess that. That... Because that was part of the thinking is my understanding is that that felt very like moral for for the hero. Yeah. Although the thing was Scrooge to me, that's always interesting Is that you not a hero. And mean he the hero of the story, but then when you make him too heroic, when the pictures of him become to, it becomes uncomfortable to meet because this whole being as a character is already. So there's already so much wrong with him being a ty like that. I... When they make too positive, it makes me more come rolled in the other way around? Yeah. I I agree. He should Severino look too here, Re. He's a... He's a complex character. So the next so on the next sequence you know, they're gonna try to address the bare. And and this is a fun sequence. These these these sequences
outside the cabin, They're a little bit lighter. It's just
meant to give the docs to delay things a little bit before they encounter
the oc
of that cabin. And so they establish
to get rid of the Barks. You wanna tell us what what they're gonna do, you are. The are building a cage trying and to learn the bear. Just the case with some honey, and, of course, Scrooge is only paying than twenty two cents an hour. So which has to do it himself. I love by the way that, you know, he he gives them that two cents an hour raise for their great idea of of lowering him into the cage with honey. And as you mentioned, Scrooge needs to do Scrooge needs to lure him himself because he won't pay the wages as fired.
So there there's a hilarious moment where Scrooge has forgotten to open
the jar of honey. And so he's forced to run into the cage. And fortunately, the jar breaks
spreading honey on Scrooge and the bear just links harmless off him. And so they've gotten... They've taken care of that beer. They figure out that their next move while Scrooge beds himself is to how to disarm the old lady with the gun. And one of the nephews chimes in really eagerly saying we've got another bright idea and basically
propose
to to have the older duct
distract her and they'll go around and sneak inside and surprise her. And his brothers are kind of wondering why did you volunteer a for this, and he says it's because I kinda like to meet that old lady. Wouldn't you? And that question is directed to the reader as well. Right? Because we're all... The reader has presumed at this point what the nephews are kind of figuring out. That we probably know who that old is. Yeah. And it's a good thing it's the Nephews going for because they're sweet and innocent.
Right. And if you look at the word surprise and panel folder on on this fish
that. Yeah. It's something about Barks Yeah. I wonder what... I wonder... I was also wondering what what were was originally there. So the nephew was saying we'll sneak inside a surprise and a and the font... The the writing of the word surprise is clearly... The letters are squeezed. So there was originally a shorter word there. But Right. Was I if it was something a little more violent, like, you know, jumper her or... Yeah. Probably something that could be the wrong way. Right. Yeah. Haven't that the panel just below it where they say twenty three cents. It's been red drawn. So... But it doesn't make sense. Well, wow, whatever. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. There's all these little little, like, artifacts. Yeah. So our next sequences what I think of Al the Ra dazzle sequence. You know, Donald is making a big rocket to try to draw her at attention.
And we get a little bit of the old lady's thought wounds as she realizes that, you know, her bear is gone. They've kidnapped. Him while the nephew you sneak inside, and she has this really cool way to deal with claim jumpers.
She shoots some boxes.
Out of trees that turn out to contain billions of mosquitoes.
That instantly
pursue
donald and sp.
It's it's a pretty funny sequence there. Yeah. I just noticed but that the word kidnapped and... Has also been written in the book, but the original version just has a different and older spelling of the word. So it's only nate. Yeah. So which panel? So you see Al these silver silhouette and she says black gone. They've kidney kidnapped him And in the... I the scan of the original publishing and there it's kid kidnapped only with one feet. Yeah. So sometimes maybe some of these edits are literally just fixing
spelling or?
That's the third time I've encountered that spelling of kidnapped in Barks comics. In the ghost of the g, I believe and in the mommy's
ring, and I noticed that every time it stands up. And so we have this sequence now where we see the old lady talking about how she's been running out was off the claim for forty years and she'll keep on doing it, so we get an idea of how long this individual has been here. And then the nephews
get a get the drop on her They they pretend that her room is actually a shot, and they they hold her up.
So we're lucky, I guess that that didn't get cut. But
she is just shocked to see that it's three little boys that have gotten the drop on her and and she revealed she introduces her herself and as we have already suspected, she is glittering golden not a surprise.
Right. And and f user surprise, I think that at least some of them were suspecting who they might be, but it's still a shocking moment. And we know that there's about to be a reunion.
And we transition back to this very silly
resolution of the mosquito trap. Yeah. So there's a whole there's a whole page
devoted to this absolutely
disgusting
very funny over the top way of dealing with this these mosquitoes where since you wanna tell us Henri Enrique, it's so gross. Yeah. So they're they're getting chase that his giant cloud with mosquitoes and Scrooge says stop don't move, let them settle on you. And as they get entirely cover
and Al cloud from mosquitoes those they let themselves fall over the ground, which the sound effects literally says crushed, you know.
As a rollover, and then they've got two perfect mosquito rug.
And seems this is actually the scene that I remember most clearly from my side. Yeah. Same with me reading this for different
part that I remember the most because it's is so bizarre. It is bizarre, and it's horrifying. But it's it's very funny and silly. What do you think You chemo... Are you guys allowed to show the docs naked these days, Scrooge there? Oh, I I don't know actually. I don't know.
I have seen
were there was a Dutch comic where the they're in a pyramid and Scrooge mixed the nephews use of shirts to store sorta they're all walking around, naked and in the Us they do And...
Yeah. Once you call them, like, under.
I'm not sure what you got it they do I'm sure of them, so that's funny. And so we've got the Scrooge is is determined to make the old lady a for this humiliation and pay plenty. And and we transitioned back to the kids converse station with gold.
And they explained that their boss is awfully anxious to meet her and that he says that she owes him a billion dollars. And I think this just has to be read verbatim. Right? Because she wondered who would try to take a billion dollars from a starving old woman, and the Nephew he replies Scrooge
dot at Y, do you mind telling us about her reaction? Oh she just jumps out of the chair screaming
Scrooge Inducks because she is actually surprised. Should not expect it to seem him ever ever again. So now she realizes that she's done. He will take every single cent cheese scheduling
because while she is surprised to hear from him, she is thinking to herself, oh, wow. He is the only first in the world who who would hold that I you and she she explains and it's very sad. She talks about the ballroom going bust after the gold rush ended
says you're looking at one of the old time gals. And you know, the nephews immediately,
the Nephews are feeling very simple static to her, but unfortunately, one of them is already headed off to spill the beans to sp my doc. And we've got this really
interesting point in contrast when screwed first years. That the person in the cabin is glittering gold. His first
reaction is to, you know, very prominently
say gold. After all these years. And her name is Inks like very in very small text. To me, I read that as him kind of saying it, like, one Lia faint in a very, like far away, man. But then, you know, that passes and and this sort of battle
between his two natures is winning out if he says that's perfect because he's planning to collect that Io you,
then we get that contrast again where he's very finally comb out his.
With a little pocket mirror trying to make himself look more dapper. Oh yeah. And love her right after, we see later and going do exactly the same. She also tries to through a up for a Scrooge. Yeah. But I read hers as more defensive.
Right? Like, he's he's looking to go on the offense, and she's just looking to kinda.
Bit of both. Yeah. Of the Barks please
sc not as a one dimensional character but it keeps the reader wondering with read Scrooge be the one that it's it's like his inner conflict
there. Right? What's who's gonna win out? Sc Scrooge
or
Romantic credits. Yeah. And I love follow with
which happens more with the stores business especially this one. We're basically we're looking on to the team together with donald and and the nephews. Like you can... Scrooge screws expression shift around you can also see their expression just around. So donald looking videos every diamond Scrooge just kind of rhino with more v eyes.
They're alternating
between them used and the disgusted. And I'm what a great sequence when he like Barks on her door. Looking all confident and then she opens it up, and he just will
and he's he's just... He's struck by her beauty. You know. She's she's old. Like like, he is, but she does. She looks beautiful. The way that he remembers her and they engage in just a little bit of banter before he gets down to the business.
Of her owing him a billion dollars. And I think the reader feels very disappointed for a moment here. Yeah. And and on the next panel, the one of the Nephews looks absolutely
discussed was storage.
Oh, I love their expressions there. But you can also tell that this whole time, I feel like
donald is seeing through it way more than the nephews too. Just from the stretch the mcdonald the whole time, you can already see... I mean, that's looking back of course, I'm spoiling the story, but it's it's donald. You can see from mis expressions that he's way more of to with what Scrooge is actually going to do it in the net user. I agree. This is that great ride donald from around this period. Now we get this, like, really sad scene where she gives him the little paul bit of jewelry and everything that she has
explains that if if you must know the other money that I had, I used to take care of the poor children who are left
by mining disaster first. Is that the original
dialogue?
Do I remember that that was, like, a redo? That's the redo? Yeah. Let's see that you refers to something that was in the deleted. But... I mean, that she gave away all the money to the gold miners gold digger
who really earned that money.
It looks look like the only words server were replaced is mining disasters. Mh. But
I think most it is related. I think off the end the word left is
close. Yeah. But then I would have it's just one of those elements where we kind of... They wanted to soften her, but we know that she's at least trying to leave here with her ride. So she's just... She's just walking off as proud of she can saying that she's gonna give her Barks freedom. And there's this very po scene where the Ducktales
her walk away and and Scrooge
stands there, and he finally resolves to himself and he has a deal to make can he chases after her. And and so, for the the last sequence of the story, he sets up very quickly here. This competition where
he references that she wants mentioned being able to dig more gold and he could. So he proposes a race that whoever digs up gold can have the claim and can keep that hold. And he directs the nephews to take her up on a k
nearby a little hill to start her digging. When the nephews
are convinced that he's still in, like mean grady Scrooge mode. So they're out outraged saying that you know there's no gold up here. They're thinking that he's just trying to save face essentially by giving her this one last chance. Yeah. But you can you can see that it's expression. You can see basically from that moment when gold is about to walk away. His expression completely changes. And you can see that he had a change of heart, but the Nephews don't see through yet right. Yeah. He... Only the reader, I can kind of tell that Huey, soft and even Donald who's time
for the competition seems to think that Scrooge is, you know, not
hasn't warned.
Because and they wonder if if what Donald is thinking at this point, but because Huey, Annoyed that ed Scrooge
screws says because the nephew basically flat tells Al this point. The column Al old fiber, which is quite... Not the language they... The nephews would usually use on Scrooge so they're really quite angry Al him. Yeah. That's true. Who says... Oh, so he wants her to win? I like that and Scrooge. This kid's will never be rich. They're two tender they're hard and Ducktales is good for them. Yeah. It's a nice exchange
And the race doesn't last very long because do you wanna tell us what immediately happens you I? Well, of course, the gl goal fines all of Scrooge gold because he directed her to the place to the four rocks in a square where he hid all office Cool.
Scrooge.
Running up to the panic which is great
acting... Exactly. It's all fake acting. And is gets on the ground keeps crying. I forgot a buried the nuggets on this snow. I should've have taken the capsule this morning. And this is Al is scene and No. Don't really
suspect something. I love Donald
expression there. His knowing
realization at what's Scrooge is done. Because as he walks away, still performing and raving and keeping up his cover,
the Nephews, the younger nest hughes are disgusted, and they're saying that you think he'd be ashamed of himself and Donald Al tells him he is boys, and he asked if they counted his capsules last night. And and they said, yeah, There were six of them. And Donald revealed that he recently
swiped the box and counted them again and shows them that there were five capsules.
And that he had rigged the race to deliberately lose it and save face for both him and gold. And and it's such a sweet and dear moment to me. I I love it. I love that ending you guys Yeah have me to. It's such an almost abrupt ending. It feels like a very... Which happens more of Barks or is it after the store feels so epic? It just ends there, but it's also
perfect ending. Like you wouldn't really want there to be anymore because this is just a good moment to end on. Yeah. And I remember also
reading this and somehow not expecting this ending. So being surprised just like the next. It's very sweet. And and it's such a simple little device. You know, counting pills. He gets so much
pap and and heart out of that. And and it's a little bit diminished by the rewriting, the the lettering being done work, they've changed slightly what the Nephews say. Because know, they say, well, what do you know? Good Al uncle.
Because yeah also wonder what Huey, said what they said originally. I guess we'll never.
Yeah. I suspect it was just a little bit pi here like, maybe well buddy know. Is human and after all except he's of ducks that they can get the
buddy what do you think you kim? How does the ending work for you? I.
And
glitch gold, it turns out to be she's not super rich. I mean, that whole cache of gold must be worth fortune. Yeah. So this is why spirit shown her that he knows that she learned her lesson. And she struggle all her life after this...
After the scene where she left him the first time. The I think you knows, that you deserves it. We get a lot of softening here even if he won't admitted to any anyone. And I think that's I think that's why people love this story so much. Right? Because it really does show this softening of screw There was a little bit of that in only a poor man, but this one really
his picture, and it really adds a little bit of depth to him and in a way that Barks didn't really previously bother with. Do you guys mind if I transition to kind of the community reception here? To
so So let's let's acknowledge. Right? I always check in on index to see what the community thinks of these stories and and this is it. You guys. This is the bid one. This one gets the highest
rating Inducks. It's it's got a score of eight point nine, which is good for number one out of all almost forty two thousand
stories.
As far as I know it's had that ranking for years, and I don't think it's likely to change
So I I guess that's the big good question
like, one of the big questions you could ask of this episode. Is this the greatest Scrooge, Donald, Disney story of all time. Do you do you agree with that? And and why why does the community think that?
But I think really trust people and and specifically
Al fans because of course, of course, we all love Scrooge. It's really the character building in this comment. So it might not be maybe the best of all the comments, but it's the one... When you already love Scrooge
you notice character really well, then this come agree stands out specifically
because it's this very rare moment where you share the soft spot and it really sticks out your memory, and I also... I I also have a soft spot for when there's character just characters, they're all tough and then they actually... You find out that they do care. So I also love that. So I really feel like when you... I mean, it's it's a great story in in any
regard, but I really feel like this one specifically stands out to people already like Scrooge character lot. Where maybe some of the other really high ranked
would also...
They would maybe be better ones to let people reach who don't already know the character, but this one basically gives you one feelings if you're already, like, more... You see more alarm feelings if you already know Scrooge well. I think I think that's really well. Said. What about y. Well, I I think that as a fan was wanna know more about the characters and how it was before you met in the first time and we see part of we see a John's
is struggles and
I think that might be the reason why people enjoyed so much. It might not be the best crafted that story Barks ever did in my opinion, but it's it's a really good story. Yeah. It's it's a great story regardless of this things and... But yeah. Also, in indeed, you get to see some of the this backstory, which it's it's so much that our ar and could also build from against so also feel really significant in that regard, I guess. And now, I mean, I'm also very sure that this comment being so highly great is also in part
rosa who built on this stomach? Oh, Yeah. Definitely agree. Right? Rosa,
he really ran with this story. And and honestly, it's probably
probably what some people might even mistakenly remember if they think that on this story because he filled in,
you know, I I think he would tell you he's not barb. But for a lot of people, they they really do treat his stories with the same sort of
seriousness that they do barb, and he was the one who was the most prolific with basically writing in Barks
universe and the most interested in it. And he loved Glittering Gold. Right? He loved using her as a character.
So she gets a lot more exposure and stories like last led to Dawson and parts of the Yukon
and the prisoner of white
Cr.
What do you guys think about his kind of follow ups to these stories. What I can say... So I... Yeah. So I I I did read a lot of Barks and comments based on Barks from a very young edge and when I was about maybe... I think I read the donald call about thirteen to two fifteen years old when I was reading for all of them And I I actually love at the time I love the life and dimes especially
even drawing
stuff of it. But then for me specifically, I actually did not like a mistake on on the word, but it's also has to do with my character and I always use a child that always really dislike any
in it in the Ko. At least depending on what the characters were like. So I know I would... As a as a kid, I I would not have liked the a much more obvious version
there's no go way around it that it's reminding and I actually... I do agree with you that... I mean, it's obviously employed, but then I I like it when it's some things are more less to the imagination. But that's, of course, with with all done rose comments because it's the fun of it that he fills in his version of all all the gaps as it all together. But... And I really enjoyed reading a lot of this
stories, but then when it becomes the definitive canon, of course, it's only one person's
version. And I do notice that that's where sometimes people also create comics
sometimes have an issue with it because once one person's version becomes the canon, you cannot straight from it anymore where parts himself would constantly break us own canon because you have to... And yes to use a different version of the characters every time to make the story works and. He resets the stage each time. So on one hand I I I loved it these love an whole life time where it's so a definitive version, but once all of disney economics starts treating at the canon and the fan street to the scan, it becomes really different difficult to create anything new anymore. So I both I... So I I love reading a stories, but yeah my personal take on on how we would how it treats their interaction. It's not really my taste So on all of the roses colleagues, I tend do like, the ones with gold, the released or at least that was what it was like, I'm I distinctly remember. I think what is the title of the one? Marty where you see the think it's prisoner of white Egg Creek. Yeah That one I was fifteen. I I I loved reading it through all of roses economics and I was
buy and all the dutch my Al the minute, and I imported the life times from the Us even and I was sending family to Bar rosa, and I remember when... So that was when that covid nearly came out. And I remember I really did not like it. And then never also... Because he also does a lot of any new windows that like I didn't even really understand them. And then I had to people explained to to me is a very sweet innocent
sixteen year.
I know that that one, you know, raises a lot of people's.
That... It's it's a little bit on controversial for that. Reason. I do really like that he gives her some agency by having her hiding a gun on the way to, you know, being taken to his claim. I don't know if you remember that hard. But Yeah. I do I do, like, aspects fit for sure.
And it's really funny to me how
the duck fans always start fighting over it.
It's funny to me too. I've been shocked by getting involved in, like, the Inducks, you know, universe on the web how how ready to fight, But I I guess I should check myself because I have my own bias,
like, like, I don't really like to acknowledge the existence of Feather for example, but
I know. But but let's acknowledge that, like, I love borrow Barks, and I don't love every bark store. Right? Like there... I think there are some that I think are pretty weak, you know, You got to, like, go to that cool exhibition this week and that particular to story that he had the art featured for the beauty business. I I find that one horror.
I mean,
comments from the period because Yeah. You would think people would get more progressive over decades, but one of his fifth... Late fifties and sixty columns feel way more dent than Yeah. A little bit more ones. But it's basically because he already wants there also just no women.
So so I mean, I I consider myself a big rose Right? And I... Like, the life and times was... That was a big deal for me. But like as I as I got older, I... I I appreciate that it's not perfect and it has its flaws. And I do think it's better to view it this kind of one version of, you know, Scrooge story. And I think it's super appropriate for the other creator shouldn't feel bound to tell the same stories in the same ways.
I love that, like, different artist have their own styles, the event, you know, like van horn wildly swoop style. But any anyway, he did do a lot for the character of glittering gold. And I I think that's really cool. If anything, his version of gold is is almost the one that's in the public eye. At this point. I I think it's often the also the fan reaction because that's the thing with very intense fans that then create who change something get angry reactions. And it's also... I think even don Rosa himself was well maybe not irritated, but also just
by the idea that fans consider his work better or more canon than
course. It's his hero so that's right. It's always know homage for him. That this is Still a Barks
podcast though. So, you know, let let's go ahead. We we gotta wrap this up. I know we've been at it for a while. I do wanna mention
that we have had a lot of occurrences,
not just in rows stories, but, you know, a lot of creators
have told stories kind of around this. Using the character of Glittering and Gold. I know there was a
another pseudo sequel by the carr and Tom Anderson and Brian Gladstone called Dyke pipeline. I've never read that one, but I'd be interested in it. It seems to be one of the more highly rated vc Barks stories.
Yeah. Read as a kid, and I don't remember it now. It's been many many years since a originally last time. But I remember as a kid, I thought was fun to see gold again. Yeah. Yeah. I should check the that. If maybe any of those stories are are stored with my early childhood memories because I do feel like I always knew this character
without somehow reading the original story so that says a lot about how bright much this part of of
again know how much
later artist took from only these few very small things in... Because she she only pairs on it on and full of pages and and then even the... I guess, my most of those follow ups comments came after
the restored versions were found or not
anyway with how this
how the original version got discovered how how did that so... Yeah. I read kind of alternate alternate tapes on it. Do you know you Barks? Boom is in one of one of, like Roses own
books the background material says that
says that some dedicated
fans
tracked bark down, like at his house I got to see it first that way, and that that's how they put it in the.
Like, I think that's what it says in... Oh, I read that in the life and times companion. Reese and some of the, like source material. But then if I look at, you know, the Barks
information, it sounded like he never got his gauge back and that may be an added or held on to it. So I don't pretend for this podcast to be the end Al. I'm gonna miss different things here and there. But I think we've done a nice job of kinda talking about the significance of this story. It is interesting fascinating that Gold is like such a memorable character for this one of appearance.
No. I mean, are you enough the vinyl rock album
gold.
Fine. She... This story was also adapted for the first run of Ducktales. It's not a great episode. I don't think it compares to the original story.
But I do like that they give her a lot more agency.
She is kind of with him by choice and to prove herself in that episode. And and, of course, they don't re tell the story in the second Ducktales series, but Gold is a very prominent character. She recur quite a few times in that one. As kind of like a an venturing
foil to Scrooge
and still like a little bit en even in her older age. I don't love the representation of it of her in that one, but it's it's fun. It's interesting. I'm trying to remember who she was voiced by. She was voice by someone interest
And then of course,
Bark did a number of awesome oil paintings for this one.
Some pretty different scenarios,
variations on the cover.
A really
nice po in sweet one
depicting is encounter with gold. It's very cute. And and then I I never really mentioned my own. You know, feelings on just how the story works overall. And if it deserves, it's it's high ranking.
I I do love this one. I don't think that I would place it as like, my number one rated Barks story or even adventure story. But it's gotta be in the conversation. You know, it's it's gotta be up there. And and I don't know that even a lot of the people who voted for it might call their number one just I I suspect that it
consistently
getting
voted very highly So certainly a top ten, probably top five. This is a Al ind, like,
unforgettable classic
that
really holds up well, except for a couple of parts. But
but yeah. So
favorite panels, guys, any any panels that you wanna go to bat for that stand out as your favorite.
We know the ball, the black ballroom room fight seems is super iconic for a lot of reasons. That's an easy like, one to mention. There's definitely some good
panels. So
funny thing is in one of my old time favorite panels. I even forgot for all that came from this story because it's could've been from any ten page but the the giant boxing glove hitting these Scrooge across just as somebody who left drawing cartoony gigs that's just such a great panel. But Yeah. I also really love the panel where
as Gold is leaving
and all you see in the fore are are the silhouette of of Scrooge and and Nephews.
And is this it's such a good use of sealant silhouette where...
Yeah. You really can sense to the seal is simple and you can even see that the nephews are holding your heads in their hands and she walks away. And it I think it's really possibly the most important moment in this story because it's the moment or screwed Al the change of heart. Yeah. You're right. It's It's beautiful. It's it's
no no text whatsoever. It's just very perfect use of just using s silhouette and just conveying so much with soil.
About Huey, any of them stand out to you that you wanna call out? Well, single pass,
we have this in the beginning of the story where
Scrooge hangs up the the phone assist. You are donald Inducks. I think that's one of the funniest moments in this story. I agree. I I think that one's a riot. I love that one. I I think just about any panel that's on that lock of remembrance,
that he's making where he has that far away look. I just love it when Barks does the far away look and his du it's standard. Yeah. The excursions. There some spot on and.
I love the panel where we talked about earlier house Scrooge
rem reminiscent wireless on the boat. So it's it's really nice set with the sunset, but then and and the the express is perfect. But then in a way it's also funny because he's honestly this really that railing is way higher and him. No of
with many of these panels so that my first favorite panel is a really funny slaps one, and then the other one is more really quiet small moment. And the fact that it's in the same as Kinda crazy.
Right. I I gotta mention that the horrifying mosquito nets or mosquito Rug sequences
gross me out, but it is like you guys said, it's Al. You always remember that. And
and his, like, I
expression when he's rem this know Yeah. I could mention so many specific expressions when Scrooge is standing in the doorway all nervous when he sees cold and But also
when when he... That moment with where he signed looks Al evil when he's saying, I we I got to see her again. Because yeah. Acting is so great and this Absolutely.
Awesome. You guys thank you so much for joining me. This was like a a
exhausting one to talk about, but we had a lot of great things to say. I really appreciate it. Thanks again.
Hopefully,
people
have made it through to the end of this up so, I would invite them to join us next time when we get to cover the horse raj story. That'll be a lot of fun. And,
you know, check us out on the Facebook page or Instagram, and
and thanks again.
Actually there is actually a perfect closing font which is yeah. The screws.
Yes. Good Al on Scrooge screws. Or whatever ten originally sent because we don't
rest.