We can have
Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer an artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comments of all time. Join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks. Welcome back to Barks remarks. I'm Mark Sever, a Grown man who enjoys Inducks comics and I am joined by a ira returning guest host, Y Kim Gun. Can you
introduce yourself and tell us about your connection to these clinics? Thank you. Sure. I'm also grown man.
Heart. Ja fan, call Barks spam is Super pants. So it's a pleasure being on your shelf. Speaking about this story or just
Barks in general, I think it very too much Barks because it ends heavily influenced by his stuff. When I wrote,
which I do have some an coming called.
We've made some a few adventure doors that speaking about this particular story, what we're gonna talk about today. Yeah. Why don't you go ahead and and tell us what what are we covering today You're looking? Yes.
We are covering a one classic call Barks story from the early fifties
called the horse Flat story or at least that's one of the titles.
Because I think that Barks didn't title this originally, or least it wasn't printed in the calling. So he had to make up some titles
and when he was asked by the fans,
do you remember any of those titles? Yeah. I I really like one of the alternate. Titles.
I think trouble from long ago that is my favorite. I know there there was at least one other. That was in some correspondence.
I I can't remember that one.
Okay. Well, this story...
I mean, I read most of the Barks stores as I very young kid. Because my my father was a doctor van. When he was a kid, he started collecting
buying this comments in Sweden back in nineteen fifty six. A few issues ran week, but in nineteen fifty seven, he began to buy them all and he continued to do so until he was around nineteen twenty back in nineteen sixty nine. Mh. And my grandparents... I mean, when he will away from home, he left all these comments with my grand. So I was a kid,
loved with visiting and because they had stacks and stacks old comics on the golden age and the course.
Treasure trove. Sure. And I wasn't even know allowed to look Al them mall because
they handed me a few and said, oh, well, we have more I wanna say more. Well, next birthday,
next Christmas
so... Yeah, a lot
visiting them. However, this particular storage. The horse raja story was published in Sweden. Back in... I think it was nineteen fifty six Yeah, ninety two five, you said, that's a year before my father started buying economics. And the first reprint was published in nineteen seventy. The year after My august stop clayton cox.
And the next was in nineteen eighty six when I was round loud So I don't believe I had really disappeared. And therefore, I don't have this strong emotional connection for this story as I do have with most of Barks other stories. So I'm looking at this though in kind of different
perspective.
Important. What about you? Yeah. You know, I I have pretty much the same story as you to be honest. Like, like you, I had these...
I collected. I I think I probably collected kind on the same time frame as your dad where I started getting them. Maybe a little bit younger. I was about seven, I think. And once I figured out Carl Barks, no I grabbed everything I could. Once a reprint, once the story was nearly reprinted, I would I would get that. Once I got all of the contemporary ones, I started to, like, look through the back issue bins, and this one just for whatever reason, it escaped me for a very long time. And so it was like pretty late. I think I was into my teens, but I knew enough about Barks to know that it was a pretty famous
Bark story, and I I finally managed to get a hold of, like, the very first American
reprint of it. Which was the gold key. Yeah. You're looking at the same one there except as you've got the Wit like icon there. It might be that... This might have been the first time read. Yeah. Oh, yours is a forty center minus the twenty cents. So that's the next... I think that's the third time around. Okay. But but regardless, like, I want a long time knowing about this story and being really, really curious about it. And so it wasn't one of the stories that I read like a hundred times
as a child. And and I've gotta say when I finally got to it. I
enjoyed it, but it... I didn't I didn't love it. The way I did some of the, like,
reprinted over and over from that era like only a plural man and back to the cl day again and and so on and so forth. Exactly. But I used read that for the middleton done, the great
incoming artist we work regardless and some
now
not in the Us. Is said on Facebook that if I want to pick the best Barks store ever, it would be this one. So it's got some big name fans. It it does and and it shows up really high on Inducks. Right? It's consistently like in the top twenties.
When fans vote for this one. So I've gotta ask myself like, what am I missing? Yeah.
And and I'll be clear.
Right. I don't dislike the story. I I really enjoy it. I just... I... It just doesn't have that same punch for me. So it's interesting that both of us kinda feel the same way that that'll be something that we can keep in mind as we go through the the story itself. Yeah. Why don't we take a moment? I I I gather that you,
you got to be part of the editorial team
in Sweden when this was reprinted one of the last times around. Right? Yes. In Swedish Kara and extra, which means donald doc extra in nine in two thousand eighteen.
We tried to reprint doris in every issue of this common book we... Are our reprint Al long call store as the main feature. And for this issue number six two thousand eighteen, it was time for ga
Opposite else as it's in Sweden. And
together with this editorial team, I wrote piece about it. And...
Yeah. It's kinda feel a little bit daunting being kind of in charge of
introducing these Barks stories to, like, contemporary.
Yes. And nowadays on
the main of this comic back in two thousand eighteen, I was just a part of team. Now I oversee every page of this comic book and I try to make every special effect or or the
perfect
giving
my teammates
sometimes I must think a little bit demanding.
Yes. Detail oriented.
Exactly. If something was wrong with previous printing, wanted to correct it. I this this painting will be the perfect printing. That's always what I I imagine that every time an a company
a publisher,
reprint it. They're probably thinking to that to themselves, right? Where this is the
Severino or the thirteenth printing.
Of this story. You know, they've gotta make a decision. Am I just gonna put it out there? Or am I gonna put it out there with some kind of life?
Commentary, am I gonna really focus on on making sure the coloring and the lettering is perfect. Am I gonna try and make the definitive version? And everyone has a little bit of a different idea what that definitive version is. Right? Exactly because the this version
has got some coloring
will lots and loss of ingredients
and I will show you since I see on screen here, you the listeners
to nigel this, but it's an water sequence
where the caller still come bonkers
with using
ingredients
every panel
everywhere. And and that would be computer
assisted. Right? Yes. I mean, some people love this. I don't. So it's Al also a matter of thinking what is the best version in which way which way showcase
Barks vision of this way the best way I think that too many ingredients
takes away
from Bark art and the storytelling because they can take over and you become conscious about the coloring
instead of reading the story. Yeah. I do refer some more so Barks. Yeah... That's totally right. Like, I go back and forth. Right? Because I love the coloring on, like the Carl Barks library
in the nineties, and I know that that was computer assisted.
But but to my eye, what they did is they tried to, like, computer assist, but to help what the human hand and the human eye could do not to substitute. So I I don't know. It's it's one of those things where I I can't
describe what I like about it, but I know
that I like it, and I think that like, Susan Dave elite who oversaw that. I believe I think she did a stunning job on it, but I know it's not to everyone's taste. Yeah. I love her early stuff. But then I think that there were too many greetings. So sure. I like some of our stuff
just like some of stuff. Yeah. Yeah. Well, let's talk about
some of the background of the actual story.
The
The first
The first publication in in the states was in four color
four hundred and ninety five. And
that was in July of nineteen fifty.
Three. Yes. And this one's a little bit shorter
than kind of its contemporary.
Right? Most of the most of the stories that were in early uncle Scrooge,
But and I I guess, I I neglected to mention, it is the four color but it's all currently called uncle Scrooge number three because, you know, when they when they went and gave uncle Scrooge, his own
monthly title or or bim monthly or whatever. When you gave him his own title, they started the numbering at number four. So officially, this is
This is both an uncle Scrooge and a four color. And and it has a companion story, a ten pager
Is it the round money bin? Yeah. Yeah. Okay. It's got, it's got a companion story because it's it's on the short side as far as the adventure stories. And I I do wonder if that is some of, you know, what affects kind of my my perception of the story. This one has not been reprinted in the states as often as again, some of its
And, like, for a a long part of my childhood and teenage years, it it didn't show up on the reprint schedule for a while. So it is a little bit harder to find. Exactly I see. All the ten times in the Us. But I can tell you that back in two thousand eighteen.
We had Al seen
six
publications of this way. So that it was time to rethink again. Right? The time was right. Yeah. Let's see. What else.
I I do find it interesting to think about the title Right? This is one of the few titles where the, like, official fan
designation feels like a placeholder holder. Right? Oh, it's It's the one with horse.
It's the horse rad story. Yeah. And let's see. I I know that this was the first story, I believe that his his new wife at the time
participated in
doing some of the lettering in Exactly.
You can see on at least a few of the pages. I don't remember exactly which ones.
But I have listed that she did most of the lettering on pages one through fourteen,
and heated did most of fifteen through twenty two. Yeah. Through the book you you... You're problem. Right? Yes. I'm not I'm not. Sure.
Her doing is
rounder smoother. Yeah. And as should say that I suspect that she did more than just selected this story because when I examine it, I think that...
She's a magazine, the villa in the story. A few of most of these panels are kind of not up to par with the regular bar sinking But
we can talk more about that when we get to those panels. Yeah, that's an interesting thought. I know I've seen some speculation that she might have done, you know, on pitched in on some stories. He's have such a prolific output. Yeah.
That the other weird thing is, like horse rad has kind of a stylist.
It stands out a little bit right, but it's kinda old fashioned
hyphen
in the middle, which you don't usually see.
You don't have that. We we usually should write that word. Right. Okay. I didn't know. Yeah. To me when I read it with that it's very distracting to see that hyphen
just... That but there's a few words like that, like, in the early Barks Stories, I see
kidnapped.
Spelled where it looks like it's spelled kid.
And and it just I mentally stumble over it while reading. But has... Can you tell me Your kim has horse ref been like read inked
the the text redone because every
every writing of it looks like someone has rewritten it to me. Yes. In the beginning of the story, you can tell that both words or and reddish
are written by someone else. Yeah. But once you get into the story later on here, it's in some places, it's definitely Barks on and and writing. In one place, it's
just the word radius that's been re
replaced. I have no clue why
of the Barks wrote course various in the end of the store. Yeah.
It it's... It stands out, and I don't usually have, like a great eye for that kind of detail, but it even stood out to me. I... It made me wonder Did the story originally have something else
and someone decided that like horse
would fit better. Was there some other, like, really potent spice that he was supposed to be a hauling or something.
I I know that in France, the story is called
it refers to clothes in the French title.
So that kinda made me wonder. Because there is one panel
where screws says, what's that source in the paper cup? And horse where is not Al source. Right? Right. Yeah. You're right. I would call it a condiment, like.
Yeah. That's not really accurate. So the maybe in mind
after a while, while joined the store and then had to went back and change it. Yeah. That... That's what I was thinking about.
Alright. So we've had some good pro log here. Let's let's... I mentioned that French title,
We'll do... We'll name a couple of the titles from around the world, and then we'll get into the actual
story itself. I looked up I've got three this time. I've got Denmark first,
where
the Danish title and you can probably help me out because it's a it's a scandinavian language so you know better than I, but it's
More Beta
and Carmel Al.
Yeah.
How bad was that you came almost
That was pretty good.
Motel and.
Most good Al pronouncing and danish.
But this... That time is almost the same as the swedish one, which is
most of the gamma good.
That means must pay and old. Yeah. Same same thing in in Danish, apparently but it's, like have to pay Al old debt. Is the translation that that Google translate gave me. Yeah. So and I know that back in those days,
sometimes the Swedish comments or translate from the danish translation. Right. So that could be the case why we have some similar titles. And makes sense.
And then in in French,
I had mentioned the title is Al
year off.
Okay. And when I put that in to translate it, it... They're really short though. In a way I found suspicious it just said, and the clothes.
Okay.
So
maybe I'll put it out on on Facebook and and see, you know, if there's maybe a pun in that title or something. And then, boy, I'm really intrigued by the German title. The the German title is
Oh, how do you say thirteen
dr sig? That's l twelve tried same, brighton and Try. Right? Yeah. Right. Okay. So the the German title is Dry
Tweed.
Thirteen
trillion. Okay. Do you know anything about that? Came? No. I have no clue why
called it. Yeah. Fascinating.
Sorry folks. Someone... Someone will educate me after I drop the.
Sure.
If anyone in germany here's this, police us know. That's right. Five percent of my listeners is German. So someone...
Yeah. And you know what, I looked up a little bit about her strategy and I learned a little bit interesting. Please tell me. I I found that apparently,
in addition to there being studies about horse,
having a nice bacterial antibacterial
component that can kill harmful
bacteria and microbes
it apparently will drive some Inducks.
Away. Okay. Okay. So Barks, did is research photo the story. Yeah. One of those moments where he seems to have gotten something at least a little bit right. That might have been... The inspiration was start the story.
Goodwill be.
Alright. So any any
other thoughts you've got before we go through the actual narrative
of the story. No... I think you can start with page one. Yep. Let's let's do this. We're we're gonna do what we usually do we're we're each gonna summarize the page and then just chime in with our observations.
And so I get to do this lead off page.
And
Barks is so good at his openers. He's so good as introductions.
We get this really great
very
intriguing
splash panel
that is kind of the back too long ago. Right? It it is the it is our trouble from long ago. And and shows a ship rep. His narrator box tells us when it tells us where
we learned that this ship, the Golden goose that was bound from Gladstone,
Scotland
to Jamaica,
sank without warning off the southern tip of Haiti. And Barks
just so so quickly, leads us into the the meat of the story itself.
We get to meet a man who is introduced first in a a sinister
silhouette.
And he is bearing a court order
that ent him to every scent of uncle sp
fortune.
And Scrooge kinda takes in the document. He points out that it it
that all he gets to keep is an old suit of clothes
and it further
indicates
that he owes him any teeth in his possession if he has
And
units, it's not until the very last panel of that first page that we get a good look at the man, who is the very memorable
Chi.
As he says, he is the last heir of the clan makes sue. He just tells Scrooge to if you wanna know more keep reading. Yeah.
And and and and first was I didn't think about this
before you mentioned it about the cy silhouette because for me as an artist I was
distracted you by having two
stacked upon its to us about each other, but but of course, it's it's a storytelling device that I don't think about. It's...
I I think it it... Sorry. It does... It does a great job of engaging the reader with who is this guy.
And you know, as I cover these in order,
I'm struck by the fact that this is the second of his stories that I've have read that opens with a big splash panel
with a mysterious
ship rep because in no such environment.
Yeah. Yeah.
Because because he does the same thing,
in no such environment, and they're very reminiscent of each other, but but very different stories. Yeah. And and this first page. I have to say that, you know, when the store gets translated,
we have
the mentioned that the Golden Goose was bathroom from from Gladstone to Jamaica. And sang to the warning of the southern Severino
of Haiti in Sweden
because Ga
to Gibraltar, and it was
it's sank in the English gel. Interesting. Yeah. Because, you know, Go
support, a big port in the Southern Sweden. Al little of the sweden. So it's... The probably try to make it make more sense
Right. For this smooth this audience. I will see that don't next page. But that it doesn't... It doesn't really mesh with the weather of the story.
No. No No.
I mean, I mean, if you try to make sense of the story, the settings
and the self seize like wrong here, the coral rates and everything, it doesn't make sense at all.
Right. Yeah. Kinda kinda reminiscent of what is it that this scandinavians
like to localize luck of the north is as Donald Ducktales Greenland. Am I remembering that right? Exactly. Exactly. Yeah.
Yeah. Well good I think this is a a pretty strong opener. Go ahead. But maybe maybe the punch would been stronger.
If Chi
for shown on page two instead of at the end of page one. So you you have Al your peach Scrooge. You think one one more panel of ci silhouette maybe.
Maybe made.
But on page two, we
continue with the Scrooge reading this
explanation.
That she's gives him. And we see that it's a flashback sort of to the four others
where the sw of like shipments suit.
Talks to kept C mac Ducktales, and make a deal. Where ci duct agrees to transport a case of horse values to jamaica, ownership,
the Golden goose, and it has a steiner contract. And it doesn't have it's Gladstone.
Unfortunately,
Because of course, this could contains a fine print which says that you will essential to lose or all of this money if it doesn't delivered and stuff. But
stephen science the contract and the the ship syncs, of course,
all the sale or is gold teeth, and she's...
She's a poor father takes over house and everything. Too surprise.
Yeah. So this is this this is an interesting flash. This is one of the few times where Barks kind of like
dwell on Scrooge
past or rather, like his his lineage.
Exactly. And the
and that Think is not a good storage panel.
Not Barks is a fourth panel where ci pump signs the contract it reads as it it's spoken in a in a tactical play. Mh. Was a a misplaced my spec
what does the smoke prints say? Oh well, never mind. It's kind of obvious
where where this is going. Yeah. I I think that's a really good point. I I... As soon as you said that, I was like, yeah, that panel,
it's it's a cool visual of him sq.
And it reminds me of, like, Scrooge sq later on in the money well. Yeah. But
but it's a little bit on the nose, and it feels a little bit like it's kinda hitting you over the head with...
Because you get the explanation on the building's page anyway. Yeah. It's interesting too that, you know, Chi and ancestor sw. They look... They're they're essentially the same character design. Exactly. I'm also struck by how plastic Scrooge is while
while he's been kinda taking this in. Right? He's being very, like reserved. Barks has him just being very very stoic and very une emotional. Yeah.
And what you think you came about this element with the false with the gold tea. Oh what about it?
It it stands out. It's... I I don't know. I feel like it's something that I I want it to work better.
Because it's such a... It it's it's almost iconic. Right? But then it it's weird.
It's every time I see those t time, just I'm creeped out by them. It's it's extremely weird because we never see the Ducktales tea,
Except this time with this golden and teeth, and it's looks weird. It does. Like, like so I'll go on to the next page where you see cfo foam kind of greeting is teeth
at that
at that contract and the fine print that says
exactly you said the small print pledges all your worldly possessions in the event you failed to deliver the horse strategy. And he's gritty those teeth, and I'm just so distracted
by it.
It maybe that seem was the reason why we used go teeth. Just gas to Al that
Maybe, I think Barks might might just have found the the very idea of someone
demanding your gold key. Yes. Just such Al dignity. I think he probably found it funny.
I guess, boy, you know, this is obviously, it's got a bit of a theme here. Right?
Contracts. This story is interested in
contracts and legal e's
much in the same way that he was focused in Golden helmet on on people using the legal system to, like, take advantage of each other.
Exactly he had not forgotten about those lawyers. And realize. Yeah. Yeah. He's not done.
If he doesn't, we don't have a shark key in this one. Right?
Chi just has the the contract itself. So so that's what Barks must have been thinking about that
contract maybe as he signed those divorce tape.
Yeah. And it says judgment,
big letters on the top of. Right.
So so we kind of flash forward back to the present. We we finished the flash
with
with cfo foam
I
running away
from Mix.
And and then we flash back to Scrooge who who sums it up for us, basically because my ancestor
wouldn't give your
a set of gold teeth. I have to give you everything I own. And we got chi sm they are saying that is the law. That's what our villains in the Barks stories like to hide behind.
Yeah. Yeah. And and Mick
tries to rush him out, but Scrooge has been very,
He points out that he does have his glasses on. And so he can read the fine print. And he notices that he has thirty days to
fulfill the
contracts original
turn
and so we we just transitioned to him
his nephews for thirty days of their help.
To Yeah. To their irritation or to donald.
Exactly. Any like to point out, if you look at power ex... Especially panel four four and five here, I would say that if you Al screwed... Okay. Here's tiny, but the
is not as good as in the rest of the panels.
So it's think that that maybe is
wife gary had hand this throwing backgrounds. Because it we'll see later on in the story where there it... Our patterson
panels with only,
they're also a bit less good ink.
And we should... And we should note that Ga was a very talented artist in her own Right. You know, she clearly didn't have, like the experience doing comic part that he did. But and he also did like hand off some of these duties occasionally his his previous wife as well. Right? Am I remembering that right? I don't know. But but I know that they're already dude. Yeah. Building the black to be lettering and did some backgrounds. So this was one of the first stories that you worked on. Yeah. Wanna be surprised if because said, oh, do just go ahead any the secondary characters
the backgrounds or whatever. Right. That and And in panel six, does that Scrooge.
I I kind of... He kind of looks like Christmas on Bear Mountain Scrooge to me. In that six panel.
Like, he looks a little bit more, like, like his original version. I don't know. Alright. Well, go. Where on next page,
here we find on unscrew
describing
the mission to the kids and within... They thirty days to abuse those gold
t or else. But the problem is that the gold
was
used by screws to star fortune and that's
why now owns
everything.
To she's so much soon. And that's why this is sold good to buy the prospect ultra. And this is, of course, something that Rosa and noticed that
he included c duct and everything and the gold teeth in the store. Right. And and I read that before I even read this.
Okay. But so the conclusion is that since no longer had, you know longer got the gold teeth, they gotta find the original case of horse reddish and bring it to jamaica but Al does points out, it's impossible because it's at the bottom of the ocean, but hey, that won't stop Inducks. Right. It's it's an incredibly long shot. Right? So
I've got some... We do have some really good steaks here, we have a very coherent
outline of the plot.
I do feel like that's a strong element of this story. And Barks, we are now poor paging into the story, you know, everything we need every four point. We now
how much is a stake. The entire on Scrooge. So, of course,
we're not engaged in the story and we're ready to get board on the ship. Will take us on this pressure.
Right. And and we get our second element that deals with contracts here on this next page.
Because the Nephews
do something very wise.
The decks don't usually do this. Usually,
Scrooge is able to kind of exploit them for
for chicken feed wages. Classically, it's thirty cents an hour. But in this situation, they say that that the the nephews have had
trouble claiming wages. So they're gonna make sp sign a contract this time.
And and as he mu over the dignity of being made to sign this, he gloss over some fine print. Yeah. Exactly. I I really
this makes me wonder what kind of fine frame the Barks encountered while dealing with this lawyers? And that might also been a
starting point for this story. Yeah. And do talking about fine frames. Because it this is the gimmick that runs through the entire store. Sure. Maybe there was some terms and his legal proceedings that he didn't become aware of.
Until later. Yeah.
But So
so the docs launch
and, you know, they they kind of they kinda mentioned that the only clue as to the
sinking of the Golden goose Al that it sank somewhere off the... Their side of haiti. And, you know, he's he's at least he Scrooge is very determined. He's got all the kinds of gear that he needs. To look.
Sure. It's widget edition, it it's, of course next to the white Dover. Mh. Since we're at the in the English channel, and I even changed the clips in the background and ten five to white plates to click oh.
Well, that's that's quite the the background.
Sure. On the next page, the find shape directory. We're we are Al on what's...
It's on page Right? Right? Yeah. It's pretty early.
Yeah. Find an old Al.
And, of course, Scrooge
brings out the
drivers gear and
sinks into the ocean here and commenting two minutes later.
While sinking into the deep. Precious getting bad. And the bottom sight how deep is that correct and then donald says the rated the rate says that it's three thousand,
you must be two it. And of course, that's three and four miles
later on in the final plan on this page.
Explains
why Chase donald that it's about chinese land lovers learned that is have is an inch. It's six feet. And this joke is totally removing the swedish division.
Is
how much do you think of adam's
one? Well, that's too bad. I I really like this.
I really like this joke. It's one of my favorite parts in the story. That this is the kind of humor that I really like.
One character
not knowing a technical
term and the other character
teaching them. I learned about a fathom from literally reading this story. I'm just comparing the old swedish
translation. And and then the first one from the fifties, it says didn't it you see it was five hundred meters, which doesn't make sense?
Apparently, Google tells me the deepest point in the Atlantic ocean is is twenty seven thousand and and a half feet.
So this is pretty deep, but not but but it's a realistic depth. Yeah. Yeah. So
okay. Be... These this part of the story that we're in, y
it and it's gonna kinda go along right? Like this for a little while. They're gonna be looking at various
ship ramps.
And Donald is gonna take his own turn.
And just think about this is the part of the store was just just fun games. Because yeah we know that they are on thresholds homes No for some fun parts that will quite not the story because we will get more serious later on yeah It's just fun. That's a good point. It's kinda it's kinda like the site Severino part because we get to see some different ship Barks.
The ship x look really neat. They're from different eras
We get... We get these different, like, Donald is kind of being a tourist locking at the different kinds of fish.
And and those are some really neat panels.
Yeah. But Scrooge.
Screws is yelling at him to keep him on track and And at some point, Donald comes across this little mysterious bit where he realizes not seeing any fish right here. Yeah. And, of course, Uncle Scrooge on next Page Al at him If you come to place where there's a ship called the Golden Goose, Wake,
long after to give me a boss. Well here. Because it's getting irritated. Why report, there's no fish while they they are an address on?
Of course
very important later to arm. And and and then get a red herring speaking fish. Yeah.
Now
seize. Finds an old Al and this side, this pressure has and we Al swedish we of course, within... Oh, he found it. If found the how horse strategy, this the nutrition and work. But he only finds times and rub and piece of eight and our surprise, why, I mean, Scrooge would be delighted to find this in any other case but when it's entire poaching the steak, this is just threat. So.
Yeah. We we see a which
jason and dolls
with this cane while the nephews are playing with the issues in the final panel this page. One of the very rare times where we'll see Scrooge very, like dis
in a and a pretty big fortune. Yeah.
It's it's about. It's. On the next page,
the today's passes. Right.
Yeah. And and this next page is really all about that passage of time. Right? Could we kinda have a clock ticking in the background?
Like in in the back of our minds, we know that they don't have all the time in the world.
And Scrooge is becoming
for
because his time is running out his chances are running out. So at some point, when the nephews hughes brings Al lunch to sc to cheer him up. And this is that part where you mentioned that Scrooge calls it a sauce instead of condiment. He he asks about the sauce.
In the paper cup,
and the nephew tells him it's worse rad,
which of course, triggers screws to be
to fly into a range because horse rad is the cause of all his problems. It's it's very convenient Right? We've never heard any reference to horse rad that I know of in any other Barks comic but but the story demands this part, and he... He toss the dinner over in a rage and went on Q tell,
about what donald notices.
Yeah. He noticed that all of the officials
vanish. There's a ring of water around that spanish, not fish will swim. So... And that makes him think about the place he visited it a few days ago and they turn the ship back, Don
And now, he makes the hottest in under
history as a as a caption says here. If finds a gallon, under Coral ledge
yeah. Because
it and bugs must had some joined this signal because I it it's Ducktales and he wouldn't have done it if it hadn't enjoyed it. Right. But donna enters
the record shared, he noticed that a dozen beams were sold almost in two So his conclusion, of course, that swim of mac was going to make sure that it horse reddish ever reached Jamaica. Yeah. And of course, in the ship, tahoe finds the host reddish. Yeah. Well, well sealed. Yeah. Very well sealed after two hundred years I find this This is pretty cool. Right? He goes out of his way to to make the ship wrapped pretty concealed.
First off. And it's interesting that it's like kind of painted as solving the mystery
The reader, of course knows that that both Mixed
are are Devious
themes. So, you know, no one is gonna be surprised that there was sabotage,
but it's... We needed to see it confirmed. Second So the Inducks haul the horse rat up and they celebrate,
but Scrooge isn't quite ready to cheer too much because they they only have
three days.
Left of that original thirty days.
And
he clarified that Jamaica still two days away if they have a fair wind but
they seem to have been be recalled
because we have no wind at this point. Not too much action on this page.
But it does a good job of kind of getting us a little bit anxious, Like, I'd say... Yeah. Because it's a nice relevant to it, because on the previous pages we have had this
outrage from Scrooge,
the trash
and know everything is called and still. That it's it a the column before the storm,
which is which actually is in this space. Because
on the next page, the in the morning, the wind has dried entirely, so now they cannot of get panicked
and Jewish is radio the
port for Tug as a they can towed to Jamaica. But also,
they see these dark clouds and there's a hurricane
coming. So even if they found all the force reddish, they still have problems. Yeah. This is nicely set up. Right? The... I think I think Barks does a good job of of ratchet up tension here.
We
we can tell what's coming. It's it's that eerie column as you said, By the way, I totally gloss over. I need to comment how great Scrooge looks in his snappy, like, sailing ga. Right? We I I can't believe I forgot Right Donald is like perpetually wearing a sale outfit.
And Barks never does this with Scrooge, and he almost never dresses him. For the occasion
on these adventures,
I think sometimes when he's in cold weather, Barks will go out of his way to show him wearing cold weather gear. But but so the best of my knowledge, this is the only time he he does this. Could be. But as would said it's always nice to see some kind of other clothes. Yeah. And of course, here is Al it don't make sense with the doll having used sailor suit and the net you said there's small sailor hats and everything. Yeah. But but but it looks delightful.
So we get this neat sequence where Scrooge is Scrooge is trying to
convey over the radio. How urgent it is. Neo opens up his purse strings. He... He promises a million bucks.
To
whoever
can
give them the toe that they so desperately need. We got a really cool panel of the shipping silo silhouette the calm
ship, broadcasting its Sos, and we see we see it being received
So we know that whoever is on the island is gonna gonna put it out there, you know, that they say that maybe someone will risk the storm to give you a tow. And then we basically see the the storm stripe. Now the these are some pretty
great panels
of water pouring on Scrooge looking very determined.
Ton looks very,
you know, he looks like he fits in and his sale or regard. Yeah. And and then the story making a good sixty knots.
Yeah.
You can tell, you remember the golden helm story is been discussed His
Barks
health
press Al.
And here we are again. I bet that that karl had
his opus Al and sunny pages at hand and drawing this storm at sea sequence.
You can tell that me enjoy doing this. Yeah. Big waves
nice
and everything here. Right. At this page,
the follows the one you talked about two thirds are only
shots of the shape from a far. No closed stops, No deductible,
we see this storm so we can
understand how dangerous it is and ship is
breaking apart and the fifth time is just one long big panel
most black to the reader not understand of
this... Red and then cut to the and his companion. Sip rings or maybe doing things some eating some ice cream on a
Al a hotel in Havana.
So is a nice contrast Our heroes risk their lives, the villa,
drinks.
Yeah. Exactly. And and you sense that Mix is, like, basically already spending. His fortune.
Exactly. Exactly. But I have a first boss hotel
best rooms, best room service drinks and everything. And then he gets the news. Yeah. But you think that O doc will never find the golden goose and the radio
says flash Al unusual
comes from the H Hurricane area, and then on next page, it gets to hear the news the all that underscore offers a million dollars for Power boat to tow speed between Like.
I like his response to the radio. You know, how he's outraged. She can't spend my money like that.
But but then he his face like, he goes into shock because he realizes is what that means.
And the radio kinda makes a joke about about screws mission to deliver a load of horse. Because because, of course, in English,
Horse rad is like an idiom
for, like, Bs
or or, you know, baloney.
Someone someone being full of And and so so mix so is
is upset and he kinda goes into it ti. And and his his account there that we we only just get introduced to. His name is Joe. Right? He's just a tough. He kinda calms him down. And until cancels now gotta to find out where they are. And and we we kinda know what's coming, but then we flash back to the Ducktales
really flounder in this terrible storm.
And and when screws
instruct dewey to keep radio, we get this neat echo the last time that he looked towards
that, you know, in that panel, it's it's a repeat. An echo go of that seen
And dewey just tells him hey, I've got news for you. The radio washed board. Two hours ago. I really like the Nephews expression there. Exactly is so sarcastic. Yeah. Wonderful. This is a very
sarcastic story overall. We don't often hear Scrooge himself that you had pointed out when he was radio to Donald while he was diving he was sarcastic. Yeah. But on the next page, and
sort of mosquito pump in the first panel, say oh what click on you? How old phone to feel for helpless and we can see how
is. The water is pouring in over the ship. The next panel, one is lena nephews
can't we see one of the net use saying the the routers broken off. The compass shows the drifting straight sideways of her course and
Scrooge just can't stand. So he gathers all the the Inducks trying to make this comfortable as possible to they go inside. This is a wonderful panel coming up next power six, such a yeah.
To the rest of the page was all chaos.
Inside, it's Al quiet. And then it is comfy. Oh, very.
And they up to their next almost with water. Right. It's it's a sort of
is it called common relief. Yes. Exactly Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Little moment and a light there. Exactly. And then paul boom bam, something happens outside what can be worse than a storm Al threatens their line. It's just Al
gun boat, pumping shelves and them from a from point blank range. So from a store to Gun thread, everything is going bad for the doctor.
Yeah. I really like Donald react
his expression there and I like the tension that it creates as as he sees it before the reader does. Exactly It's a well executed World planned time. Nothing necessary we only is
because everything seems so very any other panels you for this to the store.
I don't think so. Yeah. You're right. It's it's not the storm that has him terrified.
Exactly this no
understand.
Bad this new situation is. Right. And I really like this next sequence. I think this is one of the strongest sequences of the story we we kinda see Chi Mcs at his most villainous. And we don't... He you know, Barks
Sometimes his villains are scary. Sometimes their confidence.
Sometimes they're like, incompetent.
But in this one, Chi is just like He's very unpleasant and he's very vicious.
Right. And he's he's cut throat in this one just because he's firing a large art artillery
Repeatedly,
he has this really, like,
frightening green on his face. And and he he eventually blows their ship apart is really spectacular panel.
Exactly but... No. I don't have the nineteen seventy Swedish edition Al hand, but it I know that three pages will cut. And if I will remember right, it's probably most likely this sequence because it's still violent
It is... Yeah. Usually, when when
the panels were cut, the pages were cut usually for violent or or scary content. Right? Yeah. Or sometimes, like, yes, just issues,
like, issues that were controversial.
So... But I don't think that this has been ever been cut in the Us.
Right. Yeah. I think that's right. If this is just another of those examples of you you guys can't really publish
anything with this level of gun play at this point. Right? Exactly. Yeah. Well we can... But back in the seventies, I know that there were lots of sense don't know with lots of stories. Yeah. And it really
escalate, you know, when when he blows the ship apart, he and his account
turn around.
And he kind of ponder how oh their ship has sun ports it's on the verge. It's going to sync without a trace. With no surviving witnesses to tell what happened. And Chi takes this really dark turn here because he's he's his thought balloon is tell us that he's kind of pondering, hey, no surviving witnesses, and he turns
on his account,
joe here,
as imagine his head
into the side of boat and then throw some over board. You just trying... It's pure killing here. Yeah
This it's a pretty violent attempted murder. Yes. Yes. In is comic. I'm surprised that this back in the fifties of this to be published one they in the previous issue of the
back to the colombia, that was heavy
yeah.
Fighting not. And that was not in killing us business. So... Yeah. But I know we I know we talked at length about that one when we recorded that episode
Yeah. Did... Do you think it's because
I don't know. It's maybe it's because the fight was, like, so just... The detail was so
intense.
And the camera cast such a loving eye and there was a woman present. I don't know. Yeah. But
in this case... Well, Joe man just to survive by
hanging on to this what's about the rope. Right. Is what the stuck in in a row hanging from the boat. And this is sort of gives a clue what's coming up later on in this story because Barks is always good at planting these small plot things. And
what we could expect next in the story. But in way, Joe,
Joe's manages to
climb back on the motor boat and since she's looks also on the board, he's now left Al sea
left to to zone the docks are making me a rash, and and that goes fast.
How do the make draft
just to minutes from the sinking ship. But anyway,
they manage to survive the shit. Joe has left
and she's a service left brownie. What will happen next Yeah. It's pretty dramatic. You're right. The raft building is is is pretty convenient. Although, I guess there have been a few stories where they've made some kind of ref before, maybe they're just experienced now. And, of course, they had some extra rope from flashing it together because we do see next to the next to the box of worst,
there is a rope there. Yes.
I I really like
Joe's little his last character b where he he forms. You know? We're we kinda feel sorry for him that Mix Huey, turned on him so quickly
and and I think the reader is meant to to sense that his promise to go home and be a square
because his mother always told him what what had happened if he got mixed up with crooks. I I think we're supposed to read that as very genuine. So I like that. I don't
necessarily like how
underdeveloped.
He is. I felt like I could've cared a little bit more about him. If Barks had had another
four to eight to ten pages
to pad this story out a little bit. But I do like how he leaves.
Accept. Usually, Barks keep this the funny names.
This guy just called Joe. No. Oh, yeah. Yeah. He's just he's just Joe is not he's not anything else. The next sequence,
we get one page of the docks.
On the raft with with Scrooge really at his low point. Right? He... The debts are trying to tell him, you know, why would you bring that horse strategy board. We have no chance of getting it there tomorrow. Scrooge makes this really kinda touching
I'd admission, you know, he says you're right nephew. But my case is hopeless, but I just haven't the strength. To give up. Right? Like, I think he's saying he he just can't bear the thought of not being a richest stuck in the world anymore. It it... It's almost he would have to be stronger than he is to give up. Yeah. Yeah. And they ponder...
They they wish that Mcs get a bad break. And just at that moment, they do see him drifting
into
in the ocean. And,
you know, Donald is able to to grab his arm as as mixed pathetic beg to be saved, And this is really the, like, this is kind of the full of the story. Right?
This is a very important moment where we see sp just pondering the advantage
that he's got. I I I I really like every
expression on his face during this overall sequence.
Yeah. Especially panel six it's one of those panels where we can see the character thinking
without reading in thought anything. It's that Barks
far away look. No one does like a far away look better than Karl barb. You're right? And now to the next page, I'm bridge is very determined. He will not stay she's like suit. But then again, pass him back to the phone right. He says I a soft old fool. I can't let the rack. And of course, he saves the villain He does something that he might wanna do, but he a soft old fool. So She's saved he's on the rash and there he discovers that it's overloaded with the horse. Branch.
And of course, it's happened. He put it into the water two thinks okay I want. It's all done. Post forever. And then the expression on Scrooge thinks. He he just staring the water
staring at this lost portion but lies there in the deed, it's all of. And to top that off, she's a like now wants to kill the the five dollars. Yeah. This is this is... I think this is the best part of the story. Yeah. That's my... This this is
it's very tense.
So we motion.
Yeah. I see the characters
drives them and and the person do of screws. Yeah. We see Scrooge being very human. Right? He's very tempted
to make his life easier.
He... He doesn't have to save him. It is of choice. He has to affirmative
choose to do it, but he's gonna be able to live with himself. He knows he couldn't have lived with himself.
Another one donation character. I mean, Barks always treated his characters
humans.
Yeah. And
boy mix suit just looks... He's just such a router on this page. You just you hate him so much. Have you ever hated?
Have you ever hated a villain and and just found them as dis?
Like
I've seen guam gold stories where, like, he's got a little bit tiny bit of humanity
where where we we appreciate him because he's that echo of Scrooge
before Barb, you know, just gave up and made him very villainous.
And and Man is just hilarious and the beetle boys are half plus, but but so. Here they say his live. And in the next moment, He tries to go them. He's so darn ill. Was this scene was later reused by Barks. In the phase
in the store, the great.
Right. Was the
the pig. What was his name and this? It's the the mix wine, whatever whatever his word it's it's it's one in the mc versions. Right? Yeah. I don't remember his name in that one.
Al make Oh, yes.
That's a great name. Yeah. It it's a similar scene
in the end of that story. Yeah.
Was the say he's lie and he would just lay favor by trying to build. Yeah.
Yeah. Barb had some... Had some pretty good villains I I feel like you could've have re... And we'll talk about it. But it's interesting that he's a one off bill. Yeah.
This is a very satisfying scene on the next page Mix two is about to bash them overboard Donald just asks all the Ducktales haven't we taken enough
from this tough.
And he rolls up his sleeves
and and all the docks reply affirmative,
yes.
And they beat the living snot out of chi.
And the next it's it's great. Right? Like the audience cheers,
this is all the routers have waited for. Yeah. And of course, in a addition story,
revenge by hitting someone might not be the
the thing to do. But It works. Well, and and they are being defensive in this specific moment. Right? He about to use a giant board to bash him off
So by the next day, they finally get a break of good weather. But but, you know, it's come too late for sp. He's just laying there for lauren.
Mix, of course, has been tied up, and he's tackling
and in one hour,
he is gonna be the richest ty
in the world And boy think about sc in that spot, you know?
Sitting there while this man
Al
knowing that Scrooge doesn't
doesn't have it in him to toss him overboard. And and things keep turning up as they spot a sea plain, which turns out to be a coast guard that has been looking for the Inducks party and the the page closes out with the Nephews telling the the crew that their uncle will pay them well to fly him to Jamaica.
To Scrooge just confusion. Yeah. Why should we wanna go to Jamaica?
And an
replies to deliver this or values because here is the reason why Barks but all this world next to the post strategy
a few pages earlier, because they they figured out. That makes you would kick it all the board so they tied it to align to detect line to the box. So it's it's Al outside. And now, it's she's a.
Turn to get devastated. Yeah. Of course, if there's a he's route because he he he can't see his own
that he's doing anything wrong. So is it's good?
Nice turn. Things happens is very very fast to it. It's things happens very fast on these few pages.
It's like the advantage.
Right
the the terms, the the the Ducktales.
The advantage changes. It shift so quickly. But the tables turn. Yeah. Yeah. And then we're back and after
we see that just like.
But he's been robbed. It's all happy docs
on the pages on the panels after. Well, happy Scrooge not happy because he owes
the other docs, two hundred and twenty six dollars. And and other things that's fortune.
And one of the net pay will we force this contract as good as solving that can't for that, but and then it comes perhaps, you should read the small print The small print, the Scrooge
explains is that it hooked? Yes. And then if you says, it says that you will pay on the demand. We will leave the box of course spanish.
And of course, screw test the payout. Yeah. It's from all the previous violence,
we know how this funny ending that Barks planned for in the beginning of the story. Ties it very well to together. Yeah. It's it's a great triumph in moment for the Nephews. Right?
The the young readers reading this They they feel great, I think because the Nephews had their clever idea
of tying it secretly to that line
and then we get to see that payoff with the fine print.
It it's a nice little ending beef. I wonder how many kids try this with the their parents. Signing contracts some tiny if I prints the bottom. Right. For that they will connect slide thing or something. Sure. Absolutely.
So so that's it. That's the yep that's the very brisk
adventure story the the horse rad story. Yeah. It really clips along. It really flies.
There are there are some stories that I think could media benefit from editing, and maybe they don't need to be thirty two pages.
But like, this is the babe question for me of this story. Right? I guess there's two questions. Is it as good as most people think? And is it too short And, like, maybe I'm kind of
showing my bias here. But I I do think this one suffers a bit from being a little bit too short. I think it's enough. Because it it hasn't quiet moments. It has its adventure
if it not too long, not too short. And maybe it will have this fun games pages,
in the beginning the tricia so the the...
And we have the signed of the storm. I mean, he devote almost two pages. Mh.
Well, the doctors is waiting for the storm to begin I I think you're right about that part. I think the storm is paced perfectly.
Can I tell you what what I missed though? Sure. I missed the third
contract gag. Okay. I needed one more. Right? Barks is usually really good when he's got a good running gag.
I I think, you know, we've... It's it's more like big big themed little theme. Right? We've got the big
overarching
aspect with the contract and the fine print and then we've got the small one. But I would love to have seen
some other small print element in this. To to do that sort of comedic rule of three that he was usually really good about. I I needed a little bit more with Joe. I I either needed Joe to not be there at all where I needed, I needed a little bit more development.
To make me either hate him more or love him more. But he just kinda... He just kinda jets off, and that's all. Except what I mean, if he had been in the beginning of the story, together was she so when they entered Scrooge from my dot money. I think that would benefit
this store yes but the lawyers in the the lawyer in the Golden Health story. Yeah. Exactly. Or or he could've walked in Midway because I did like. I did like the silhouette introduction. I did like the solitary
man. I also needed I needed I needed one more flash.
You know, I needed... I think I needed that to book or something. I I I like this story. I think this is a really good story. But when I... This has been an interesting and unique one for me, lucky you because it's the... Like I said, it's the only one that I barely remember. Yes. It just didn't It didn't leave it's Barks. And I've been looking forward to going back to this because it's almost like reading it for the first time. I remembered it so poorly. Yeah. Same year actually.
It's it's a it's okay. It's it's a got some
superb great scenes especially towards the end
squeezed in between back to the
and the Hawaiian story
a romantic story that I think they're more memorable
than this one. I totally agree. I think just just by din of where it is. Like, I I have... I have such high
expectations for it. It's on Scrooge number three.
So
And if you compare this door to many other...
Dis.
That was not Barks by this time it's it's it's about piece.
Your always compare
but the Barks
at the top of this game with all these stores though. Right. It won't storage. It's not a fantastic story in my opinion. It works. Yeah. Now it it did a lot right. Like, you said the the ocean stuff...
I mean, he... This this he's so comfortable. He so loves drawing the ocean.
Every bit of that is just great. I I do like Chi Mcs Al a villain. What do you think should he have come back Well, he did in some european stories. No doubt. Yes. When I was a kid, I remember reading about in in a story hold on here and Yeah. But while you look, I'll just... I'll just ponder, like, if he had come back in another box story. Right? Would that might have had more impact. Right? Because, like, we really remember that first appearance long
First parents magic on the Beagle boys. I I do love to hate Mix,
but
I I like his character design a lot. Tail. I'm trying to find
second appearance. Yeah. Here it is. This is a story that I read
kid in the light must have been nineteen eighty d here.
The, the roots battle ax. Oh oh I remember that. Yes. It was apology in the Us Barks ninety two. Yeah. Can we
the breeze apple?
Drawn by the car. Mh. And this was my first encounter with the she's alex.
I guess they wouldn't have in mine as well. Technically although I I obviously don't remember it that well. Yeah. Because
back in the eighties,
the editors and
who's no in Copenhagen. They tried to make sort of new bark stores drawn in bark style but Mh most the car yeah
they're inspired by storage big techniques and they brought Barks some characters like it's just like
gold, etcetera. Who wouldn't you know, love to use Barks characters. Right? It's it's a natural
tendency. I'm sure Well, let's see. Let's
let's go go over. We're we're getting some good reflections in for this. Well, I'm I'm gonna talk about the consensus then we can keep reflecting as much as we want. So, you know, I I did mention that this one is very well recorded. Even if it's not my favorite or yours,
There a lot of Ducktales fans who would list this as one of as one of their favorites, and if you check it out on Inducks, it's currently got an eight point four rating out of ten, which is good for number fourteen
overall out of all nearly forty one thousand Disney comic stories. I do have to imagine it's a little bit inflated just because it's uncle Scrooge number.
Three
it is
during his golden age where he could pretty much do no wrong. And of course, like he mentioned it's referenced
so heavily
in in Don Roses as great life and times
series.
So I think it just... It feels very, like,
screwed canon. To people. Yep. Yeah. I guess so. You you did me the favor of mentioning that Chi
has been used again. I think in at least a couple of stories.
That battle acts one being one of them. Never by Barks,
Rosa, course will have referenced tim in in the life and times. And and Rosa will have referenced, you know, cfo phone, Mc, and and the gold teeth themselves. We do see that moment in the life and times when sp
turns the teeth into his
steak for
his prospecting
outfit.
This one was one of the stories that also got adapted into an episode of Ducktales.
The... Oh, really? Yeah. The original Ducktales series, I think there were only about twenty.
Stories roughly. I'm probably getting that wrong. That were like adapted into episodes. And and this is one of them. It is an episode called down and out in Ducktales.
It uses an original character
instead of chi mcs,
and they're not delivering horse.
Oh, I think they're delivering marble if I remember. Right? Okay. But but in the same way that I somehow
didn't get to see that read the story for a long time, it was one of the, like, small number of duck
episodes.
That I, like missed out on when I was a Scrooge obsessed kid in nineteen
eighty seven. So I I have no memory of the so whatsoever. K. I was so much looking forward to these Ducktales
tv cartridges those bit and
say what's the eighty to seven? I think it's...
Start eighty six I started launching it, I think, an eighty seven if I remember right. I could
unless spend around twelve
And I read about them in Gladstone comments, you know, the first issue of on the of ventures was
to be a Ducktales
comics, and saw the ads for the... For this in the economics, but the thing was. Sweden. It was only showing
three. That was not a shana I had. But had had friends seeing it, oh seemed to be so good. And I sort a few years later. I mean, those was too late to be hooked on it as a sort kid. Yeah. From kids perspective. I was so disappointed saw and I. Yeah. I I hear you. I loved it. As a kid, I discovered the comics probably, like, six to nine months before I discovered the show. So even then I was like, oh, this isn't right. It didn't get this right. But but I loved Scrooge and Donald so much that... And and the theme song was so rousing
and the animation
was very strong compared to most other things on Tv
at the time
that that for all of its flaws, I think it's easy to understand why a generation of kids, you know, really loved it. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. So
Any other thoughts you are before we talk about before we wrap it up and talk about some favorite panels? There's another story called delivery dilemma
from the
from ninety to sixty four. And comments and store not two hundred and ninety one. That I think is kinda
related to this story.
It's supported that it's not original by Barks, but I think that it henry been reroute it. And it's all the story about
delivering something and find friends in this case, the bigger boys in the disguise once have screws to deliver wild rubbed eggs or the king's children. And, of course, there's a fine range that he has to sign sign way is type fortune to the bigger voice if it fails to deliver with those eggs. It's kind similar. You see, it's
related to to the other story. Yeah. Sure.
Was a original writer
spider Barks store or debug Al this kind of talk thing to the story afterwards. And do we know who the original writer was? I don't think so. Yeah. I mean, it's a it's a good concept especially if you're a kid, the idea of contract they there's such a powerful piece of paper. So it works on an adult and a kid level, I think. Yeah know. Let's let's go ahead and highlight if you... Ya'll...
Are there any panels that really stand out to you? Oh, good favorite panels, favorite paths of to me, it's always the emotional,
like, it in the end here, where we see... You mentioned the Barks there
screws thinking.
Eleven.
Yeah. Yeah. That sequence is great where where the dots are really
where Scrooge is really pondering, you know, and thinking. I also like his kind of grid. We can see a little bit of his teeth, but it's not creepy like, his ancestor.
Where he's like got that sort of steel
determination, you know, that panel ate on that page. Yeah. And of course, with magnificent title panel. Yeah. Let's sucks way into the story. Yeah. That's an easy call. I I really like the
silhouette
the Ducktales just beating up chi mc
on that raf and too. I think that a great panel. Yeah.
Maybe Barks
did wet because can you that since, you know,
back to the clone?
But I've seen Al big cut away. Yeah. We played the same pair. Right. Yeah You also noticed two that it's
It's an action packed panel, but it's a very modestly
sized one. So Yeah. He's he might be playing that game there hiding his violence.
Similarly that violence step, pretty violent
sc between Mc and Joe. He really, I think, got away with what he could just right at the edge.
Yeah. And
that unusual scene that I mentioned before we only see the ship and of the Barks. It's a yeah unusual
page in this account. We're actually
no regular
console or Al. Yeah. That's a good point.
Why the ship rats all look really nice as well. There really are a lot of panels in this one. I just I wish the story added up. To a little bit more. Yeah. It's it's a very enjoyable one. It's just not never one that I was gonna sit down and and read
every night for a week, you know, the way I probably did when I first got back to the cl.
Or any other number of stories. Awesome. Any other
anything else? Nope, I would Covered.
I think we did.
So I definitely invite listeners
to drop a Al line, you know, on Facebook, the
the podcast does have its own Instagram now, and we're on Twitter
Barks remarks for everything.
Join us please next week. Oh,
you can maybe a French listener
French and german or can clear up my questions
about those titles.
And
next week or or next
adventure length story we get to cover the Many Hoo mystery. So thanks. Thanks again, Welcome.
Thank you. It's been great.