We can have
Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer an artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comments of all time. Join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks. Welcome back to Barks remarks. I'm Mark Sever, a grown man who enjoys dot com
and talking at length about them.
And I'm joined by a couple of returning guest hosts for our episode today about the Many whom mystery
I'm going to introduce them and ask them to say hello and
tell about whether they have ever gotten to travel to Hawaii. So we've got
Warren Harmon
and Sarah Santiago.
And warren How about you? Hey, Mark. Great to be back. Yeah. I have a few memories of of Hawaii. I went there as a college senior with my roommate on a whim, with less than twenty four hours notice and that last of the weekend, that'll probably never get back. But that was that was a college kid, but then I promised my wife I take her there for her our fifth anniversary, and we spent a week and a half on Maui that was wonderful. Nice. That sounds great. How about you, Sarah?
No. I haven't
trying to think of, like, the next most tropical place I can think of, but all I can think of is the
wet and Rainy island that I live on that is not tropical, which is great.
Yeah.
Yeah. I I too have not gotten the travel to Hawaii. I was supposed to go in my early twenties and it fell through for one reason or another.
Probably the most tropical, the most
Hawaiian hide away type place I've been to would be Cancun.
Mh. So Hey you guys. This is gonna be a really interesting one today. We get to talk about the Min loo mystery. And I for one, I don't know about you weren't I have to force myself to remember the title because I got this one pretty early on in my bark collecting hay and the
album that I got it in had
Hawaiian and Hide
prominently
displayed as the title. With really cool braun rose cover. So that's how I've always thought of this. Oh, I I I I remember it only as the men honey mystery. I used call the Huey,, and then I had to remember how to pronounce it. But I do know that the alternate title the Hawaiian Hide way was there. And there's a lot of reasons why Hawaii it was chosen Al this
is this local for this adventure course. Right. So you guys this is gonna be, I think a really
a really interesting one to talk about. The the Men mystery is in a lot of ways, it's not a very typical
It's not a very typical bark story. Right?
You know what it kinda reminds me of is is it kinda reminds me of Severino sit com had like the Hawaii
episode.
But like when was this written?
So this one,
I might as well go ahead and launch you to that. This one has a cover date of October of nineteen fifty three. Mh. From that pre the the the sixties
trend of everybody going to Right.
Hawaii, like the brady bunch, etcetera. Yeah. We've that of trend
before that... Well I go do you think? I can't say that I know for sure, but but like you, I feel like that didn't really become a a cli a until the sixties,
but I think a lot of this had to do with Hawaii statehood
being relatively new in the in the early six days. And, you know... And when the story was written, you know, we're only
a few years after World war two and twelve years from Pearl Harbor. So it was still pretty fresh in people's minds is probably a more of an exotic location where a war started, but also,
it it had a mystery to it. It had this wonderful... Well, which is depicted in the artwork here. Yeah. Just definitely.
Romance to it. Yeah those are really good points for and I'm I'm glad you brought up. I I wasn't thinking about fact that, you know, Earl Harbor wasn't wasn't all that long enough. So why you would have been really in people's in the forefront front of a lot of reader minds. Mh...
I I kinda think of this as like Bark Honeymoon.
Store.
Sure. And it Little was almost his honeymoon one.
Yeah. Because, like, the... This is
for for a few reasons. Right? Because
I I guess it's fairly well known among Barks fans that ga, his his recent.
He he remarried.
Relatively shortly before this. I guess I guess, it's been a year or two. But they they're they're still fairly newly married and and Gary is from Hawaii isn't she? Yeah. That was her home she grew up there.
Yeah. So it's it's really sweet. So she she actually... It did suggest this story to him. He... There was a letter that he wrote to michael barrier in in the late seventies.
And he he told barrier that Gary had suggested the local for the story and she told him some of the details about them men who is,
and some of the other local stuff So like, she had a real
locals
knowledge
of the islands. And she... And that in that kinda shows. Right? Because Barks is really good at researching but this one definitely has, like, more local touches,
more local,
lingo and language
than than normal. It does. And I was I was pleased to see that and and I think it it is almost stuck. This collaboration pin between Carl and ga was just kinda beginning here. I I think this is the first story that she lena as well. Yeah. So she she collaborate with him. I believe that she did do some of the lettering on the previous one horse Rad story. Okay. But
But like, she's actually doing some of the background where some of the...
Because she is of course, a a very good very accomplished artist in her own right. And she would do a lot of collaborating with him starting at this point. And and so for these reasons, you know, this story is is a little bit different.
This is
notably,
so this is the fourth of the uncle sp Adventure stories.
Sarah, I'm gonna have to have you read at least a couple of them because they're really
legendary.
Right? But Uncle call sp, one, two and three are actually some of the last of his four color stories. And and this was the very first issue where it
formally got numbers. As uncle sp number four. It didn't it's not a four color issue at all. Al this point, he's genuinely got his own title. It's not quite monthly because it's It's basically as...
As frequently as Coral Barks can pump them out.
Yeah. So uncle So this is the first one that kind of isn't really dealing with uncle Scrooge is past
and his mythology.
Right Now now he's set up. This is this is one of those first early stories that's gonna have this other typo apology
that Barks is gonna go back to a lot. Uncle Scrooge is paranoid about his money and he does something to hide it. So... And, Sarah, you probably
even know that story type just from Ducktales. Right? Because that's like a famous.
You know, that... That's one of the stories that people tell about Scrooge.
And I do remember it from when he
built some kind of a repository for it and then, like, broke down into, like, the center of the earth Oh, yes. Yeah. We'll
I get to cover that story in in a few months. I'll be very excited about that one. Because that's a duck
episode that is based on one of the Barks stories. Let's see a little more background.
This one has been reprinted
kind of an average number of times.
Eleven reprint County, the first one. It is one of his, like, full length ones. It's a thirty two pager. So that makes it a little trickier your reprint. Can always
include other stories with these. And
because of the Hawaiian
setting. Right? There's definitely a a fair amount of background to talk about. And and I'm I'm one of the things that I really like about this one is that you can tell he really
made an effort.
To localize it. Sometimes in some of his stories, he really goes out of his way, he does international
geographic
and does some great background, like, lost in the end is very much set in the mountains of the And
in indian country.
Other
other stories, you know, he doesn't take as much care. He uses like kinda made up jargon
language for the characters.
But in this one he's not going to, like, have characters
speak Hawaiian.
He he's gonna actually pepper in a lot of real Hawaiian.
And and Sarah, you were asking me beforehand if if I look up if I verified it. As far as I know, all of the Hawaiian words are are real and accurate.
And and then there's a lot of, you know, local Flo and fauna, the vegetation that you you can tell again, he would have talked to Ga.
Full disclosure. I've never actually heard her name
pronounced.
Right? Her... Her name is Margaret,
and
as like an artist, she had the expectation where she went by G r and an accented
e. So in my mind, I've always, like, mentally pronounced that as Ga.
But In here. I... That's how I pronounced to to mark. Who knows it we're right maybe a fan.
Exactly. Yeah. Someone might be screaming at the podcast right now. No it's not pronounced like that. But, yeah, This this is a really
interesting story. There are Barks, I love this one is the kit. Boy, I went back and read this over and over.
I see some parts that don't hold up as well today. I read a review of it online where someone was really critical of it. But I don't know. It's just it's it's nice sometimes to have some of these Barks stories that are radically different. So
you guys
let's let's mention some of the titles from around the world, and then we can launch into the story itself.
So I... Hey, Warren, you you're being very brave often for Denmark. Tell us about the Danish title. The Danish title translates to the invisible friends and it's dead
then. I hope I did that justice. I I think that sounded pretty good to my American year. That's that's a fun title. Right? It's it's evo, but it's not direct
get too. It it teases you. Teases is the reader. Yeah.
Sarah, why don't she hit us with spain's Spanish? I did spend
and they called it La delay, they last Esp,
meaning the king of
spinach, which I found interesting because learning Mexican Spanish.
Spinach has Mocha being an a non count. Right? Like, like say lettuce it we don't eat lettuce is. We eat lettuce. And so I thought but it was interesting. I looked it up And... Yeah, in Spain,
they... It's a countdown. So they say
instead of just s not that kind of engine in general. They would say spinach it. Yeah. That's fun. One brand and spinach. Yeah. Yeah. Thank you for that. And then I I've got a couple to just
rattle off here for French it has generally always been
little
or lu me start them the menu.
And then
Germany really confused me. I I would love it if someone could
explain this, but wound name in free
appears to translate to company island peace.
I... I'm sure that that that an example of Google not doing a great job of translating.
But but that's what I got. And then
you know, in Italy, we've got
Nelly Sol day Min
on the island of Men and Likewise in Norway. It's Men Mu
Oh.
Island.
So some some of them straightforward a couple of them a little bit more puzzling.
And so we've mentioned the Men
already. Right? Let me ask you, Sarah, were you already familiar with the, like, legend of the Men? Feel like that's something that they might have introduced to us in one of those sixties
columns where they travel to Hawaii. Yeah. But I don't have any, like,
specific knowledge of them. I thought it was interesting when
the they were learning about the in
and the kids were like oh, is that like a brownie? And I was like, Oh, I could... You know I could talk about brownie, you know, living in Scotland, I'm far less familiar with Min.
Right. But a good reference point. Yeah about how about you were
No. I I I learned about the men from this story. I... That's what that would revealed it to me was this the fan
that I just assumed I really didn't dig into the Hawaiian culture to to check it out until researching this for the podcast. But as a kid, I just enjoyed the mystery. I right doing. That's why I love the title the the men mystery. So are you just learning today that they're not just like in this story that they're
standing legend.
Yeah.
Nice. That's fun. Yeah Yeah I love that part of it. Yeah. That is cool. So like you, I learned about them
from
this story, but then probably years so later. Like Sarah mentioned, I think I saw in some hack hack needs Sit home that there was, like, some something about Min. And I was like, oh,
And I realized at that point that it wasn't just
like, the plain off,
you know, Barks didn't invent them at him. Yeah right. So because it is like a standing legend, I'm not gonna, like, read off the whole wikipedia entry
for you guys or anything. But but I do wanna
share just a little bit about them. Right? Because they they go back a little bit of a ways but there's a little bit of debate because there's not a lot of like because Hawaiian legend, you know, is mostly oral. There wasn't, like, a lot written down. From going really far back. So they are indeed a mythological,
like, race of of little people
in Hawaiian tradition that are said to live in the deep forest and hidden valleys of the islands away from humans.
And they're described to be superb craft people they build
temples and fish ponds, like we Severino this story and roads and canoe and houses and so on.
And and then some... There are some stretch that still exists that are, you know, legend
said to been made by the Men.
And so the the fun thing I think or the interesting thing, I think is that
there's, like, some scholar
debate that they
are actually
they don't really pre date. The settlement by Europeans of the iowa. That that it was kind of a a myth that was created around that time, because there was, like, some oral memory
of
an... Like Al a tribe that were called the?
And and that it referred to, like, lower cost
people
instead of little people, and then that may have gotten corrupted over time we're mis misinterpreted
by settlers.
So so I think that's interesting. But whether
regardless of how long
stand the legend is, you know, this is a real legend. This is a real story
about these productive keep little people who are helpful,
resourceful and and very secretive. So all of that stuff is totally accurate to the man. I I love that part of it, Barks, and I was fascinated by the... By... As you explained it that it's possible that the storytelling table actually came from western in their interpretation of what they Right. It didn't come from Western, but it was it was kind of like a case of telephone.
Where where... Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. But I think that's just a a fabulous
way to
build a story. That the beautiful part of that is that they just... They they they had been created as this wonderful kind
loving people, group of people. I I I love that part of it. Yeah. It's it's very intriguing. Alright. So that's that's a good amount of pro lock. You guys let's let's do it. Let's go into the story. I'm gonna I'm gonna talk about the narrative part of this, and then I want you guys to chime in as you have some thoughts.
So men mystery
starts out with something that's very dated. A a slideshow show. Uncle Scrooge is presenting some slides.
To Donald and the Nephews.
Showing a picture of his Private island. And right away, Barks is explaining that he wants to take it his money there for safe keeping. The island itself looks very
cool, very intriguing.
It's got some neat geography. It's got what appears to be Al inactive vol Volcano.
And,
you know, the Inducks are very interested. Donald is asking
where is it? Is it in the tropics?
And Scrooge
explains that he's bought Severino
it in order to be alone with the money, and he just kinda keeps pushing through the columbus converse. Station
ignoring
Donald
and explaining that we are all going there, kinda of bull them into it.
And and this annoys Donald who says, you know, no way, I'm not going to some fever
steam tropical island You can't hire us to go, and he's playing into screws his hands here because he says...
Alright. Well, my... My island is a few miles from Hawaii. I won't get lone some. And and as soon as the Inducks hear that, they changed their tune and they get very excited to go, and then Scrooge fin this into them agreeing to do it for free
instead of being paid.
Shaves of earlier Scrooge, I think here. I I see a little bit of a an old Scrooge here. Yeah. I mean, he's got a twinkle and his eye. He's not like He's not the scheming...
He's not like the almost villainous and Scrooge of earlier, but he is very connecting very scheming here. I looked up up what their wages would be in twenty twenty two dollars. U. And thirty cents an hour... I did nineteen to fifth because I didn't know specifically what year this was from Thirty cents in nineteen fifty
is three dollars and thirty
nine cents in twenty twenty two money. So
between what tipped wages are in the Us and actual minimum wage, Right. And and this is a long running trope of Barks
specifically, Sarah. The the thirty cents an hour is the cli.
I I like the opener. I think it's very
intriguing. It's funny.
I feel like it it makes us very a side by laying out the map of the island, we can't wait to see it. I thought it was clever that using this slide projector as a device for... I don't know if it's called a mas head in a comic but that opening...
Yeah. We probably all of the splash panel. The splash channel, I... It didn't... I didn't look close enough below because I just saw the the pretty volcano and I was like, oh, that's cool. It didn't occur to me that it was actually part of what was going on in the panel that there was action in that panel. Yeah. It's it's pretty cool. So
the next sequence
is going to be all about how Scrooge is preparing his money. Right?
And and this is a long standing thing. This isn't a bunch of these stories. I really like this this
archetype of story where he's gonna do something to convert his money. In this case, he is having everything
changed into
one million dollar bills which, of course, is a denomination that doesn't exist
and placed into cans as though it is
spinach.
In twenty twenty two money, one million dollar bill would be the equivalent of eleven million two hundred ninety five thousand
so sixty four dollars and, like, twenty four cent. Yeah. So those are those are that's not lot to
me that. Right. That is no. Don't see that it.
Whatever that metaphor is. It it sounds like it would take one or two. Somewhere between one and two of those cans.
Would be about
Elon Musk or Jeff bezos is fortune by by that math. I'm thinking. Right. Yeah. It's a lot of money.
And and so it goes on to show that, you know, each of those...
The the the cans are then put into Barks
in boxes,
and they're they're getting prepared to be shipped to Hawaii. And we've got this cool sequence here of donald kind of poking holes questioning
Scrooge.
Right.
Warren, do you wanna tell us about some of the the ways he questions Scrooge?
Yeah. You know, he's... It Donald is fascinated by this process, and it's it's the exposition is happening very quickly here from the spinach cans to his concern, of course, about the boxes will
ship all the way to Hawaii, but he starts questioning screws about aren't two afraid of being robbed and then Scrooge just innocently says by whom, and and by pirates And here's this incredibly large number. U.
Five hundred with seventy five zeros afterward. I don't know if you guys did your research, but I have been the name for that number. Oh, yeah. I I plugged into to a generator. I bet you did the same. Go ahead. Hit us with I... Is this warren... Before you do, is this the first time that we get, like, a named
amount of his fortune or Oh, no it happened in magic hour glass. I something more. It happened before, but I I just don't... I was so enchanted by this number. I know
and of course, the sixteen cents at the end. This Tidy sub is actually called Q
Vegan Ti. U u. That is the
the the actual name for this number. And I don't even wanna to know what that is Sarah in today's dollars, because I like I don't think the world economy. So that was... That was just a great gag.
It got... It got I'm sure kids thinking about that's a lot of money and a lot of kansas spinach. But Donald, Donald Al challenge him a little bit. Then they look back and all of a sudden see this robot that he's... Or what he would donald thought things are work man in Ten sips. And screws just laps and says no of those are rented from the Ducktales
Institute of Science, they're real squares. And... But this is where the Nephews start getting a little suspicious even of them. Don keeps pointing out then as they are at the docks that what about the crew and the ship won't they talk. So Donald runs back and ready to pack for the voyage, you know, he's excited, but sc really gets gets concerned about all those little challenges that donald throughout. Yeah. I like I like the sequence how he starts out all confident and then he transitions into, like, paranoid because Donald has... I I mean, right fully been poking holes in it.
And and he starts to panic and he thinks that the one thing that he neglected was whether they didn't love spinach.
I like... I like his that he he imagine all of a sudden that they're just gonna be absolutely
raven.
For spinach.
They'll
They're more... Yeah. They're gonna care more about spinach than they are about
million dollar bills, and then gonna
try to cook it. And this is after months of planning too, and so it shows it's it just Scrooge.
Really didn't think of everything. And that theme kinda carries throughout this whole story. If you think about Scrooge just always a few steps behind and a lot of things and what we'll get to those Yeah. Because he often
see a slice of donald. Right. Because this is a Scrooge story. Right? And, Donald, Donald is a little in in the early uncle screwed stories donald is a little bit more rational
and reasonable than he is and a lot of them.
Carrying over the life
the donald Inducks stories around the same time like Christmas for Shack.
Mh. You know, which wasn't too long ago. I really... I love this next sequence because it has a line that I have used over and over and in my own real life One of my favorite things that Barks has ever written. So
Scrooge calls donald up in desperation telling him you've given me the jitter
get back down here right away, and and he wants Donald to sneak around and report if there's anything to suspicious before sailing time. And Donald says I would open my big mouth and get a job stuck in it. And for whatever reason, that line just jive with me I
love that saying and I I use time
anytime the the situation fits, I... How always you say that. I would open my big mouth and get a job stuck in it.
Yeah. That's great. I love. I love this sequence a lot, and
it's the the spy donald now and and screws just absolutely
loving his money. He's really materialistic here. You can really see it or never. Right. And and Barks gives us a a a hint Barks does something that he does sometimes. He includes this in ahead of time on the narrator box
saying that Scrooge
should look long at his money. As he's wall in it. It's going to be many weeks
before he sees it again. And we flash to Donald. Skull around, wondering if he hears the robot
whispering.
Alright. So you guys this next sequence. The next few pages are gonna be all about donald sk around at the voyage
getting ready And and in short term
Donald is gonna figure out that indeed, the work men are none other
than the beagle boys
who have
stripped the gears
out of the robots and or disguise as them.
And and you know, he he also discovers that he hears the crew talking openly about the money, which sets off alarms.
And and I... Warren and Sarah, I like this a lot because this is like this is still a pretty early b boy story. But this might be the first, like, really
finalized
beagle voice. Right? They're they're basically
now
They've got every aspect of them. I I think Warren, this is the first time he referred to them with their numbers all starting with one seven six.
That could be... I I was intrigued by the way they referred to each other Al, you know, b eighty and and that sort of thing. I've never seen that before. Maybe.
But... But, yes, this is where you get the one seven six and then the variations after that And and and I can't keep count Barks and sarah about how many legal boys are actually onboard the show it but I... It could be that number five.
Maybe there a few more... Yeah. I feel like there's there's a decent number enough to, you know, captain and Scrooge the ship. Right. Right
But, yeah. We've we've got a good number of beagle boys. Donald is figuring out that
everywhere he looks. It's not a robot. It's not a captain crew. It's all beagle boys.
And we're we're meant to find them in imposing.
What did you think of them as Villa here, Sarah? I didn't think that they were as
dynamic as what I was used to,
Inducks.
And I didn't think that they were as dynamic as they could have been in this issue.
I I feel like they felt flat They... Their one note was punishing the Ducktales with hard work and
with the, you know, undertone of being
g
criminal,
which
is fine. It served the story.
Yeah. So I'm not gonna complain too much. I feel like I used two so much better
characterization from Barks. Then I got from him in this issue. That's fair. I think a little differently, Sarah. And if you don't mind, I I I'd like to say think the where where we see Scrooge kinda fall here in his scheming to protect his money, the big boys are just the opposite. They've They've worked this entire plot to get on the ship to dress up like robots and to to... They the knew about the canned spinach. I mean, they knew everything based on their
filtration, if you will. Now, yes, after that scheming that they did that that fell flat for Scrooge,
then I think they take over this criminal
kinda one note
men part that I didn't
necessarily care for.
But Mark, you said it earlier. I think this
story
puts the B boys into a
a strong featuring role. Where they really get to really see them
come full circle. Yeah. I I think I think your criticisms totally fair. I I really like the characterization of them in this. I like that they're... Sometimes he's gonna have them be a lot more bumbling.
But in this one, they're very efficient they're great planners
They're usually really good planners. It's just that something usually goes wrong.
And and they usually make some dumb mistake after they've implemented their plan. But but in this one I like. They... They're really a forced to be reckon with. Because there's a lot of, like, they're they're not violent, but they're always in implied
violence. Right? There's always the implied thread. They're obviously very tough.
And and they're just there one step ahead of Scrooge,
I love this
setup that we're gonna get here,
how they low Scrooge into
this false sense of security. I can't... I can't... I guess I can't gloss over the great moment Donald is is in goat aging and his skull.
And he ends up getting himself. He he hides in the hopper
that is
casing up the Cans of Spinach, and he gets himself nailed into a box.
And and this is like our our cartoon logic. Here. Alright? Because that's like a death sentence for any regular human being.
So that... That's a little stressful to me. But but it's a cartoon. So it's gonna have a great payoff.
A few pages down the road. I was a little stressed out by the accounting
aspect of it if they had had ordered the right number the boxes for the specific cans of spinach that they had. They going to have have all of these extra Inducks. Has spinach at the end.
So that's where I had to just remind myself
car watch X sarah.
Right. Right. Exactly.
So, you know, Donald is out of commission. And I like the fact that he's he's off the page long enough to almost
forget that he's in the story.
Right? So we're gonna transition to Scrooge and the nephews boarding.
Scrooge just feeling a little better because he hasn't heard from Donald, and he's supposed that he must still be talking around that he would have told him if there was any kind of a problem,
and the beagle are gonna do this great job of lull him into a false sense security
by just being the most obedient
respectful captain
crew, they give this snappy
salute and I click to their heels and say, I I, mister Inducks
every time they're told to do something.
And and the post I... Barks, I think, rings some real great humor out of posing the beagle,
all in the exact same
manner. I really like this aspect of the story. And they
lull him into such a great sense of full security
that he makes a tragic mistake and he waves off his postcard
protection
supposing that he won't have any issues from this fine
crew.
This one, I I I bet you're right. Absolutely. That waving off the coast guard sets up the story for the the adventure to begin. But
I I I look at the big boys and and
you you... They're certainly recognizable by face, but they cover up their masks with sunglasses and glasses and and
And anyone else would see that these are the big boys. It is right. It's just so much fun watching Scrooge
love these guys this most immediate Scrooge that he's ever had.
And they love the fact that their scheme is working against Scrooge. So it's beautiful, writing and beautiful storytelling telling you. Yeah. And we've definitely got that trope that cartoon the Sky trope where the reader can see through it. I can't say that I'm opposed
to
this kind of section of the one percent
getting them to
trust you and then, like,
taking their money, like... But, you know, I'm not gonna take it off for me and my be super done. You know, distribute it. Right. Scrooge
is is only a hero because
he's our protagonist, of course, any generic trillion,
you and I are not going to actually root for. I can only root for him and the guise of him being beam Scrooge Dot.
Right. Alright. So the the story really accelerates here in a way that I find very sad fine. Right. Because as soon as he waves off the Coast guard, he
directs one... He directs the captain again.
And the captain gives him the brush off. He says, go jump in the drink.
And and, you know, screws is like a hu ass to me. What's going on
and they...
This this is really good payoff. Right? Because they've said I I mister Du every time. But this time, they say, you know, there's nothing that your cargo of spinach won't cure. Miss
Du and reveal themselves to be the b boys and Scrooge finally
recognizes him and he's in this situation where he's five minutes
away from safety.
And the beagle boys have completely taken over
another thing that I love is bragging b Boys.
I love it when they brag about getting one over on him. In this case, they say, well, you know, we we bought this ship legally. We bought everything we did legally with the first canon of spinach off your assembly line. Yeah. The resourceful news of these Villa
is just great here. And I love the pan my favorite panel on this page is when they're all appearing inside of their cell they're just smiling and
unfolding their plot,
reminding
screws. They are smarter than him and Yeah. Rubs it in and Yeah. I love the bragging deal boys too. That's that's a great story. Yeah. They've got what I can only call spinach eating green. They've got great bragging brand. It's it's awesome. K. So so they throw the docks in the brick.
And and what they're gonna do is they're recommend gonna keep going. They're gonna
head onward to Scrooge island because it turns out they like his plan. They just want to use it as their own hideout out,
they're height away as the previous title had Inducks indicator. And Scrooge starts yelling for donald, but the Nephews has remind him, you know, hey, they don't know about donald. So he's our only chance.
We've gotta keep quiet
and they get to scheming.
And they realized that the kids can get out
through, like, a ventilator shaft. And so the kids have some time to kind of plan.
They they skim how to get the key to the bridge from the captain,
and inflate a little ref with a Al portable
air bottle.
And by and large, they come up with this really
ingenious for a comic book plan.
Right? I I like this. They
they recon
and one in the nephews is yelling for the captain
saying that his uncle Scrooge is swallowing his treasure map And
so when the bible it comes in to help
Scrooge has hidden one of those air cans behind his back and he shove it in his mouth, phil him up with presumably helium
there's a little bit of common logic there. That doesn't really wash out. But... But it's it's a fun moment.
He's inflated and swelled up. They're able to get the key. They hop into the raft
and and Scrooge can't resist. Taking along just one crate of his
precious money. And and as they are just drifting
into said like, almost into the range of safety,
the beagle boys have spotted them, and they're training a harpoon gun at them. When one of you like to tell us about the... This great sequence
because this is hilarious. And I if I gloss over anything you wanna... I know I'm I'm Well, this sequence is great because it is it is... It would fit into a cartoon and an animated cartoon too an extremely well. And yeah. Yeah. It's it is great. I'd love to hear serious steak kind though. It is very cinematic. So
so
uncle Has taken that box.
They get on the inflatable rubber rafting, the Boys point, the,
and Donald
makes Al plea, not for his left.
Storage makes the play. Right? Rouge.
I'm so used to... I know. It's mostly been donald for.
The kids are doing such a good job, they're kind of in the role that I'm used to
where they are the problem solve
they're the ones keeping the cool head and calming everybody else down.
But this time, it's
screwed. It's a different uncle.
So uncle sp, please
for
the
fifty of the box of money
and
The people boys think about it, they say open the box let's make sure it's not a trick. Spirit opens the box and groups. It's actually donald all. Which is you know, a good stroke of luck because he could have been in there forever, but not so good for the
motivating the legal boys not to shoot them with a harpoon apparently.
And then they do it.
I was actually surprised about this. The... They get it through the first time,
the...
It puncture the draft
And then
the the Captain b boy is
floating because
the air that got
and and he inflated with the the air that was used on him. Yeah it's
on a rope.
Loading above everybody that great. We'll pick them up and make them work. Which I love in this comic that they, you know, they... It's in why that they're violent... The worst that they actually
receive is just work. Let's go make them work. Right. Like, really grueling
work. Or and you gonna comment on on the beagle being held like Al balloon. Well, my for my favorite four panel sequences where we see donald fully out of the box, and his his word bubble is all in square too. I mean, I think Ga had a great time doing that. He just... The joke is is pun situated there.
The discovery have Donald the square and
the next two panels and then the the the hard into the into the raft. But I just love the captain screaming as a balloon. I I think that's just one of the best sk
drawings of this... Of this story. And and wrapped up nicely there with with sort, like, now that
conservative begins. Yeah. The this page is great. This page is wild.
I I wanna really dwell on what you were talking about
Right. That moment where where Scrooge is expecting to pour out a pile of cash,
But instead Donald
falls out and he he has become like
cubic quebec and it's such a funny drawing because he is all right angles
you can see him kinda unfolding gradually. It's totally ridiculous
and then that text balloon as you say, even the tax balloon is like, everything is square. It's so funny to me. And
and it it's something you can only really do in a comment. Right? They're taking advantage here of of this medium
where you could show him fold it up like a square in a cartoon,
but you couldn't give it that little extra za.
Of making his very text speech
actually looks square. But you can't do that in the animated cartoon. But this this this sequence really stood out to be as a kid. This just made me laugh and maybe. Actually wanted wanted be a cartoon to sit the time made before I get up? Brief nice.
A brief time in my early life where I wanted to do this. Yeah. It's it's really funny. And and so, you know, the... This transitions us to the next,
like, phase of the story. Right? We're gonna arrive at the island.
And this is also the the part where the duct certain like real
dr because the captain allude to it. We're gonna make them work.
And for most of the rest of the story this it's gonna be, like, almost exhausting.
As the reader you're gonna really feel or at least I really felt for the Ducktales. Because he goes out of his way to, like, really well on the
the toy.
Like you were saying sarah, I think it's a good stand for that kind of implied violence, which we expect that they are capable of if they had to, but they don't really have to. They're they're the out number them. They're bigger than
them and and it's still a kids common. And so the arrival is is pretty neat The island looks really cool. This is the part where we're really gonna get to dwell on the the the Florida,
especially
of Hawaii
I don't really have a good feel for which of the background backgrounds Ga
might have contributed to,
but it but it's really lovely. It's it's really nice.
And and the beagle boys you're just na about what a perfect setup they've got in this kind of hidden harbor that Scrooge had dr out
and they're going out of there way to talk about how the Ducktales their servants now. And they've got a lot of work.
Had Al. Just a bit of comic art here. I I love the way that Barks depicted Scrooge
top hat on top of his box.
Just a way to maintain
his identity
in... As they carry the boxes of spinach off the ship. Oh, yeah. You're right. That is a offensive of common Barks. So it looks like in this next sequence that we have at least a
minimum count. For how many legal boys we have. As they are fighting as the uncles are fighting over who's going to actually climb the mountains was set off the bon fire
distress or whatever.
That's right. They they
Uncle Scrooge says that he watched dishes for thirty people boys. Yeah. So we've got... We do have... You're right. It's at least a minimum count. We've got at least thirty beagle. We don't usually see more than a half a dozen time.
But we know this is a big family. And that night, we see the dots talking about how exhausted they are from all this work. And and Scrooge
explains that he does have one good backup. Right? He's got He's got one measure. He's indicating that on the top of the mountain, the volcano, which is called Mona K and Me, So he he has stocked
the wood for a signal bon fire up at the top. And,
you know, they argue over who should go up and
and light that fire, you were mentioning Sarah, that they're kind of like, competing over who
have the most dr. And and it ends up being Scrooge.
And Warren, do you wanna tell us a little bit about the night hike that Scrooge has, this is a really pool sequence.
Yeah. Yeah. And, you know, again, it Uncle Scrooge is the the key figure here who gets... Who's know storm off or March off and and concord this mountain but Al he claims into the jungle and
goes in there, and this is his first of a few attempts to go up to the mountain.
He gets spooked a little bit here.
I I have heard of all the people cleared off the island, where are those voices,
I think wild dates
any hears and and the great artwork here. The silhouette of everything is his challenging his imagination to know in. The Barks sq, there's a horrible claw creature that grabbed my ankle and well certainly not a creature. We know it that we know that and this huge shadow of what he thinks is an elephant or a beast charging down on him He's gonna hide the shrub, but then mistakes the rubbery is a tang of giant fish ones, but he is completely terrified. His imagination has taken over and it dawn, he makes it back to the camp, and that's when he kinda
Tells donald that take my shift for that that morning donald I haven't had a week of sleep. Not ask you've got to bite the beacon he goes no, and that will then chase me into the how tree, and it was all night getting back out. He had his imagination there, but he failed his first attempt to to go up to the moment. This is a really cool page. I think I I like it a lot. To me, this is like one of the ones that I remembered the most.
You you nailed it. Right? It's really cool how Barks
let's us see the ci silhouette, we can see what he's encountering but Scrooge can't. So we see it's just birds, you know, tackling at him and and so forth, as you mentioned. And we get this neat little taste of the of the Flo and fauna we learned that a how tree is a tree that that, you know, grows to be as large as, like, a forest.
Where it looks... It's just it's this massive
sn tree. And I'm I'm pretty sure that's a real thing.
Oh is. Yeah. It's a it's an actual native to the the islands. Yeah. Yeah. And and
I don't know. It's it's it's a really cool sequence. As you said, it's our first attempt, It's gonna end in failure. I love the detail of the floor and Fauna as you were saying. Although, I'm not sure what it was that he thought was a beast. Like, obviously, we know it's not an elephant.
Don't know what it is anymore than Well, we're gonna see it. We're we're gonna see it in the light of day on their next attempt.
Right. We can presume that it's probably leaves, I think, most reader so like oh probably a big leave, but we can see how he would have mistaken it. I was actually a little bit frightened by it. I think that
walking at night is kind of a basic human fear. Oh, yeah. That that packed into mind, even
at at my age and
so, you know, not being as immersed. I was a little bit scared. I definitely agree. Right? Because even as a reader, I even though I can see what's going on, like, I can put myself Al Uncle Scrooge head space and be like, this this feels really creepy and and getting tangled on a vine as you're climbing up. That sounds spooky.
There... There is one little aside that that's kind of casually mentioned
that's really unfortunate. And probably the the the the aspect of this story that makes me win the most is on this page. And it is that first
panel where he says I had all the people
cleared off of this island. What are those lang or voices?
Right? So that that is
I guess there's a lot of room for interpretation there. But Right this this is extremely colonial.
This is not a deserted island. This is an Island that had people
living on it, and it's entirely possible that he relocated them under
circumstances that made them happy
But more likely, you know,
in in the way of these things,
their
was.
Right.
Right. Right. This was kind of the typical treatment of...
There there are a lot of conflicted feelings from, like, Native Hawaiian today.
Many of them want their independence
the... That part of the story hasn't aged well. There's almost no scenario that is like, good. In terms of what he's referencing here. I would glad you brought that up because the the the the first sentence is is pretty telling. I had all the people cleared off this island. It doesn't sound like something Scrooge would do or does it perhaps, but it does not hold up well. And right. I agree, I I hope that he have them relocated to another beautiful island, but the fact that he removed them from their home is.
You just wouldn't see that today. Yeah.
So
before we get to their second attempt,
we get this inner inter load
And and again, this is a part I really like. The story has gotten into this kind of like, it's it's almost not even... I don't know. It's if it's very lang.
Almost like it's it is a vacation even though the dots are clearly under some registry here. We we cut to the beagle boys.
Who are
reading up on on the on the islands
and it's kinda funny that they're interested enough to learn about it.
But they're very concerned about what goes in their tum.
So they they have read about
mu being the surprised fish.
Of the islands.
And they learned that the fish which are called
Mama are caught in shallow bay and title Gladstone.
And so they they yell at the nephews
to go and catch them some mama. And the nephews
go down to do just that, but they're
they don't know,
you know, what to do.
They they can't... They can see the fish, but they have no idea how to catch them. And this is when they are gonna encounter our new character for this story.
He's a really interesting guy.
Named open.
Sarah, what do you think about openly league? I think he's a little bit calm for being the last remaining person on the island, and I think that that is a little bit of a disservice. Maybe a lot bit of a disservice. To our perception as readers
of the culture of hawaiian.
Right? Because it's he's he's passively accepting what's gone on and he's still, you know, happy to make friends with the kids and and tell them about how the, you know, how to catch fish and and and the
be the... It's like a... If it wise
throat went indigenous.
Yes. I think I've heard it as the friendly native trope. Okay. Right. Yeah. Because he is definitely that stereotype. Right?
And and here, I think you're exactly right. He's very calm and very passive for essentially an apocalypse has happened to him. Right? Everyone he knows and Lu has relocated Al left his home. He is the last of his of his nation has tribe to be there, and he he it's a very pate
depiction. Right? Because he's like, very happy.
But but at the same time, there are some nice things about this representation of him, I think. I was feeling.
I'm gone like, I was curious It he says he is called the old timer, and then he goes with the others when Mo hi by our island, what does Mo
Male
translate to because he was referring to Scrooge. I think that's foreigner. I looked that up, like ages ago. And my memory, it means poor. Okay. Because we also uses How, which is what white people if I recall correctly? Yeah. But also think this is where Ga really really put herself into the story with the education and the background on Hawaii. You know, she put the Al at into the book that the bigger boys were reading. She Mo is is a stranger. Sorry. Interrupt No. No. That. That's good to know because this is all Ga
doing, I think. This is the education. This is the background. And this... I think it's done rather respectfully and it's Gladstone in good taste. And... But, yes, under the circumstances, his he is just enjoyed of watch and I just love the drawing. Yeah. I I think you're right, like under the circumstances. And with the added relative to the is the time, Barks is going for, like a very nice
respectful. We like this character. He's very helpful. He's very
warm. He's very kind. It it it's definitely like a very pate
representation. There's no getting around yet. But... But he at least has some agency here he's decided he's not... He's an old timer. He doesn't wanna live this island believe this silence.
Hi this this next sequence is pretty cool. Right? The kids are meeting Op,
and he is teaching them
this really cool thing, which is real, you know, how you make these title fish traps
by creating damn that the fish get get trapped in when the tide goes down. I don't know about you warren, but I loved learning about this as a kid. This was...
This really satisfied me Al the young reader. Same here. This is this is why I think I liked the story so much or at least so why I liked it so much and appreciated it when I was a kid because I learned so much about this culture, which I Severino existed and some of the the teachings and the the history. Right.
And and they they learn a little bit more about
this this native this local Hawaiian
and an
wee. Sarah, what does that mean?
He claims it means big tummy, but I'm skeptical because we also have the island being called what keep a new.
And it it feels like I I want to know more. Did you look it up, mark??
I I know enough about Hawaiian and Poly languages
to know that they
they make a little do a lot. And I don't mean to generalize about about these languages. But like... And they have a lot of words which are used to which which are common.
A tummy could be a mountain. Right? They're they're all mount.
So I'm thinking it's probably
context whether it means belly because if you Google translate it, yes, op
translates to Big belly.
And and this is it that makes sense so.
And this is a neat little thing. Right? Because another aspect of Poll culture is that a big belly is
is like a status symbol. It is
is a sign identifier of someone who is higher status
and so this kinda trap with him being like a village Al. Right? He refers to him himself being a long timer who didn't wanna leave.
So while it might seem like a way that he's poking fun at him,
this is probably something Gary told him. Yeah. The chief often or the the people with the biggest Al. That that's my thank.
I always appreciate your
linguistic background. Now Yeah. Not a little bit of anthropology there. Too. And warren, I just thought of this right now, but Barks is gonna go back to that kinda of concept in the status seeker many years from now, right? Where
where
a big tummy is is
recognized as a status symbol. That's right. Looking forward to that one. Alright. So we transition back to sp and Donald who are just
dr
Al at the dishes, that never ending dishes and Sp is having a really hard time of it. He says he needs to be rescued soon. Donald pope said him says you better not see any more elephants on your way of that mountain. And I sense the Donald knows, it's ridiculous that there being no elephants and and on small islands. And so Scrooge and Donald are gonna make the attempt number
two. To scale that mountain. And they do see in the cold light of day. That
the beast
was
elephant
Barks. And I think that's actually the name of that plant.
It is. We have elephant Barks on our deck. Yeah. Nice. If it's
it's a nice plan it's beautiful big Barks. And I knew right away it was an elephant deer, of course, but it's neat to see it f. Isn't that cool? Did you get it because of the bark connection? No places is my wife loves gardening, and she's the she's the green thumb here and that's fine.
And and this sequence is really funny. I I like this. They decide that they need to gather their strength. So basically going up the mountain and they They keep sampling the local fruit. And they eat a mess of mango
and lava
and and they're just They and they it, and they're absolutely
nauseous by the time they summit it the mountain.
It's it's silly. It's one of those bits of sell so sabotage that I find very funny. Yeah. They self just a good way to put it. I I just thought it was hap to come on guys. You're you're trying to get out of there and you're eating.
I was glad it was as inn as overheating. And not that they mis
the fruit and we're causing self greater payroll. Yeah. It's just a bit of ridiculous Let me
very funny. And and so by the time it's the B boy's lunch lunchtime,
there are no cooks to serve up the Visuals as they say. And one of the big boys Hall Donald and Scrooge Barks. There's this funny moment where he's like carrying them each day in one hand kinda reminds us of how small the Ducktales as characters.
And he he found them up the mountains side too sick to work. And so the another beagle goes to identify what's up with the kids
and he catches them only halfway
through building
a damn. And so he chases them with a switch ordering them to make some lunch and then come back and catch some fish. And there there's this moment where we see the Nephews looking very miserable. Yeah. You're right. They... The nephews are rejected. And they they just wish that there were somebody
there to help them. And we see this dialogue box narrative the Barks that just kinda of revealed for the first time this mystery. That most sooner do the boys pass this ancient wall than the flower part and the sound of running feet goes along the Moss stones. I just love that reading that as a kid. Because my imagination was running wild now. Yeah. And we see these little eyes amongst those flowers. We have a hint that there's another mis mysterious
force here. Oh, man, if I had read this Al a kid, I would have found any wall with flowers I could and looked for. Little
that would that would be nice to me. Yeah. That's exactly right. Kids kids eat this kind of thing up. Right? Little little no, little fe little
little faye, two creatures that only kids can see and encounter.
And this next part is a neat little payoff. Right? After
some dr, the kids, they're already exhausted they returned to work on their damn and they find that they are completed. And the kids see fish flop around all over the place. It's a it's a cool moment.
Meet artist,
and They asked both N if he did it. Here's is an expression
poo poo which I think I it means crazy. Am I going crazy or something like that. Because he's very confused,
and he tells them that there's only one way that this could have happened he has explains that Mo
laugh at our believes, but we hold Connie know who builds And he's using, like, very pigeon speaking English that I'm not gonna
reproduce. You know, he he uses me instead of I and so forth. We old Connie who builds walls like magic, the tiny ones. Men who And, of course, in Real Hawaiian, there's no plural s at the end.
And he explains that they are little connie,
little men that did things like build the wall that you see here that keeps the island from sliding in ones And there's a little bit of reference to kind of the overall legends that you you must... You probably imagine Ga must have
informed this part. Right? Oh, yes. And in fact, Op new is is referring to the other islands of the Hawaiian chain to Kauai Oahu,
you know, I think it's wonderful. Yeah. It is neat. It's
a little bit more of the mystery
explained. And I liked the moment when the kids return.
I love that one vehicle asks, have you done fit kids caught any fish yet and they come back dragging one of those elephant ear leads? Just teaming
with fish and they get to sm say, oh, yes, One or two. So next day, we get
Attempt number three, we see Donald and Scrooge
Gas we their way up the mountain. This is the first time that they get to the signal fire.
Waiting to be lit. And this is a silly trope, but I love it. It's still funny. Right? What what's gonna happen in a comedic a comic book when characters struggle to get to a signal fire Inevitably,
they don't have any matches.
There is a little Scrooge play on this. Right? Donald like, no. This is this is your idea. I don't have any matches. Use your own.
And
and Donald says, you mean to say, you climbed all the way up here and didn't bring any matches.
And screwed says
Well, after all, they cost a penny a box.
Very typical Scrooge being the cheap scape and putting himself and more peril. But again,
a third attempt did not work out as well. Yeah. And and then there's a great cap to the job where where he says maybe we could start a bla by rubbing to sticks together.
And and as a tropical rains storm,
And sue Donald says you could start one with my blood pressure.
That's a great joke. Rachel deal.
It does feel like... It feels like their roles are reversed from what I used to with
Donald being the one frustrated
with Scrooge mess up. Yeah that's a good point. And and it also occurs to me that March just really revel and putting them through through some bad times in this one. Mh. So
we transitioned to the beagle boys and one of them has like seen Scrooge and donald through his spy glass, and they're laughing at this attempt to light a fire in in a rain shower.
Until the other b boy realizes is they must be
attempting to light a signal fire
And so they they go
to
stop them and catch them. And the Nephews user sent to catch more fish.
And this is the low point. Right? Because the Nephews are putting putting it together. They're realizing that this is... But basically our last chance now that now Scrooge and Donald are caught, the beagle boys are gonna be keeping them really close eye on us. And again, they pass by that flour wall and we see those little eyes.
Mh. Are only hints
of of their chance.
So
we then transitioned to them engaged in some more dr.
And and one of the beetle boys, here's some loud noises that sounds like shooting.
And we get this really cool visual that honestly, I I like the visual, but there's so little payoff
or there's there's so little lead up to it. Mh. That... I always forget... Oh, yeah. There's a volcano here, and this is gonna end with this
it it feels like a cool element that other stories he might have built up to more. Because
we see the volcano is spewing these cool rings of smoke.
And it's just an neat visual. And
Sarah, why don't you tell us about open louise
explanation. O
said that it was the min hoo who were
making that happen that they were throwing rocks into the crater to make the mountain match. Now I'm not gonna say that I actively
predicted this. But there was something in the back of my head, especially as a lover of volcanoes.
Right. And that it was kind of like a checkup fa volcano. Right? Like, you don't put a volcano in one of these stories unless it's going to erupt in somewhat.
Right. Yeah. I
did predict this. And I'm
glad that it was erupting in
a way that was favorable to them. Know, this is such a nice story where I just like nice things how happening. Right? Like, even when the bad things are happening,
right there than night, we're doing nice things for them, and the volcano is even being nice in a certain way. Yeah. You like to see it turn out well considering all the the suffering that the doctors have been through. Right. Now I did wonder
keep,
open
claims that that means big cigar mountain,
and that feels like such a
phrase? Yeah. Looks that one for. Chic
blinds
sink r. He is the Hawaiian word for cigar.
Also means cigar in addition I love it. Love Look at that, he generally got everything right on this,
including
the fact that volcanoes can blow smoke ring. U.
And that's... Yeah. And and again, thanks to Ga for for her contributions here because this this... I thought he actually made up big cigar mountain. And I didn't look it up like you did. It's wonderful that that keep a means bull. Yeah. And it's it's apparently a very rare
occurrence. But even as as most recently as the mount Ae option.
They they saw some,
like, hundreds of meat of feet large
smoke rings.
The blown out of of Ae is not cool. Is very cool, like intermittent eruptions. So... Yeah.
Yeah. I will say that the shape of this volcano is completely inaccurate yeah. Type of lava that happens at the hot spot that has created the Hawaiian chain? But I'll it slide. Yeah. Yeah. I think so. Alright. So the b boys is panic. Right? Because they they figured this is likely to attract attention
And so they've gotta load up all the the cargo of money along with the Ducktales. How we get this really neat
suspense race against the clock where the Ducktales
have to load it
and and the beagle are rushing to get it set up and and head to another islands and finally, it's all loaded up and they are only waiting for the tide
to be high enough to leave this harbor. And the nephews
think that they've figured out their one shot their one remaining chance.
Warren do you wanna tell us about what the nephews used do? Yeah. The Nephews, I think it put it all together now. So they dive off the ship, and they said we'll we're gonna just get to shore and and tell them you know somebody that can stop the ship and who well, we'll find out. So they they dive in the kids are swimming back to shore. The bigger boys take advantage of that, but Scrooge finally
finally gets the better of the big boys and the boys Barks
screaming by the wall yelling by the wall. The many who wherever you are, please help us.
So
they believe in them they've
you know, listen to the legend.
And as the boys are are yelling the big... The B boy turns again on donald and Scrooge. Kind of a awful looking panel there with ripping them by their next. Mh. But
but get back on board you brad and so they... The boys having done their, I guess their appealed to the Men who jump back on board. And so the the Bigger boys think, they've got it free and clear now, but they really don't. Yeah.
You're right about that kinda unpleasant looking panel. Right? Because there there's a lot of good...
Gets some more violent. Here at the end with the eagles hauling out a shotgun and my life Scrooge just very actively her at moment where he just butts him right in the belly, not the shotgun gun out of people's
head. But, you know, he was really gonna shoot at them. And
so
the...
As you said,
warren
things finally turn around for the Ducktales
as the beatles
realize the instead of the tide coming in, it's actually getting shallower
and
mysteriously a wall of rocks is rising from the sea like a damn fencing them in, and we see a coast guard ship
coming in the distance.
And
so we learned that Scrooge gets all of his money back and the beetle boys, go to the poke. We're informed by a narrator box. And we see Scrooge making plans to... You know, he's lost his taste for this attempt to keep his money safe. So he's gonna take them back to doc. I just wanna comment on that one panel. It says so much. It's just a great panel. It's not big enough to be a splash, but you've got the rocks thing cost in the air, you know something's happening. You got the ship on the horizon. The three nephews are standing as as the know the heroes of the day. Yeah I just love it. This is a classic Barks art and and writing style it's so much going on and you see resolution here. Right. Hey I love that. Sm look on the Nephew face. And so the story wraps up that this is... This feels very touristy.
To me. Right? There's the cli of, like, tourist who
arrive in Hawaii. They're given given lay of flowers
Suddenly, the docks
realized that they have lays around their next. Mh. And the Nephews
explaining that they think it's... It was the... It was many who
who put the delays on.
They explained that they're the ones who built the wall.
Very quickly, they kinda wrap up and and
explained to their on pulls, and they realize at the end that, hey, you can actually
see them in the mirror
because they're visible when they don't know and anyone looking.
And and this last panel is just so, like Hawaiian legend
Hawaiian. What do you... What do you think that the closing Sarah? Do you wanna tell us about how it how it concludes?
Sure it has open
in the, you know, the behind the tree, and you kinda get to see how big he is compared to the minute Who who are distance we, there's more on and... There are a couple around some elephant ears and they're much smaller. They're hiding behind the ears. They're on the shore. They're all over. There dozens of them with little colored flowers.
They're waving and smiling,
what is even swimming. It's just so colorful
too with the local laura. Mh. And then you see some music
kind floating of across the top that has the famous
Hawaiian song Yeah.
The... It's it's... You know, if you hear it, you'll think Hawaii immediately.
Aloha.
I think it's how you
Huey,
yeah. Got it. Very nice
up. I looked it up and it was written
by queen Lil corona who was a famous swing of Hawaii before it was
completely
by the Us.
And it was written in the late eighteen before. So already this was a famous song that was associated
why.
Yeah. That... That's...
I like your description. It's very colorful. It's very warm. It does not feel like a typical Barks ending to me. What do you think Lauren? No. I I I agree. I... First of all, the last page reviews the men who for the first time. Yeah. Last panel, last panel and even the explanation with the mirror, which I love in the final panel is a mirror image, you can see the green trim. But I I find this extremely... And and I I say this as a kid who read this who remembers this panel really, really well. It was very sweet and satisfying.
It was almost, like I said, we now see the the mysterious little people. And and to me that was just fun, but very rare to be exposed like that and then the story done. Yeah. It's some... It always struck me as a little bit of a pot and I mean, he had to reveal them. Right? We had to see them in the way the volcano had to go off, I guess.
But but it it's it's a little sap here than most Barks endings in a way that I'm not entirely satisfied by. But I do like the story a lot. As an adult, I would agree with you, but as a child, I just was captivated by it. So I think I'm I'm this is one of those generations must past and I must get older, you know, and see about fifty years go by before I really see that. Yeah. It's a bit of a a postcard
from Hawaii ending, you know, it's to to pat bad story ending.
But, again, I think he did this at a time in his life when he was
And I'll say this, I know we're gonna talk a little bit about our final thoughts, but I he was happiest happier than ever now. He finally found happiness in his life with Da
and she contributed to the story, and I think this was just kind of a message of love for her as well. Yeah. I think that's right. Right? That's why I call it kinda like a honeymoon
story. You can sense that he just was having a lot of fun. So... Yeah. Go and tell us one what what are your overall thoughts?
Yeah. And looking at it much later in life,
it does have the feeling of a happier
story.
And and you and I were talking earlier Mark about some of the critics out there online who are maybe talking about this not being a satisfying story.
I disagree in a way on the other hand
when you look at the golden helmet when he was probably at his lowest,
and what he came up with, which just like what a few years earlier. Mh.
I think you've got two very very different stories two very different motivation. So I guess I would ask is it true that Barks was more more of the genius and his writing in a story telling when he was at Al lowest? Or
what was he finally
able to express what he wanted to when he was at his highest in his happiest. So I I find these two stories very contrasting.
But I as much as I enjoyed the Golden helmet, I found this one just a happier story in in general. Yeah. Isn't it nice that we can get both kinds from him. Right? Yeah. Yeah. And the other thing I noticed in the story of we're not for the men annuities this was one of the few stories where the Inducks and gen ingenuity did not take over and save the day, it was done by the fairies by the Men who by the right. But these people is that's that's... I think a little more rare a a day ex min. Mh.
Right. Nice. I did you say that that warren, it does make the story and the legal boys
a little bit more men.
Right. You know, we... I I never thought about it. What if there were, no such thing as many
what if they arrived in a place where there weren't admitted hoo? Mh They would... They have gotten now this. Donald couldn't even get out of that box. By himself. And and who knows if the... If the other Inducks would have found him My catastrophe brain is going what if what.
They would have been good sucks he did a really good job, I think. I I like seeing characters
in in hardship. You know, I I I find that really appealing. I like. I like the aspect where they're really
under a lot of deprivation in in this story. It's something we don't get to see a lot of their... They're just carried along by events in this. And and that's the part of this story I. And I really like the mechanics
of it. You know, just the the way that Scrooge
identifies. His plan and the b boys talk about how they t him and and
we get the explanation of, like, the fish traps I I feel like that this story has been just really well
executed really well set up and engineer. But I didn't get your, like, kinda overall thoughts, sarah. What did did you enjoy this one? What did you think of it? I thought it was pretty good. I felt like it wasn't as dynamic And yet now that we go into it a lot more, I see... I see a little bit more of the depth to it.
Despite the setting.
I felt like there could have been better art, right, going through and thinking about what my favorite panels
were. Mh. I was predicting that I would want to say, oh, this one with the Floor. Oh, this one with the special flowers, and they're just weren't that many. So the the art serves the story for what it was. But the settings set my expectations is a little bit higher than I think sure were appropriate.
I could see that. I I will say, I think considering the, like, colonial nature of this story. It holds up a lot better than it could happen. Yeah. Right. Like he
went into this.
I really wanted to celebrate hawaii. Right? Yeah. It's an especially got. Oh that point. Yeah. Yeah. There's deaf at least some like pate
elements and and the the whole
moving that happens off the islands we talked about why that's a problem.
But... But ultimately, this is a good it's well still problematic. This this was made with the... I think, very good intentions.
At least.
I really like this as a showcase for the B boy. I feel like this might have been one of the first adventure stories that I ever read that feature to vehicles.
It really sets up the history between Scrooge and the Big Boys well. Yeah. It really set some up. Yeah. They feel like a real force in this one to be rat. So I I like this one, I I think it's impossible for me to, like, disconnect it from how I felt about it as a kid, which is to say I just loved it as kid. I loved the setting. I loved the mechanics of it I think it has as an adult, I think it has some extremely sharp writing. I think it wraps up a little bit too hot. It's a little bit savvy in a way that isn't very Barks like, but I do think it's nice to get to see these different kinds of stories. So all in all, I will say it's not like an all time favorite of mine, but I I view this one great kind very. Very warm. I like this. Where was it Inducks Barks? Yeah. That's it. Great transition warren.
This one is very highly regarded on dot This one right now as of today is it's an eight point one out of ten, which is good for number twenty out of all, you know, forty
one or two thousand stories. I think that it probably stands out and keep memories because of the the very memorable
setting. I don't I think that that is a very generous rating personally but I get why people like it. I would agree. I I would agree. And there are a few great gigs in the story that that stand out. The square donald is my favorite panel. Of all Yeah. And and the writing in there. So... Yeah. There there's a lot to really like about this one. You know, I always thought warren that it was shame, there was never any painting or lit graph associated with this one Nope. This one did not. Earn internet honor.
Unfortunately, I think it would have been a wonderful painting and lit. Yeah. And
to my knowledge has never been adapted in, like, Ducktales or anything like that. Alright. So you guys... This one has some pretty cool panels and we've talked about a lot of them, but we haven't really formally set our favorite.
Warren, do you want to go first?
Again, I... The story
was with me as a young boy, and I and I remember some of these panels so vividly. I'll say the first splash panel, the opening panel with the slide projector and the the image of the island brought me into this incredible fantasy world And as we go through, I think the other memorable panel early on in the story had to be a little bit of the spinach
explaining the canned of money. But I think the first glimpse of the robot kinda took me by surprise and that that that That was great when donald points to them is work men and tin suits. And then I think my favorite panel I may have mentioned it before was donald coming out of the box. And that little sequence there. And my final... My my my favorite, like, panel sequence would be that that first attempt by Scrooge to break off into the jungle
with a lot of silhouette in there in a lot of darkness and Severino to me that was just a fabulous sequence. Those are really good choices. I I largely largely am gonna echo what you say. What about you sarah? My favorite was when the men luna, we're building the rock to trap the legal boys and the duct. Mh.
But it was it was a really great visual just seeing the floating
rocks. Right? Like, it it wasn't revealed until the next page but they were always around. He just couldn't see them. I had thought maybe, like, oh, they just do things behind your back But no. They're truly invisible. So these floating rocks above the c wall were great. And then if you zoom in, you can see that maybe shipped that they were worried about And I'm sure that, like, I I don't know shifts, but I liked the detail of it that it was far off and vague and yet very specifically
naval at the same time. Yeah. That's quite and skill. Yeah. Those are those are
really good choice. That is a really
I think Warren mentioned that that one's really action packed. Right? Again, for my favorite panels warren almost completely covered them.
I would be remiss if I didn't mention the volcano blowing the smoke rings is really cool. I really like that seen where Scrooge is bud his head into the beagle boy, making him lose his shotgun. I think that one's pretty great good dynamic movement there. And then uniquely for this story, a lot of my favorite panels have more to do with the tax.
Because as I mentioned, I love that. It's not really a joke, but to me, it reads like a joke that that line of donald
saying I would open my big mouth and get a job stuck in it. That works for me because of it his expression, but also because of the writing And and then
the square text Al Donald is is all cubic. That always cracked me up. And and then just the overly long digit
describing Scrooge is fortune.
It's It's it's only tax but but it's funny seeing that in a word. Yeah. Good call on that. Yeah. And we forgot about one of the panels that we all left at and that was the Helium and the be yes. Yeah. Love that one... Oh, and and I I have to mention I love that panel with the nephews
calling the the.
I think that is a great one. I love their triumph and expression and the big pile of fish and how resourceful
they've been or probably open knew we told them, you know, pull it on this elephant ear.
Yeah. Some really cool visuals, some great writing in this one.
Again, not like an all time for me, but but it's just just outside the range. Yeah. Of of the all time great stories in my book. You guys have any closing thoughts? I'll just close with this. It's the only time you'll hear this word on any podcast
internationally, cute vegan ti.
That's right.
Alright. So thank you guys very much for joining me. I have a new thing by the way. I have stroke of genius. I never really
figured out how to close these episodes out. Going forward, I'm gonna close them out by saying what's written on the last panel. So
I would encourage everyone to get in touch with us if if they have any thoughts, you can reach out on Instagram or the Facebook page, or remarks,
Please join us. Our next full adventure episode is is gonna be a du. It'll be the secret of at lan.
And
our last panel is is the way that I'd like to close this out and it's... In addition to the song,
That's it's really the last two panels here. I'll be dogg on el or something. They're singing two. A song I know.
Warren you wanna give us another nice rendition there? Sure.
Aloha
hawaii