We can have
Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer an artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comments of all time. Join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks. Welcome come back to Barks remarks. I'm Mark Sever, a Grown man who enjoys dot com.
And I Al joined by another grown man and returning guest host, Ryan Bailey. Ryan, if you could please introduce yourself
and remind... It's been a little while since you've been on. So remind us your connection to bark comics,
comics
in general.
Yeah. I'm Ryan, and I have
had essentially no connection to Barks comics except by knowing Barks. I just remember them on your books shelves, and
you and Eric talking about them sometimes, and then
doing some episodes at this podcast with you So this is essentially my first exposure was whatever our first episode was. That was... Let's see was that back with frozen gold. There was one before that, I think. Oh, yeah. The the mommy's ring. The money ring. That's it. Yeah. That's right. You and Eric have been Among my Barks newbies. Right? When I started the podcast, my idea was to
introduce you guys to these and and I'd have on newbies and get that perspective. And, you know, Al time's gone on, real life gets in the way and so I had to mix it up with other bark, fans and and Barks, artists and writers, which has been really cool. But I really like getting to have newbies on and and get their feel for it. So this this is a very famous and very cool Barks story that we're gonna be talking about today. We get to talk about the secret
of
Lan,
which was first published way back in uncle Scrooge number five.
So, Ryan, it's been a while since I've had you. I think the last one you got to do is the stack Us spend three. Right? That sounds right. And and that was around the same time that
bark finally got, like, uncle Scrooge
spun off into his own title.
This is technically only the second numbered uncle Scrooge because they they counted his first three adventures that were actually published as, like, part of a four color series
as, like, officially uncle screwed one, two, and three. But but we're at the beginning of the series, and just to give you an idea of how important Barks was to Western Publishing. They did not publish this series
that these issues
when they didn't have a Barks story. Like, he was the line for for dozens of... It was a long time before they, like, featured other artist. In it. Wow. That's something.
And and this is way back in January of nineteen
fifty
four. This has been a really
fertile period for him, It's widely considered his golden age, probably at the very end of... I think what most sparks fans would consider as full niche. Huey, still got some really
classic stories yet to come. This one's been reprinted a pretty good number of times. It's had twelve including the original, but it is a longer story. Right? Thirty two cad,
which kinda limits.
You know, the opportunities for reprint. Did you notice this was kind of long? I did. Yeah. Yeah. You were asking about my connection to Comics. I've read several thousand
Marble comics
over the last several years,
and
they're almost always twenty four pages. Everyone while you get a big a big deal, you know? Because it's spider man's seven hundred issue or whatever, and they'll have a long thing. But but
twenty four is what feels correct, you know? And it's like, like watching a three hour movie or something where you're like,
this is starting to stretch out a little bit, you know, and this doesn't... This feels little long, but... Yeah. So
It it is a little weird to be a story this long.
Yeah. I I think that's right. You know, Barks got to really
stretch his legs with this one. He had
plenty of space, there were only about ten or so where you got to go to that full thirty two page length. And there was just a single
Well, there were two that were longer. His very first one, which was a weird adaptation
of a never made Disney short. Donald Duck finds pirate goal which was sixty four like, largely worthless less pages. Because was almost like an animation story board and then there was a very special one that right
they had Al extra splash page for thirty three pages. But this is in fact the very last thirty two page or that he's ever gonna get to do.
There will be one more thirty one pager. And then for the most part, they are gonna land around that, like, twenty four page ish length that you mentioned.
It's...
One thing that's striking to me is that it's such a significant issue. It's you know, it's long.
It's one of the first ones Scrooge series, as you mentioned, and my copy here does not have a title.
It... In fact, it doesn't even have an issue number. It just says walt Disney on Scrooge, and it has the months and that's it. You you're setting this up, like perfectly
for me to do the layout or whatever. Like, because it it's it is a little odd. Right? The cover is a gag cover. It doesn't have a cover that's even connect to the story. And and it was un title And
as part of my trivia,
there there was a Al letter that Barks exchanged with a fan in the seventy Dine named Malcolm Will.
And and will it's ask Barks to please come up with some proposed titles for some of his very famous early adventure stories that for some reason Western Publishing. Didn't do a title for. And Barks
you know, he suggested for this one, the title of the Sunken City which
is is actually how glad stone
presented
presented it in the late eighties.
And so the first the first time I read it, that's how I read it. And I for one think that's a much better title? Because I think it it gives you a little more impact to kinda bury the lead and not reveal that that it is.
Yeah. Let's see a little bit of cool trivia for you, Ryan. This issue
is the first ever reference.
To the junior wood chuck guide. Really? Yeah. Now when we get to it, we'll highlight the fact that it doesn't have its final name. It'll be the very next issue where he kinda lands on on what it's called. But when they consult their junior wood checks manual, that that is the first time that they do that. Sweet. Yeah. That's that feels like a very distinctive
we do and Louie thing to me. Exactly. It's it's definitely icon it.
Another thing that's icon, although maybe not quite as much. Is is one of... I think Barks all time best gag
This is the first appearance of screws worry room. I love the worry room.
I I love the worry room too. Barks Sparks stands love it.
It it's great. The little bit more background,
Barks mentioned in some other correspondence
that he got the idea for this story. It it was actually provided to him by his editor at the time named Chase craig But his editor or presented it as a possible
ten page story. Barks is the one who took that and then really ran with. So I'm curious about that because that is the thing that really like, makes the story special to me. Right? Is that it starts out
has basically this great ten page po story. Were you taking the back at how it how it kinda takes that sharp term? Yeah. The progression is really astounding. That's
I mean, it's it it kinda feels like I feel like the very best, like Simpsons episodes or seinfeld failed episodes or whatever
or, like, it starts with some little thing, and then it progresses to this other weird thing, and then it takes an even weird turn after that and and pretty soon, you can barely remember the, like the, like, big sale at the beginning of the episode or whatever now that you're on the moon, fighting aliens or whatever and
so this was a... Gave me... Gave me that kind of vibe of the Let's see how how far we can go from a to b. Yeah. I think that Simpson comparison is a good one. Yeah. I it... No one knows this for sure. But it is generally thought that he did start this as one of his ten page stories. And then just ran utterly ran. So that... That's kind of the significant famous thing about this story Let's see. We we're just gonna do a couple of the titles from around the world the for the most part, this one has a a pretty pedestrian direct
translation of the Secret.
Right? So in Spanish, it will be all separate right they have.
But I did give you a fun one
from Italy. So so what do we got?
I'm gonna say
which translates to uncle Scrooge
this guy really. Yeah.
For all I know, that sounded great.
Nice.
And then I picked Germany
where one of the most common
translations titles is der
the lost ten. And and I'm just guessing that that's the
and they picked for the... For the famous coin in this one that it's not a quarter, but a a ten Deutsche mark at the time.
So let's see. Ryan, do you have any thoughts
before we plow into the the content of this one?
This is also the first issue I've read that had
a little a little short at the beginning that was unrelated to the story. Yeah. You know, so I These were usually presented with a little one page gag at the beginning or at the end of the story,
depending on their length. Some of them might have had, like, a ten pager
a ten page short if it was like, a thirty, you know, a twenty page adventure sport. They might have a little backup there. But what you think of the little one page I can't even remember what it was.
It was a hospitality week where
Scrooge just supposed to invite someone to dinner everyone in the Neighborhood is inviting someone over to dinner that week, and
he's afraid that a guest might eat up whole dollars worth of food.
And then in the in the last frame, he sees cast iron Charlie, eat old razor blades, broken glass, rusty nails, etcetera. And and screwed says, what you're doing this evening? It's it's good for, like,
breathing a little bit loudly through your mouth. Right? It's a my little chuckle. Yeah. Yeah. So, you know, Barb, if you count up every story, every adventure story ten page or one page or etcetera. It's over five hundred. But a lot of those are the one pager. They're they're great. Right? But they are what they are. I'm not covering them in the podcast for obvious reasons.
But I'm glad you mentioned it there because like, I literally
have not referenced a single one of them in in the entirety of my podcast, so far. Yeah. No. I think it's... It reminds me of, like, the Sunday comments I used to read or whatever in the newspaper. Like, you get, you know, a little set you get a little payoff off at the end. Get a little a little choco. Right. They're they're exactly as funny as it's possible to be in a panels when you're doing this kinda broad. He sure is rich, com.
Yeah. Definitely.
So
the secret of Al lan,
I prefer the sun City, but that is not the official title. Where we're going with secret of Atlanta.
As mentioned, it it starts out like it's one of Barks is most clever ten pager.
We've got a really classic splash panel of Scrooge looking through a ledger.
Pondering
rev the decking stool for dead bait beats that never pay their debts. And he's like, really thick stated on a no good well that has owed him ten cents easily dimes since nine fifty. So for four years now. It should be quoted out also while he's looking at this ledger. I can't see it a chair that he's sitting on. It appears. Just sitting on money. He's just sitting on a
huge pile of money. Right. There's so much great signaling about his wealth on this page. He's lit... He's burning a candle instead of using lights.
He's got there's a great site gag bills
in the first volume then bills over, do bills long overdue and nuts.
But it's great self like monologue
two here where he says that's
disgraceful.
Anybody that owes me less than two dollars is a pike. And here's where we see that worry room. Right? He's pacing a groove, a circular group thinking about what he should do about this p.
Because he can't sue him for such a tri song. Norfolk we're clothes on his house. And at the end of this he gets this great devilish g and says I know. I'll put a collector on his trail. Very ominous. I noticed he also has a word bin in the background of his worry room. What is in the worry been Is that revealed later? No that's kind of a weird little throw gag that I've never really thought about and he doesn't repeat it again. Yeah. I'm not sure what that would be. I don't know. I think this this is a super strong opening page. I've been saying that with, like, all of these episodes because we're in his golden age but Barks is so good at grabbing your attention here. I love this one. So on the next page,
we see him make a phone call, and it turns out to be to his nephew, Donald because he wants to recruit him to collect the bill. When Donald arrives, he proposes if you go and
to... He gives the address. If you go to thirteen thirteen web foot walk, you can collect... You can take keep half whatever you collect. And Donald has this very funny. Tell me about what Donald pondering Al he goes there.
He's pondering collecting a bill for a million dollars from whoever lives at this address. I'm surprised that he did not recognize his own address upon hearing it. From uncle.
Right. We've got... So he says, that'll be five hundred. I think he's saying he'll get five hundred dollars out of the million after taxes.
That was my reading of it too, Right? Which which feels like a a very Barks dig at at taxation.
The the pace of this story you alluded to it. Donald is going up to his own address. But because of the construction and how Scrooge is like plan to the seed of earning this money. That... That's my justification for. Donald does even register that's his. And so any when he opens the door, It's his own nephews, and he kinda does the double take and realize he said his house.
He opens...
He opens the note and figures out that, yes, it is his own Io you for ten cents to uncle.
On that third page, could you read me the panel about what he says about his old skin on? That old skin flint that greedy old turnip squeeze. He sent me out here to collect a time from myself.
Why why don't you tell us about money he returns as well? So he goes back to
his uncle house, and throws the dime on the desk and
screws kind of climb up onto the desk and begins
tackling badly.
That he never forgets any any debts no matter what. And he's been watching and waiting. And he starts kind of chasing donald out the door. He nobody gets the best of screw Inducks now. Todd along. So so Donald suddenly gets his bearings again and turns around and says, nobody gets the best of Donald Inducks either. Donald has both feet up on the door now on the exit. That was twenty five cents I gave you. Give me my change. So just to be petty, right, Donald has made it so that he's gonna have to give him change and he points out he needs a commission.
And so this little exchange is like gonna start this kind of sequence where they're escalating and trying to one up each other.
You know, he talks about how he just settled a ten cent debt for five cents.
But as he leaves, he realizes Scrooge payton him with a worthless old,
nickel,
but Scrooge points out that he said that it was settled
when he returns to the nephews,
they figure out that the baloney nickel is a bit of a collectible worth five dollars.
And I
love the panel that closes out this sequence ryan at the end of the at least the fifth page here. Yeah. Yeah. Tell that. First of all, when when the nephew tell him that it's worth five dollars,
This is five dollars.
Donald had turns around almost a hundred and eighty degrees, and he's holding glass of water that slides out of his hands onto the ground and this flashing on the ground as he's in shock at this kind of wealth.
Right. So and even even with inflation, we're talking fifty bucks. It's nice but it's
So last frame of this page says, so for the next two hours
exclamation points,
It's so.
You didn't give me five cents. You gave me five dollars. Have you ever been took? Scrooge just just sobbing
on the desk and pounding is fist on the desk and defeat. For the ninety ninth time, have a heart sub. I I love that. I love that they're both so invested in this little brink ship.
And and so
you know, Scrooge
decides that he wants to turn things around. This is very screwed. Right? He never wants to come out on the the downside of a deal.
And so
it's given him the idea that he would like to sell
the rarest
coin in the world
and he indicates that quarter
that Donald
just handed it to. And he calls it, you know, this sounds very dated to me now. But a plain old nineteen
sixteen
quarter, which I'm going like the rarest coin in the world. So let's see We're
about forty a little less than forty years old. I guess the equivalent finding a nineteen eighty some coin today yeah, That wouldn't feel too old. Yeah. Yeah. I hope it wouldn't since that's my vintage.
Funny little panel of donald having left.
Wondering if his smart old uncle isn't getting fuzzy and the w.
I also, like
at the beginning of this page, we can see the the stream of tiers running out from under under Scrooge arm.
As he swear, he didn't know the nickel nichols were so rare. So rare to be worth five dollars.
Right. Alright. So this next sequence
is is all about how he is going to manage to make it the rarest coin in the world. Ryan, why don't you tell us about his plan But what's he gonna do here? So his plan is to... He has he has waged a massive
advertising campaign nationwide
where he if any... Anyone who will send him a nineteen sixteen
quarter, he will pay them double and pay them back. So everybody in in the country has heard this message because it's on every station, and
everybody in the country mails him all their nineteen sixteen quarters, and he collects them and and, I guess, mails them back fifty cents. I like the notion that they're basically sending it to him just to to shut them up. Yeah. Why don't you hit us with your best nineteen fifties
advertising copy? Scrooge will pay double for nineteen sixteen twenty five cent pieces.
Excellent.
So the next part of this plan is the shockingly legal part. Right. I mean, I guess, I guess he has the plausible den.
Donald says that
he'll he'll have to make... If he wants to make them rare, he'll have to make them disappear. But but he he seems to be assuming that he'll hide them somewhere. Right? But but Scrooge
flies them out into the middle of the Atlantic. It is specifically named as be the middle of the Atlantic
and he dumps the bottom quarters in
in a certain spot. Out there. And
and he goes home to he. He also...
It's also worth noting. I believe I believe that's a b two Bomber. Yeah. He is piloting it himself and it bumps away as he dumps the bumper orders.
That's right. I think you're right. I think it is meant to be one of my guest hosts.
Ruben and Al had shared with me that there is a book that details all of the planes the Barks used in his stories.
So some in there, it actually does tell us confirms for us. And, apparently, they're, like, all real play. Nice. I made a note really quickly that this story was just a couple years after he did a very famous coin collecting story. His top rated ten pager,
which is called the trouble with Dimes. Feels very reminiscent and it deals with scarcity and a valuable point. But, anyway, He price the quarter,
what is it worth Ryan? It is worth ten sky dollars. A million times more than he paid for Right. And we're not gonna do the math because it it doesn't spoiler. It doesn't clock. But
but Scrooge is feeling so triumphant about it that as he tells, Donald, he's, like, tossing it around,
like it's old penny as his nephew says,
And Donald is, like, freaking out, he's telling him. Go sell it before something happens.
But Scrooge sc once to let it appreciate a little bit more and he enjoys the feel of it. And the the inevitable happens,
it
It drops out of his hands and rolls into an open window. Do you mind telling us the company Ryan? The Atlas pie company.
Yes.
And,
you know, in in researching this, I someone pointed out that that's for foreshadowing
because it looks like At lan.
And and I never picked up on that. Oh, yeah.
Interesting.
And and so this is great. Like, this is just Pure slaps stick and pure mayhem.
This is like I love lucy or the three stu.
And and I mean that in, like, the best way. Right? Because this is very low, but it's... But it's...
It
is
amazing. What what happens down in this
Fat? Look, if people... If there's anybody out there who can't get any enjoyment out of a colon on
ten man Desk one pie
then
maybe maybe they're a little bit dead inside.
Yeah. Because this is just it's just shameless. It's just just buys in the face. It's just a hundred pis in the face. I I couldn't have set it better. This is this has gotta be one of comics
Nay cinnamon,
greatest pie of all time.
I'm gonna say that there's never been a better pie
depicted in in
still drawn for. Yeah. There's... You can definitely feel some some genetic force in the way these are drawn.
Right. Especially just that glorious
half page splash panel
that that is captions. There is no better I then a.
I... That panel work art. And and whoever is coloring it and... I I don't know how it's colored Inducks uncle Scrooge number five but the color
in the graphic album that I have is really on on point. And then I like how
when they run out of Ammunition, you know, these bakers that have gotten in this massive raw with Donald
Scrooge and and the Nephews who have joined and looking for the the quarter, which I I buried the fact that it's fallen into one of the pies on the conveyor belt, and everyone who's list has read this and knows would happened here.
They they they clean themselves off once the
Has come to an end, some pigeons come along to help out And and again, the predictable happens,
a pigeon grabs that shiny little quarter. And tell us about where he takes it He takes it to the top of the vampire state building, and Uncle Scrooge decides he's gonna run up there and catch the pigeon the top of the Tallest building in
in Duck or wherever they live. Right. And we've got a a flag pull gag. Barks has actually quite a few of these
where screwed has to climb out and reach it at the knob at the end of flagpole pull. He
almost gets it. He has, like, a hiccup as he reaches for it and so it falls.
The the other Inducks try to catch it. But but last, you wanna tell us what happens.
And Donald tries to catch it in his hat, and it just rips through the hat because as as anyone who hears our been urban legends know, it's
fast enough to kill a person or or whatever it's best in this speeding bullet. And it rolls off the curb
right in front of a steam roller naturally, steam rollers constantly going by
on the road and
smash it out to where it's
I would say three feet across. Yeah like. A perfect
representation of it. It's still a perfect circle you can see the design. You could see the year
Right. It's it's a neat little visual gag. It looks about the size of a manhole whole cover
I I remember that in one of Don Rosa stories, he's gonna have just a little offhand reference to this. But Scrooge, of course is devastated.
And Donald just like
you know, what what's the biggest deal? You can just get one of the other quarters hidden away.
But, of course, you know, off panel,
Scrooge
reveals that he's hit it a little bit too well. It's kind of an unusual expression that devastated
expression at the top of the next page whereas eyes are very small. I'm not a accustomed to Severino Barks.
Like express dust. Is that way? Yeah that's interesting technique me. I think that we're about fourteen or fifteen
pages. Here into the story.
Which, you know, is... To me, it always felt like it genuinely was a ten page up to this point, and then he, you know, veer into the
adventure story. But... But it's it's really interesting. He is given... He's devoted so much of the time of this story for the Inducks. Again,
they're about to journey to land.
And and we are still fourteen pages in. And And the perspective shifts over to the nephews here who are just kind of like, describing the problem, pondering the problem
you know, they've obviously talked to screws who's recounted to the best of visibility where he he dumped him in the middle of the ocean Al about this angle southeast
And the only thing different about the spot was the color of the water, which was greener than the rest of the ocean. And then, you know, here it is. He... One of the nephews.
Comments that our junior Wood chuck book of null says that could be caused by tiny
plants in the water, which would be there because the water is shallow. So you know, the that's are really excited Al implies that maybe they are recoverable and maybe they connect we find it.
And I guess...
I don't know. Did you what did you think about Scrooge is bath there when they find him to tell him the good news?
At first it actually confused me a little bit. He's taking a bath of course in a a pile of shiny silver coins. The bathtub is just filled to the top with coins. And he has a bath,
made out of dollar bills. But I at first, I thought that
the Nephews had gotten the coins. Like they had found like were dumped and had brought some back and he was now taking a bath and his tense got really got really dollar coins. No. This is just one of those site gag that it was occurring to me.
Is, like, totally background, but is is a very fun Barks thing to do. Boy, he's gonna get a lot of mileage out of what will be renamed later the junior
guide. Our next couple of... The the next segment of the story really is is dealing with the Expedition.
There there's nothing too special about this, except that Scrooge
pays his scientist
to develop. What would be and just an utterly incredible advancement in real life. Right? These
these suits. These underwater suits that self press and refreshed the air without any cables.
They've got a pretty cool dome shape to them as well. And they journey out to that green spot. There's a fun gag where
Scrooge and donald are about to jump in, but but Scrooge polls the redirect and chickens out, and Donald jumps on his own and the nephews have to have to push him in
And he ponder Al he as he sinks into the brian, he ponder as well. After all, I'm paying Donald thirty cents an hour. So The next page is is another pretty big Al transition. Do you wanna tell us about this? This is really cool.
So they noticed that the water's getting lighter as they go down and it's coming from
bio and fish?
Just this, like, thick thick crowd of bios lu and fish that they sync through.
And they get below them and
the fish are acting like, like the sun essentially, and it's all daylight under underneath them. And they see a bunch of whales. I don't know why Scrooge says no no not wales. Well, I think screwed to don, it's it's... The lead has been buried. Right? Donald notices is the whales.
Scrooge notices the huge metropolis
on the ocean floor. Right. It's like one one wonder after the other. That this is... I I really like the look of the sunken City here. Yeah.
I think it looks pretty spectacular. I think it's a really cool
reveal,
especially if you haven't already seen it on the cover because it's a again cover originally.
Mh. That's yeah. I I like that. It has some, like, distinctive architecture to it. It has kind of a a feel to it, but it doesn't feel like it doesn't quite feel like moscow or the Ink inca or anything, like, you can't look at and go. Well, that's that looks... You know, that's influenced by whatever. It feels like it's a new culture. Yeah. I I totally agree you. I think that's exact what he was going for, and I think he really succeeded with it. It looks cool. It looks realistic, but it also looks fantastic.
And, you know, as they send all the way to the sunken city, there's this this interesting vibe to me. This tone, right? Where they're like, they're very impressed but at no point, do they consider the possibility
the their habits? They think that it's like a sunken city, you know, the they're not gonna encounter anyone here.
And and so Donald
is is pondering
in a way that is not very characteristic of him. Like, I guess because the nephews aren't there. He's saying this must be part of the lost continent of Al lan that sank beneath the ocean. Thousands of years ago.
And and it's interesting to me, Ryan that Barks
reveals the inhabitants
so quickly and so, like almost casual.
But what do you think of that?
I kinda like it. I I like that
you can tell our heroes are being watched without
them knowing that they're being watched
which can can add a little tension or suspense or whatever. But
then we get the big
the big reveal at the bottom of the page where the king is just there on his throne
and all of his attendants and guards and
And now everybody knows, you know, the whole situation, but I I think we could have probably stretched that out a little bit for a little feeling of possible, payroll.
I agree. This is... I love this story. I think it's a classic, but this is part that I
criticized this a little bit. I I feel like it's really abrupt.
As you said, it's a little bit unique. Because that is usually. Usually, there's a little bit more suspense. But we see these, like, in these these creatures that are down there, they're they're very
fish looking,
maybe a little bit frog like but mostly fish like
and they're just kind of... The ones that first see them are like, playing a board game. It seems to be with the quarters.
And and the kim actually tells them, welcome to lan.
And, you know, the Inducks
are
astonished as we would expect
and they
they immediately try to flee. It's interesting how he doesn't kind of let let it sit and let the reader kinda take this sand a little bit more. I feel like everything moves so fast here. Maybe because he left the pie
and the coin rivalry
kinda similar on the other burner for a while, you know? Yeah.
So
Scrooge
says that he's suddenly lost in interest and intense sky dollars as they tried to flee.
But
the the locals, the
They capture them. The... I I do like that they don't really seem hospital. They seem like they're just living their lives, you know? But the king asks what brings you air people to our water world and Scrooge lunges at him because he's wearing some of the nineteen six team quarter. And he tells them that they're mine. I dumped them in the ocean I came down to get one. And the king explains that their loss says whatever comes to the bottom of the sea belongs to the water people. When Scrooge asks him for just one, he says, you can have Al lots. Doesn't... Doesn't matter. You're gonna be staying here. Two. And you wanna tell us about the reason that they're gonna be staying there.
Because
they also
fell to the bottom of the ocean, and they belong to the Al now as well. Right. And when screwed
protests. Right. Yeah. So then they need to be, you know,
taken to be recon conditioned essentially.
That's though where they'll no longer long for the surface world, but they'll they'll just
consent to
remaining in Atlanta for the rest of their lives. Right. And and the Land, they can't... They say that they can't let them leave
because he owns
newspapers and
the king, and and this is really one of the only times that the king gets kind of a fearsome look on his face He says met some greedy people would be here killing and robbing us for the treasures of lan.
So so as you mentioned,
they are in a big jam. They're now in jail,
and
they have this... I love this character. This is such a goof ball move. Right? You wanna tell us about this character that they meet.
So
this guy is clearly a nerd. As signal to by his glasses and his motor board, as you know, smart people always wear their mortar Barks just around as Yeah. Head gear. Yeah.
And he's got... He's got some books, like a big nerd and
something to write with or, he has a little pointer or stick. That's what that is. He If If they had electricity more electricity, I guess, he'd probably be running a podcast few decades later. Probably, yes. This is definitely the the type.
So he starts teaching them
in a a pretty pretty dry
about the history of Atlanta. Although his entry begins with How do do to do? I'm your teacher.
Right. Yeah. He cracks me up. And again, we get this pretty abrupt
transition
where
the the Nephews,
as we would expect or worried that it's been a long time back on the ship. So they draw straws. One of them has gotta stay behind and two of them can use this... The custom suits that the uncle that Uncle Scrooge had made for them. And they basically
have the same progression as Donald and Scrooge. Right? They they send
and counter the sun City.
They verbal eyes that they're can't be any in. Have. They swim past some hidden lan,
and
it only takes one page later before they are thrown in the
aquatic poke along with their own calls. And I like the difference Ryan between how the uncles receive the the nerdy teaching and the nephews. Do you wanna tell us about that?
So the net
are really interested to learn more about. It's And
they like learning what the Al atlanta used to look like before they begin living in the bottom of the sea.
And so if you actually get an explanation of how how lan
switched from being a a normal Land Continent to to being a an underwater
city.
But thing
about the explanation there. Ryan? Do you wanna tell us a little bit about it?
I
I actually was
surprised that a little impressed that there was one because I I feel like most
comics like this and probably even even previous Barks comments have where they encounter a new weird culture somewhere it's just weird. And it's, you know, hey, we live in a cave or whatever and so we're weird, and you just have to kinda roll with it. But here he actually tried to explain the evolution of how the city... The
the land was sinking very gradually. And so they started building their buildings taller,
and pretty soon they just started building like air pipes out of the tops of the buildings,
and eventually, those were even underwater. But by then they had already been kind of stretching their ability to breathe them to water and just
evolved into gil and finally scales and apparently green now
and all of that. And so
Yeah. We have web fingers here on the on the same page from from the nerdy professor. And... I I I like that he took the... Took the trouble of coming up with a a vaguely
scientific explanation. Yeah. I I like it too. And and you're right. It's still very hand wavy. It's still, like, millions of years of evolution into a few generations.
But but he obviously
thought about it hard enough to kind of make the
look like that they look vaguely egyptian
in in this flash Barks.
But but it's neat, it's a cool. It stands out too. You don't really get a lot of these kind of, like,
flash Barks
thousands of years sequences in these Barks pos.
Let's see. So after this bit of patient. You know, the Nephews are really they're being
star Huey,.
They they say that they'd love to see more of the city And
I think it's really touching how the teacher gives them a hug and he says bless you boys, your interest makes me very happy be we get this little contrast between
between their faces and Scrooge who has the thought balloon
with his quarter on it having flown away. And, you know, they they got results from this. Right? Because the teacher does offer to show them the sites.
But he is not taking the older dots,
partially because those two w ones as he says with season opportunity to a escape. But but also, I think just because, you know, the nephews have really softened him with their natural
curiosity and enthusiasm. Yeah. Yeah.
You know, teachers teachers love an enthusiastic student. They sure do. You you don't have to be in detention or
get conditioned
Right.
And and Donald points out the hey, but the kids have w minds too. So just watch, they're scheming a way to save us. Ryan this next sequence
is I think this is probably, like, some of these stories that I read is a kid when I was really young there are specific parts that kinda stand out in my mind the most. And I think this is the part apart from the, like, big whale
and city reveal. That stands out in my mind the most. It's it's the welcome to lan
sequence.
We don't get a ton of it, But we see these
cool
interesting
quirky sites. Do you wanna tell us some of what what he shows the nephews?
Yeah. We can... We get a little sampling there. We get kind of the the main drag of town there. We see a diner
with its sign made out of fish.
And although all the lanterns in the streets are just by lu and fish
and
flower merchants,
who appears to be selling
No. Al.
Probably. Yes.
Then we get to see the whale milk station
where they're milk over a hundred whales, huge, huge whales, by the way.
Okay.
They're not like or something
and then they go to a stadium where they watch wrestling matches between train squid, and there are currently two squid training in the ring right now, one of them is slamming the other one into the mats with its tentacles,
which would be a site to see. I have to admit. I I would pay super bowl prices. To see two giant squid rest.
I think this is a lost marketing opportunity
For whoever's out there right Espn or somebody.
And would you get the other... I think even more hand way the explanation as the dot ask m y why he speaks English, and he says we have lance to understand all languages because ours was the first language and all others were learned from it. And I I feel like it's unlikely that say
someone from ancient Rome would
understand Spanish.
Right. Yeah. Like you said, that's very hand wavy
That that would mean that say someone who spoke ind you're inc would Would know would be able to just talk to people who spoke. Anyway he had chi
Sherman, but
I do like it when there is some attempt to explain why characters can talk to other characters who have no reason to speak English. You know, Bark does this in some stories then in some stories he just doesn't. Yeah. Yeah. It took two frames. It was right. Yeah. Yeah. And now we get kind of this little en of the human world. I I like how it kinda cuts out to this empty year part of the city Right. Where there is this old
cargo plain
that has
sunk and is precarious resting over one of the balconies there. The teacher is warning them. This is one of the few things he doesn't really know about down there. He says it's a fall from the year
and to keep back, it's dangerous.
I like that they have it that have lint actually have a cord.
So that, you know, you can't you shouldn't approach it.
And he points out that ships from your world are filled with dreadful things that
explode. Don't go near it. And I mean, he ain't wrong.
And we're what, like, nine years after
the ends
of eight years after the end of World war two
when
how many submarines and planes and cargo ships?
Would have brought down to the ocean floor. Yeah.
And,
boy, I I really like this next sequence. This is probably the hand wavy of all of them, and it's it's very... It's it's maybe even still than the pie.
But but it works for me. The nephews go in and they discover that the cargo
is a a a big load of
By
that were packed water tight.
What do you think about this sequence? And you wanna tell us a little bit tell us about what actually have
So
they decide that
they could use the j boxes to distract the.
While the Ducktales escape,
which... Sure, you know? I... That's fine. It's is a new weird new thing for them. So Al At first there, ne professor is
nervous about
what what it is or what it does.
He's probably experience some other things that fell out of the sky during World war two as you mentioned, which would probably during his lifetime
and Inducks reassure him, and he accepts that. And they would get one of the quarters from him and plug a quarter in
and are sad that it doesn't start.
Because for one thing, the water is shorted the electricity. And for another thing, they have no electricity. It's not plugged into anything. He's just holding in a plug out in the water.
Right.
So naturally, of course, if you live under underwater, you have a natural source of electricity which is electric eel. You just stick plug in their mouth, and you can power whatever you need to power. Electric cables have a hundred and twenty volts as nature intended. Yeah. You probably don't even need an adapter.
I mean... Yeah Yeah. Just ram it in far enough down heard throughout. I like the eel that that just looks kind of per terms
got like a little question mark balloon, like,
and I like the professor saying, you must think we of lan are old. Fashion. And so the
the box fires
right up the sound transmits
through the water
there are, like, just eight different reasons
why this shouldn't work. It is a... It is definitely this issues example of of cartoon or comic watch.
But but I don't know. It works for me. I think it's really fun that it's this cool old fashioned looking
box with
some like big band hit from the forties.
With the Lyrics Mop head Molly,
jumping in Jive Jeep Golly, Mo had Molly is off her trolley.
And my malik is a Huey,. I I... This is as far as I can tell, not a real song.
I would love for someone to record. He's he's calling you out listeners. Those of you who have
nineteen forties
band.
This is your... He's giving you a mission.
That's right. It's it's your time to shine. There's also the lyric later, beat your chops and flap your gums.
It feels very pro rock and roll to me, actually. I... I've I in my googling is, like, supposed to be big band, but it sounds like, like, roots rock. Sure. So this works out
exactly how the nephews wanted it to. Right? The professor is just utterly
delighted.
He cries out music. The one great art, we never had in Atlanta this. He had referenced previously that all they can play the liar.
And and he says, come here everybody, and I mean
everybody. And
in in short time, they've... They've broken out the j boxes
and and the whole city is filled with music, I guess, for probably fifteen minutes before it does short out.
I would also like to point out even the electric eel who is powering this juice box. Seems to be thoroughly enjoying the music.
Beautiful that's really good taste.
That's right. They love they love some swing. Yeah. I think this was the inspiration for Mg mgm t's song electric field. I believe that is... I believe that is factual correct. Right. Right. No fact checking.
So the Nephews are... You know, they they're left to their own devices they're talking about explaining how to... How the people can get the coins out so they can keep using it. They get a good supply of the coins uncle call Scrooge, and Donald who are just lang back into the...
In the cell. And then Donald sees the guards leave.
The Nephews approach
And they they know what to expect from their uncle. He's distracted looking for the coins as they head to the surface. So they the rest the bag that they've collected and tell him to get going. At the next page is is a is is a I think a pretty unique
escape sequence. I really like it. You wanna tell us about the escape
So they're just swimming upward word towards the surface
as fast as they can.
Which
probably is not good for you.
I I assume there there's suits, their suits are next, you know, advanced technology. Right. That's main they're avoiding the Benz?
Yes.
So the Lan throw a spear through screws bag of of nineteen six steam quarters, and he's trying to grab just one before he gets up to the surface.
But the
the Atlanta are unable to go any higher because the you know, the character of the water is changing,
which seems seems reasonable.
And then the king beg them
not to tell any of the greedy ones about them. And
and the nephews promise
give their junior wood chuck promise that they will not
reveal his secrets. I I like that. I think it's very sweet. I I think it sub converts some of these this scape tropes where sometimes the heroes will... Well all but, like,
set the place that they're escaping
from on fire
or it destroy some ancient
civilization as they leave. So
I I watch Ducktales a lot in the eighties and
it's been a while. I
I have, like, a little flash memory
of the... This escape, essentially. I believe donald dot Scrooge is taking... There's an underwater some underwater culture that is trying to stop him from escaping, and he is getting away with his money. They think it's garbage, and he is escaping with his own money,
and they try to stop him for a while until they remember Oh, this is garbage to us and we don't want this, and then they, like, cheer him on. Yeah. It's very similar to this. You... Yeah. You you got it. That come... That is I I was gonna mention this during the part where I usually
kinda wrap it up and talk about other
medications.
Yeah. We'll we'll mention it then. But that's something some sharp remembering, because I barely remembered that one. So we're... Boy, we've we have
storms through these thirty two pages. I I think, like Barks, we kinda dwell more on the the nineteen sixteen quarter and the Pie. But
but, anyway, the lan part of the story wraps up with the duct escaping
they they make it onto to their boat, Scrooge has managed to retrieve a single
of the nineteen sixteen quarters
Yeah. He said he says he's on top of the world again, and Donald cancels him to to, you know, sell it as soon as we get back, and he a sure Donald
that he has learned his lesson. And and so he takes sit in as soon as he's back to a coin shop, and he now
he announces that he has come to sell is nineteen sixteen quarter. The only one in the world And and the coin, the the guy at Coin shop looks pla at him and says the price is still ten sky dollars do you mind telling us about how this exchange wraps up? So Scrooge screwed says, okay. I'm, you know, I'm ready to sell it. Are you going to buy it and and the guy this? I don't have ten really in dollars.
He says there's only one guy in the world with enough money to buy that coin. Scrooge says who's that, and he says an eccentric
named Scrooge Inducks.
I I love this guy. This is like one of the times that I've actually laughed out loud. I remember the first time I read this.
It's just paced so perfectly the way that the guy doesn't even realize that that's who he is. Yeah. I I think this is perfectly paced one of the funny moments in these adventure stories.
I'm not sure that it even needs the little extra cap the last two panels where Donald comes in tells Scrooge that there... He's just learned that there's big money to be made in the rare stamps and we transition to donald in the trash
pondering. What did he do this to me for?
Because I I think that other gag is
way better. But what do you think? Yeah. Yeah.
It's great. I like I like showing that Scrooge has thought through every stage of his plan to become
outrageous more wealthy
except for the fact that nobody has ten Sky Dollars.
There is no one who can sell this to. It's just it's just I guess, you know, double the value of his his assets or whatever. And
it can never be liquidate because it's the one... One of its kind I I look yeah. I think I think there is a good I think the extra two two panels is nice.
It provides a little
cap to show kind of the change in the character over over time to show that, you know, screw has had it with these scarcity
collector, get quick things Right. Because of nearly nearly
getting assimilated into Al lan culture just to be able to have the only one of these quarters in the world. Yeah. U I'll buy that. I... Thought that sounds good to me. I mean, it's it's a nice cap. But
maybe I just like that other gag so much. It's excellent.
It it really does seem to kinda wrap it up very quickly. The the whole story is very stretched out in the beginning. It's like very lang, I think. And then And then that middle and second half just just go by so fast and so quickly.
There's not as much breathing room. So So, yeah, that that is the secret of Al Lan.
You were telling me that you are off... Before the podcast, you were telling me you enjoyed this one. What what are your what are your thoughts on this? So overall? I like I I I appreciate the story.
Like I said at the beginning that would... That that goes so far from the beginning to the end, where it's not just like, here's a problem,
you know, we have a little conflict about it. We resolve the conflict instead of you know,
Scrooge is upset that Donald still owes him ten cents. And here we are,
you know, a couple weeks later, and he he is the owner of a ten Sky dollar quarter that he can never unload.
And he had to recover from that lan
Yeah. He's discovered a hidden civilization
below
below a layer of
lu and fish.
And they milk hundred whales and squid each other in a stadium, and this is all just for the ten cents just because he's sting son of a gun.
Right. Yeah. To progress from
like, a little sq
over a debt to
a pie. Maybe it's the world's greatest,
but it's still pretty pedestrian
compared to, like design the most advanced diving app apparatus the world has ever seen, and then discovering the law city of Lan.
And then swallowing that secret for all time. It's it's quite the journey. Yeah. Yeah. Like, at one point in this issue, the central the central conflict is, how will I get the the quarter off of a flagpole pole that that the pigeon has it all. Right. And it's just it's just such a a a huge journey. And and each stage of it is amusing in its own way, you know? Yeah. You're right. I think each each stage of is very solid.
For me, there there are parts that are super early, but it's a little uneven. Like, there are parts I think are very enjoyable, but not like maybe all time classic. But
but but the journey for this one is great. My my impression of this one is that, like, the the thing about it that stands out to me that's really special is that transition from, like, ten page story that really could've have stood on its own. If he wanted to, he very easily. Could have made this a goofy ten pager I never gone to Atlanta. But then it does. It takes that left turn, and it turns into this really wild
adventure story. With some pretty unique touches,
I like how he brought in the Legend of Atlanta. I didn't really talk much about it. But
Lan, of course, is goes back thousands of years. This is Al good... I think this is as good of a a representation of Al atlanta this is about any I've seen in pop culture.
I like the Disney movie.
Okay It's not like one of the all time best. But this is a pretty good
representation of it.
Yeah. So let let's talk a little bit about how the community feels about this one. You know, that we always like to check in
with the the website Inducks where people can can vote the stories.
So, Ryan, this is actually
ex
extremely highly rate. This is the fifth highest rated
story on index.
It is... It gets an eight point seven in the voting. Good for number five out of more than forty two thousand stories.
I think this is an excellent
story. I do think that that's a little bit overly generous.
I I I understand why the community likes it. Right? So first off, we're still... We're at uncle Scrooge number five. It's early on. He's kind of a establishing
the, like, mythology of Scrooge,
and it's been an incredible run. Right? Because we had Uncle screws number one was only a plural man, which is a super iconic stories and sets up a lot of the mythology of Scrooge. Uncle Scrooge number two is back to the Al deck, which deals with his past sets up in gold. It's also icon.
Again it's like I'm creating the characters group. Uncle number three was the horse rad story, and it it again established a little bit more of that methodology. Four and five are the first
of those stories that are not like just about establishing that mythology, but they're just about having this good
solid
adventure. And he's like, firing on... He's hitting all of the highs
of like this great comedy
adventure these twists and terms I think the element with the worry room and the junior shots, even if people don't realize that it's like their first appearance
probably makes it feel a little bit more icon it.
So... And and it's got this high concepts too of the of the nineteen sixteen.
Quarter. So what do what do you think? How does this hold up? I
I can see why it would be
one of the highest rated. It doesn't have any, like, weak points, it never drags. Aren't any gag that, you know, don't land
almost every page has something really great on it, like the word room or Yeah.
Or the squid wrestling in the in the boxing ring, You know, he
he really just kind of ramped every every element up all the way. And
and so it's just kind of a fun ride. Yeah. I I think that's right. It's just it's very solid all the way through. It's never... It's never worse than solid, and sometimes it's just outstanding.
Sometimes that's what you need. Let's see. So I I do mention I like to talk about
if he's done any of his oil paintings things or lit photographs.
Unfortunately, he never did one that correspond to this story. And you had talked a little bit about the Ducktales
episodes. So there was a duck
episode that this was that was loosely based on this. It really doesn't
take that many elements other than just Lan.
I guess the fish people look a little bit like them. You all... I I saw a couple minutes of it before recording. The only thing that really stood out to me as identifiable as those kind of dome shaped helmets that he used on it. But, yeah, I was like the one where he was trying to get these
these glowing
fruits or something and it was like a four episode. One of those special Tv events, so you were probably likely to see it. For that reason.
And it...
There was, like, I guess this meme for a while, there was a scene from the episode where he
is ranting
about
the the c monster
eight my... What is he even say it's one of a few something from Inducks pai. Has gone viral. A c on straight my ice cream. That it. That's what's coming up and... Yeah.
But I I think that that may have been from this this arc maybe not this specific
It was never included in the more recent Ducktales.
Although I think they referenced it briefly in one of the
episodes. They never like, adapt it or anything like that. And let's see We... We covered. There's a lot of really cool panels here that we've already talked about for me, I think I think that some of them are just totally obvious. Right? Like the the descent where they see the city of first is an easy choice.
But
so is that massive pie?
Of course. That's another easy call
As far as kind of more quiet
subdued panels
I guess I like the ones where
the
mer people, the
Are having their big dance party out there. And I like the kings, like, really pleading
expression as he's like, begging with the nephews not to not to expose them. I think that's a nice little panel moment. Yeah. How about you? What what panels stood out to you? With ones did you enjoy?
We did mention
the one where Donald finds out that the Baloney nickel is worth five dollars.
Just about just about Barks out and excitement. Right
several dollar signs popping out of his head more than five dollar signs, I would point out our got said.
Yeah. And then just the one below that. Two where he's laughing at him and he has been for two hours.
Yes.
There's also early on when we have the one panel, this would be on the third page,
the one panel of Scrooge inch over his desk and finally getting over the front of his desk climbing down the other side, pointing his finger right into Donald face.
And and shouting again. I've been waiting on watching and then right below that two frames later,
is this is reversed as donald as pressing against the door, the exit
pointing right back Scrooge and saying, and that was twenty five cents. Give me my change. That's a really good catch. Those are great
and and... Yeah. It's great turnaround. It's great that they're
to each other.
Both characters are essentially
horizontal and their in their argument.
Yeah.
Boy, Donald just bouncing lite light is a feather on the second page going to collect the the bill. If this is life owen one. I I gotta mention the opening panel too just him looking very
Scrooge there.
And in the worry room as well.
There's another great one
that has kind of a feel that I associate with these adventure issues.
When they're... They've got their twenty second century diving gear,
and
they're on their their boat
they're both with a a a money flag. I just noticed. Yeah.
And... But it goes wide. And so you see this little boat on top of these mountainous waves and just nothing else. And you see some wi clouds in this sky as the sun is going down
and it shows kind of this isolation, it it provides this kind of feeling of adventure and, like, you know, we're really going somewhere where other people are not and and going to these links.
You know, to to reach our goal, and
it's cool. It's kind of... It makes you feel like something interesting is gonna happen and, you know, and then and then, you know, two pages later, we're dropping through the the layer of deep sea fish and and seeing the flock of whales, I guess, I would say.
Around the around the sub mediterranean city and you get this kind of wonder that I think was kind of
alluded to a couple pages earlier there. Is there a loan on the surface Yeah. That's that's another good catch. Good
good commentary. Excellent.
Well, I
really appreciate you joining me to talk about this classic story.
Just to be clear, I I do think that this one is like a a classic
an all time class even. I'm just not sure that I would like put it, you know, in in the top five. That's like
really verified air. To me this is, like, maybe a top fifteen
top twenty of all time adventure story. But but well worth checking out, any closing any closing thoughts? What do you think about the sting man in the world? Dumping an unknown number
of quarters into the ocean. I mean, apart from
how many federal laws
brakes.
I think this is one of those very typical
Barks
hand waive moments where that's he needs to happen for the story. That's true. But... Yeah. But you're right. I think it... I think you could very easily have a scene where Scrooge
felt
extremely
conflicted. I could easily imagine, like, Barks doing a a cut away panel where Huey, like convincing himself that he has to south the money. Yeah. That that's a good thought too. Nice. Alright. Well,
listeners, hopefully, you enjoyed this
episode.
Please feel free to reach out, tell us what you think of for the story.
Barks remarks. Is on Instagram and Facebook
and so forth. Next episode, we get to cover
what is certainly an all time classic
Trauma law widely considered one of the all time grades
And Ryan, I finally figured out a way to consistently close these out. I'm I'm just gonna read the the dialogue that is on the very last panel. So that said, now, what did he do this to me for? Thanks for joining us.