We can have
Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer an artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comments of all time. Join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Welcome back to Barks remarks, I'm Mark Sever, a grown man who enjoys dot com, and I'm joined by another grown man who gets to make and enjoy dot com.
I'm gonna introduce him as we get ready to talk about one of the all time great Carl Barks Stories,
T.
I am delighted to have you back. I've got Patrick Block who
is it is a great Ducktales artist in his own right, and
you've got a pretty
a pretty strong connection with this story. Is that right? Yes this is one of the story that I really remember as a kid strongly viking. And I still like it just as much today. So it's it's a case of you appreciate it as an adult end as as a kid. That it is. It's one of my very favorite uncle.
Yeah. I I think I think you're in good company.
Right? I think most Carl Barks fans
pulled T a lot and special regard. And I have to tell you something that I didn't even mention
before
before we we were chatting before we started recording, so you may remember from previous episodes where I've had you on. I always take a little bit of time to talk about how the... How the community likes the stories on Inducks, you know? Yes. So I I follow index very closely. It's it's the website where people can...
They they have a lot of great information about stories from
all kinds of creators. You, of course, are, well well represent it Inducks.
And, you know, they'll they'll rank the stories. For the longest time if you click the top one hundred Disney comic stories T
was firmly in the number two spot.
With basically the same score as back to the cl. And when I checked it yesterday,
or this morning, for the first time, it was the only time I had seen it, click into that number one spot. Oh, really. That's interesting. Yeah. Yeah.
I've never seen it there before, but but they do have almost the same ranking. So I have to imagine that sometimes they see saw if you check it by the time we release the episode, it might be back to number two. But that should give you a a little bit of an lesson know what we're dealing with here. Right. This is one of the all time grades this is an amazing bark story. This. And so, Patrick, we're gonna talk today
about the story itself, of course. We don't talk about some of the background.
But, like, what I'm what I'm really interested in is,
why is this one of my favorites, one of your favorites and and so many many members of the the Ducktales fans
duct community. Why does everyone love this story? What's so special about it? What do you think? It's reasonably short for a long Scrooge story.
It's not there's much longer story but the thing about this story I think is it's every inch of his action packed. So much that goes on and and it all serves the same purpose. You know, to got that theme of wealth and they've been silly to you couple money to cover anything really like that. And I think that the combination of Barks is master for writing and drawing. Huey, to storytelling abilities, the showcase here with a theme that he really took to hard to. He really good at things where he's making cooking fun if Huey, kind, which is during good time here. Yeah. I think that's exactly right. This is this is one of Barks stories that has a big idea. Right? Like, Some of his stories are just great works of adventure, or comedy and and we love those. But this one is a great work of adventure and comedy, and it really has something to say
about kind of the pursuit of wealth and and what really matters. And And just the modern world. And he and approaches it and his only unique way. He he approaches the human unique condition with this Sparks attitude his story and nobody's Severino people have covered the same basic ideas, the models and other things. But but no one's approached it in this like, funny off the cuff that the called us. Just, you know, it's amazing the way he the idea of using bottle caps. You know his money and. And it makes it seems a nashville when he when he does it? When this start rating from this guy, it's just like a
the story runs so naturally. It's surprising, but it... Yeah, it makes so much sense. It's silly at the same time. Yeah. It's definitely one of his best concepts.
It it is such a great high concept that... That's probably a big part of the rating Right? Everyone remembers this story. It is the bottle caps story. That's how it stands out in people's minds. Yes. One of the moments like Al all the the Barks comments, Certainly one of my favorite panels is the same with the bottle kept falling out the clean. That big bottle cap plain smaller in the background. It's like one of those images it's burnt into my conscious
as a kid. More so even than when the plane dives into the valley. The while kept falling out it's such a Scrooge thing and most people who like comic Barks stories don't have panels like that that happen like, mid story, and then they come up and then then everybody seem minor but then becomes a significant thing later story. Give second. It's like a plot device that's more complex than most comic Barks usually have. Yeah. You're you're saying it great... Because that panel really does. It packs
such a punch in a way that there there's definitely Al other bar panels like that. Right? We we got to talk about the dam
and only a plural man packs that kind of emotional punch
I would argue that first
view of playing awful
you never forget that. Sure. There's there's a number of them, but but this is definitely among those all time great Barks doc moments.
It's a personal choice for me. I'm not saying it's like the greatest I'm just say it's my personal thing that I remember about all the stories is the probably the moment I would pick the the most burned into me. Yeah. It's invaluable. It's an easy choice to make.
And and I've got two really salute. You shared with me a piece of artwork you did. Water color at the thinking water Al an ink water color painting
that
is... It... Well, you wanna describe it, and I'll I'll make sure to put it up on the Facebook page and highlight it? Sure. It's sort Al collage of.
Basically
that the idea was to tell the whole story of Carl is T ally in one painting. So so not only is it just Al a single image? It's not a single image from the of the story. It's the whole story itself. So we've got individual panels that my picks for favorite or storytelling devices throughout the storing. So it's Al and collaboration those panel put together. And I also tried to make it so that not only were they telling the story, but also you could look at the piece in, like, Al abstract way and still enjoy for the color and the composition. Not too. On just Al storytelling aspect. So it was a really challenging piece even though it's me taking parts of boxes panels, and red drawing them together and arrange them. And I had to to, like,
draw parts the Karl didn't have in... In the individual panel so that they work together. So it's like a real challenge and painting. I thought that it came out really nice. I really love the piece my. Yeah. I mean, I I definitely agree. It's says spectacular piece of doc card. And and well worth
people checking out. So I'll I'll definitely you that. Yeah.
And I we were talking about how, you know, Barks never got to do one of his wheels or or lit the graph for this one. So
to me, it's really nice that there's some spectacular creator or that can do justice to the story. Thank you. Tried. Yeah.
So let's see. There There's definitely a lot to say about T law. What I'm gonna cover a little bit of the background
initially.
This one but by now, Carl Barks has, you know, been successful enough that western is spun off on Scrooge stories into their line,
and this is gonna be numbered uncle Scrooge number six, Technically the first three or four callers. Stories, but we we get to start counting from only pore old man. As you mentioned, this one's a bit shorter. It's only twenty two pages, so it was paired with the... It was paired with a ten page originally.
That was published
in April of nineteen
fifty
four. At least, that is the cover date. Yeah. So this one was paired with a ten pager called out fox. To the Barks.
And
this one as you might expect because it's so
because it's short enough that it's not too hard to reprint. It's had a good number of reprint.
Including the original, it's seemed fourteen
printing.
Yeah. In in the United States and and many many around the world. A little bit of fun background
information about this one. I don't know if you knew this tidbit about the story, But this is the first, like, official appearance of the junior would check guide.
I did know that. Yeah. So it it was referenced in the previous adventure.
Secret of Lan, but it wasn't called by like, it's full formal name in there it. And it has a pretty important
It's pretty pretty significant in this one. I noted
that
this is the second kind of classic Barks adventure where there's this, like, element of medicine of sc needing something
to keep himself
whole
In this case, we're gonna have this running gag with the nerve tonic.
And then, you know, couple issues of going back to the Inducks. We had the memory pills. Is Patrick, what what do you think of that running gag with the nerve Tonic? Oh amazed that we got away with it. This was the error nineteen fifties where house wise
taking like the in and barbara and stuff try and keep their lives together. It's like a a time kind of a nervous cold war time of of America's history and his Scrooge does these. I guess you gotta wait that because of pop bottles and you're ph. It's busy short
pop nerve medicine. Is shaking without them. It's, like, hard know what make of it.
Yeah. That's a good point. I I guess it's possible too that maybe they didn't like it, but they just they
identify that it was so important to the story. Yes. It was vital, why was a vital kind of element in the store. I think the pop will saved the you probably thought that he could get away with it with a baby little f f pop auto containers. Right. And I did find a neat little quote about this running gag where bar said this was from an eighty one interview. He said the nerve medicine was a running gag to help pull parts of the story together. I had learned about running gigs before I ever worked to Disney. It was a kind of thread or connecting length stories such as load house's stories,
p.
And in the movies, Chaplain and Laurel and hard had running gag I liked those movies more than a romantic ones or shoot them up last. The running gag were a necessary
part of the stories. Like a period at the end of the sentence.
Very interesting. Yeah. So that's fun.
He had some truly great ones and this is among the best of of the running gaps.
Interesting. We I've seen the cases like that, like from the fifties? Like the case that the bottle is in? Oh, yeah. Black and color and they're store what leather covered. I seen those auctions before. So that exact case
interesting that existed. Right. It feels very like vintage, snake whale, salesman, you know... Doctor
doctor Know nerve tonic or something like ones I the ones I'd seen were, like, sample cases for people selling things. Nice. That's one. This one, of course would have been originally published
un titled.
The title suggests itself, this is, you know, how everyone thinks of it. But there was like an exchange that Barks had with the exchange with the collect or Malcolm from will. Who had asked him to kinda rattle off some suggestions for some of those un title stories, you know, and I think that's where he had suggested the Min mystery,
And and in the case of this one, I'm glad that no one ended up going with his choice. Because
he suggested hoop plot in Shanghai?
Much better.
Right. Well, and and
what's your background with the ins swiss chain law the the inspiration for Trauma Al lot. Do you know much about
the the movie and the book the lost horizon, Not much.
Okay. So so this is pretty cool. Right? Because T has this really
strong literary element
I knew this that it was based on the very famous, like, lost Al story called the lost Horizon
which is about, like, a group of people who explore this legendary
city and Valley. Called shanghai.
Right? That this is something that Barks was inspired by. Let me get his quote here. So he said this this was a direct quote. It's obvious that Trauma alive is a parity on lost horizon. At the time I wrote it lost fries with its land of shane law was very popular.
I saw the movie.
I never read the book, but I read so many reviews of the book. I felt I knew it anyway, it... I felt it wouldn't matter if my version of Sc law was a parity of the book or not. So I I think that the movie was a Frank Capri film Oh.
So so it's pretty legendary and like like That quote indicates people would have known about it. But in researching the background of this, I did learn that it's is actually a real
myth or legends too. So this is based on, like, a real actual
to tibetan
a a real legend. Right?
And I I guess I'd heard this name before, but it's originally...
The the legendary city is called Sham ba.
But I I didn't and then Frank or the writer of the lost rise adapt into Shanghai
and and Carl Barks
adapt to that, into T ella. U. So that that kinda cracks me up. It's neat that it's like...
Yeah. It's like this little third hand ren name of it.
Go look the movie up. They're like Stuff. It's a really good movie. I haven't seen it in many
many years. And I don't know that I saw all of it, but it's it's it's old enough to be black and white, but it's very exciting.
Very well made and very famous. Right? Because, like, everyone knows what you mean if you talk about a sc lock, Yes. What what's your understanding of what what is a sc law, Patrick? The care free place. It's doesn't have problems of the society we know jesus guess. Yeah. That's that's good. That's it. It's like this hidden paradise,
basically.
The the movie
itself, you you would say it's a... It's shorthand for like, a lost paradise.
So the the movie in very few words, is basically about this character who who finds
peace and love and and a purpose.
In en law when they make this expedition, but he has to reluctant leave by the end. So it is very much in line. Barks Story is very much in line. With that.
Alright. And then the the the last thing I'll mention before we kind of transition is the the Genesis of the story. I found I didn't know this Patrick.
There's a a cool quote where he talks about what gave him the idea to do this. Did you... Do you know where where where the story came about? No. I heard that story. So I like this. He said that he he he wanted to do a story that had a billion of something in it. Right. He he just liked the idea of of how it's
difficult for people
to truly
visualize what a billion is.
And, you know, he was a bit of a... He was a bit of a across the old c when it came to economics. So he said
I read about the
appropriation that congress makes of a billion for this. Ten billion for that. I got to thinking about how much of something a billion really amounts to. You can visualize a million
because you can think of a thousand thousand things Mh
of bottle caps or whatever. But when you multiply that pile by another thousand. Then you're into numbers that are beyond the ability of the minds to visual. How wonderful he picked at too There was the million bottle caps following, and then it's gonna be every couple of hours another one for... For how long during time it was like a long time. Weeks. Right. He's gonna turn it into this life for death
situation all because he wanted to explore that idea. I I think that's so cool. And then he ties that into the the concept of a sc lot too. It's it's brilliant. It is. Pieces as... I think he says it's going to fill the Al of the tree tops. Yeah. And I didn't do the actual math, but I don't have any reason to
to doubt that. And of course, we don't know the exact size of the Al, I guess. So totally plausible to me. Oh, yeah. Here's another quote that kinda to the same effect as for the quote S law story, which poke fun at the idea of humans living together in un
utopian Harmony it started for my efforts to find a way to use one billion of something in a visible way. And the bottle cap gag was the result. It's great. So patrick, before we
get in to
dive in the actual meat of this
wonderful story. I do like to mention some of the titles
from around the world. I I think it's fun to see what other publishers have chosen.
So
as you might expect this story is icon and not that a lot of publishers
did just go with T a lot. Right? But but not all of them. I encountered some interesting ones In in Argentina,
it was only published once, because that country, they don't they don't publish a lot of them through argentina.
And it was called bo
lac.
Which is
enough with silver or enough with the silver, I guess obviously referencing the model caps.
And I think plot that technically means silver, but it might also mean other kinds of, like, metal or Precious metal.
Right. And then in Belgium,
you know, how they speak dutch there as well,
I guess it's what Al.
It was once
Or,
stopped.
Al
everyone get out.
And then in Danish, Stan denmark had past
Inducks
on the run from his wealth.
I thought that was interesting. And
let's see. Two more. I'll do Germany.
Dev then
Cro,
which means the faithful
crown cork and I've gotta assume crown court is how they say bottle
And then in Italy,
it was
called
the Al of a law, but just as often it was called uncle
and the dollar allergy. Yeah So I I like that one a lot. I think that's pretty cool.
Alright. So lots lots of good baseline information there. Yes. I am ready to do some reflections on this great story. So, you know, listeners as we do, we're gonna go through... We're gonna alternate these pages
and and then we're gonna comment.
So so, Patrick, I think T
has one of the strongest openings.
In any Barks comment. I agree. Right. And and I think that the most classic of the bark stories is the ones that remember that people remember with the most fauna, usually
have Scrooge in, like, some heightened
state of emotion. We see this a lot. Right? Like, we saw the the memory
concern and back to the Al deck. We see him stressing
about his money and only a plural man And in this one, uncle Scrooge is in the midst of what we can assume is just his kind of typical
routine. As a ty.
And and he is just rushing about he
responding to crisis after crisis.
The narrator box tells us
everyone sometimes dreams of getting away from the cares of life of finding a place where he can be at ease. Even uncle Scrooge would have such a dream if he had time to dream. It's a beautiful table. Yeah. It's it's wonderful.
And so screws clerk is telling him about all these, like,
requests for money,
requests for his attention
He's looking at the stack of correspondence
he gets and asking and being asked to answer them and and he says what does stack. Are they Al from... Are they from the usual people and the clerk says, yes, from sellers and traders and beg and buns. All wanting money money money.
There's a great gag where missus seven chin smooth story. Demands a million dollar donation her home for home of filming visions.
And and he he says to make out a check, which is very un,
but it works in the context of this story. Right? As he says, it would be awful if the pigeons came here and I had to feed him. So, you know, Barks will play with screws his generosity a little bit here and there for for comedic effect.
But basically, the the idea of this whole beginning sequences
is just to communicate to us the reader about what a terrible time is having right now being a ty.
And
what what do you think about this first page and tell us about the system?? I think it's a wonderful first page. I love that opening. It's very that open tag. It's a demonstration just how powerful
karl could be with a minimum amount of words you could tell. Just tell why.
Beautiful way. And he says it words it simple, but at the same time no one else would say very beautiful
Barks open. I agree. It's like a really strong first page
the second page just carries on with the stress from the first page. It's worse really.
Yeah. You gonna go meets a tax collector and there's a lady with a go herman and trying to figure out how I can get rich. Little kid looks not helpless, but the mother wants burn to be rich and there's a rich guy, to address the club and then this guy, looks like he's radical or like a protest or kinda guy. It's a fifties. So he's like a big nick, I guess or what some kind of error. I don't know. Right yeah. Demanding it to give a billion dollars to Lt a through jessica what that is. And so lead to a billion down with the rich. It's like quite funny, but Al the same time it's like, you feel sad for a discouraged, because this just getting it big up. Accurate. Can I interrupt briefly and and tell you I think that gag there, the the? As you said, he looks like a radical Al Barks
it if if it was made five
to ten years later, he would been a hippie, but
that dad,
that's one of the funniest things that I think Carl Barks is ever done. I agree it's very funny. It is is is it is brilliant. It is So funny
yeah and that's with the with the rich opposite conservative
guide on the panel before too makes this guy looking even worse.
Really. You know little driver
invention behind the right guy. Take shape one real car is entirely ass apparently like And are interesting.
Keep going. I'm so so we're introduced to the for the first time to nerve medicine which comes in further so bottle pop auto which.
It's like that work of genius to put it in that little bottle. Because we could get away with a lot more call as far as it being like, some sort of drug oriented, you know, better score it says this each time that comes off that the words come off, which is just a funny thing too. And and the last panel is that is the great moment on this page two for he's looking Al the score all the screen sleeping the little Scrooge those z Barks coming off and the Scrooge And yes patrick, and feel free to read that balloon. It's like this all day day. So how I ended with I care Scrooge
sleeping on that piece for about and and and Karl here is using the same sort of approach is it first tagline. And he's got Scrooge talking sort of more poetic sort of way. And that really is nice way so counter to the the horrible actions going on to bridge around at know. Right
Reflective, I guess. Yeah. And this is... It's gonna set up such a such an amazing gag on the next page that that page, it just really continues the other brilliance.
Because every one of these every one of these interactions
is different and funny. And you know what? They feel
so realistic to me the these these are the kinds of problems and I'm not gonna waste any time feeling sympathy
for ty.
You know, I might I might feel a little bit of sympathy with the Lt b guy. In some respects,
I I love screws because he's our hero he's Scrooge Mc duck. But but, you know, I get where that guy's coming from. But regardless,
the these are the problems that someone like Scrooge would deal with and it would never end. It's it's sounds Al hilarious skype because obviously,
if Scrooge gives that guy a billion dollars, then he's a billion billion.
He's he's he's the lead to a abolish building know. So like the whole whole concept is that works on on on so many levels is so well. Alright. So we... The the the next page, we get the natural out come of all of this. Right? We've been seeing Scrooge like, steadily
send into... He's clearly veer for a breakdown And boy does he have one. It is a breakdown for the ages. It is so funny Bark doesn't usually
draw characters looking as wild as he draws
Scrooge. It's got x eyes. Yeah. X specs.
Yeah. And and he's come to...
He's come to hate his money. Right? He is so stress that he says, I hate my money. It's brought me nothing but work labor toy and engineers, keep kicks it and says, get out of my site you ugly stuff. And in the next panel, we get this wonderful moment where he he makes good on that pine
moment where he end the squirrel.
And and he rushed past his clerk checking and chicken on all fours acting like a squirrel, and and the clerk is using the operator a nice little and there to connect to donald duck. And and that our first panel with Donald is Donald receiving the phone call that reads come down and help catch your uncle Scrooge. He's running away into the Barks chatter like a squirrel. And Patrick this next
exchange where Donald does track Scrooge down and then sees him. Bo is head out of a hollow tree Yeah. Really, like, climbing down that tree like a squirrel It's it's hilarious.
It is. So fine screws those those. He's not really Al scroll and makes say better. Right. Yeah. He's he's very reluctant and he's like, I know I'm not a squirrel, but let me put pretend. And any really events and he starts to unload on Donald and he just... You imagine that this is a little bit,
but he says I want to go someplace where there is no money and wealth means nothing. Donald kinda stands in for the reader. Any he ponder. I wonder if there is such a place
anyway it's the perfect timing at the end of the page and it's like, kind of enticing you into what's going to happen like that? Yeah. Next page. Or it's the doctor's office and
this so happens is the doctor who's very serious looking respectable like phones. It's heard the strange Al in the mountains of asia. Called Trauma, Nobody's ever seen it. It said to be a place without money so that sets up our old four story we're ready to roll with it really subscriptions just coming, people must be happy there. And that's the place for me. And gets all excited about it. He's gonna go himself to Twelve
nobody pest by his switches.
So the kids in donald, we're gonna see him off to airport with him, and
donald makes a slight mistake, and he's a wonderful expression that suppose. The saying that if Scrooge wants to give away his money to take it off his hands, it'll take it. And those expression on exclusions space again is got x eyeball thing going on. Loses it Al together. And Scrooge realize is that as he gets this medicine that he's gotten So the point where it goes to pieces when my mentions Al well. So he's not gonna be go run. Other words is what's happen. Now like way the last panel is laying on the ground shaking has donald
the bottle kept his bottle.
Is like a bad shape. He really is. You you really feel for him. Right there's some real
desperation in this story. And then the, like, the shaky artwork work, it it's two things at the same time, it's very funny. But it's also very convincing and very heart, I think. It is. It is. I love the panel with Al the Scrooge which two to the two different
expressions really both are very extreme. Yeah. Yeah. You're right. I I like...
I like this setup. Right? Because This is like some real steaks that Scrooge means this to potentially be a one way trip or at least to take a a long span of time and that would be a hard thing to talk the Nephews into, but Barks needs him to be in bad enough shape that he can bring the other Inducks Al lot. And so, you know, they have on the next page, they have this conversation. It's the usual wages combat converse conversation about being paid a a ridiculous
Scrooge
amount of money, but
it's it's this rate running gag.
Right, where every time there's gonna be a mention of money, even if it's a little careless one, this is the worse each time. Yeah.
Acting worse and worse. Yeah. And Donald Tells tells them, after they mention it and they set them off again, hand me two bottles of his medicine from the way he's acting. It's lucky you didn't ask for a dollar. And you sense that that anthem up again as well.
And so, you know, this very brisk very short story has to accelerate pretty quickly. We transition in that half page, we are now at the foot hills of the Hi himalayas.
And
sc is asking around the locals if anyone can tell him the way to trauma Al allah, and we get the kind of exchange that you would you might expect. Right? Like if there was a paradise,
and they knew about it. They'd go there themselves. So so no one can give them that info. But when Scrooge press a little bit harder,
the the local that he's talking to says,
my grandfather, once said that his grandfather's
grandfather saw a traveler that had seen the Al and unscrew fumes
must have been big news at the time of Marco Polo.
It's a great punctuation guy.
It is a great gag.
A couple of things about this too. We don't always get to talk about, like, Barks is usually very thoughtful about depicting locals Al, he likes is National Geographic.
Sometimes he had some stereotypical
representations of.
But but this one is not one of those cases. You know, The people at the foot of the Himalayas are drawn very accurately
realistically.
Yeah, very realistically in a way that's not kara at all, and and they are humans
too
Didn't get to do as many.
But I remember is a kid even. But when I read this for the first time how different the alliance were from these people just across them mountain and
analytics, and they were like, totally different kinds of people too. Not at a different place. But the people were entirely different Yeah. And it's kind of unusual too jumping ahead just a little the trial allow you, Lo,
lions are gonna be Ducktales then I don't...
Usually his lost civilizations weren't yeah There's something
about that. It's meeting yeah not sure what exactly it is.
I now I did there with a thing. I think we're supposed to... I think we're supposed to be able to envision Scrooge kind of sliding in with them and know it and existing.
And I think that makes it easier to.
But yeah. Any any any other thought yeah go. I just just would like to point out again.
Just how tightly
script this thing is it's such a masterpiece of moving along and getting the kind of information into each panel, you know, it's so it's overwhelming the way at corn of comic storytelling telling them this short amount of time. For me. Like, I can imagine, imagine trying to trying to script this thing I.
I agree as short as it is it almost never,
almost never feels rushed. So the kids ask the man, if grandfather said where are they... Where the On Al said though, And mean there was in a around Deep Al rings by high mountain. The kids coming it could be anywhere in.
So they're thinking about that. And they decide to start asking other people, you know, go on foot and ask different people if they see seen the place or heard about it and kind of get together more more ideas. They don't get anywhere, but eventually sure they stopped besides the huge spring. And donald suggest that higher airplanes to search for Al, and of course, it's gonna be too expensive Scrooge screws comments so you cost me fifty dollars an hour just to hire one of the contraption. And of course, that leads to more medicine. U. But at the bottom of a page, the big development is the kids say oh, yes, we kids have already started. They they already have a clue to what where this place is at. We're like looking in the phone. The your have thought was interesting is a is a kid too after was Al clue. I was like, it's just what this all about. Look at it. It's possibly be what they say. It is a very fun little bit of, like kinda wish fulfillment where the kids get to solve the problem. Yeah.
And it's it's a really convincing
like, the evidence that they use is it pretty cool. The way it ties in with the whirlpool Al little bit makes it even cooler. Exactly.
Yeah. It's... Like, ties the two world together Right. Yeah as you said, the story is just so tightly
constructed. So so basically, the kids
explain that they've noticed the fountain that they're in front of they're they're proposing that it it must be the end of an underground spring that comes from T law.
Because they can see the twig from fruit trees
popping up in it. And so there's no fruit trees newer.
Right.
Exactly.
It's it's a little bit of a stretch and it falls apart that the locals wouldn't have noticed it over. Centuries, but it it's convincing in the way that it's he construction to. And so they
they kinda consider where could there be fruit trees in those mountains?
And this is where they get to consult the fully named Junior Wood chips Guide book, and they say that the waters of a spring come through fishers in the basic rock and and they go on and any kind of hand waves a little bit here and and Inducks indicate
that it's... It must be from beyond the field notch in the big high mountain which seems to form a v. It looks really imposing. Does. And and we're at a point in history where, you know, the world's been mapped, there satellites
just kind of being launched but it... It's really at the end of an era where they're still...
During Barks career, there actually could still be these, like, valleys that weren't fully known. That's... I think that's part of what makes the the stories
so wonderfully, like,
thrilling. Right? Because at the time, some of this, you know, now you get on Google maps and you could you could see. Oh, there's no trial a lot. But but this was possible at that time. And Yep. Scrooge says, you know, that valley could have been hidden all these sent because the mountains are over five miles
high. This is where you start to really ponder or what they're going to discover Barks may you wait for it. Know Because yeah. Al as we go come forward you won't get to see it right away. If I fault and stuff and stuff in your way you wanna when get to. So was like why whenever I read this, I still get that feeling like, you wanna see the place. Oh it's super interesting.
Yeah. So local scratch and freezes this purse. Tires Al plain. So you see the loading eats and socks in bags Yes. Pretty fun. They're taking oxygen,
and it feels like with the oxygen, we feel serious. It does. Yeah. And you're bringing the nervous and along. There's not many bottles left comments. Kids come... This is the shot that I remember. I saw this, I knew what they were talking about as far as that were bag with the his carrier medicine. Those existed there were like weather. That was like a real thing. Yeah. And Scrooge says I don't care. I won't need this stuff after we get to travel line and we see the pilot with his to your model oxygen outfit on feeling it's a new story Al the time. Like, modern times. Yeah. And it tells them to zip up the boot it's going to be off cold at six miles up. Right? The next panel is one of my favorites from the story, but the first time you see that ring hidden with clouds and wondering what's in there. It's in very enticing. High above the world's highest people this compounded cloud type of view to scanning the ground with radar in the pilot. And so there's a deep solid below us right now. So I found it's very serious as it get particular area of this story. Totally agree. Everything you've just said, I love that panel where, you know, you just see the top for the most part of that mountain and obscured by clouds.
It's so intriguing. You you wanna see there. And you get the feeling that he, you know, radar is still relatively recent. Right? So
I think there's the idea that... Well, this is the first time anyone's going over this with radar. So now we can see there are houses down there. And so so basically, the next page is all about, like, Scrooge
attempting to negotiate with the pilot. Right? Because yeah. This is a really dangerous
situation to try and pilot a plane into.
And the pilot refuses
He references the plane costing a million dollars. And so screw has to steal himself by, like,
proactively taking a bottle of his medicine
and he shu a lot of two million dollars
telling him to find a hole in the clouds.
And the pilot is ready to Al oblige.
And we get this really nice bit of build up before we send
where he says ominous if there's feel down there big enough will land.
Otherwise,
and then the otherwise is otherwise, we do will jump and take our handset. Really really building up the suspense. And we have a wonderful wonderful moment with the bottle account first bottle count falling out at the plane that very important very shortly in Thank you for highlighting that. I almost gloss over. Right? We get this and and you would miss it if you
Barks seems... It seems insignificant and he makes it so big and in the it's so almost big Al the plane, the bottle for
He does this great point of view panel where it's like the bottle caps
the view of it falling just to make sure we really
know it's so important to the story it's so early
not gonna see
the consequence of this for time. So it's like... It's like a rare comment moment for a animal economy anyway. For something to happen, it seems so
insignificant. You might miss it on your first week, but it's super important later. It's like a very sophisticated storytelling
device. It... That's a great way of putting it. He really had a lot of trust in his young readers.
Yeah. So we got half page panel and Barks is, you know, famous for for large these large important channels. And this one comes like fairly early in the story like in the middle, so there's the plain diving down get our first view distant view of.
It's in the pilot you're listening it's the pilot is saying Telling crash wagon It couldn't get this playing into that app with a derek and we see down below, we can see the whirlpool distant in the bottom of the valley. We get a shot of the whole Al, so it really sets this up to see what limited places, and can't get out of the once you're in the says that that means we have to jump boys first thing costs their supplies out as the plane continues to circle around. Now out we go, and it's like a very serious jump up. It seems like oh real person to jump out of a plane Mh. And as a falling, and on I sure this place is Al is cracked up to be. If it isn't, oh when a jam were in, we just see the phone. It's very, very wonderful page.
Yeah. It's got the right mix of shots and medium shots, you know, it's like Al it's perfectly
perfectly drawn
page. Right. And the any art is what really, like, draws your eye. But the writing just, you know, the that first panel with the pilots like, okay. How in crash wagon.
And and donald, you know,
about
what a jam we're in. It's it's great comic right. Can page before and the two pages before this, see adds a little cross in a couple of panels. So the all cross actually here on this page isn't, like, distracting. Like, earlier in the story, there is much cross on the last page. The page before, there's like, some bits of process the black places
because
tell us a little bit. That's a great awesome bit of but tell us about what, what is Cross switching? This is super realistic. You know that piece approach to this plane and going into the valley. Right? And you can see the mountains side. It's got all kinds of really nifty pen work or brush work. Think Al mostly as pen, and it's like you know, it's like a vertical little lines that are, like, bridge traditional illustration kinda like the like, like frank god or Alex raymond might do just, you know, very realistic. And just to throw that in without any kind of preparatory
preparation kind stuff, we can throw you off from we're disco growing the docks. So on the pages before he's got the claim, helping the start with the cap falling out and the plane got a little bit of cross that you know, just enough to and that if the plane at the bottom got a little bit of shadowing too, and then the panel be forth with the little the shot of the ring mountain that I love. It's got a bunch of cross attachment on it too. He's kinda of leading up to this page. He added that in order to make this work better. Thank a great bit of insight. Thank you, Patrick. That's. So just like Al artist you kind yeah. You I I love it. Yeah. Alright. So
at every page really is kind of about one sequence in this story. And and the next page is gonna be all about their descent.
Right? They're they're a pair.
They don't usually get... I mean... I think we see the Ducktales parachute and other stories, but this is pretty extended. So to me it feels like the reader really feels like they are with the Ducktales
they're in this parachute fall.
And they're taking the time to admire the valley, screws is checking it out for signs of wealth.
There there's this real attitude that's set up here too, and and Barb almost has, like, a thesis
in this story. That it is not human in nature
that is corrupting the people. It it is the money. It is the shiny stuff the the wealth that is doing the corrupting. You know, that is his thesis in this. And so they're looking, he's he doesn't see any gold or jewels.
The the nephews are my the orchard and cattle and rice pad.
It does really seem to be a land of abundance,
of milk and honey, you know, a famous old, like biblical reference
for a land of plenty.
And and screws is so poetic still too like he's particularly poetic on these pages where here I Al be able to rest here among people that have no desire for my wealth. It's very like I don't know It's like he's like added iq points to his intelligence. Like, in this story, like in John.
There's a real flourish. You're right.
A lot of the Scrooge dialogue really is very lyric.
Always struck with like, this through this particular story that's got that tell about. Right. And and so the first half of the pair to send the first half of the page is very positive And then the second half is very stressful because Donald notices they're about to fall right into the giant whirlpool pool that we just... We only saw briefly at a distance. Now it looks very
men.
And the the nephews are kind of pointing out very like placid that if not, for that, you know, the Al, which is so contained, would otherwise fill up with the water, the the melt water.
And and Donald is puzzled why they're so blessed
there's a great panel with screws looking into the oracle for the panels made a little bit extra big. Squish into the bottom panel. So really good use of that space. Yeah. Yeah. Definitely. I really love these pages.
Like this page you just talked about in this next page to my favorites from story, you get to see the valley. You get to see it from all different angles. You know? Get the see the world from the distance and medium ground. You hear this first panel. We get to see the people up on the on the dock watching them as the landing within the whirlpool, and it really looks pretty pretty tragic to you. Look at those people why don't they do something to save us. Maybe they're too surprised how help and we can see on the dock the neck the guy... It's Al kid, I didn't see when I read this panel right sprung up I looked back and there it was. Yeah. It really rewards re reread. Right? Because I didn't notice it the first time. Yeah. So the kids tell to slip out of your parish because I know what's up. And they'll be scared sp
this bet comes up and saves them. It's done such a short amount of space, you know, that whole episode just happens And it's perfect you can understand it perfectly how it did it. It works it works great. The kids saw this from way there with our junior chuck Telescopes
use of the wood jr of tele. So the Or king or leader person greet them in some foreign language, and we see it plumbing that maybe. Flying by. And Scrooge is able to answer them back because This is speech of ancient cafe, which I learned when I was a black buyer in tibet on funny
Right. That's a beautiful beautiful page again. It is a beautiful page. And and so here, you know, at this point, Patrick, we've met the the residents of Trauma.
It's interesting that, like everyone kind of steps this place is real. Right? Like no one is...
It's it's kinda unusual. No one is skeptical
about this place existing. That's not really the point of the story. Mh. And and the trauma La or however, I would say that. That's right. They're they're interesting.
They... So they're they're a generic east Asian
culture. Right? And and for the time they're they're depicted very, I would say very respectfully.
You know, like, look something... Yeah. Like, like, he he he has the best of intentions
with them. They're they're definitely a little bit kara churn
looking back. But in general, this is a a pretty benign
representation. I was struck reading my, like, fan graphics reprint for the first time. I... Most of the reprint I've seen,
the the coloring, they'll get the same coloring as the other dot. You know, they'll be wipes. And in the original print, there's they're they're yellow, which, you know, that that is not something that a publisher would run. That would be regard as a stereotype. Barks himself wouldn't have had anything to do with that. And it doesn't really make any kind of Al impact. On the story. But it just is worth acknowledging. They're kind of like generic east asian.
They fit... They're very much model after the characters in that. Movie. Too. We're very... Yeah. They're very, like, passive,
very peaceful
And and, you know, we get the setup up on this next page that Trauma law is proves to be everything that Scrooge
expected of it. You know, and talking to the leader, he learns that friendship is what they value the most on the doctor talking about the help they've gotten getting their stuff together. No one asked for a reciprocal favor and Scrooge, you know, he kind of mar for them. All we have to do is bear our share of the work and the people will leave us strictly alone. It's interesting that this this this feels like Barks
describing
the socialist
community. It does. Sure. Which is fascinating. Right? Because Barks was definitely not a socialist,
but he is also
presenting this is a very positive place. So there's an interesting little, like, dynamic there. I love the guy in the first panel, The way he's sitting was holding this tea cup is very civilized.
Super super get that impression. Yeah, Barks, this was like the character the car was using to represent Al these people and just looking how he is, you know, he's like very
just very happy and civilized and, you know, this point is supposed to be. Just like what I should be. There. And and he seems to be like a thrown room, but it's it's a pretty modest thrown.
Right. He he seems like he's probably first among equals Yes. So guards around when on the pier.
Yeah.
And there's some, like lovely
art. Very... Again, it's just very east asian it's clearly inspired by mostly Chinese Barks.
Yeah. I would say there's an urn and some cool cabinetry. He had a lot of fun drawing this I expect. Yes. Like too. And and so we get... We get the turning point. On this page, the the initial one. Right?
We get we see that bottle cap again. Is it been four pages?
Five rough four or five pages ago. We ways.
We see that bottle cap again.
One of the villagers who's working in a rice pad finds an object.
And says that it's the shiny stuff called Metal.
It must belong to the old duct name Scrooge. Huey, do... The villagers do speak with a little bit of, like, a a kind of a stereotypical
accent But it's it's really within, you know, kind of very reasonable, I think. And so he brings it to Scrooge who is visibly working with some mortar and brick clearly making himself a home, and Scrooge faithfully says why. That's only an old bottle cap. It's like amazing like, whether they really finds the bottle cap
then you remember falling out the plane because it so there it's wonderful wonderful moment the story. And like four modern times come to twelve.
And I guess you're pretty well know because of the tag. Things are ideal until one day, what's common. But even then there's like, it's like it's like shocking talking the wonderful moment. I think Right.
Doesn't realize this yet then. But he's just like you can have it I don't want. You guys. Oh, thank you. He's like very happy. And as soon has it to another person in Charlotte. It's all over Look at the old bug, the bottle cap Inducks gave me. You'd lucky lucky like. Right? And it's like oh no. It's it's just horrible. And you just know what's gonna happen. It's gonna ruin all these wonderful. Bridge gave a beautiful bottle kept to hudson. Gee, I wish I could have one, then people starting to trying and get to sell. He doesn't wanna Al they start offering more and more. And nancy man's husband or wife suggest that team that whispers. It's a worth main.
So So by the end of the page, one I was telling albert you got a bargain neighbor. I'll give you twenty sheep for that Shiny Barber. So it's thought progress or This is like a a class sick
economics thought experiment. Right? I'm sure Some Economists somewhere is written as Phd
on this comic book story. Yeah. This is what, like, an Economist would call a closed system.
And and is the idea what?
What happens? Social behavior to... Right. Right. What happens when you introduce
this foreign object to this closed system
and we see
Yeah. That... It it is almost
commentary on collect.
Because the value of it Skyrocket
and this
We understand this to be real. Right? This is a true economic force. This is what it causes a lot of problems. It's just as real as gold.
If we think about it, and the gold in the ground. Right? People they it up, and put huge amount of efforts and define. Gather together. Right? And it's not like you can eat it. It's not like you can really use it for anything to join maybe to. End up taking it some british guy ends up with it. Where they do they mail it down? Put it back in the ground people guard.
Exactly. Except that now you've got people ga someone one those takes. And it doesn't have any really intrinsic value itself That's exactly right. No inherent value whatsoever.
And and so by the next page, the next page corresponds to the next day. And it has
escalated
so quickly,
and I could easily picture this being stretched out over one or two more pages
if he was given some room to breathe. I don't think it... I don't think it suffers.
At all. No. I don't think so either. I think that it could stand with a couple of the key things being bigger. I in say quarter pant pages or smaller that another little bit more space little a bit nice. But I think the actual structure doesn't yell renew anymore. Right. I agree because the part of what why this works so well is how quickly
this happens.
Because by next day, the guy who has it is being absolutely
hound
for the bottle cap. And and one of his country men says, I want that bubble, I'll pay you all the right recycling row for ten years.
And he says that no.
The pride of owning. The only bottle cap in Trauma is worth more to me than food. And so
We transitioned Scrooge and Donald who have no idea what's going on, and he makes a bold decision as the narrator box.
Says.
He says Tells Donald that he has decided to stay here and trauma a off for forever.
And as an aside as a kid,
I was like,
this moment was painful in full for me because, like, I knew it wasn't gonna end like this, but it's still the idea that Scrooge would abandon his fortune his adventures.
It it was a little upsetting to me yes.
But he explains that, you know, everything is... It's everything he wanted, and so he decides to celebrate by empty his his bottles of nerve tonic and which is really clever way for to go about it. It's brilliant. Right? What I what a great setup. He... It's such an organic way to bring
more bottle caps into the equation.
And he's casually looking for a bottle opener to do just that and a fish sherman standing next to him.
Sees the bottle cap and then sees that he has
one, two, three, for, five bottle caps,
and he
explains to Scrooge
that you're the richest duck in all crawl la. Oh, unfortunate.
What a moment. And and you know what I forgot to mention
Patrick is that
the trauma
Have five fingers.
Need come on
most are. Saw that. Yeah. I can't claim that I noticed it. I saw it pointed out on one of the, you know, but. I think it was c Barks dot d interesting that. Yeah. It's not Al It's it's... Again, it's it's more of that making them human but setting them apart. I don't know exactly.
Very special. Yes.
Exactly. And so, yeah. You just love the close of this page Scrooge is like dawning
realization. Yes And then it's like you sort of returned the beginning of the story with... You now everyone, all of a sudden bottle caps. I see that's five bottle caps and sort of charge Al. These like the first he's like just upset. I'll give you two eight hundred pigs for just one bottle count. He's right at the edge of the water he's gonna fall in the whirlpool portal that's. I'll be your reserving for forty years. And then it's like, he's back in Inducks because it's like if this rich adviser doesn't give his bottle caps to a people like me, he's an old meaning raises taxes and he's sting. It's horrible. Right? So the fridge the starts coming apart. Is my nerves my nerves. Young leash is the bottle kept from his bottle
shoots it off to the pro lines for free, but it was tough enough to take it. The drinks is... And the next was great. Silhouette panel screwed distance drinking this bottle of medicine as half the trailer fights it out, like a both top of each other box bam just the wall of.
And just Scrooge
about keep medicine. Looks like it's gonna need. It it's great. It's
it's fantastic. We're we're really picking up they're like falling off the pure. They're gonna end definitely in whirlpool was where we gonna end up. Yeah. I know I thought about that. It's stressful.
And so we transitioned to, you know,
Scrooge old problems have found him again
inadvertently
he is just being pastor. The the price... The asking price is still
astronomical. Someone offers his
story very.
And and Donald, you know, tells them why are you people so greedy for bottle caps? Why don't you greedy for good things like sheep.
And and they've learned what people learn under capitalism
that, you know,
sheep are not common at this point. Her sheep are common at this point, it's bottle caps that are rare, that are scarce and they have that assigned value that everyone's agreed on. Mh.
And so the Nephews tell their their poor uncle who is just shrouded in in Al blanket for comfort that they should send Donald over the mountain to bring back enough caps for everyone. And Scrooge likes this idea and
You know, he he gets a little bit too excited, Patrick because in his
enthusiasm, he goes from proposing a a million bottle caps to... No. I'm I'll make it a bill yet. And and they they all share, it doesn't really dawn in Don on anyone what he said. Because again, Barks knows, we have trouble
visualizing what a billion means.
They're saying, you know, we can get planes to dump them in and everyone will be happy And and so, again, we have a great set up here as the such tight storytelling
it is. Donald is able to use one of the bottle caps to hire an army of guides to help him over that imposing wall.
And all they have to do now is is wait
until the place is made perfect
again. So the trail of waiting for wildcat caps to arrive. Becoming a Scrooge promised a rain of bottle caps in the sky. When does it start?
And they're neglecting their crops and Scrooge
pursuing false wealth. Then have done that's stupid things since the beginning of time that kids laugh that he should talk because he's little wealth this time too. And just the idea of get Scrooge up settings like shaking all over the place. There there's only two bottles of medicine left. So donald have to shop same with the caps. And then it happens, the bottom of page, we see it's starting to rain Barks caps and the villages of Trauma running around with perhaps catching them employment basket And the last panel we see trial
with a basket floor caps riches. Millions of sheets were beautiful shiny vinyl caps. Really.
Yeah. So caps are here. Right? Things are gonna be good again. Yep. The bottle caps and and Donald pair of in, thinking about a job well done. So so Barks sets it up very well, like that that finishes the aaron. Yeah. Right. That's what we think. And then they're celebrating how trauma law has been saved. And then we get an economic lesson. Right? Pharmacist is is saying look at this. Watch... Watch what happens now. He says this through Scrooge. We got a couple of neighbors that are puzzled why why aren't you offering to buy my bottle caps and and it's the log supply and demand.
Everyone has all the bottle caps they could want No one needs more. They're not worth anything. And so Scrooge is acknowledging they've... They've realized that the richest they had all along
you know, what they had were the richest all along. It it would be a very sap ending.
If it were the real ending,
Right then in a bit of perfect timing, we get another rain of bottle caps and we get that
devastating
realization that dawning moment where where Donald tells him that first claim load was only a million caps You ordered a billion. Remember and Scrooge the top and next page is covering his head. This is the building bottle caps, my star is well that's a thousand plain.
Yes. Planes will be flying in here and unloading a million bottle caps every hour day at night for the next six weeks Scrooge realizes what's up. So he's gonna leave town because got ticked of hills way still got a chance. I lying and it's just it's not quick. Right? He's like said we don't need to process. We know what's about to happen. Yeah. Soon those caps have knocked down half of my race plants. That old screws Al pay for the damage. And but cheap can't eat their grass because it's covered with bottle caps and and you comes another way, the terrible things, oh brothers, Scrooge screws you ever going.
They're hiding in a cave and there's a mall bro the Al looking for them. And screws says if they find me, they'll make me pay damages. What can I use for money? Don't says caps, no they're out.
I I love that, yeah. I guess it's a dumb guess, but it's great. It's great though. It's crazy so and the big served is bad again. How and here's the part of the story that does feel a little bit brief to me. Right? Like it feels like they could been on the run a little bit longer. You know? So they only spend, like,
six panels really
lighting these caves. But but Barks wants to move this along and he has to move this along. Yeah. He's that's certain page count to deal with, I think. Right. And and so,
you know, we get the acknowledgement from the mob looking for them that if the Inducks are hiding in those caves, we may not find them for years.
So the debts have some hope, but that hope is pretty quickly q when Scrooge starts to fall the pieces again and they have to give him one of the last bottles of medicine.
And and the predictable thing happens and we've seen it. Patrick. They've set it up. We hit that sp,
which alerts the the search
and we transition to to the Trauma law being a very civilized
place has a high court. You know, we imagine they they handle their disputes very carefully. Go. To right.
I I really like this, you know, when Scrooge goes before the high court he initially kind of blisters
and he says
Those follow caps won't hurt your land. They they may stop coming
time now. But the Nephews are just they're they're the real conscience the real hard of the story here. This is one of the best examples of the importance of owning your mistake. It's a great object lesson. Right? Your you have to own up to it. They tell him you won't save yourself by stalling. Tell them the truth, and they explain that the bottle caps are going to keep raining down for weeks
and potentially will choke the whirlpool pool and flood you out and and I've got... I've got a figure
that they're, like, heartfelt fell honest
right no Bs
explanation is what
convince that this, you know, authority to to help them to trust them and to, you know, do what what you're gonna talk about on this stage. Right.
So the one nephew you standing on the heads of the other one.
There was only one way to avoid this
how you it's important There's only one way to avoid this awful calamity. How and those guys really upset the judge by sending up the prescription us stocks out to stop the planes. And one the citizens says it's a loose to save their next. Throw them in the world pool but the big.
I think and the judge wise. No. The words and the small doctor wise. We Al are stuck. So they send send away, send them off to turn off the flow of both caps because they don't want anymore. Several days later, we made it back to civilization. There's a science of India. Which is very convenient. Right.
And whom will be wonderful after that's scare. And you won't mind, being asked for anymore that's donald. Right? Donald saying that. Sorry. Heaven's know Scrooge, In fact, I'll never need this last bottle medicine now. So if things are wonderful. We're go to hear that Scrooge,
we were we're just going to ask you for a thirty four cents an hour wages. And then at the end of the very last panel, there goes Scrooge off again this Huey, he way is ever, you know, it's from Oh, my goodness gracious.
Here I go again. Yeah. And there's not a wasted to panel in this story. It's a sensational...
You know, it's the running gas. When you when you establish a running gag like that, that you have to close it out or you have to give one really good one at or near the end. Most most people comic storyteller tell, including myself probably would need twice the space to tell the same story and with the amount of detail and stuff that the karl puts into an cy eight masterpiece
and storytelling ability as far as writing and getting those panels in there. It's a it's an amazing accomplish And and I... It's my big thing on the story right. I agree. It's it's amazingly paced. It doesn't feel rushed
except for me the and does feel a little bit clipped. I. Could've used they could've have used another page. Right. Yeah. Because we don't even get... Yeah. We don't even get a full page
for their their departure.
It's six out of eight panels.
We don't get a returned duck. That might be a good choice.
I don't know though. Maybe we did... Maybe it would have been nice to see that kind of book and. Yeah center... The center of the stories where bugs splurge. When they're coming down in the parish, and he takes all that time for them floating him down. If he doesn't rush Al all and it's like Huey, uses a lot of panels. They're in the air forth for like They throw the supplies out one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten pounds. They're float than the sky come the bury. And know he like he sees that the the story needs that that right the essence
of ci T
understanding what it is. Huey, uses all all that all that always those panels for left. And that, know, doesn't leave on the room for the engine for a similar sort of for, like, standing by and new dwelling on like the end. You're right. It seems
it's a good choice. Yeah. It seems to have been a very, like, deliberate... I don't... I mean, I don't know. For all I know, you know, he was like, coming up on deadline, and he had to deliver a twenty two page or
I don't think so because he finished this one at the end of April nineteenth for he created it, you know, till the end of October.
Nineteen fifty three, And it saw Al publication,
you know, publication date at least was April of fifty. I imagine that they told in how many pages you had to work with? Had the story, you wanted to use the stories. I wonder
he was inspire, obviously. And he said, well, you know, his last three pages here. I could use another page, It work. You did. It's it's also not the point of the story. Right? Like the the meat of the story is in It's the bottle cap catastrophe.
It's this it's it's the sc law.
It's the economics like lesson
and and the little
economic
experiment. That's what he's interested in. That's what's memorable and fascinating about this.
It is. Wonderful.
What a great story. I I love this one so much, Patrick. I found I was looking through
a few months ago. I was looking for something on one of my old computers. And I found a text file I made that was titled top twenty favorite Carl Barks stories.
I was like, Oh, what a cool thing to find. I can see what what I liked what were my favorite stories I I gotta share that at some point. I don't know why I didn't think to share that. In... It would have been probably about fifteen to twenty years ago that I made that. And so I I was thinking of myself, I can I can be honest, you know, if I if I changed my mind at some point, And and the only thing that? And this was on the list. Right? And it and it was absolutely the stories that you would probably expect to be on the list for the most part.
I've I've cooled a little bit to Voodoo Hut over the years, which I had in my top ten But this was way up there. You know, I definitely listed this story. I love this. I read this
over and over. Weirdly. I only had, like, one printing of this one for the longest time.
But but it it holds up amazingly well. It's just an Al
story. It's it's notes. It's message is something. It's not gonna go away people just still do the same things. Right. Absolutely.
So the the graphic album
that I have had some pretty... I thought it was pretty good
commentary from Gil more, you know, Jeffrey B had done the commentary on most of the Gladstone ones. Not I thought he had some pretty sharp good stuff to say I haven't read a lot of more in stuff. But I I really liked a couple of the things that you had to say about the story.
And one of those
was just
how...
So Scrooge carries the seeds of his downfall with him albeit
unconsciously. I thought that was a good dissolution of the story. And then I think he must have been really proud of this line. Scrooge finds that he has fled the capitalist
system only to found a bottle
capitalist.
System. And he he builds bottle cap and bottle of capitalist.
Mh. So I like that. I I found myself thinking in this story about other lost Al stories that he's done you know, such as lost and And,
Sure. And then I found it really interesting. Again, as I mentioned, Barks is really
purposely
saying that it's the metal. That's the problem. And I don't know that I agree
with that,
but... But it's an interesting... It's it it definitely works within the context of this story. Yes. Yeah. Yeah I think that's... The whole the whole thing's is fairly silly. And the bottle that they weren't after the can opener it's made it me. That one of those. Was where we're still. That's true. That's a little plot hole that he doesn't
doesn't go over. I guess, the bottle account was establish the whole the whole business of man kind doesn't make any sense to begin with whole the way we actually operate, you know, the things that we covered that don't have Al value. It's like, you know, it's like perfectly true. And it's not really the metal. It's just something that everyone agrees on like you said earlier.
Everyone agrees on being valuable. So that alone takes everyone else agree. Right. And and this kinda of ties in with a couple of the ten pages that he did a little, I think a little bit earlier or that some of the shorter ones like
the financial favor, you know, the corn crib story I find this reminiscent of that one and the rare story that we cover Right. As well, definitely.
As well as the the really short ones, something fishy here where Scrooge
recreate his fortune with fish. There's something that I've forgotten about. They was same with Carl Scrooge remember all his stories either. He had hundreds of the things.
Yeah. He had a couple of other fun things to say about this. He said, you know, I I dreamed up this cap business, this file cap business that disrupted the people's way of life. They had always been satisfied with what they had and suddenly, one of them got one little piece of metal that no one else had that started it. It really tested these people to see if they were all they were cracked up to be most human nature wouldn't allow them to be quite that good when they got up against the real nitty gritty yeah. And really, they're they're not on purpose that way. Right. You know, they're that way accidentally because they're cut off from the rest of the world, I guess. You know, they're they don't they don't know if everyone else covered some particular thing. Right. It's very innocent. Is he innocent about it is the thing that
to me, don't thing. Yeah. Because we really we really like the trial Alliance. We feel bad for them and in going through this. At least that's how I felt about it. So Patrick, we had talked about how highly
you know, rated that this one is by the community
I I'd already mentioned that of the outset. So I won't be labor the point. But
This one does rank
at number one or number two depending on the time of day where you're checking Inducks, basically. I suspect that back of the Al will probably probably
take it again
in short do, but it's it's clearly an all time classic. Right? Yep.
Great story around. And as far as as far as other media
other appearances
I'd mentioned it previously, Unfortunately, Barks never
never got a commission to do... Part of the reason I'm so glad that you, you know, adapt to that for that.
Wonderful painting is that Barks didn't get to cover
this one at least a fish.
But he apparently did do some
preliminary work
on one that would have represented this story. Did you ever see it? No. I would have expected that it would have shown, like, the bottle caps falling or their
their descent on the pair, but it actually
seems to show
they're like journey out
but kennedy ray, he Severino got to finish that one. Yeah. Maybe that's why he never
kind of a tricky thing to compose something to really show that and pay.
This one...
Don Rosa did do
an a sequel, like a formal sql story to this one called return to X dude. Did you ever read that? I did. The really when was new. Can. Yeah. I I like that. I... It it was kind of a sneaky
sequel.
The way Disney comics presented it Al like a I'd they presented originally is like a two partner with a little cliff where they reveal that you were were back to Trial a lot. And and I did think it was pretty clever of how he
made trouble a lot, be the legendary
city of X. And he kinda tied it into the famous
Cool black khan poem. Yeah. Sure. Makes a lot sense. Yeah. And and, of course, he kinda tied it together with the other Himalayas. Tail of
the
crowd. The lost crown of
Khan. Which I I don't think is one of births.
Stronger stories, but, you know, they're geographically related. Yep And
this one was pretty famously
this one did have an allocation in the... I'm not sure if you're a Ducktales fan or not, but this is one that was adapted.
For the shoes. I don't think I've never seen it plan where they they give it a shot. Yeah. So I I haven't seen that episode Ducktales in a long time, but
I recall. It was pretty good. It was pretty strong at least for Ducktales. And a pretty pretty direct adaptation of the story. You know, I I didn't have the impact that the the story, the comic story did. But, you know, I I didn't have the impact that the the story, the comments where he did. But but they did adapt it. And then the second Ducktales series, they did not do any kind of adaptation, but I learned very recent that they had something called a three hundred and sixty degree adventure.
It's a Youtube video where you can like rotate the camera perspective and see it in full three.
Yeah. And it was called the last key of t la but apart from that, it didn't have any connection to the original story. It's gonna cool. Yeah. It was interesting.
So, you know, we we cover the story I think pretty well. The the only thing really left is to talk about
any of our panels that we would like to highlight as favorites if there's any that you didn't already get talk about. Maybe like the pin rooms looks at the Scrooge really on in the stories is like drinking bell medicine he's ending the scale scroll just I remember always thinking how cute there's nothing really, special about the panel, but just the... What's happening and it's just a really nice moment story. Yeah. I I totally agree with you that The Scrooge just whole breakdown sequence is full just wonderful panels.
And the both kept falling out the plane remains one my most they favorite panels of any any c during to to me personally. It is a great set of I'll note too that that Ducktales
episode I I looked up just a little bit of it briefly, and that is one thing that they did just to is they really held the quote camera on that bottle capsule falling for a while. Yeah. That's great.
Look at I'm gonna look that up and watch Yeah. First things I do
Yeah. I was Al alright. It it had the character fe and crack shell pretty heavily
pretty prominently in it and I'm I'm not really a big fan of and. For my part, that that joke that we mentioned the league to a abolish.
I I continue to think that that's one of the best the funniest things that Barks has has ever done. So I've gotta mention that. I've got echo.
What you said about the squirrel So there's just there... We we covered it pretty well, though. There's there's so many great ones in this.
Alright. Well, listeners, I I really appreciate you
checking out our listening to our thoughts on this story.
And hopefully,
you can join us next time when
the podcast returns and we get to talk about
a pretty pure adventure story, the seven cities of
Great story. That is a lot... That everyone's a lot of fun. And and you can check us out on Facebook or Instagram, of course, barb remarks, and Patrick, I've I've
figured out a closing
that I'm doing that and the episodes. I'm just saying whatever is in the last panel.
And I I think that... And it's it's a pretty good closure for this one. Do you wanna read it for us? Oh, my goodness gracious meal. Here I go again. Thanks from both of us. Thanks, Patrick.
You bet.