We can have
Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer an artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comments of all time. Join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks. Welcome back to Barks remarks. I'm Mark Sever, a grown man who enjoys Inducks comics, joined by a returning guest host.
Warren, could you
introduce yourself and remind us about your
level of experience with the Karl Barb comics?
Thank you, Mark. Yeah. We're in Harmon here
back for another great podcast and reviewing a story that I grew up with. I I'm a long time Barks collector comma collector all
mostly, and got into the lit graphs later in life and all around Ducktales.
So love the podcast and love sharing my my
and story thoughts. Excellent.
Warren, have you ever hung out in the American Southwest
before? Well, yeah. You know, when I was working,
actively with Mayo Clinic here in Rochester. We have Al clinic in Scottsdale in Phoenix, So I would go to Phoenix and Scottsdale two or three times a year. For many years, and I... On one of my adventures there. I I traveled the state, you know went up to Northern Arizona went down to Southern Arizona really enjoyed the the landscape
and the desert and
this brought back a few of those memories.
Oh, that's excellent. Yeah. So we we are going to journey to the to the Southwest. I guess I should say return
to the Southwest for this episode.
Because because Barks really likes
setting his stories in this area.
And I'm happy to hear that you're pretty experienced
with the that that area with the the the Southwestern
Desert, it's a beautiful place and it really figures
strongly and in this story, which which is, of course, the seven cities of.
Yes. Also known as the seven cities of gold,
in a lot of reprint. I know we'll talk a little bit about that, but
I was fascinated with this story at ten years old when I bought my very first gold key comic. I think guy told you this at our very first podcast that was the best of and donald dot number two, which feature to featured luck of the North my favorite story, but look at the secondary there, the secondary was is right. That's.
That's where I discovered this story for the first time Al a ten year old and nineteen sixty seven. And absolutely
was a maze at the sheer adventure and vast of it. So really, I'm looking forward to share my memories as I gonna revisit this story. That's a great, like, pairing of stories to be introduced to the to the Barks universe. Right? Because you get these two great stories two very different adventures,
very different settings
you get good exposure to Donald Scrooge Gladstone,
That... That's that's an awesome comic to have started. Yeah. It's my favorite, actually. One of my favorites? I can understand why. So I have a lot of experience with this area too because I I spent about I spent almost fifteen years.
In the desert. I I lived outside of Phoenix
for much of my life and so
it figures really strongly in my
imagination and and memories.
And
and and I think Barks just really enjoyed depicting this area. You know, he grew up in
the inland part of California. Right? And the that's where we're we're gonna kick off in this story and and and they're they're actually... I can travel a a pretty pretty long way through some pretty
unforgiving,
but really think wonderfully drawn American Southwest Desert. That's what struck me was the artwork and the incredible...
Just his depiction of what his memories were of that area. And his love of of the native cultures
comes through in this story so well. And
and respectfully as well. Yeah. I think you're right. You know, he he's definitely Barks shows a lot of interest in the the lower and the history of the region that he's in. You can see that he really likes to focus on and stories like in old, California,
and in this one. And and so you you see a lot of personal touches
in this story references to some actual place names is gonna sneak in a little cameo if someone he knows Eleven. It it it it makes for a really
absorbing
story. My kind of initial thoughts on this one warren. Right? We're we're in... We're at uncle Scrooge numbers. Seven, and and this was this came out in July of nineteen fifty four was the publication date. And and so we're we're still very pretty early in the uncle Scrooge
series. And one of the things that doing this podcast has, like, kinda crystal
for me is I I never really thought about the sequence of stories that he did, you know? And to me, it seems like he spent the first handful
of the uncle screwed stories,
really
concerned with kind of like,
establishing the character
softening
some of the kind of light negative edges that he had given him when he was kind of a side care. Right. Now now I you you gotta imagine that he's proud of of getting a flagship
title
like an act shaw comment but with feature his creation. Right? So can he really threw a lot into
creating uncle Scrooge and establishing him in number one, only a plural man, number two, back to the dyke to a lesser extent, but still concerned with some of that making of Scrooge
number three as well. And then gets further
into this series and, like, starting with issue number four of the series
and into the rest of it. We're more in this mold of just kind of having these adventures.
And this one's a pretty big deal in a certain way because, like it's it's really his first
official
treasure heinz. It is. And and I liked what you said about the evolution of his character development in his own series what what I think is wonderful is as a young reader back in the fifties you're seeing this old man duck if you will. Who's this multi billion billionaire
and and yet he's not afraid of anything. He'll do anything. He'll travel be a treasure hunter, he'll go
everywhere with his nephews and I think he just established this wonderful
character
in in Scrooge
who... Like you said, in this story goes on his very first treasure hunt Right. And and this is what the character is really gonna be
remembered for. Kind of interesting that it's taken like, so many issues.
Right? Because most of the previous, like, quote adventures have been
about protect as fortune.
They've even been these really deep character studies. Yeah. Right? Concerned, like especially uncle Scrooge
one two and three, as well as number six. T,
are are these really, like
mu
on on aging
and memory,
and and the past and and your origin.
And and it's not until this seventh issue where it just kind of gets that classic
Scrooge mc Ducktales template
that this is like what what duck
is gonna focus on.
Exactly.
So
so, yeah. This this this... I like this
story
a lot. This one is just a really good
pure
adventure story.
I love the twist and terms of this one. I read this. I remember, like, this one really fired my imagination as a kid, and I read my copy of this over and over. So the... This will be fun to talk about I I'd already mentioned a couple of the kind of background details
this is one of the longer stories. We we won't have any more of his quote full length thirty two pager.
This twenty eight page length is is as long as he's gonna get to do at this point. Kinda hits a sweet spot, I think. I think, you know, this one
gets to play out pretty well.
It has not been reprinted as frequently as I would've have guessed to the it mind, it only has nine reprint in counting the original in the United States. I also realized that in in that reprint in that best of uncle screwed or Donald dot Scrooge from sixty seven. I believe
the the podcast listeners will correct me if I'm wrong. But I believe that's the first time that this un titled story...
Well, no. I take that Barks. There was... It it was called the seven cities of Si.
Originally,
I believe. Was that right mark? Did it have a title on the in in the original
I think that this was one of the un titled students originally
Yeah. You know, Barks had that correspondence
with with the a fan early on about potential titles for some of bullets. Yeah. Yeah. Now with with Will, and so he had proposed the seven cities. I think he proposed the seven cities of gold. And it officially land ended up landing on on Cy ebola. But for some reason like you said the the fan... The recent fan graphics went with the seven cities of gold. Yeah. And I I I... That's fine, I guess. It it tells the story. But I believe that this... That the first time it was really the seven cities of S ebola was in this reprint the school key reprint. It's isn't think that's right. Yeah. And and it's worth... It's definitely worth dwelling a little bit on on the actual legend here. Mh right. This is
boy this a really fascinating legend. Right?
The idea of the seven cities of gold is something that comes up in in American hi straight for a long, long time. And this
this legend,
arguably
is one of the most dangerous
stories in the world.
Because it it animated the spaniards when they came to the Americas,
and and it just it led to
all of these fruit list
searches for these supposed
cities where they were just cloud and gold
and full of mythical rich is. And and this is kind of the second time that Barks has
has feature this. Right? Because
the the El, the guild man yeah. Was was based on... It's like an overlap legend. Right? It's it's kinda of this oral legend
that every European new
quote that the Americas were full of riches if they could only find them and lot lots of lives
were lost in in pursuit of these cities.
Yeah And the research should that you and I both have done on this
Legend
takes us back to the sixteenth century to fifteen thirty nine to all of these great
excursions, which Barks points out
to actually twist a little bit of fiction and fact in this story, which I thought was really a a brilliant storytelling technique and blending two different legends to kinda make the story even richer with with the the ship of the desert and and that sort of thing. So I thought it was really a fascinating way for for Barks to take, which I read in one of the critical of this story was originally he thought he had something like a ten page story. He did a twenty eight page story until he did more... He was... I think he was over... Hearing a conversation from an old man in a restaurant. Busy. Did you hear that one? Yeah. Yeah. He he called him. I I don't I didn't copy down Al quote, I don't think. But he called him like
it it was a very Barks and funny thing. He was like a notorious liar. The notorious liar who was telling a story that was absolutely not true, but to really bring the journey to the seven cities to a full adventure.
Right. He he just felt compelled to say, okay. Now I can make a long adventure story, and I can give... I can give Uncle Scrooge this vehicle to really showcase his this new personality this new quest forward more well. I mean, this Scrooge is a very different screws in the first screws we saw when he was just hun over in a chair and he could hardly, you know, kick get out of his chair.
So I think this is true transition. It's worth reflect how much
how much we've changed from
Christmas on on bare mount
So, you know,
I had alluded to a Cameo that Barks included. Yeah. With with a friend of his. Was it his editor I don't know. I wasn't clear on that. I I know he was a friend and they were having drinks and and
something. You wanna tell us a little bit, you wanna relate how this kinda went down? Yeah.
Barks was inspired with a visit of his friend. His name is Elk C or Cook. I don't know, but k o c a He was the manager of the Riverside Welfare office in,
California.
He was an authority on local Indian drives and toll Barks about an old Indian trail near thousand palms. Barks explore that trail and decided to use it to set the Ducktales the road.
So I thought that was kinda fascinating.
And as a form of acknowledgment,
Barks drew him into the story in that wonderful seen where this really realistic looking man looking character, not a dog character.
Right. The Big Boys out of the welfare office, and that was his little tribute to his friend Al. Yeah. It's neat when he sneaks these little cameo in. So
I think that the kind of progression
of this story. This is something that I wanna be thinking about as we talked about it. It's it's one of the the
the really cool thing. Is how it starts on this really small scale. Mh.
Looking for Indian arrowhead
stumbling onto to this Indian trail And and then just eventually
progressing, to the seven cities of S. It's very...
It's very captivating to me. The adventure becomes more grand with every panel. Yes. Right. And I've gotta tell you when I read this, it would been... I would have been about nine years old. I'm thinking
and and there was a... There was a show at the time that was just a few years old called the mysterious cities of Gold. Who is this, like, joint production between
Japan and France? And
just really beautiful animation, kind of an incredible and deep story. And and I was absorbed in watching this, like, cereal story. I don't think there's anything else like from that era of animation.
And and so I was just getting all this information. All this input about these these
mysterious
cities of gold. And so that that's... I I feel like they just figure
very...
This myth just cast along shadow and pop culture, I think. Well, it does and and we'll get to some of the other
great story of the modern era that Barks inspired with this story. As well. So...
Yeah. You know what? Let's not t's. This this is one of the things that everyone quote knows.
Have the story. What what is this fun fact one? Well, certainly as as the story ends in in our comic, there's this wonderful scene where the big boys take the idle off of the
the mount there in the cave and the boulder starts throwing around excellent splash panel, we'll talk more about it. But certainly that inspired
Stevens Spielberg and George Lucas to
develop and further develop this action sequence at the beginning of
Indiana Jones razors of the Long arc. I mean, that that to me, is the perfect
salute to the master story from two modern day story retailers. In the... In some of my research, I I just cringe when I said, yeah. They were... Spielberg and Lucas were having fun buying all of Barks oil paintings it's like oh come on they could afford it. Right? But but but he they decided to give him the greatest honor by putting something from
Into his their their film. So, yeah. Like one of one of Cinema, most iconic scenes that does seen from from Indiana Jones. I think it's lupus lucas himself he said was was specifically
inspired by this story. And and they're very different in their kind of, like, placement and progression, but but
Lucas himself has has... I I think he's even
done a couple of the four words for sidebar
collect.
Yeah. He was a Barks collector, a a a huge
fan
wrote the forward in in a few of the books that I have and...
But I was lucky enough to find a a book called art of Carl and it was one of his oil painting books. And I got it in auction because this was the book that he actually gave to George Lucas, and I have that one. Like the copy.
Is if you
George Lucas. Thank you for and and I I I I gave it to my son for Christmas last year because he's such a huge
that's pretty doubt.
It's a pretty cool thing to have. I'll I'll this...
That's awesome. I would love to see a picture of that. I'll get a shot for you for the podcast. That would be neat. Yeah Alright. So...
Boy, yeah. Al lot lot of great stuff around this one. Let's let's go ahead and mention a couple of the titles. Would take a moment to pan to our international listeners.
Yeah. I'll I'll go ahead and just list a couple of the pretty straightforward
ones. I'm gonna try the French, which is Les set seated.
The seven cities of.
And then I like the... I like the Danish why don't you do the the one from?
Yeah. That's a lot of fun. That's very different
from it's certainly not straightforward, but it's it reads far least teal pro,
no kia, I guess.
Sorry, baby my danish friends, makes you want to try something new is the translation.
I thought that was fun. Yeah. It seems to be alluding to Scrooge in the beginning of the story. Does. Yep. And then
German,
again is just a pretty straightforward
translation.
This
Dante
von
and
and that leaves you with Italy. Yeah. Again, a little bit more straightforward.
Scrooge
of the Severino
Yep Alright. So let's
do it one. We're going to cover this story.
So,
you know, I've been having an exchange very recently
on Facebook where it it was pointed out
ruben and who's been on here couple of times. Just kinda highlighted. How many of these stories start out in the money bit. Right? And and I remember when I had y chemo an editor at E on. He was talking about how important it is that a good writer and artist.
Really
this character
every time. Right? Because you you don't know how many new reader.
You might get on a given story. And so
It's fascinating to me how Barks.
He does such a good job of returning to this like familiar ground
adding something fresh to it. And and so we get this great establishing
bit of Scrooge as impossible rich
in his money band. And it it just tells us a lot about the character each time. And and in in the case of this one in the seven cities of S ebola,
sc is
getting a money bath from his butt
which is a side character that we don't
see more than a couple of times.
Yeah. That I'm aware of. And
it's a very funny shot. Right? It's very screwed. Usually he's got a bathtub for this. If and it feels weirdly into intimate to me warren. Yeah. He doesn't have any close.
Yeah. Yeah. It's it's pretty odd.
And and and we don't usually see screws getting pam this way either. So
I I think Barks kinda tried this out and then probably was like, yeah, this doesn't feel very excruciating that like. And and what he's doing at the beginning here is he's listing off the many different ways he makes money, the different industries he's involved in.
It's it's all the kind of usual
suspect oil wells, railroads, gold mines, Barks, factories, steam shifts,
and he's very content
talking about how he's made money at on just about every business there is on Earth
any kind of ponder
if there are any ways that he hasn't made money. And eventually, his his mood Do just a little bit because he's saying that
you know, his life is becoming Ducktales.
And so he wants he gets dressed he tends to go out
and see if there's anything new that he might have missed. Yeah. I love it. I I... He... He he's determined
to find a new venture, and he says at the top of the second page, I love the risk. I love that line. Yeah. I I really like this opening. I think this is really strong.
This is kind of a theme that Barks will return to a few times and it's very in keeping with the character. Right? It's not it's not just enough for Scrooge to be rich.
He wants to be good at being rich. He wants to master all the trades. He he likes the adventure.
Of it, basically.
And Al you mentioned the opening panel, which all the splash panels in this story are fantastic. Mh. So this shot, I remembered as a kid just absolutely loving it. The first one. And then I go back and I look at all of the paintings that he's done about money bins and all the Lit ramps that have come from those paintings.
Barks was absolutely
enamored with the the money being
story and and the the the the gimmick. And and again, trying new gigs
you know,
I love this almost as much as I, like, the diving like a purpose Yeah. Yeah such a good anchor for the character.
It
And
so when he ventures out, basically the next couple of sequences
are gonna be about his his efforts to find something new.
To invest in to get good at. And and this this gives Barks a really good
systematic way to move the story forward. You wanna tell us about his first attempt one? Oh, yeah. It's great. Because a little Cameo by Jai Gu here in his one wheel motor.
And he sees it and and he lights up and says that says Al lot for you a million dollars, your too late Scrooge
Auto factory bought for fifty bucks And then he said, aren't, you Scrooge Big duck. I thought that was an interesting twist on this little character that, you know, my old pal and aren't screwed to big Barks Yeah. This this a really funny exchange like
that this is gonna be one of those kind of running character beats and guides that Barks use a lot. Scrooge
being such
octopus that he's not even aware of of all the things.
That he's involved in.
You know, I just... I just did an episode about the ten page spending money where
where he famously, you know, just his unaware of all all of his personal businesses.
And then I...
Yeah. This is part of that right here. Right. And I like that we get
Gyro rose goofy
single wheel and car here because Barks loves this thing. Right? He... He's been pepper it in. The background
of different stories.
And I this is the first time you actually kind of, like highlights it, but but you see this in in all of these stories as just this random background guide. You do. That's a good point because I remember being it much smaller and just in a frame too. We get a good glimpse Al Gyro who came out what a few years earlier. Right? Right. And and this...
I was wondering if this little cameo is his first interaction with screw. I don't know. That's a good point. It might be so before going on to that
next
efforts to make money it's something new. I just gonna know I really like this guy Bark himself seems to really light this type of gag where someone
doesn't
recognize someone else. And I I love it. It's great. It works for me. Why don't you also tell us about the the next effort? Well, after he he says he'd like to get into something simple,
that he can run with his own hands and so he sees this peanuts.
Peanut
charming little, they think a peanut way would be a great way to
make some more money. I love the guy calls him short too bad short. I can't sell it. He doesn't know who's Scrooge just. And he says, well, it doesn't belong to me fridge mc dot owns and he all the Wagon in town and.
Says oh jeez. I it he offers him Al He storms off. Upset that the fact is lost his taste for peanuts now. So he's he's discouraged now he he he doesn't know what he doesn't own.
Right. And and those two instances are enough to to give us the reader the idea. And and next, he's gonna encounter his nephews.
And
they let him know that they are on the way to the desert. To look for Indian arrowhead.
I like screws reaction. Like no. And
and donald explains that they can sell the arrowhead for fifty cents of peace.
And
Scrooge sees the opportunity there, but he goes to verify something first. And he he calls his bookkeeper to see if he has any companies in that realm.
And I like that the bookkeeper is very gas and says that such a pun business would be beneath the dignity of a great billionaire like yourself. Right
So that settles it, you know, he's gonna join them.
And
this is a very Scrooge Inducks sorta of thing. Right? Like he's not his time would be much better used
quote unquote better
his time is incredibly valuable.
Spending hours to find these fifty cent arrow. Doesn't make sense
except in the fact except for the fact that it's just he's a excited about it. And it's something new and it's it's this adventure.
It's a new adventure way to make some money. Right in a way it's it's it's a little bit akin to his
you and looking for gold. I mean, it's it's is the adventure of finding the the item out there in the middle of nowhere. You know, And I like... I like his and Donald exchange for yeah. For fifty cents each I'd root arrowhead heads out of badger or holes with my bare nose and Donald tells him. Don't be so greedy. You may have to do it. That's right. And so
next we transition to the great
of the west that... Which are mysterious regions as Barks notes in his
his narrator box. And and we don't know, like, exactly
where they're going.
But we're we're gonna kinda have an idea that it's somewhere in the lake...
The really... What I consider the really gross part of California, right? We're looking at, like,
Outside of Riverside, once you get into the Desert areas,
D o,
we we see a sign that says thousand homes.
So we're starting out in the deserts of California. This is not really far.
From civilization. Right? And Barks hadn't really established
Duck.
We we kinda know that Inducks is is isn't in California like play. So this is very
very possible. Right? This is Al plausible day trip. And and so the Ducktales start to look four arrowhead heads. And and they talk about state Inducks that used to live in the area. They talked about how, you know, you can look where they're... Where the game was to fall.
Warren, when you were a kid, did you have any Indian arrowhead?
You know, that's a great question. I didn't, but my my my wife's
grandfather collected indian because
for many, many years at in his house before he passed, there was a huge frame with literally about forty arrowhead heads mounted in very beautifully
aligned, you know, by size, and he found all of those in
you know, in South Dakota, North D dakota and in the Nebraska, Kansas when he what he traveled.
Yeah. I I have, like, a an old Cigar box Al few of these. My grand grew up in
Oklahoma and Arkansas.
Right
and would find these as a kid. Like this is this is a real pursuit that people really did that
native Americans use these for thousands of years across
across the the area. So this this is like something you can actually do and they're their fewer
around to find, but... But this is definitely something real. And so the docs start to have some luck. I think for the reader, this is an exciting moment. Right? We see them finding these and and we enjoy it. Think the reader, Mark, I think for the reader, I also... This is the beginning of Barks history lesson here. He's really wanting to educate the reader a little bit through the so the humor and through the adventure of the story, I just loved the all of the references to where the game was plentiful and here's an had here and
they have fun with it, but I... That's what I love about this. It as a kid. I just ate it all up. Yeah. It's a good point because they talk about, like, the ambush hunting Yeah the that the onions would have done and how they have to look at places like box canyon and stuff. And as they begin to have some luck, we get this little off offhand reference.
To... Shouldn't they take a campaign of water with them? But but they don't intend to be very long, Donald says And so as they find a really good spot and start to find arrowhead and spear heads and Scrooge find some stone acts and bone beads.
He's very excited at his small scale fortunate in there.
Suddenly,
a dust
storm comes up, a desert sands storm as they as they call it. So warren, when you... When your travels took here to Arizona, did you get to experience any of these?
Only once. I can't remember what they called them.
There a name for that sudden sands store that kicks up. It's it's called a.
Yeah. And and I did. I was in one. And I was in a hotel room though. I was not out in the middle of the desert. It was quite ominous and I can imagine this is kind of like that. Yeah. I mean, this is a pretty good depiction
of of a sudden storm a hub,
I mean, they they never last as long as he's gonna show them later in the story. These these these are serious business.
So
the the dots are not able to get back to their car and and they they have to hold on to each other not to be separated.
We're blown away.
And and they quickly get lost. And this is the part of the story that takes this, like,
happens dance turn. That's pretty cool.
Where they they stumble
into this trail this groove in the ground. Yeah. The group's been there is definitely a established, and they use that as the trail to follow.
I love the exchange with the the Nephews.
Where is it taking us
to a soda pop scan no doubt wouldn't surprised if it did.
But they are absolutely
surprised when they
hit the the oasis right there. Right. And and,
you know, he mentions his desert polls. Those were not exactly native. A native speech but... But that's the okay.
The...
I we don't really see oasis
the way you do in other parts the world in the American Southwest.
But that that's alright. So the that's, you know, they have their water, and this is gonna be one of the overriding themes of the story, the importance of having water with you and boy, Al someone who lived there long enough to consider himself and native.
He gotta half water in the desert.
Yeah.
I always feel thirsty on behalf of the characters in this one. Well, this was at a time too when I was ten years old. I was a boy scout, and
and I always knew the importance of being prepared on those hike side to up in Northern Minnesota. So so
there's this neat little element here where the... They're able to get a good look when the storm
subside. I like how they can kinda look back and see the trail they followed.
And they figure out that it's this well attended old Indian trail that was worn
the with a groove that was worn down over thousands of years.
And as they follow the trail, they come across amount of rocks Mh. Way
there is a hidden bit of pottery.
And do you might tell us what happens with the potter?
One of the nephews picks up the pro, and it just breaks and outcome just these
these these jewels and and and screws just
looks at them ornaments of heavy gold,
and he just leaves on them as if he was in his money, Then he just says let me take a look at that stuff. An expert on gold. And so he
he goes right at it, and
he verifies that, yes, these are the real thing. This is the thousands of years old, Jewelry, and thanks to the nephew.
Found. Yeah. Yeah. And and so we get a little d tours, they go back to... We do see that they're actually an
Yes.
Right in in the background it identifies the India Gym society.
And they they asked a professor
to
identify where it would have come from.
And we a little bit of hand waving here
Right. This guy just knows that but that's okay. He's he's he's clearly Al authority. So he knows that it could have only come from one place and we get this neat little dramatic review. This is treasure from the original seven cities of symbol
And this is a... This is a favorite gag of Barks, Right? Where
Scrooge
you wanna read us the line that the Nephew says? Oh, said.
Have you got some ice water, professor, there's a cash register ringing in uncle Scrooge head
Right. And and
Scrooge being overcome by visions of a fortune is, of course, a class. Well, it it
is pupils, but every little expressive
flair out of him is a dollar sign, and that's again, he...
This is what he set out to do and he found this new fortune. So
Right. And and so we get this brief little history lesson for the benefit of readers,
where the Nephews talk about
the how those seven cities are the ones that explorers looked for for so long. The streets were said to be paid with gold
And then Donald chimes in that... That story was a fake. The seven cities were found to be poor mud pueblo.
And and this is true. Right? The the yeah actually Correct. Yeah. Yeah. So
I know that there was an x
an expedition
launched by
the Pad Barks,
who
there's a high school near where I lived in tempe Arizona that was Barks
high four
Okay. So he's he's I think he's famous as, like, the first European supposedly in in the territory of Arizona.
But
he
apparently corroborate the story
someone's
reporting about the seven cities, and he led
Who is the Con the that he led? Was it coronado?
Yeah. I think so. Yeah. He... He's the guy who led
from Francisco
from Francisco. Right? From Francisco day Coronado.
Right.
To to to mount and next expedition to find them and And when they got there, they were, like, deeply under overwhelmed to find though. It was like, these
poor,
like mud pueblo
that
were at the Z Pueblo
in in New Mexico.
Right.
So the So Box is doing this good job a kind of mixing fact and fiction, and he's got this professor here who is an authority. And he's able to chime in and say, oh, were they fake?
And he tells that the Never guided search to the real cities and that no white man has ever seen Cy ebola.
And and there is some sub opposition that the the very legend of them was basic like a native way of just getting them off their pack.
That's mh. But
but he he p ports to have some like artifacts that prove that they're real.
And and so the docks
they they sense that they have
they've got kinda of this in where they they have the best chance of finding the cities and that they can just follow that old indian trail. They do in it but it starts off with Uncle sk asking the professor, but where are they? And he says, hey, if I knew,
I go there myself. So there's still this mystery. You're right? And then they get... They had to go back to the trail to hopefully find at the end of that indian trail where they might find it. Yeah, it's interesting that the professor Ponder briefly in Spanish. Right? He said.
Can solve it? I knew I'd go there myself.
Yeah. Everyone while Barb does that. Mh.
So so the next sequence is pretty funny to me worn.
We're we're introducing the legal boys into the store. Do you wanna tell us about this? Well, as as screw and dot of the nephews go to the cafe to kinda
strategize their next step.
We see...
Again, this is a character chair drawing of Barks as friend who actually works for the Welfare apartment in Riverside.
It says it right there aid for the bo Riverside County Welfare, and he's kicking
the five boys out saying you bum were tired of you giving you relief checks and the the depiction of him is of his friend Al, who he strategize the story with. So what a nice little way to put them in there, But I just love... I love the way the big boys now are just sitting on the pavement outside the the County Welfare office, and they're complaining that there they are needy cases.
You're kicking us out here to starve where we're gonna go eat and they start falling and crying.
And I love this line. I have to read it. Since Barks put in burglar alarms, we've had a hard time making ends meet
So and tired of jail cooking. It's just classic. Yeah. I'm glad you highlighted that line. I like that. I love it. This is a very whining
n
version of the B boys. This is also
this is also one of Barks frequent, like, kind of poking at the Welfare state. Yeah. He he doesn't like it. No. It's evidence through the... Yeah. That's true. Right. And and he also does these frequent little gigs
kind of suggesting that criminal justice to system Ducktales
criminals like the b boys.
That definitely is evident here in this And, of course, but only... The only way that I kinda buy this is that we know who the bigger old boys are, They're they are taking advantage of the system. They are burglar there not good people
and so I'm okay with them getting kicked out, but I never thought of it as a commentary by Barks that's interesting.
Yeah. It's it's funny. And but it's just just definitely a little bit of Barks editorial.
Question.
You'll you'll see it later in in what's it called house of house of Hot? Is that what it's called? That late story where the b boys are cons.
Anyway, I do love... I've do love the artwork and done this in many stories who where at the end of that page, you see the big boys,
all with their hands on the shoulders walking off in line, we've seen that so many times. It's just whether they learned that in prison
or that's just how these these boys behave. I just love that Yeah. It does look kinda like a jail lineup up for something. That does love.
So the beagle boys, they're they're very conveniently here, and they're gonna stumble on the du in the diner.
And,
you know, they they've got their immediate assumptions Scrooge
is always into some kind of big rich business so they plan to
quote listen in on his diamonds studded words.
And so they over here their plans to set out and find the seven cities. There's a very fun couple of common
complimentary
panels at the end of this page worn
where the Inducks
toast to their adventure the next day.
And then the beagle boys is very, like, self satisfied
snugly also
toast to their Identical.
That's a it's a fun parents. So you see the b boys and and the ducks kinda go back and forth. Now, the next six sequences, you see them,
both on the same quest now
the big boys, however, are following the Ducktales and it's an interesting
trade off yeah. Exactly. That's exactly right. And and the the next couple of pages. They're not too
consequential.
It's really about it's really about the journey The it is... They are really interesting because there's some really cool
lovely desert scenery,
and
it's it's fun to see the beagle trail the Ducktales.
We get to see the Nephews bust out the junior guy... The Junior wood check guide book couple of times when they get a little bit s.
We we figured that that's the only way the docs are able to make it likely farther
we imagine that people have probably followed this trail before, I think But the guide book is what gives them yet. Right. And I go Scrooge acknowledges that and says that the boys of god is here through their their knowledge from the Junior wood chunks annual. And again, these two pages, as you said, really nothing much happens here, but a little bit more education.
And and we establish the the big boys following them from a great distance.
Right. And and it definitely makes it feel like a journey. Yeah.
And and we see the Ducktales ford the Colorado River. Mh So
we we can assume now that they've crossed this that's the state line, basically, they've crossed over into Arizona Al this point. Right?
And and once they make it across, they run out
of trail to follow.
Mh.
And and there some conversation about how, you know, some some big flood must have deposited
si. And so they... Barks make sure to highlight that they need to fill or
with water. And and when we pick up on the beagle
hours behind them,
tell us about that. They are coming to the Colorado.
They're aching,
hiking is worst torture than the prison Rock quarry. They really are ready to give up and head home. But then they they cross the river. And then one of the masks about filling their
and one of them says on w... Well, we don't have time for that. There'll be a spring ahead. Well, that comes back to haunt them. Right. And and they've had to rush Yeah. Has...
I think they had the rush because of the... Was it the storm. Right. A big dust storm. That's the which which is why they have to like, make.
It lasted two days, so they really wanna make a time on wisely did that filter their their.
Right. And I've never seen a dust storm last that long there. That. But, you know, I did... I did live in the well developed area.
So we
transitioned a part of the story where
everyone's having to really carefully rash in their water. Yeah. The beagle boys are they they haven't... They haven't been careful about Al storing theirs.
And so they they end up getting stuck in a dry rocky
being too weak to climb out. And they they they're in pretty bad straits.
And so
the Ducktales also get down to the point where they only have one more drink of water. And we see them deciding to rash it and preparing to cross a swell that being the shortest way to the amount. Right. Right.
And it's funny that Barks doesn't show us obviously, the Ducktales are about to collide with the beagle.
He keeps the the comics camera and
outside, and we just imagine
Al the narrator Barks ten seconds later which which which me I had to reread this a few times, Barks just so from a contact context standpoint, it looks like the big boys actually caught up to them and passed them up if they were already in the soil. Yeah. I I had to imagine that they've kind of
maybe been circling a little bit. They don't have the clean trail to follow now. But we had to bring them together at some point, and this was the vehicle to do that. Right. It's it's funny that the doctor only learned that the B boys are in this story, so many pages in.
So anyway, the the beagle do what we'd expect they steal the Ducktales water, and they decide that they're gonna head back. This has been too close to the call. For the... Yeah Yeah.
And Scrooge is optimistic because, you know, he thinks... Well, you know, Al least now we know it's only us that are on our way to the seven cities.
But Donald is more realistic about the fact that they are out of water and in grave danger.
And
we're we're about to hit this cool little x... Kind of an extra sequence almost.
Where the docs bump into this other sort of urban legend of the American
Southwest. You wanna tell us about Yeah. The the the this other Urban legend as you call it is this this lost ship in the desert,
which they discover
They think it's a mirage there and sure if they're looking at it or not, but they see an old Al, and it turns out to be very real. The
nephews look Al the the do to up man and verify that this is the law of the desert, which has been seen several times in the last four centuries.
Now the reality of this this table of this is actually about two hundred years later
than the actual story of the sub seven cities. But Barks to creative license and kinda blended the two stories to bring it a that adventure as I said earlier a little bit longer and a little bit more richer. So I do love this part where this this bolt just sitting out the ship sitting out there. And so they rush on board,
they go down into the galley and they see water cast, which, hard believe there'd be still water, but Yeah. That there's just a little bit in there. So they did get some water. I would not personally drink it but they do and it wet their whistles and
we've made the second biggest find in the desert they say next to the seven cities themselves. Yeah. You you said how much you like this. I really like this too. Right? Yes like it's almost like this this extra little mini adventure this extra
discovery that they weren't even looking for is is what saves them and route to the to the real price. Yeah. I like the romantic nature of but just this boat out there and there and they're... It just adds to the whole adventure story.
Yeah. It it does. And and as you say, this is a quote real
legend
and and it's easy to see why. Right? It's it's as you said, it's very romantic to imagine this
serious ship in the desert where you wouldn't expect it. Mh.
And and so they they investigate further and they find the ship's log book intact. And it explains that it is the story of of captain from francisco
Oo, who's sailed west from Lower
California in fifteen thirty nine. And was never seen again.
The Nephews note that fortunately, Scrooge can speak Spanish. Mh. Reed Spanish and and Barks
notes in a little caption that Oo is the commander of Cortez this fleet. Which is affected. I think he he inserted fact in there to bring some of that fiction in fact together to verify it. And as he said in one of is... I think it was in Thomas Andre Book.
No one's gonna check me on this. Right.
He he does that so well. He does
just
enough
research. To give it this, like, v
of
just enough. Of you're.
See. To make it totally work. And and the log book, it's it's a really great pi
explanation.
They... This was the last route where they were... The Expedition was looking for the seven cities.
And
the... On this last voyage, they were caught in a great tide, which swapped the ship up the river, forty weeks or more.
Where upon a great birth earthquake lifted the river and hurled its waters far east word. And and thus explaining how the ship came to rest where it was. And at the end of it,
Scrooge says, oh, but the best part is here
where it says that they looked over the bow and saw a great host of onions coming from a clef in the cliffs
who are dressed in gold. Yeah.
That ominous
was the last entry in the book
They figure they must have been Inducks from Zavala. Yeah. It all now pulls. It all comes together with these two legends. Right. And and this is just he's creating this out of whole cloth, but the way he's stitched it all together, just if it's such a great progression, and it feels
so believable, and it's it's been about, I guess, twenty pages or so, roughly.
Is until we get to this this
the methodology or this wonderful lawyer and this story really unfolding now. Yeah. Yeah. And and like, that's not that much time. But it... The journey is felt pretty ar. He's done a good job of making this feel like Al feel like a big journey.
So Tell us about
What the nephew you sees warren? Well, first of all, the nephew is up on the the mask and and looks forward. It says the clef he saw must be that one and the right in line with the ship is this
clef in the in the hills
and so they all come...
On Scrooge urges them to run toward their they're just thrilled. They go up this little narrow path, and it... It's a very much reminds me of the ne path that Indiana Jones would go. Right? It's just an into into the into this And and there's this, again, another
incredible for me memorable splash panel.
When you see all the seven cities of Ebola,
in their own little area and all Scrooge can say is well, doesn't that take the cake, I love it. I just, like, get there in awe and that's what he says. What do you think of this panel? Mark? Oh, yeah. This is like, one of the all time memorable splash panels.
As you say, it's great it's icon. The du,
just are in awe of it. I think the reader
is to. It's it's
very striking. And his artwork he he depicts each of the cities
in their own little area
with the colored rock being different, so you can actually count the seven cities here to verify that this is what they finally found. Right. And it's interesting that it's seven cities
altogether. Right? Because because there it it really is one big community, but but they are delineate in a way that I'm sure everyone who reads this the first time counts them. I don't wanna you wanna see that there are there are actually seven of them. And and their styles
they're
after, like, the the quick cliff dwelling.
Yes. That
tribe
did. Right? And and this was something that Barks model at after his beloved National
geographic, there was a feature
called the ancient Cliff dwelling dwell of Mesa Their.
And and so this is this is what what Barks used. For the actual cities themselves, and I... It's kinda neat. Right? It it it leaves in that little factual element that they were just these quote mud pueblo But when they get in there, it it really is very rich. And it's this very
striking. There these
there are these pillars
supporting the clips Yes. That
are
really in pose. Now don't don't think too too hard about the mechanics of this city. Because then then it does fall apart.
But for a comic book adventure story, it's it's very gross. And to know that these are the first people to actually discover these after thousands of years is is another
probably unbelievable event, but it's it's great to see them all look up and awe. And and just realize that they've made it right. And and so Scrooge kinda recap the story for us helpful here. He says the seven cities of Si, and we found them because we were curious about an old Indian trail.
Do you wanna tell us about some of the sites they find weren't? Yeah. I think they...
They they looked down at the the bricks
the nephew say, it looks like yellow bricks, and
Scrooge immediately knows that those are gold bricks. They look at baskets,
woven out of gold, of gold nuggets
and and sister in full of op and South fires
and jewels beyond anyone's imagination.
They look. Everything is here that
solid ruby Arrowhead
Barks really likes this. There's only a handful of stories I guess, but but I think there's some it was most memorable.
Right? Like, when they when they get down into the minds of king solomon,
he really takes pains. He he likes to depict all these different forms of riches. And oh yeah. The different types of riches that are out there the jewels, the gold, that the... The the... Yeah. Right. And and while the docks are basking and all this,
all this treasure, the beagle have decided that they're gonna
they they feel emboldened by their one drink of water so they decide I don't know. Maybe they made it back and and tanked up somewhere else, but they decide to go back and finish the job and and they're able to pick up on the Duff trail pretty easily. And then we see
this
idle. Tell us tell us more about the idle. Well, the idle but when you see it when I read it as a as a young boy,
it's stood out as sort of the find of the year here for for
Scrooge.
He calls it the single most valuable object in the whole world and
nephews, of course, no. It's a baby trap and don't touch it. But this is Pure Emerald. It's sitting up there on
the the perch
and it's definitely brake up to a b trap, which then is easily explained in the next few panels in this great artwork
of this immense boulder
and the boulder is perched upon this thin column of bricks and stone
and they realized that yep you were to take that idle, it would vary the seven cities here. And now we're temp up on that scene which is we talked about earlier from
routers of the lost arc. Yeah. It's a it's it's a doom state device, basically. It is. It is. This will destroy it and... Yeah.
The the idle itself. It's supposed to be this Giant Emerald that it does not look very, like, place accurate
to me. I don't I don't know Southwest
art that well, but I... But I I spent enough time there to be like, yeah, that doesn't look very very originally accurate. This it looks kind of generic.
Oh, okay. It's nothing yeah. Deck or. Yeah. I I don't know. It it... Yeah. It kinda looks Al tech in a way that it shouldn't.
Right. So so this is a trope
that
appears in a ton of these kind of adventure things. Right? An ancient
civilization
has like, this Doom day device that
and we know it's it's like it's like check gone. Right.
We know that it's... The audience
wants to see it happen.
We know that this almost always happens. It's very exciting. It's very interesting.
But, like, as I get older, I can't help but think how the mechanics of such a thing like falls apart. Right? Who who leaves something intact like that? Long enough for their civilization to just disappear how does this boulder
stay in place over thousands of years
I'll tell you if if the United States have like a button
that was designed to ob obliterate us
that was this
accessible
I don't think we go more than forty eight hours. For some
just like frantically push the button. So.
You're right. You're right. But it is a... It is a fun control. We've seen it time and time again in the adventure movies and in these comics where they they they rig this up And especially the the... What you just mentioned, which really hit me at home was the bag up with thousands of years. The earth didn't settle enough to knock it hold on a little bit. Right. It it falls apart under a little bit of consideration, but but it definitely works in that, like, sort of comic book realm.
Just just one little sour note for me though. But
they yeah, like, it... The boulder
itself is of course, very much the the Indiana Jones
boulder, but but also this kind of pressure plate. Right? I... Now I...
As soon as I see this idle, I think through Throw me the idle. I'll throw you the width. Pretty exactly yes.
Alright. So the doc
just like they... So the Ducktales do give the idle some wide birth. They... They're smart enough to be like, okay. Don't mess with that.
They they continue to explore this. And and just like they discovered this
ships log of kind of the last days of the voyage. They discover this picture riding on the wall.
That also
explains what happened.
And it says that, you know, they use their guide book of course. And it it says that with with that a great sickness came with the white men on the big canoe. On the people fell ill and all went to the happy Hunting round,
and that the that wrote this was the last to go. Mh. That's a pretty sobering thing to include. Right? And it it really is and on and Dials reaction is is is actually quite nice. It's the poor guys, all their gold and jewels couldn't buy their good health back. I mean that's a really nice little lesson
I think that Barks put in there. Right. And
and I mean, this is, like, this is what happens too much the the arrival of the Huey, the doors and and the
and the European settlers was was a form of apocalypse
for the native
population. Absolutely.
And and small Barks wiped out and all these settle many of these settlements and villages.
So
so that definitely rings sadly true. And the debts keep looking and they kind of ponder what happened to those home keys to doors, one of the nephews is like, oh, we haven't seen their arm or what came of it. Mh. And how me get this little
little scare beat
yeah, kind of a ghostly
almost a ghostly
visit if you will, where, you know, the nephew sets it up with where what happened to the armor, and all of a sudden, we see these shadows these omni shadows and the clan of them. Yeah. They they are right away. I don't think really realized where they are in that last panel. Right. And and, you know, we learned pretty quickly that it's the b boys. They've found this armor and they've put it on as a Barks
And and we have this... Now we get this confrontation where the B boys
say that they want all of this fantastic wealth. And
it's pretty g what they do. Right? They
tell us about what they do. So, the they all... They they do
throw all of the Inducks into they're... They say they're going to jail them and they break up a wall to for them if you will. They're they're they're sealed in in a wall behind
bricks in right. And, you know, the the beagle are so goofy in this. But but Severino once while they Yeah. Are very men. This is a medicine scene
You know, Scrooge offers the a trillion dollars to let them go
That'll be chicken feed compared to what we're gonna take out of here. You know?
So
now what I find interesting on this is that they they take off the armor
and they begin diving into the money just like Scrooge dives and right another story. I think the big boys they tried to do this and that was Scrooge attempt to stop them because they hit the... They hit the money and they they backed. Right. Well, that's classically his
his means of stopping them and only a world old man. That's right. And it's... But it's not from quite that same height at least that's true. But they think I the money. Yeah know. Yeah. So this this wraps up pretty predictably here. Right. The the Ducktales were smart enough to leave that idle alone. But as the beatles are re and all this wealth around them, a couple of them spot it and
and they start to sc with it arguing over, who can have it in in who's mansion.
And and they trigger
the the doom day
device than the the
Have left behind. I tell you if I was an average citizen of
And
my leaders
said alright people, we have a grand plan
to
to create a Doom day device. If anyone jo this one idle,
we're. And we're we're all gone, everything is gonna be destroyed. I would not vote for that person to the you again. Right.
So it's that's a a pretty scary proposition for the for a society too.
Something.
Yeah. It doesn't make sense. It's true. The moment we see that boulder
at the beginning and these pillars and we see the mechanics of of how it's gonna happen. We want
to see it
and and it's pretty spectacular as ko as it can be on the on the page.
Right? For something that got so much motion.
The way the boulder does what it does. And and the city
collapse is pretty
spectacularly.
With our Inducks
sealed nicely. Yeah the wall. They are able to
know what's going on and Scrooge looks out. And says he'll never see his bill of money again. Yeah. And and the beagle are trapped,
everyone gets buried, and and everyone should be should be killed Yeah. But but another instance of of cartoon logic. Boy, it's a it's a pretty big
instance of cartoon logic.
Yeah. They Al escape. Mh.
Yeah. So everyone eventually
eventually
emerges.
From from Beneath the rubble. And you wanna tell us about what's happened to every character warren. Yeah. I I found this to be... I I I gave you village and comic book logic and just
substantial humor and everything. But here every
member that was in there, the Ducktales and the big boys all emerge safely
from this wreckage
with amnesia. They all have bumps on their head and they can
remember
why they're there. And I thought like, okay, what a great way to wrap this story and keep the mystery of the seven cities alive. And I thought that was in a way brilliant in a way like, oh, come on.
I'm much How did you take that? It's it's definitely a bit of a cop out and yeah. You know, knowing that just an Al as of a couple of issues ago, he was still
two issues ago, Secret of Atlanta was the last thirty two pager. Yeah. And and I've I've can't help but wonder. Okay. Well, if if we had four more pages,
would he have wrapped this up a little bit more satisfying?
It... It's a fun little
camper of a gag. Right? He's guy amnesia. So the only thing that he remembers
screwed remembers his arrowhead Hunting.
Yeah. And the pads. That word is pocket. Yeah. Right. Right. Four arrowhead that he lost in his pocket, but it's not worth digging through that pile of rubble for two bucks. Of course, the reader knows that there's a countless
billions of dollars under there. Yeah But
those four extra pages would've have brought. I I gotta believe it would have been a little bit more grand. Yeah. And and I mean he's able to do some great storytelling
in a lot of different lengths sure. So maybe maybe this is just how he did want to end the story.
Al amnesia like a common trope. He doesn't go to that well very often. And he doesn't... It's kinda of the edge sketch. Right? How do you get everything kinda back to normal? Yeah. I mean, we don't see the Ducktales. They obviously have a lot of deserts to make it
back across.
But...
But but the story ends very much back to status quo. And So I I think the ending. I think he really wanted to do what he did and have that spectacular
destruction
of.
I think he wanted to take the dots on this cool
journey.
And and then when the story ended, he was pretty much done. So,
you know, his energy, he really investors his energy
in the places that you wanted to in this sure. The the travels,
the big boys following the doug, the discovery of the ship
all the trials of of finding water and staying hydrated and everything.
And and he maybe he got tired and all... He he finally saw this thing come to this incredibly grand ending
where the cities were buried,
and this is how you wraps up. I I I I read it for the first time yesterday, in a long time, and I didn't remember the ending. And when I read I went, oh, well, that's convenient.
But it works in the comedy world, if it works to bring that mystery keep the mystery alive if you will and keep the legend the alive. They'll never know again because there was never any reference to the seven cities of
Because they were only hunting Arrowhead in the big boys. I don't know. That was the biggest stretch for me. At least Inducks were already in the desert or part of the desert the biggest is we're just thrown out of the welfare office, and now they're sitting on a pile of rubble in Arizona. So I I don't know how they just that.
Yeah. There's there's a lot of hand waving at the end of the story. So I I would say that's my only real criticism of this one. I otherwise think that this is maybe not an all time great, but, like a very strong, you know, second tier Barks
Scrooge adventure.
What what are your overall thoughts on this. Or yeah. I would agree with that that assessment, not at all time grade. But when it was paired with luck of the north and that that best of series back in the from sixty four to sixty seven when he did three three, gold three of those. Where they pair these stories that were similar
adventure stories. It worked so well there because it was the first time I read it. Which stood out for me again was this this screws
absolute
forward more treasure
and and and the great track that he went on to get it. Everything from that first splash panel of him and the money been to that last flash panel of the rack just circulating and destroying everything.
Those are the memories I have of this story. And that's why I have a fun recollection of it. Upon reading it again,
again, I put it in that you do describe it as the second tier. I think that's where it belongs.
So, yeah.
Great artwork work. Again, beautiful storytelling, he kinda misses fact in fiction to do it to make it the Barks reality. And I think that it works. Yeah.
Second here kind of as an overall story, but it might be a top tier
story as far as the, like, treasure hunting.
Storage.
That vein, yes. And the fact that this is Scrooge is first time out
makes it very special. Yeah. So I I like this one. I think it's a great story. It doesn't have kind of the, like, wait and and impact of some of the earlier screwed ones that are, like more
interested
in some of those deeper things, like like poor man and Dyke, but... But it's just a great solid adventure
Again, all of the different little twists and terms
that it takes... They feel very earned
to me. And and that mix of real
history and legends
and Barks
creation is just so nicely balanced and everything is so nicely integrated. I love it. You get you get this great setup up it feels very true to sc, how he wants to try new fields to make money.
You get this fun little gyro gear loose
cameo, you get... You hit the the sn w version of the beagle boys that that are very funny. I I like this one. It's it's a nostalgic favorite for me. One thing I noticed and and see if you agree, there was that one or two panels where the narrative, it is on page twenty where the ship is seen in the flood. It's a flash right of the earthquake for lands I think had there been more pages and had he given that. He may have introduced the more flash sequences lenses of the citizens of Si of maybe some of the... What they were doing. That might have been kind of a nice addition to the story. I was hoping for a little more of that. I see it here. Where the ship settles and then we go right back to reading the the lock book, but
that's only one little minor this decision for me is I would have liked to have seen more of that flash to really set it up a little bit more Yeah. I would that would have been cool to see. I think I would have liked to have spent a little bit more time in.
Itself. Mh. I think you right of a flash in.
Could have been really interesting. But
See that with the cave wall paintings
that they they look at and it would been interesting to maybe see what the you know, and he's done this with others where he think he goes back in time to show that the
how the culture evolved. Yeah. Yeah. So so let's check in with how
how the community feels about this one. I I think I it's pretty much in line with how you and I have been just describing it. Right? If you look on Inducks, which, of course is the community site where anyone can vote on these stories and and it has lots of great facts and material about them.
It gets a seven point eight out of ten
which is good as of right now as of today. It's it's barely in the top one hundred. It is number one hundred
right now at this moment.
Alright. That's a very strong ranking. When you consider that there are, like, forty two thousand stories
voted
by that fans have voted on
on index. And
I feel like it's
I feel
like it's a pretty accurate ranking. I'll say that I think that it is one of the... For me, if I think about those first ten issues of Scrooge,
Mh.
Which is just kinda useful. It's a nice round number. Right? And there's like,
there's like,
four
stand
that are
one, two, three and six. Yes.
Pearl man
Dyke
horse rad story
t Al.
And and then Secret of Lan
is again, it's more of a pure adventure story. It doesn't have the like. The them asymptomatic kind of maturity that those other
three do. Those that those other four you. Yeah. But it's just such a great adventure that those are kind of the the those five stories. Are the best of that run. This great run that he has.
Yeah. He was really
in his stride there Yeah. And And so, like but to me, this one is probably
apart from the secret of.
This is the best of the just like adventure stories. Yes. In that first run. And again, there's no reason to consider the first ten stories other than the... They are the first ten stories. Right.
But... But I I like this one. I might even rank it a little bit higher, like, I think
le with the locket
and
fabulous philosopher Gladstone,
I think they might be ranked higher than this one is Inducks. And And for me, this one works better. This one hits
this one hits better. I like this one better than mysterious stone right for sure. Which I think is also ranked quite a bit higher. Okay? Well, again, the three... The three reasons I like this story, I grew up with it. It was in the first common I bought. It was paired with my favorite story like of the north.
Number two, the splash panels in just embedded in my memory. And and and just I love
the storytelling technique and the the fact that this was Al adventure. And then later, my third reason is that it inspired George Lucas and Steven Spielberg.
Two of my favorite phone filmmakers and great story tellers in their own right. To
to continue on with that and back the they, they saw Barks as a wonderful story and Al inspiration.
Says a whole lot about about Carl Barks. Yeah. Well.
I think
I think this clearly
inspired. A lot of people who came out with some pretty great stuff.
So as far as other media goes,
one, do you
own
this lit itself? I do. I do. It's
it's good. I wouldn't call it great because it's a... You have a picture of it, Are you looking at it? Yeah I'm not right now, but I'm I'm know well familiar with this. Yeah. It I I I think I would liked to seen more of the adventure
in the little
This one features them, I think, with the idle, if I'm not mistaken,
and it it it kinda sets it up, but they're all very happy to
see the treasures of si. But yes, I have that one. It's it's a beautiful one. The colors are incredible. Yeah. I really like this one. I I
This one always struck me. So...
Yeah. I and as far as I know, this is not one that have had... This story doesn't have any big sequel.
And then I don't believe that it was ever adapted into a Ducktales story. I was gonna
it is kind of, you know, reminiscent to me of the pilot
episodes where Scrooge is looking for some golden cities.
So I think they might have kind of adapted the spirit of this story,
but I don't think they're like... I don't think they ever specifically call out seven cities and
or anything.
What I found interesting was that this story came out in nineteen fifty four. Correct? And then I? Yeah. The nineteen fifty five out of Hollywood came
adventure film called the seven cities of gold and then in nineteen fifty eight, just a few years later, there was the classic Clayton moore gold... Loan ranger
in the city of gold. Again, all based on this this
story of of the seven cities of Yeah. This this legend really does cast long shadow. Excellent. I think we've covered it pretty well. And. Are there any favorite panels that you'd would like to highlight?
Well I'm gonna go back to the the... What I called the three big splash panels. The first one and the money Bin, which just to me is just makes me smile and I love money been opening shots. You mentioned that it brings the new readers back into who uncle Scrooge is,
and those the first when they see
and when the boulder hits. Those are my favorite big splash panels, but I I think some of the other panels that just I just can't get enough of our with the big boys when they're thrown out of the welfare for office.
And when they when they all march off together in in defeat,
with their arms on their shoulders. And then when they appear as they case the doors and surprise Scrooge, I just love that. Yeah. You listed some good ones there. The
almost required by law to mention those great splash panels. Yeah.
As far as others,
I I did like
the panel
of the ship.
In the flash.
Yes. I mean, all of the panels of the ship, but especially the flood, it it feels like it should have been a splash panel. Oh, yeah. It could it easily been. And, again, that's why I wanted more more of that backstory because it would just so romantic and it's per trail and just so adventurous. Yeah. And and honestly, like, the the Ducktales whole journey,
just feels very very impactful and very cool.
You mentioned those beagle boys at the beginning. Those are all very funny panels. I mean, this one's full of very nice panels in general.
I do like when when Scrooge is re recoil,
at
the peanut guy telling him that this
this peanut wagon already belongs to you to you. Yeah. Yeah.
And of course, this the scene the the short scene with Jay Is,
you know, asking him... Are you Scrooge I your prescription back I made to on, you know? My old hotel doesn't recognize me. And then I I was wondering if the big boys ever wore those outfits again. I don't recall the white shirt and the blue pants. I don't know if that's the original color. I do have... I do have Scrooge number seven the dell. So I'm gonna go take a look at the color reference. It's probably pretty accurate.
Yeah. I think I think they're still sporting that in the next
I mean this a good segue
to
telling listeners to please join us for for the next episode when we get to cover the mysterious stone ray. Mh.
I think that they're still dressed like that in this one in that one, but
but I'm not gonna fact check it.
So,
yeah, Any any closing thoughts one? Just a just a fun adventure story. Knowing that that that... I think Carl Barks probably felt that now into his seventh
issue
of of Scrooge title he was hitting his stride with really fully developing Scrooge into an adventure a treasure hunter.
Now he could do anything. And I think this is really setting up Scrooge for the reader who
I was reading in one of the essay sa that I read online that
a come from a reader just said Scrooge is my favorite superhero. I thought that pretty cool because liquid doing it is age and he's doing this stuff with, you know, all all this action.
So I thought that was a pretty cool complement to Pay Barks and to pay on Scrooge. Yeah. Barks is really showing a lot of confidence
at this point. Excellent. Alright. Well,
listeners feel free to reach out on
the socials. You know, we've got Barks remarks on Facebook and Instagram.
And warren,
if you don't mind, I've been closing out recent
those by asking guests to just read whatever
is in the last panel. Alright. So the last panel of the seven cities of.
Screws walks off and says, well, let them go. I'm too tired to dig back under that pile of rubble for two bucks. Awesome. Thanks so much, Warren. This is a lot of fun. Thank you, Mark.