We can have
Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer an artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comments of all time. Join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks. Welcome back to Barks remarks, I'm Barks Sever a Grown man who enjoys Inducks con and I'm joined by a returning guest host sad, why don't you introduce yourself? Yeah. I'm thank mer.
I am a long time Ducktales,
specifically of Carl Barks.
I've done a lot of commentary for the Fan graphics collections, and I've also done a lot of localization work for the various
new publications of international stories.
Very cool. Yeah. I I really enjoy having people on who've got some of the behind the scenes. It experience.
You know, you get to see kinda how the sausage is made. That must be interesting. Yeah. It can be.
Sometimes it's very
eliminating
how these things are made or... How they're not made in some cases.
And you know, I guess that's appropriate too because the the story that we're gonna be talking about today, which is of course, the mysterious
stone ray. Definitely had some like behind the scenes not drama. None of it's, like too exciting, but but rarely
for a Karl Barks comment. We kinda get to see
some of the, like,
revisions and rev
in how he made this one? Yes. It's fast naming that all that survived
because so much from the period is long gone. And it sort of says to me that Barks
wasn't really sure of how this story should go. And I'm not sure if we see much of that in the final project, but it's very eliminating seeing those alternate
pay that do survive Right. And and what we're referring to, of course is that there is this, like, surviving or that ultimately didn't make it into the story.
It's it's nearly
complete. Right? Like, it's it's drawn, but not fully or something is my understanding? A couple of them are ink. I'm looking at it right now, the Fan Graphics collect right now. It looks like there's at least a page worth that's inked
and the other is cancelled
and I'm gonna read what Barks said
yeah. You don't mind.
He said Barks said do, Bruce Hamilton, Jeffrey Bloom and tom. Andre in nineteen eighty four, he said, I cut panels to shorten business, which was getting tire assembly overs stage.
And it says he may have been planning this as a thirty two page story and got a word part way through that he had to cut it to twenty eight pages.
May have been a bit of both, but you can... As they say, you can see Barks storytelling sense Al work. Yeah. It's it's almost like you got to see his notes. Or or thought process or something for this one. Right? Because he he he did a lot of work that ultimately he left out, and it's not like back to the
where they could go back in and put it in later because it's... He reworked the story. It's not. Yeah. It's it's it I would I would definitely go towards Barks as and explanation that he thought he was overs staging it. I would definitely... I I would I don't think he got that, you know, the hammer came down from the western office
in this case betty he had to cut stuff, but he was just doing it himself. He was doing self editing Right. Yeah. This seems like him a case of him just just trying to be disciplined about how again, as you said, how he stages it. And and I like... I like how the the more recent printing have chosen
to just kinda tag along the extra panels. You know, they're not trying to show.
No. No. That's the way... And that's the way it should be because there's no way to incorporate it
just like with the trick treat. They print that all... They print it ultimately. They either run Barks. They run Barks as are intended edition. And in the back they'll run the sense the sensor version or the Al. Be the published version.
So it's it would be. Right. It's it's a nice way of kinda having your cake and eating it too. Mh. It works out pretty well. Mh. So let's see. So the mysterious stone ray, we you and I were talking beforehand,
Right. And and I I mentioned
that, you know, this is not really one of my favorite marks stories.
But but you are a pretty big fan of this one. I am I've I've always liked this one. I've
I first read it... There was
many years ago with my father on. I was a kid. There was a comic books in Toronto,
called dragon lady Comics, and they basically had a gold mine for me, like,
maybe circuit age thirteen or fourteen, but, like, they had, like, the whole Gladstone and Disney comics run and they're long boxes in the back of the store, you know, for sale. And, yeah, this one I picked up
and the
the eighties lights don't reprint. That's where I first read it and it old files Scrooge two twenty two I yep. Yeah. With that beautiful
cover Yeah if yeah. And...
No. It just stuck out to me.
I kind of go against the grain. I know you said you were excited about the early uncle Scrooge you getting into. And I can see the excitement for those.
But I'm general... I generally go against the worldwide grain and think that the uncle Scrooge stories generally aren't Carl Barks as best work. I do think that the first three stories
that he did
and when it was just a four color, and it wasn't the ongoing Scrooge series. I think those are un past.
Right. I I would I would rank those and if if I top three, it would be in that order because they have an energy that none of the other stories matched
and
I can sort of see why this one would be un memorable
and the earliest stories because this one doesn't have a lot of the spectacle
doesn't have a lot of the Grand here, you know, the the fantastic settings like
the seven cities or T
or glen
and
it doesn't dig deep into screws lower. Like those first three stories did. But
I always like this one. I think you I always I always like it because it's very creepy. It's a very creepy story. It doesn't start off normally, like one does, I mean, I mean, the beagle boys are initially not the the main villain of the story. They're petrified. They're trapped on the island. Petrified and in a in both cents I guess. Exactly.
Exactly.
And I don't know I I I would definitely rate it above the
whatever It got chris and Hawaiian holiday or whatever it is. Oh
honey mystery? Yeah. Man mystery. Yeah. That one always just
I was kinda... It struck me as a mis fire when I read it as a kid. I I might have to re reread it again, but That one's pretty divisive. I'm I'm finding. I do like, some some people love it, and some people really if not hate it, they I did probably agree with you that it's a miss fine. I sure don't hate it, but it's... The the big boys are truly the terrible, terrible big boys I'm that one. Yeah. That not maybe what what I like about it. I kinda like the degradation
in that one Oh boy. But the Inducks have to to overcome. But but... Yeah, it's interesting to think about these this first
collection. The the first... I don't know the ten first ten or so screwed story is it's it's a random number, but it's a round number, so it's easy to kinda think of them together. And as you say those first handful are like unmatched setting up screws lower. They have some really deep themes and then even even up to, like, trial a lot, you know, is
kind of along those lines. And then that, like, second.
Of ten. We're we're just we're kind of getting into good
solid
adventure stories. Well, it's
it's funny. The first ten is
that that's the cutoff off point the after the first ten Scrooge issues, that's when the letter changes, and that's when generally,
I agree. It's it's the general consensus
that's when Barks started selecting. Glen his wife took over the lettering. Well, I mean, it... It's it's, I think probably just a matter of consists and see. Right? You got some... You get some really stand out classics Sure course. But you also get these big, like,
swings, these peaks and trough. But Right But Barks being Barks. There's... I think always something to like really appreciate. Oh, of gosh. And and again, this one, I I do enjoy this. I just I don't love it, and I think I really I came into it really wanting to love it for a few reasons that we'll get into sure. So what that's kinda... I think the dynamic that we've got going into this podcast. Right? And that be fun explore little little bit of background.
We we've mentioned that this is an early uncle Scrooge
specifically we're uncle
number eight.
This one is a bit of a shorter
story, where I guess it's it's kind of like what is gonna end up being the average length of his adventures.
Right. I recently recorded an un
an for secret of Al, which I I realized was his very last full length thirty two pager.
So it's it's interesting to think that going forward this twenty four pages is kind of the norm.
This one was released cover date was December of fifty four. I I would say this one doesn't have... It... It hasn't been reprinted. As often as many of the early uncle Scrooge adventures. It's it's only at eight in the Us counting the original print
So it feels a little bit under
exposed. And
like a bunch of his stories, right? You mentioned
that
Hawaiian hide away was kind of the working title for a while for what fans eventually landed at being the men who miss history. Some of these very early
stories. For one reason or another Western did not run them with a title. So there's this cool bit of correspondence
between Barks and a family named Malcolm Will. Mh. Where he asked him to suggest some titles for this one. And the
title that I originally read this under, I guess you did too
was message from ast mysterious islands.
Mh. That... And that's what Bark had suggested.
But eventually, we landed at the mysterious Stone. Right? What do you like better?
I like mysterious Stone Ray. I I think that's okay.
You know, it's just funny is that as
so many of these were printed without a title. So it's honestly,
I could just generally go by what Barks officially settled on. Yeah. I mean, I I kinda like that they hide,
you know, that that little element of the story. I guess you get it in the cover if you're looking at the One. But just like Hawaiian hide way, I I actually preferred that one I think message from the mysterious Island does a good job of bearing the lead
a little bit. Let's see. You did a nice job already about talking
about the the
revisions that he made just a little bit of kinda of random trivia.
You you mentioned the b boy. This is a very big heavy
story. And I do think that's a thing to to appreciate about this one. Right? Oh, yes. Oh, yes. Yes. The b boys they're becoming
very more defined
and there's an important character trade introduced in the story but I I think we'll save that for when we actually get it. Because I think everyone who knows this knows these stories knows what we're talking about. And so I don't... I don't wanna spoil it ahead of time. Sure. That sounds good to me. Yeah. Let's save right for when it shows up. So before we get into the story, I'm gonna briefly hand to some of our international listeners
by noting some of the titles from around the world.
And and, you know, that these aren't too remarkable they're kinda what you'd would expect. But just a couple of them are fun.
Denmark, we have Uncle Y kim Ogden Garlic professor,
which is screws in the man profess sir. Oh, boy Let's see. Italy has a pretty conventional theo pepperoni
del
which is uncle Scrooge and the Cabbage Islands.
Oh, Got one. Oh yeah.
I'd might prefer that the Barks this title. Sure. Yeah. There's something for that. And then we've found kind of a Da one from Germany,
d or dump.
That's one of those, like German words where it's one word, and it translates to the Cabbage
steam island. Mh So I like... I like how they manage that.
Alright. So So let's do it then. Let's let's launch into this story.
I'm gonna... I'm gonna summarize each page, we're not gonna cover everything every every gruesome some detail, but
we're gonna highlight stuff that we find
interesting and and notable.
And so so the mysterious stone ray opens
in
kind of a unique manner. Right? We've got... We've got this little subversion where Scrooge is doing his typical
pursuit. He's diving through the money and has bin but you can tell that his heart is just not in it. Mh. You know. He's he's talking about
He's naming his fortune that. This is one of those...
I'm gonna I'm gonna start to track these because this is... I think, second example
where he labels his fortune.
And in Min
history, he gave Donald
described it as being this pretty round number, but here he calls it five billion quadruple till on two and Al
fantastic
and
Tilt san
billion dollars and sixteen cents.
Of course. We've always got the sixteen cents. Mh
But he's just kind of one about it. He's very, like, half hearted and he's talking about how the side of his vast fortune doesn't share him up I get used to. And so by by the end of the first page, he's already resolved that he needs to go see a doctor
to figure out what is wrong. So, yes. It's a very good hook. You know, It captures the reader. You know, he's doing his usual money swim routine, but, you know, he's very lack of day about it. And we want as a reader wanna know well, what's causing screws this? Yeah. It's definitely
intriguing.
And on the next page we transition very quickly
into the doctor's office.
This doctor is not one of the quack
that Barks
sometimes poor.
Right? Mh. We don't have any, like, goofy site gag about him being being class. And and screws is explaining that he feels tired and heavy at times.
Something that we can relate to. Right? Of course. This a universal
kind of feeling and and probably, you know, what we're meant to think of screws is an old man. Too. Mh.
And and and again, very quick pacing here. The doctor
immediately looks at him with the magnifying glass
uses me. And and he
explains no wonder. Your skin is the full of gold dust.
And any... He goes on to explain that it's actually clogged his pores.
He's not getting any event ventilation and And this is this is gonna be a good one of the better gag
of the story, right? Is someone
expressing
surprise and how how on Earth could this happen to you? Do you like roll and money? Yeah. It's... Yes It's someone's actually calling this out like, I...
What are you insane? Are you are you just rolling around and and gold and Scrooge, of course, is you know, what it... What is this daily routine is getting embarrassed by by being called out on it. And I've gotta say too that This shows how much more
Barks respected is audience
because you would not see something like this than one of the other
Western comic books. By the other authors and Kurt
because skin ventilation,
that's not a topic that
I can't think of a single other story. Yeah. You you can definitely tell that he like really thought about this hook and how to make this element were.
And and so the doctor, you know, gives him a remedy, he tells him that he needs to go to get ras, basically somewhere windy
where, you know, it can just kind of brush the gold out and stop plugging his pores. And And so Scrooge kinda resolves in his mind that the the compromise is to take a few minutes Al the beach
and who let him air himself out And and that, I really enjoy this goofy panel of him kinda holding open his broad cloth and just
getting
getting some breeze. It's silly. It's it's... It looks very pleasant. Mh.
Yes. And this is a the dilemma we've all faced. I think those of us... Those of us in the working world. We
kind of
sometimes sacrifice our health and well being for the sake of work.
And it actually makes Scrooge a little sympathetic
until he turns it around. It says, oh, I would take a sea voyage if I could see some way of making a little money on the trip. Say, okay. Now you're back to mick doc and
not not quite as that is, you worked just a panel or two ago. Right. Because he's gonna constantly be scheming how to make or save money on on the ultimate voyage. Mh. And and again, it's a shorter story
so we're already into the third page. He's He's moving it along. Scrooge sees his nephews doing some beach coming, and I old fashion
pursuit. And Huey, dewey and, Louie. And you know, I think it's interesting that he's got them there without Donald. Right? We don't
necessarily see that too often in the adventure stories. Right. They explained that they've noticed a bottle is drifting in on the tide and they're waiting for it to come in because,
you know, the What what does everyone know about bottles?
Sometimes they have messages.
Mh. And I and I love how Scrooge sees down. He's it's he's got this screen expression on face. I'll join them. I one's found a Chinese penny that way. This why I like the... I this is why I really love this story is because there's little character beats and flourish like that. Like, he's it's not interested in going to see his nephews for the sake that they're just his family he's...
He got... He got some money that one time seeing what they were up to. I mean and that's why he's that's what drives him the run over
Right. Like you say, every character beat is reinforced.
On the other hand, I do like how he's kinda taking his nephews serious. Right like, they see this thing. They're they're being very.
And he's right along there with them. Right? He's smiling as they watch it come in. And then when he sees that when they realized there is something in that bottle, of course, he gets very excited, pondering, maybe it's a map to Blue blueberry yeah pressure. Yeah. Yeah.
For. But we learn in fact that it is an
Sos
which says
Save me. I am a maroon on an uncharted island at about one two one thirty West latitude
twenty
south. And this is just kat to, like, junior wood chips. Right? Because they configure this, they can figure this out. Right. So on on the next page, you know, they they talk about this message, which is clearly referring to an un uncharted island where someone is in trouble. The message goes on to say approach island only from Southwest
to avoid being turned into you. And unfortunately, the rest of the message is blurred by water.
Mh. So that... That's what a neat little message, right? Or a neat little hook because it seems very realistic that the message could be don't, you know, avoid being turned into the the reef or something like that. But if you've seen the title, you probably know what it's referring to. Mh.
Mh.
This is why I like the story is creepy and for building. The whole... The message you're getting blurred. It's actually a very dire warning as well as
you know, Al sos
and it also
addresses,
you know,
what some of us readers might think of his common sense. It's like, well, why don't they call the navy or go to the cops about this? You know? And
of course, Barks answers that immediately. It's Scrooge just pure agreed Right. Screws
imagination is racing that, you know, it's an un uncharted island it could have lots of riches.
And and you're right, he's doing a nice job of, like, filling in potential plot holes. Here. Mh. But before he races off with his family to to rescue
the the poor sale slash look for riches, he verifies with the police. He asks
about if there's been any news of the legal boys. And he learns that they left the country months ago. So he's reassured himself
because he wouldn't wanna leave his bin un bombarded with those crooks around. Mh.
Yes and that's an interesting tidbit he drops.
It kind of tells you that the big boys are gonna be involved in the story in some capacity
because Bark doesn't just put in things for no reason.
Right. Definitely.
So we we get again, it's It's a very brisk paste for this adventure.
Bark
introduces donald to the story and in just the little narration box. On the next page. Right? He is added to the crew and the downey rescue a sale on the morning tide.
I do really like the panels again that show Scrooge airing himself out while he's ten. Oh, yes. And part the best... Yes. I love one
Barks draws those eyes.
It's it's a very goofy picture. And it's also a way of Scrooge
getting out of the work. Right, that the
requires. Because he's like, hey, Ducktales orders.
I need to air myself out but Donald
explains that, you know, he needs to steer the boat and each of the boys has their own task Mh. And Scrooge kinda like
shrubs. Okay. So... And Donald snaps it and somebody has to cut. Mh.
It's kind of a unique exchange. I don't usually see screws giving that kind of a sc. And so he
Al down into the galley.
And this is where we're going to be introduced to an element of the story that I meant to bring up before. I forgot I forgot to ask you about So we we get to talk here about habits
can I ask you, can I just kinda d a little bit is this like a cli that you know about?
The idea of, like, boiled cabbage being
super stink. Well, it's... Well, it's obviously something
Barks is employing because
cabbage is notoriously
cheap food to cook need.
And it's sort of invoking
Scrooge
Scottish heritage because it's, you know, it's it's an irish dish course corned a beef cabbage, but it's probably something they ate and that neck of the woods too a lot.
And the this panel is like, this Al be the cheapest dinner any ships crew is ever eaten.
And he's saying it with such pride. It's it's it's lament, but it it's is it's really funny. Two tons of cabbage because it was only two cents a pound.
Right. So Scrooge has stocked their Al with nothing but habits.
This this always felt like such a strange element to this because, like, I didn't know about this plus. The idea that
people eat boiled cabbage first, and that it's super stink. But like, when I Googled
res researching, you get times of stuff about, like, how to remove the smell of boiled cabbage from your house.
So I... All I can think of, that this is, like, probably,
you know, in my household,
this is not.
But it was probably pretty popular
in America
around this time. And I can remember other references and, like, even bark stories
and and other, like, pop culture of the time that talks about this. So I I guess that it like releases a sulfur
smell
just a little bit too long or yeah. Especially if you're
being as frugal as Scrooge
and, yeah, it's
it can be quite a disgusting aroma. Right. So I'll I'll definitely take your and the Internet's word for it. I've never smelled boiled cabbage.
But this is gonna be some of this is gonna be one of the big running gag
of the story
and and we're we're throwing together boiled cabbage along with the c journey. So, you know, we get... We get the Nephews basically re over the edge of the lowest at the end of the page.
And the next page is really about just the the rest of the journey. There's there's nothing too eventful as the Nephews
as Scrooge and the nephews approached the island. Mh. There's a couple more funny references to the fact that they're eating nothing but cabbage on the way and they
I do like the exchange where the nephews say think of think of being rescued by by someone who has nothing to eat, but cabbage.
Mh. And so they do
eventually
arrive at the island. They get a good view. What do you think that of the the view of the island there?
See.
It's very non Scrooge.
It just seems
on it just seems very ordinary. And
of course, as we'll see, there's nothing at all ordinary about this island. So it's a good bait and switch and Barks
and Bark as part. Yeah I've gotta say that first view looks pretty una assuming. Like said. So they do take care. You know, to to listen to them notes warning and they approach it from the Southwest
side. Right.
But they see that there's nothing that looks like a natural harbor.
So they, you know,
make themselves ready to go shore as carefully as they can. And we we get reminded again that Scrooge is really all about the prospecting
because he brings a whole outfit with him. Mh.
And,
you know, there's, I guess the end of the story or the end of this page kinda adds to that, like, ominous field that you're talking about. Mh. Right, where the nephews are talking Do you do you mind reading us the Nephews exchange at the end of this page. Yeah.
One of them says it's strange the maroon sailor or has shown up to welcome us. Maybe he smelled us to come and hit. And it's it's a funny exchange, but it's also...
Yeah. Where where's is this guy that's been trying to be rescued
Right. It definitely plants that seed of, like, everything is not quite right in in the reader.
And and so Scrooge Donald are the two that go,
and Scrooge initially thinks that he's found a golden nugget get only to have it be a brass button
And they realized that they've got a... They're gonna have to look in some of these the caves that are in this kind of cliff face.
And so Donald and sc
split up And again, Fad, do you wanna kinda tell us about the... What happens the end of this page. Yeah. There's a... Yes. We're not kept in too much suspense.
Anyone who's rad uncle Scrooge Story can tell who that is and so silhouette.
It's Donald looking in a cave calling for someone in there. And
it's definitely a big boy about to tie them up. Yeah. You're in you're right, it's not like it's not a big mystery, but it is a very, like, sp
staged
panel, I think. I I do think this is really effective. Mh.
And it's weird to see a beagle boy by himself. Friday.
Yeah. You've seen them enough times to know that B boys are always plural. Yes.
And and on to the next page, we get this kind of rare instance of, like, the perspective shifting to the b, we see his thought balloon as he's subdue Donald.
He's thinking to himself, the kids on that boat will be neck
and he also thinks I've got reasons for wanting to manage my rescue myself.
And we get this pretty cool sinister
approach where he
start the nephews. Mh.
Claims on board, they say, oh, my grandfather's ghost. It's a big boy.
And I I really like their, like,
confrontation.
Do you wanna tell us about it?
Yeah. It's it's a it's pretty terrifying. It's
it's it's the one big boy practically str to kids for several panels trying to throw them overboard into the ocean,
and they're bay... They're begging... They're act... They're actively begging him do not
them. It's... Yeah.
Again, these early stories, they're truly terrible, terrible legal boys, and it's a nice
inclusion of the cabbage again as one of the nephews to tax the legal boy with it and maxim cold and enough long enough to be subdued. Right. It's it's weird that cabbage would cause that much damage, but we'll go with it. Right. I I do like it. Because you're right. It is very...
It's very frightening. You know, the way he's trying to toss them overboard and they're pleading. The steaks do feel really high there.
And so, you know, the Nephews figure out, hey, if there's one beetle here, there's
uncle Scrooge must be in trouble because there's gonna be more beagle on the island. Mh.
And so we flash back two Scrooge
on the island, and he is pondering.
He's still looking for gold, but he's thinking... I'll surely find some rare stones.
Yes. Yes. Good use of language there by Barks. Yeah. You tell us this is where Well does turn creepy.
Yeah. And he finds all these
petrified
stone animals. He's a turtle, he sees a bird.
Cock two with which you can pick up by the tail. Yeah. That's what... I feel believe that's what grace that get discover.
Very for bold.
And screws just estates off and he's Severino more and more on max page
wildlife that's petrified fried
butterflies, monkeys,
and
What's great is a a pack of four beagle boys scheming,
completely petrified. And as Scrooge says, carved b no no. That's caring realism too far.
Right? Because he's he's initially thought it must be carved.
But now he's realizing there's gotta be something else. Going on. And any calls for Donald
saying that he must be having a nightmare
and tell him about what he saw.
And Donald says,
He says I just saw a whole row of stone beetle boys.
Donald gets off a good line here. He says I'm not surprised, the one that hit me must have been solid granite. Mh. Yes. And the next page we're back with the nephews and the subdued legal boy tied up This is a bit of exposition that explaining the situation.
Right It's... It is kind of... And this is where I I liked it. It's creepy because the beagle boys are victims here too. Well,
not so much because as he explains, they came to the island to pill yet. And you know, so not too... Not too many tiers shed for them. But Right.
You know, they ran into bad trouble and
talking about
martian or whatever they are up there turned ray on us. I was the only one who escaped and he he explains the whole situation to them, and it turns out they believe him right away because he...
He corroborate the story about the bottle and what the message said. Right. And he also tells them about his fellow beagle and one of the Nephews is able to see them through the bin.
And there's... It really does do a good job of ramping up the anxiety by you know, the beetle boy has this really
desperate
expression that I think. Works very well for this.
And so the Nephews head out to the island
to worn
and donald all but but I'm I'm gonna mention I I was struck by the Beagle description here. When I re re reread this, you know, the most recent time. I was thinking that this reminded me
the mention of martian and array. That sounded kinda like the war of the world. Yeah. That that absolutely
would have been on
Barks is mine, especially at the time because...
But that movie was just released in nineteen fifty three and you know, that would have been on Barks is mine. He would have seen that. He would heard about it, and might have incorporated that into a story.
Right. And and I think the book was in, like the... I think it was in the thirties. Yeah. Of course. And Barks would have read it then too. But I'm just thinking of the the the film would have Jocelyn is... Jessica's his interest and, oh, well, maybe I can do a story with some elements of this. Yeah. No doubt. Like, it definitely, I think help to enter pop culture.
I haven't... I can't remember seeing the movie. I think that's the one where it's a very static looking
robot
kind of fires beams from his hands. Am I remembering that Right?
I you might be... I I'm embarrassed to say Al an all move stuff. I don't remember it much. Because.
Sci f is not my forte k. I know enough that
that's... That's probably what was on his mind. I just... I am a little familiar with the book and I remember that, like, the the creatures
in the book. To me, they really do vote we're what we're gonna see later. So. Well, this... Well, it's around this time where a lot of the more... The what what you would call the classic era of sci f fe is really becoming prominent pop
and, you know, it's starting to influence Barks. This is... Yeah. This is his first side f type of story that... But, you know, it really isn't in so much. But because it's not so much natural as it is,
you know,
one of Ge Gear
lost relations doing something. I I think that's a good point. I think that really Barks, you know, mentioned that this is one of the the first of these, like, really sci
influenced adventures.
Mh.
So, you know, the next segment is really all about the... All the characters coming together on the island.
The nephews have to take the beagle
tied up so that he won't try and steal boat. And they encounter screws and donald.
About to crest the hill, because donald wants to show the Scrooge wants to show Donald, those stone b boys but the nephews worn them off
explaining
about the gang of martian up there with the ray that will patch
and screws, you know, he's been up there already and and nothing happened to him So he's extremely skeptical call.
And and he goes up there and he looks around the nephews are are pleading with him telling them them about the beagle that saw buddies turned into stone. Now sc realizes that they're really are big boys on the islands and the... And he takes an advantage of the stone beetle boys. Mh.
Yes. He decides to kick one in the behind.
Because brother, what it chance to even a lot of old scores
Right before see he swear he broken his foot now. And he calls to his nephews that it's perfectly safe.
But on the next page
turns out it's not quite so safe because donald than the two nephews that cross over the ledge,
they're immediately petrified.
It rights with a big
z It's a it's a cool little sound affected. It's cool. It it's definitely creepy. Right? Severino them seeing them turns to stone. Absolutely.
And and so on the next
the next segment, we transitioned to, you know, sc
sobbing
about
leading his poor nephews in this.
The b boy pleading that they need to sail away and kinda really the Nephew was the only one keeping his head and and looking pretty annoyed.
Understandably.
And we get this moment where the... They start to get pepper with what the b boy believes to be Barks shot
but but the Nephew points out that it's nothing but petrified
rain, and we learned something really key
Do you wanna tell us what we learn about that? Yeah. It's it turns out to be petrified ring. It's it's not Barks at at all. It's just passing through the raise of effects,
Scrooge realizes that as the rain is getting far enough away, turns back into water,
So
he zones correctly that if they move the nephews away,
if they move down and the nephews away, they'll turn back to normal. And
So there's a nice little exchange. They're coming back to life. Their heads are getting soft and Scrooge says well, let's hope they don't get as soft as mine. And then immediately, we're full on screw hero mode
where it says, now I have another job to do. This time I've got to save the whole world. This is I'm pretty Gladstone highlighted that. That's that's pretty weird for
he's not usually
interested in having Scrooge be the hero. Well, well, it's immediately dash their next panel on the page, you know, because the global reader in that, is like, wow Scrooge is, you know, being so
thought lesson. I mean... Mean he's being so you know, he's he's considering of faith of the world. But then it's like, does march just take the rate of the mainland, They could petri the police and climb all my money. So
it's self interest once again. Yeah. So so Barks always has to his character.
Right. If if something is going well for Donald in one of these stories, like can say the brittle mass your
or if he's having some big success,
you know, he's gotta have something
fall, him he's gotta get some
and and same thing with Scrooge, if he's showing some
mobility, I guess he's gotta tampa that by having him think about his money again.
Before we go on, you know, it is really affecting. I I felt nervous watching Scrooge
and the the one nephew carefully
lowering the petrified
duct
down.
You know, that that definitely felt stressful to me. I'm also used Al Scrooge pondering. I'm I must be too tough to petri.
Okay
So Scrooge
does go to approach as he says the whole martian army to to try and lick him with the... His bare hands.
And
while he's off, the Nephew is talking with the bill boy asking if he really ever saw or heard anything of him and he explains that I I didn't. I don't know anything
except for the first two months I was here because he's been there for seven months. The first two months I was here, I smelled cabbage cooking Severino day.
So we're we're back to the this weird
running gag slash,
I don't know of of cabbage being very important in this story And then we flash back to Scrooge.
It is a nice suspense moment as he kind of sneaks past some groves of coconut trees and gets close.
And then we get this view
of where the problem is coming from. Do you wanna characterize it that?
Yeah. It almost... It it almost looks like a margin creation the way it is. It's it looks like a mechanical masters
hissing and sci and spotting and singing and f all at once. And,
yeah, It's really the only
I I can see why that this story...
If this this panel sort of defines why this
story might be lower on people's lists
because a lot of the other earlier stories
with Scrooge, they have more spec than this. And this is, like, the only
half page panel that's like this and Right. It's it's not I mean, it it it is a little terrifying, but it's it's almost a little under we
considering all the personal drama that the characters have been going through up to this point. So it's like, yeah.
Okay. We see that this is too terrifying, but, you know, it's almost like, oh, well, that's not that's so not so scary. You know?
I Almost
yeah.
I I think that's right. It's a little under overwhelming. I I think it's about as as cool.
About as good of a payoff as he could make based on kind of the trajectory of the story. But that you're right that compared to, like, some of the the real sci
splash panels
in trauma
or. Only a poor man or Right. Or or whatever recently,
that it's not It doesn't have that much of a punch. It is cool. Right? And it's definitely got some of the, like, fifties
sci f five
Really seen.
Yeah. It's neat. But I I definitely... I do think it... It's a little under well.
Well, especially
what what comes after
is frankly more terrifying than than the side of the array itself.
Scrooge gets captured and he doesn't get to see his character
because he's locked in a basket
and it turns out it's this
prospect,
shirtless, old man, one of those creepy creatures of Barks is where he gives them ears even though they're birds
Oh, yeah.
He he runs right out and hurts
Scrooge pirates
and he and he starts
x.
And, like, even when the beagle boys bleeds with them do not shoot,
he petri verifies the big any gets donald, but the nephew is escape to the boat.
I that's frankly,
it's frankly a better payoff to that
sight of that. It's a better payoff than the side of that gray is. That this professor is such a goof ball. He's so weird. And he's mer. As you say, he really... He really goes for them. And his little portable
touch certification array. It really looks... It evo one of those old fashioned like,
Al d
or... Yeah. Yeah exactly what it is. That's what's why it's one because it's old... It's old tiny.
That's a common theme with Barks something old time or, you know, constantly... So something common, but it it does something incredible.
Right.
Right. It's what Donald was using to
spray fires when he was firm and donald, basically.
And and
we we get the professor
thoughts.
Right? He clearly thinks that they're all just criminals and and like the b boys who have come to try and pill what's his.
And, you know, the the nephews do make it back to their boat,
and they plan to go away for help. But Scrooge has the ignition key with him. So again, it's some type plotting there. Filling in those platforms holes. And
we get this fun silhouette of the professor pushing around the large version.
Of his invention. And he's thinking to himself. Nobody must stop me before I have finished my great invention. And that's an interesting
right? Because like first off, you know, as far as we can tell that the invention is finished. It's something that that it's like ind,
maybe.
And and what else could he be working on? This is what he's creators is pretty terrifying. Yes. So the nephews, they don't have a lot of options here, but they do just... One of them remembers what the vehicle mentioned about cabo.
Mh and smelling it cooking for two months.
So they... The kind of is like, well, what do we got to lose? Let's start cooking some up. And it's it's goofy and it's silly, but the way he's set it up, it does... It is logical. Right? What else can they do?
Mh. Do you wanna tell us about the next page where the adjuster is looking out over the cliff? Yes. He's about to set the ray on them, but this the scent of that cabbage. All my drilling taste buds, he immediately gets on board swimming,
dropping off his equipment, know,
losing all his agencies
just like and he gets tied up immediately,
and
he says, I'll talk. I'll do anything if you just give me a butter of that wonderful tasty cabbage It's... It's it's quite a quite a turn
because this was one this
supposedly leave the character,
you know, it just that becomes just
completely helpless just Al the percent of disgusting.
Right.
Right. It's it's a weird turn.
And so we transition back to sc in his basket.
And he sees the kids returning with what he thinks is the martian monster. But the Inducks, the Nephews quickly explained that he's actually a scientist from Du burn conveniently.
Mh. And and we get a little bit of quick
exposition about
how he invented the ray while trying to take the fumes out of the.
That is the whole
allegation for this fairly dark and suspense
smart that this, like,
kind of a mystery. Right? And and so he he came here to the islands
afraid that the ray would fall into the hands of bad people. Mean, he's been working on his cabbage and we can see that he's really
distraught that every time he perfect the cabbage, he took out... He also took out the taste.
And and he's essentially lived in fear of pirates ever since the beagle came, and he had to turn the ray on them and and he's
it references him being trapped there by a typhoon.
Mh.
What do you think that about the next page where screwed tells him you're wasting your time with simplest cabbage, whether that ray would make you master of the world. Mh.
Yes. I I've always liked this little bit of Barks philosophy
Sure, but there are too many masters in the world already and not enough france.
It's...
You know, I I just can't help thinking that this...
It's just step definitely
almost gyro two point two point o or something or an alternate version of them. Because he's got very dry like ten cs
especially the early jay he's more app and mind. Know he's more.
He's got the glasses.
Alright. And
and it's definitely a gyro that he would invent something by acts I'm trying to do something else. Think he... Is is...
This character doesn't have a name that's professor.
Right. And I I think that's just his way of saying, well, I kinda of wanted to use Ji, but I couldn't because he's established.
So here's this other similar character.
And Gyro sorta got the same viewpoint on life too. It's like, no, no. I I I don't wanna do that because, you know, the world's bad enough, why would I wanna take over or do anything?
Yeah. I I completely agree with everything you said there. Right? That was well stated he he seems like such a stand for Dry that you feel like maybe Barks
considered using Gyro but couldn't quite figure out how it works. And right since he already knows the Ducktales.
Especially that as spec.
They would all know him already. Right. And it is a good line. I think that's probably the only reason
that he has screwed say something so weird like he's encouraging him to take over the world. Right? I think we're just he wanted him to say that good line about how there are too many masters and enough friends. Mh.
And then and we get the the second little turning point here. You know, we think that everything is okay. But it turns out that the nephews of noticed that they they've been approached by the b boys. Mh.
Who have the ray
aimed at them,
And they have a pretty
specific
threat
here. Do you wanna tell us there a threat? Yes.
Surrender or will fire your nephew forever. And and this is this is why I like this story that it shows a lot of character beads.
There's no real jokes here. Scrooge sees the seriousness of the situation it tells them.
Now how you hire my nephew is I'll pay you any price to let them go
and it's like, any price, even all of your three cubic acres of genuine money, and yes. Even my last sixteen cents. And the beagle boys sc this off. And, you know, because they're gonna get everything in the world with this array. We'll where will pill and wondering and grand style and Scrooge of course, what a horrible faith to fall the world? These guys are gonna be masters great.
And there's this wonderful page.
It's almost entirely the beagle boys.
Both thing about what they're gonna do to the world with
with styles mansions with two thousand bathtub tops.
Why the bathtub. We never take Barks. They're to hold our jeweler you un cool ru in. You know, they're doing their trademark dance with their
they're showing off their that they're terrible, terrible, terrible
behavior.
We're gonna be Al of the world with kings and presence growing at our feet. And we want turkey for breakfast with Turkey. And here's what we were alluding to earlier.
And we when we approves for breakfast
Everyone's... All the other big boys scream at him. Shut off. They have proof for breakfast to Every morning and prison. Are you getting home sick and really
minuscule, the one big was, but I like pros. And I think this is just playing off. You know, we had one disgusting
characteristic
disgusting food already with the cabbage. Here's another that's an acquired taste pros.
Acquired taste is pretty generous. Right? Yes. I I don't know if this is universal around the world. But like, prune are kind of a punch line in the states. Right? Yes. Because, like, You're an old prone. You're an old prune. Yeah. You're old. Your.
Yeah.
No one likes prune. The only reason you eat a prune is if you're like cons
Yeah. I need to go. They're they're for old people. So so there's a lot of humor in this one big boy randomly loving prune. And, you know, Bark? Like he doesn't do a ton of running gag that span
stories. Right? Like Right. Heat but he'll actually come back to this one Google,
liking prune in at least a couple other stories.
Over, like his whole career, I think it was the Giant Robot Roberts. Mh.
And...
Oh, the one horse around with history, Right.
So, like, he remembered that. He liked that shit It it's it's very funny. Mh. And And it's also something that, like, people in the whole dot community. Oh, yes. We we... All all of us who have worked with the docs have worked with the being Al boys. We've all tried to incorporate prune at one point or another
Right. It's it's just a just a wonderful little gag that this
fog has, you know, he he has a tape his his taste bud is for for proof something
something
And it's something
they probably would serve in a prison in the fifties because it's cheap.
Right. Right. So it's a good bit.
And the beetle boys you know, they keep talking and arguing amongst themselves while screwed Yeah. Understanding there. Yeah. That's that's... Yeah. That's a good segway.
That find that the final panel is Scrooge. She's leaning against the trees. Like, well, make up your mind. You asked me to surrender. What happens next? Like, alright enough of this. Right. Because it's just it has going on for the whole page.
Yeah. For a fairly short story, he devote a a pretty good amount of time to the beagle Al.
Wrong. And I... I like that part of the story. I find it among the more memorable Barks up there with, like, the the the view of the array and the petrified
animals. Those are probably the things that I remembered best from this one. So they they remember that they're looking for the boat key and they tell screws to hand it over, and we get this interesting exchange where the professor
very confidently tells him Don't listen to them, don't do it.
And we can tell that for some reason the professor knows that he actually has the upper hand. Mh. And and as the b boys go to go to freeze them, Go to petri them. We we learn what that upper hand is. It's the fact that he has key
in the way to the yes. In his pocket. Yes. I I love this dialogue. It's like, they can't make the raise why for the same reason they can't make your boat z. I have the key in my pocket
and. Yeah. It's a it's a well.
It's a well
weld developed bit of dialogue. It it is. It and it is. It's such a deflation. It like, you cheated Al your is, like, yeah. I... Yeah. Of course, I'm not care you... Idiot if think I left the key to the
unattended
and and the the professor gets like, downright
gl again. Yeah. Always he's
as he, like, uses this his little manual
thing to Yeah.
It his man... His manual... His manual pump brett and his manual pump. And I just didn't... I I... And I enjoy it this time that is Al because did they deserve that what's gonna happen. So let's not have any more rough stuff boy. Right. Right. And and so, you know, they're their journey on this island kinda wraps up with the the Inducks telling the beagle that they're gonna need to construct to raf to get home because there's enough room on the boat. I do like that panel of them crying amongst themselves about of all the people in the world those Ducktales to be the ones that got my bottle message.
Mh.
And the professor just gonna hang out on his island, because now he's got a great supply of
of cabbage,
and he can blast the world with his future invention of fu cabbage. Yes. There's another good little bit with that that. What what do you think? Are we are we over doing the gag here when Donald says what a pity he hasn't got it invented now. No. He's just got reinforce, you know, this is definitely one of Barks is gross or stories.
And and, you know, you just gotta keep throwing it in at every turn. And we're we're not done with it quite yet, but... And we've got we got the great explanation too because it's probably what we were wondering as readers is right. That long last mystery. Yes.
Why didn't the ray pack find Scrooge desks and the professor asks, I'd like to know that myself,
something is in your skin and in your clothing that deflect the ray. Gold dust. My goodness, mister,
You roll in money.
We won't discuss that. And it's together. Like, it it would you...
It's the outside world that doesn't know screw. Like, going, I wait what how does this happen wouldn't Sanity is this. You've got gold dusting in your skin?
It's it's a great book.
Yeah. Right. It so
because he didn't call... He he didn't do the callback until the very end. That's why it works so well. And Right. And as Readers, you might have forgotten well what was the point of them coming out here in the first place and Barks conveniently reminds you, and it sets up the ending. Right. And we've got that great, like the the same pose with the professor holding the Al magnifying glass just like the doctor and Scrooge blushing.
And and that makes it funny. Right? Yeah. The the way that he's concerned... Yes.
Yes. And and so... And and as far as I'm concerned, that beat is is, like, the end of the story. He he just kinda like
let sit lang grossly and with a little bit of their boat voyage home
and one last exchange where Donald tells him, you know, you better get back to cooking dinner,
but but he's fed up with that. He says, you cook Isles.
You know I'm a sick dot and he he
It's a cute panel. He stairs with his feet while he hears himself out
and Donald old finishes closes the story out by just being really annoyed at how you just can't win with uncle around as he is
yet again cooking
stinky cabbage.
Mh.
Yeah. So that that wraps it up.
I can sort of see why
someone like you would con... Who's not particularly
you know, one favorites says it's un remarkable.
And it kind of is, but
it's just... It has a lot of character and the And that's what I really don't like about a lot of the uncle Scrooge stories in general that they start to follow a formula very fast.
Know, it's...
Scrooge Donald will get in trouble and the nephews find some way to get out of it. This is very much all the characters are present for throughout.
Donald not so much. And how you even the Nephew is not so much either because this
Scrooge really drives all of the story Because you yeah because it's it's unique in that he's the only
person, the stone rate does affect. So kinda... It's it's almost.
It's almost a superhero story and that sense. Because he's got this power and none of the other characters have. Yeah. That's a good point, and it's true more than a lot of the so called uncle Scrooge stories. This really is like
specifically about uncle Scrooge. Mh. A lot of them are are as much about donald or than use Al they are.
You know,
One of the things I I really enjoy about doing this show and, like,
diving into
obsessively into the specifics of these is that I do end up, like, finding a lot to appreciate about stories that maybe I hadn't, like, really sat down and thought about. And as we... As we went through the story, that there's a lot that that we talked about and that you pointed out and and kinda advocated for that. Made me realize, hey, you know, this this story does actually have quite a bit going for it. There's there some really unique really cool things. The the kinda ominous tone is very unique. I I wouldn't say that, like, my opinion has shifted. So like say it's like a favorite, all of a sudden.
But but I it it definitely is kind of an average Barks adventure
and an average Barks adventure is like, it's still really really good. Still yeah.
Exactly. That's pretty
error to be in. Just to just be a a good
Barks story is is really saying a lot. And this one does have a lot going for it.
Mh. I I do still have some problems. You know, I do find parts of it under well and the I've never really gotten over what a what a goof ball the professor
is. Well, yeah. He kinda of this. He he almost is kind of enough thing. You know, like I said, he's a stand for jo and kind of on
It's it... What defines the
it how overwhelming he is is that he bark to even bother to give him a name.
Right. Yeah. Definitely.
Such to cruise so for such a crucial character.
And it's interesting too. Now that I think about. I just had this thought in so many of the early Scrooge and and for colored donald, you know, he really wants to go on like that mass
geographic journey. Mh. And he wanted to, like pick a little bit about
the the location or or with the legend of whatever he was talking about, and and this story has such a like anonymous
setting that doesn't have any
underlying, like, cultural
significance, really. And, yes, I just looked up, like just refresh my memory...
If you look... If you just Google war of the world's, and look up the illustrations.
You're gonna see the ray that Barks. Huey, stole right from H d wells. So... Right. Right. And that that is the... This is see this... This show
educate me as to how
underdeveloped a lot of other just a knowledge and pop culture. But, yes, that is that is the the ray in that panel is just a direct rip off of the fighting machine and war of the world.
And I think that's probably why it's well because Barks wasn't doing anything original he just stole it. Yeah. That that was my.
Why don't you look Al up right now yourself, Mark just really quick. Is going together. I will, but I can I can totally
picture it? Al The
fighting machine war of the world's
Google it's it's.
Yeah. Yeah just be already just store it. See, so this is So this is another important lesson and, you know,
theft is a part of.
It really is. I mean, I see so many people crying fall when, you know, people see, like, oh, you crib from this. It's like, well, call Barks crib from H g. Wells. I mean what's the big deal, you know? He just... He just uses his Al element in a story. You know, it's... That... That's... You know, not... You know, there are only so many original ideas on earth
obviously.
So, you know, that that can be forgiven. But that that is a that is a blatant
Al blatant been play Al I'm there, though. I'm glad. I'm glad that you agree because, honestly, I was surprised that I never really saw it mentioned in, like, any of the commentary by Jeffrey Blu.
Or anyone else. Maybe someone's pointed it out before, but I'm just gonna go ahead and say that I I I nailed that.
Yes. You did. Yeah. Okay. Well, despite that, bit of theft. I I just think it's a really fun story. It's always stood out. I remember is it teenager I asked. My friend David Ge who is the archive editor on the Gems Barks. It's like can you reprint this one? Because it hasn't been printed in years and years and
turned out in June my birthday month,
this mysterious stone ray showed up and the uncle Scrooge jumps own Barks. So nice. Yes. So I I don't think that was that intentional, but I like to think of it that why? That's a happy coincidence.
Right. So let's talk about, you know, the community
impression. I always use Inducks
as kind of a representation It's not perfect, but it's by far the best, like, way to judge what the overall community thinks of a story. And people have voted this one to a seven point nine out of ten, which
lands it at number forty seven.
On on the list of all Disney comics. Well, see, I I think that's reflecting it bet I might have talked about it. But, you know, the worldwide perception is that the screws stories are as best work. So Inducks is incorporating a lot of that and they're rating Yeah. I I think that's probably right. I think that the
original,
like, the the earliest screwed stories, Severino
like... Well, this was an Scrooge number eight. Right? It must be great. It was one of those Scrooge screws right I think... I think that's a little bit generous.
It is. I don't... Even if I was thinking if I really had the do it. I I think this one might be lucky to be at my own top fifty of the Barks stories, but that's only because so many of the ten pages would take it up before that Right. Because if you like, pull out, you know, the the stories by like there are some Gottfredson
stories and rot stories and cassie,
and a couple of rows the stories probably in the top fifties. So if you build them out, that that makes it like a top thirty story roughly and.
That's that's that's generous. This is a good story Mh. And and is is memorable in a lot of ways, but I do think that that's overly generous
Nothing against people who call this one of their favorites. It it's... I I... You know, I I know where I stand, Like, I I don't know if I like it enough. Where I would consider a a top favor, but I like... I like it too much to, like, you know, just a nissan hand sure. Yeah it's definitely
out of that fan of the fan print is definitely my favorite and that's in that book and anyway So... Yeah. Which one was that in? That one that's that's in the Severino city book. Right. So I I think some cities is self. I probably enjoy a lot more. Right. There's it's it's... Yeah. It's definitely got more of the flavor of what people would like in a Scrooge story. Know. There some fun ones from that era. Sure. Sure. No. It's some...
It... I I just... I just like it two much. I I don't wanna dismiss it at all. But I I would definitely agree that the Inducks rating is
little skewed, but a lot of index ratings are skewed. So... Right. But I'll as we've discussed and we've learned
in the past, hey it it gives us something to talk about. Or I love that.
Is not you gotta hang your podcast around something structural.
Right. So so we also talk about kind of other references
and follow ups. Now to my knowledge Barks never did any kind of a painting for this one. But know it's kinda says Al all he didn't think of it as too memorable. Yeah. I don't think it would have been a great subject for a painting. He did paintings for some pretty un memorable stories, but they definitely had had some key moments. Mh.
I
I I took a little look, and I didn't remember. I couldn't come across any time that this might have been adapted into a tail story. Mh. For either of the the series.
That now there was one big follow ups. Yeah. So one of Don Rosa is the earliest stories. Right. This was a very early story of Dawn Rosa, and I'm I'm gonna confess that I I read the rosa story
before I read the Barks original.
Yeah. The... This this was
you know, as everyone knows, I I quote unquote shade dan rosa I don't hate Don Rosa. I just
We we hate any creator
podcast. Right. People are welcome to be critical of them, of course. Right. But I'm not the biggest fan, but I do enjoy his early stuff, but the... His cash flow story,
it it just hinges too much on you knowing that this... That's why you probably baffled this kid when you read it before because, you know,
you remembered this character
from
what is... What we've already discussed is not one of Barks,
you know, top tier stories
and
it hinges on the device that he doesn't remember the beagle boys at all. And it's it's really dumb. It's sorry guys. It's So that is a weird element. Now I'm I'm gonna I'm gonna say something maybe a little controversial. And I I I've heard people express the a lot of people who like know the story as well. They do tend to feel more warm towards Roses early stories. I Mh. I love cash flow. I love it. I think it's stronger than this story actually.
Well, I'll have I'll have to re look at it again because I keep seeing it on my shelf I picked up the slip cover with the too earliest fan graphics,
Rosa books
oh I keep find the second one. It showed it's it showed up randomly
for fifty bucks, which is the list price, but I just took Al, like Alright. I'll grab it. Fine.
Because I actually had a freebie before, but someone over at my apartment I gifted it to. But
No.
I'll have to re look at that one then. Because like I said,
I I do like Rose as earliest stuff. Now I I totally agree with the criticism that, like, the the professor
shu warned in and the fact that he hasn't recognized them that that's Got it. You gotta kind of just give him that. But the story itself, and and the high concept...
That's roses strength. Right as the
that he does, and the the two rays the follow, the sequel raise, I guess.
He... So in this one, it's a stone ray and in the follow, he does array that, like, reduces in nurse
and another one that reduces momentum, I think. Mh. And the way that he plays that out I I think it's Rosa at his best.
So
maybe it's an artifact of me reading that one first. But might be few months It might be. I'll have to look at that myself once I I'll have to look at that again myself because I just remember the stand out just being it's just too can try that the professor doesn't remember. The guys that want tried to use his invention to take over the world. I thought that was I thought that was a little bit of too much creative license and on, mister Rose. Right. And and I remember the big say that disney professor won't remember us. And I mean in in fairness, he is a pretty busy guy. So Sure.
But but, yeah, it's it's weird because it's not really a sequel
to the story itself yeah the sql element is that there's another array and the b boys still that big still likes prune, and that's pretty much it.
Pastor
yeah fast still wants his cabbage.
Yes. So...
But but I do really like that story. And,
you know, this one
this one's a lot of fun. Not not one of the most memorable, but definitely worth reading, and I'm I'm glad that we got to talk about this Yeah.
And and so I I will say that I've got kind of a new
appreciation. There... There have been a few of these stories where literally as I go through and talk about it with the guest house. I like develop a real appreciation for. Oh, good. Well, good. I'm I'm glad I I'm glad my sound reasoning could help
turn you a little bit more towards this stories favor. Yeah. So we've covered it pretty well.
And and we did mention a number of of panels that stood out to us. Are there any that you'd like like to highlight that we didn't mention or that you think really
kind of merit
you know, oh, this this is my favorite panel. I don't think so. Just those panels where
the doctor and the professor discovering the gold dust and his pores
the... There's two many... There's too many masters and not enough friends
the p... That whole page with the beagle
Yeah they're they're them showing off. I I think we got... We got all the beats covered. And I think I think that's why... I think we just sort of emphasize why this might not stand out as much because when you think of, you know, the more character driven stuff you sort of lean more towards Donald whereas this where screwed you lean more towards adventure.
And, you know, the... It's kinda like the defining, like, the split off point
when he stopped focusing so much on donald Inducks stories and more on uncle screwed stories, you know, that that his the quality of his work went a different direction. Yeah. It definitely does feel like a dividing line. I think I I I probably agree with you there. Some of those earlier Donald Stories are more memorable.
But there's a lot of great stuff. Oh of sorts. And... And I don't mean... I don't mean to dislike on screw... The screwed story so much
Now It wouldn't be... I wouldn't be a a Car Barks fan, you know, if if I didn't like a lot of Scrooge. So... Right.
But... But, yeah, I I can't... No. It's I can't think of much more to say about this one, but just that I've always really had a soft spot for. Yeah. Well, and and I'll just mention we talked about a lot of my favorites. I I do like the initial
silhouette of the beagle
sc about in the cave. I like... I had mention Scrooge kinda airing himself out. I'm a sucker for those panels.
And
and that opening where he's looking all joy
flashing through his money is definitely a striking one as well. So thank you listeners
for enjoying this
episode.
Feel free to, you know, check out our socials. We've got Barks remarks is is on Facebook and
Instagram. So... And and that you've got... You've got a a podcast of your own. Right? You wanna be
Sure. It's a podcast I did run with the Bob Jacobs the animation director,
Animation director running s.
Called Ka logic. We have a backlog of couple dozen episodes.
We're kinda restructuring our now, we both are pretty busy with our lives right now, but we, you know, we dissect the classic cartoons
from the Golden age of Hollywood, New York animation and just discuss why a lot of these titles work and why some of them don't work. So if you're fan of
specifically worn cartoons and flight cartoons,
We cover them pretty well there. So...
And I will be working on getting our pope eye centric up so which we're a A
exclusive for a while.
I'm working on getting those public. So yeah.
That's that's about the size of it. Yeah. That's great. I have listened to a couple of those. They're really good
and, you know, that a lot of influence
on Barks stories. Like Oh, of course. Yeah. We actually did do an episode. I specifically picked it because
on the on donald Inducks cartoons, and we guys accepted
the cartoon timber, which bark cole with Ga hannah. And and so we certainly... Well,
It turns out it's we don't really like the card to that much, and we sort of go into why, but...
Yeah. Yeah. I don't remember that. One. Well, our... Well, our thoughts generally, are we love the Carl Barks stories, but we don't like the animated donald duct
so much.
It's...
Something that I guess we agree with mister Rosa.
Yeah. I mean, I I I loved them as a kid, but they don't hold. There's there's there's no there's no contest whatsoever.
No. Right. Absolutely.
Yeah. Well, people should definitely check that out and and the come... Join us next time when we get to talk about
a a very unique adventure, we're gonna be diving into the le with the lock it. Oh boy. And fact, I've been closing recent
episodes
by just
reading the very last panel. It's my closing
strip. And I don't know how well it works, but I'm sticking with it. So
with uncle Scrooge around, You just can't win. Mh.
Alright. Thanks a lot for joining us that. Thank you.