We can have
Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer an artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comments of all time. Join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks. Welcome back to Barks remarks, I'm Mark Sever, a grown man who enjoys talking about Inducks Comics,
and I've got a couple of returning guest hosts with me today. As we journey to Norway to talk about
pretty famous uncle screwed story, the le with the locket.
I and and I'm I'm very excited. To get a local
perspective
because
my guests are both Norwegian, So I'm gonna have them introduce
themselves and
mention
their their experience
with the comics and also some of the work that they've done. And why don't we start with
Michele? Hey, Barks. It's where to be Barks on here again.
My name is Michael H, twenty five year old man who grew with Barks marble comics, and a great fan, especially of Local Scrooge adventures.
So
what I previously is previously done is
the both me and Rubin has participated in this norwegian reader
competition where the readers made the wrong download magazine. It was a yearly
competition running from around two thousand and twelve to thousand two thousand sixteen and I also got to write pre phase to one hard cover on that book as well as
illustrate one story for the editor, and both of us also
this channel which I'm sure rubin can tell us more about.
Yeah. Yeah. Hi, guys. It's good to say
I'm Ruben.
Yeah. Sure. This is channel. Let me just first talk about that read the competition for norwegian weekly rico on that com. So I guess, yeah. Michael has a couple of
stories in there, and I got to the cover of the the so first of those readers weekly on the com. And in the second one, I also got wire in one pager. And the because of the what this need Europe or something nor they ask both me goal to do this, like sound little through you session about us being young down that fans and comic with fans. And of course, we're working with it. Being happy to do this as as a covid. So within like this little snippets in between the commercials of the business channel area europe that's that's super cool you guys. That's that's awesome hear about. I would definitely
like to see those. And happy to share it on the Facebook page if you guys are down. What a fun thing to do? Also have this one little fun experience after actual air yeah the Tv commercials because one day I was taking the bus, there was a little girl coming on and I'm she just saw man and she walked up to me and almost points her finger up in my face and I saw you on Tv, and then know she run the away.
What
little kids are so funny. Oh, they're little the little minute of fame right there. Yeah. Yeah. That's awesome. That's so great you guys, but that's really cool.
And I should mention that Ruben, you have recently
supplied us with some great cover art for the episodes of the ten page
podcast. That that we put out, which
turned out great. So thank you. You guys can can check him out well, we'll mention that. We'll mention at the end where they can find you if anyone wants to do a commission or anything. So you guys you are both... You... You're both in Norway. Right? You guys are are perfect for this episode
because I figure you can give us a local
perspective And and this story is great. It's it's kind of a travel log in a way. Right? Sometimes Barks really Huey,
really take some effort.
To localize stories going into the national geographic that you loved so much, learning about the place.
I've gotta imagine it's kind of like a good news bad news situation. Right? Because I don't know. There's probably some pretty big stereotypes in this. What what do you guys think? Where did you enjoy Severino Norway featured in this story?
Ruben?
Well, I actually didn't create. I'm you about for a long time, but it hasn't actually been printed that much no way. So I actually didn't get to read it. I guess until I randomly found like this best stories from Dom coming and edit. And that was, I guess, it was after I actually saw the Ducktales that itself. I saw Ducktales episode three release of error reading the Barks story. In Ducktales
episode and norwegian and translation. They also
call it Norway. We're going to Norway and I find found it. Was this little play? Pull in the duct savers and also in the comic book Barks medicine bit more weight. But for me, that's pretty much where it ends.
And it's it's Al. It's an okay
presentation of no weight that bad. I guess we will go back to it. Yeah. How about you, Miguel to stand out? Kia. I think it's stand stood
or it was not the best story I ever read at the time, but I actually found it first in in an American printing.
Before I phoned them in the region. So my first residence in the call greatest Ducktales stories from Jen that in Published in two thousand and six So I read it the first time along me back to the clone, for example, stood outs
a little more to me but sure. But, yeah, I'm I'm quite proud Barks and docs on a question by why while this hill was in his golden age that is concerning the character the design of the Barks. And it was still a few years away from those way two twelve we got around nineteen fifty seven, And this is a little, but
the reason for
throwing style changed around than the end of the fifties well because
west provided him bit more with less quality paper because it cheaper. And
Bur phone is hard to get the Barks
and their heights bright in his first try. So it would he would usually shorten them a little before he ink. The new paper made that impossible since the pencil dug to deep into the paper and thereby making it hard to fix So we you would just try best to get the docs right for two years
before he just gave her in nineteen fifty seven with story and stories like T any gan. But after forgot and provided in the better paper. That's interesting. That's a it's fascinating little and tidbit bit that that's something like the paper quality can make such a big difference. You know, since you guys are our artist yourself and do fan are, you probably
relate to that more than I would. I can so that's very much with the poor paper policy. Nice. Alright. So you guys... This is I I think you mentioned right, that this is maybe not the best of Barks stories, but is an awfully
fun. Little adventure.
And and I I do think that it's like as un remarkable story as it is, it's very memorable. Right? Because we've got this really cool yeah. Hook to talk about this neat
journey that the debts are gonna go on. So let's get into a little bit of the background
of the story. It's itself. We are talking about the le with the lock. It came out in uncle Scrooge number nine
back in in January of nineteen fifty five. And
has been reprinted kind of an average number of times. Ten in the United States, including the original printing, This is a... This is a shorter
adventure story. At least for this era. It's only twenty two pages.
We're just a few issues
from from his very last thirty two pager. So that these are kind of a different style of stories to me a little bit brisk. And you guys something that I've been thinking about as I've done
episodes, I've recorded a bunch of episodes recently
for this run of the first handful full of uncle screwed stories. Right? So I can't help but take a little bit of time to think about what the early part of uncle Scrooge
run looks like the comic of run,
specifically, like issues number one through
tan. And it's really
interesting to me how we've got these handful of the very early stories, really deal with kind of setting Scrooge up as a character
establishing his origin and what motivates him a little bit and and exploring some really interesting really adult themes. Right? Like Inducks to the lawn can only a poor man and the horse rather story. And then at some point into this first
ten stories Barks,
I think he's figured... Okay. Why I've got this character. I've successfully soften his edges.
Now I'm gonna take him on some. Just plain Al adventures.
But but the other thing that I think Barks is doing around this time. Is he's thinking about his character.
What is his hook it's that he has an enormous amount of money. So he's essentially cycling through what are the different things that Scrooge
can do with his money. Right? And in the horse rad story, he's trying to hold on to it in Manny mystery,
he is trying to keep it safe. He's
relocating it. We're gonna see him do that in a number of different stories going forward
in Secret of Atlanta number five. He's trying to recover it.
T lies another of those kind of more
mature
exploration that to me goes better with the first handful of stories.
And then in like the seven cities of S.
He's trying to think about new ways, new interesting ways to make money.
And then... And then the mysterious stone rate is just kind of a a pros adventure, I think. But in this one, it is one of those stories where he's trying to just
protect his mind. Right? So so Barks has this great hook. It's a character with a huge
physical
fortune. And and now he's gonna develop. All of these different story templates. And and to my eye, first ten or so screwed stories. You're just him trial all these different types of stories
that later he's gonna kinda go back to the well. You know, eventually, we're gonna get kind of comp petitions
over his money, but but he really sets out, I think, some interesting templates for the rest of his run. What do you guys think? I think it's results. Also interesting Barks have used
Scrooge bin being sick for three times already. First back to the plan, memory loss and
is sick of money and stress. And then the mysterious stone right is the skin is full of gold Yeah. Harry,
there is really center about this a billion of something. Like it is already used in Al or trial Barks wants to visualize this billion of something to show people
astronomical
amounts this really are. Yeah, You're right. I talked about that at length and in the trial. Really was something that he was very interested in
just the idea of visualizing that. And thoughts ruben? Well, I think you're completely the right about how Barks are previous from this, but developing the characters, soft Scrooge sanchez. And I definitely feel that from now on, we have the character. Let's find different ways to use it. Right. It's it's almost like he's winding him up and and just seeing what will happen. Right? Because it's such a good hook he's got. Not only the character
himself, but the Money Bin, which we'll talk about here momentarily. Let's see. The the only thing that I did wanna talk about background wise before we get into the story itself is this story is gonna deal with this very
pervasive
long lasting
myth. Right? This this
misconception that people have about le.
Does this drive you guys a little bit crazy as as Norwegian? Does this come up with with people who, you know, the I feel like it's one of the four or five things that Americans think about when they think about Norway. Right? He got like, we're we're scanned
and Jen People think about, like, the swedish chef from the up.
They think about the
they think about Denmark Lego land and and like, and and Ikea, I guess, and that's and Le, and those are the, like, four or so things that Americans know about Canned.
How about it ruben? I don't no. But you Ill, but I don't think you're about letting that much.
Ain't neither. It's not something we usually talk about here.
Not in my everyday talk and
norwegian. I really love talking about what what we call typical marie,
like what is like the most norwegian things? It's the knobs
our national clothing.
It's the moves and it's the... Well, I was almost gonna say polar bear, that's also Made an infection.
Eagles trolls,
the brown cheese that I wanna come back to. Did you say chills?
Yeah. Definitely nice. That that's cool. Yeah. Trolls are actually on the thing or I wanna say. But my point where that I don't put
in that list I never think about lending Al something typical region
along with the fields and the moves and
and the high and stuff like that. So it's actually pretty interesting to see the story and compare what should say, mark about Yeah. Planning being one of things that Americans first think of when the
because because it definitely is. Part of it is that there's such a good metaphor,
right? Or or at least this mistaken idea Right? And that any idea to be clear is is there's the idea that le are this animal that every few years vary seriously
will
end mass, like in in in enormous crowds, they'll migrate towards the ocean, and they'll just keep going
They they they'll swim across rivers and lakes and they treat the c as as a late or something, and they'll just jump off into it and and drown,
you know, and and massive amounts of of le will will die on these mysterious journeys.
Do you?
Well, it is it is true lot le from time to time doing this huge
migrations, but that's just because they for some reason, getting
way to many of them and then they also to move to find fruits and unable to cross river and on and
travel over the moment. That that's not the collective I mentioned. Right. And I think that's the misconception Right? Is that they're deliberately jumping
to mindless leslie, jump into their debts? Yeah. And I just have to do little research because I said I don't actually know
and don't know that much
and I found
live the mountains and whether like swimming
we call when huge amounts of limits. They'll eat up
there's no more mouse or plans
or bear is there and then they'll come down for the mountains and they could come as close as still short but they won't actually survive their So just because there are the type of that that they would eat, I guess and around type of climate that... Or maybe tours welcome come. Right. I don't the gym out the ocean.
I at least I can find any information about it. All of them. Well, what we're gonna talk about later? I don't think so jump into the ocean, but I think they accidentally drone and they tried to cross the rivers reverse and so on. So then it... Maybe people talk them wrong out. When there right. So there's this, like,
misconception. Right? Because anytime that that many millions of something are gonna move in Unison. Some of them are gonna tram folder whatever. But I I guess very famously walt Disney had put out a documentary
called white Wilderness
back in the late fifties,
which in in which it was found later that this crew, this documentary crew is actually hurting them and throwing them off some clips in this very terrible and sensational way
to match the myth that everyone apparently believed about
swimming.
So the... Apparently, this did not create,
you know, the the belief, but it really popularized
it. Because, obviously, time
the in the timeline,
Barb already has this concept.
And and he doesn't really talk about them being like, suicidal or anything like that. But he does talk about it being this, like, mysterious
purge that people don't really understand. So I guess we can talk about it more when we get to that huge c of le
moving about. Very quickly you guys we we're gonna pan to some of our listeners from around the world. I've got a couple of titles
to
to share. And what's more appropriate?
Right? Then for our Norwegian,
set story with a couple of Norwegian guest host,
But for me, the American to do the Norwegian title. So
here, I'm gonna go ahead and butcher it in Norway,
you all call it le yacht in, which is the le hunt. Hopefully, I didn't embarrass myself too badly there.
And then, Mi miguel, you want to
hit us with the Italian title? Yeah. I will I will say So serena in advance if really really but
the italian title is ill
the with.
Yeah pretty good Al far as I know. And how about you, Ruben, you've got Stain? Yeah. I love this very like poetic title. It's ten at
pair and means that thief melts or the correct, I believe. Yeah. I I enjoy that too. The Spanish Publishers
seem to to my eye, they seem to do a better job than many of the countries of finding these kind of poetic fun translations. Alright, you guys. So we've we've talked about kinda of what we're gonna be thinking about and, you know, as we go through the story, we're we're kinda thinking about what is Barks
idea of Norway,
What is this kind of impression that people have of le and how is this early Scrooge adventure
gonna shape up. Are you guys ready to go through the story itself? Okay awesome sign in to the money.
Alright. So
as is the case with so many of these screwed stories. You know, Ruben, we were kinda having exchange about this on Facebook. They they so frequently start out with Scrooge in his money Bin, Either enjoying his fortune or worrying about it. And, you know, I... When I had
Y came from Dan Denmark, who's an editor with Ag on a few months ago. He talked about how Barb did such a good job of, like,
reestablish the character each time. Right? Because this is still a pretty new series
So he would have expected thousands of new readers each month.
And we get a lot of information
about Scrooge immediately
with this opening
where He is focused on his immense vault door.
His office is adorned with money symbols and actual money just laying around.
And and we see that he is very satisfied
with a new safe that he's got. And we we kind of flash back
outside to see his been with a new
configuration. It is
this big block of what he calls in imp.
Al an ind.
Metal. That's ten foot thick, and he's now got seven locks
meaning that his remaining two
So remaining is because Scrooge is p reported to spend
half of his fortune.
On this new bin. Right? And and his remaining two hundred and fifty
fab italian dollars
is safe because
only
he knows the combination for those seven locks.
So so there's
right away on this first page you guys, there's a lot to
unpack here. Did it ever bother you guys when when you would see Scrooge do something like this like spend half of his fortune to protect the other half. I'm kinda happy. It's just extra sketch in the next story because this is kinda crazy.
To see half portion. And then just right after that it will be... It will be scared that is rodent into rat will be now is way into this box Like you even me really bought himself some poor
feeling of safe dealer. Right. Yeah. And and and I'll note too that in these first few uncle Scrooge issues. He identifies the fortune
multiple times and this is yet another new dollar figure that we've got for it. And and we've got this new configuration of the Bin. What do you think about that, Ruben? Yeah. I I couldn't stop thinking about because in the region translations, instead of saying it's his new safe he says it his new one that.
And I see new money. So I think
when was the last time we saw the exterior of the money? And then I just kept digging going further down into rabbit and I actually started...
Let we just say, I'm about to talk about the
evolution of the monitor actually. Because let me just start... This is the last time we see like a configuration of the mono that isn't the iconic one we know. This is like, the last time we see Barks experimenting with the exterior
visual of the one of it. Right. So the first time we saw edit type of one event, I believe, that isn't just a mac Ducktales building entrance is actually in a financial
when he has this corn grip. And the next time we see him is in the terra of the b voice, say nineteen fifty one. We see this skyscraper
with a dollar sign on top. Right. And then becomes a big on K Hill. Well, we mostly see, like it's a on killer hill. And it's a square box, and it with all these wrapped pretty much the one know. The only thing that doesn't really fit is that it doesn't have that giant dollar sign from. Instead of having a safe lock, and oversized face safe look. Bin itself just Barks like an oversized site We just with an idea. And then for Christmas for Check count one year later, we see the mona bam visually or one of the drawings that the scientist hold up to them. So it's only drawing. And then we come to only Al man.
Number one, I believe. Right? Pretty close. That's pretty close. It is we have the big dollar sign on the front, but it's not completely specific. It's more of. Also there are a couple more windows staple details like that. And of course, it be in the city center with.
No k motor hill there. That's which was necessary for the story. Exactly. My the the inside of the money be in the money vault and the Barks have kind to find it already in on the portal man and back to the front So it's just exterior I'm gonna keep changing. I guess
about stereo. That's true. Antonio is shown multiple times. But we... It's very rarely in this space of time. That we actually see the exterior of. Mostly just like this small entrance of the Mac building. So the next time again, is the round one event which is a new one completely, and also that that is different because it's around and then we come to this story with this interpretation with the Ban
Well, mark, would you want to, like, describe product it looks like? Yeah. Sure. In this one, it has definitely its kind of Barks
structure you know, it's a top its perch on the hill. But it has almost this like, vest
front, right? Like an an x str front building or a front front entrance that seems to be devoted entirely to, like, the office space. And honestly, it's it's a pretty cool look for the Bin. You know, I I could see if he... If he had kept this,
and just added that iconic dollar sign. I could see that becoming like the icon look, but there's really no replacing the release Barks
spare, I think, look of the the quote real bin. What what do you think Rubin? Yeah. Exactly. I think it's great. But and kinda
Al like but that like office building in the front that was Al already and there, and then he failed built like this big vault on the back of it. Like a new building connected to it. That's kind of the way I to pay it. It looks great. But I'm very glad that we ended up with the bit with it because it's it's a cube and it's great to be playing right playing around with. In that way. And that one them as we know it will come in the mix four it's in... Yeah. It's in the next four issues after this one of the Scrooge. It won't be shown in land beneath the ground in nineteen fifty six I thirteen.
That that was like you were coming through my lecture of
evolution.
Now there will be a snack Going room. Real sandwiches and left tomorrow glass beef.
I'm.
That is a great ted talk there.
Now thank thank you. That was a cool tour. You know, I I talked a lot about that in my episode on the big Bin. Kim motor Hill, which I paired with the round money bin, but it didn't go into it. Nearly Al systematically. So that was awesome. Thank you. So let's go ahead and delve back into the the progression here.
Interesting that in the very beginning of the story. It's mostly Scrooge
internal monologue. He continues to think about how satisfied he is about how safe his new building is and that it only he has the code
the combination to the seven locks. Which, he places... He's written down on a slip of paper,
any he places
inside a tiny lock.
And then he subsequently hangs the little locket.
Around a small statue of himself and then he just kinda sits back and bath
and and how safe he thinks his money is. What you guys think you you probably were old enough when you read this to to kind of know how this was gonna go. Right? Miguel? Yeah. This is immediately set for catastrophe, because Scrooge not.
It thinks is in control of the situation. And this whole story is basically about the illusion
about being in control. And then screws data plunge into chaos.
I would like to just bind wind back a little before we move on with the story because
the splash panel has screw and Scrooge closing the vendor.
Well, we Al already talked about
our Barks has
established
because we will as a character and the previous stories. Having has only been showing as well And here we have screws closing the door to them to both. Kind of closing the door on all these previous establishing stories from
no on, we move forward the new adventures.
It's kind of a poetic
special panel right there. Yeah. He's not in inside the Bin.
Like, the the vault itself and this one unlike most of Yeah. It's a good point.
The one thing I can start thinking about both when I was here again, this time, Scrooge is hanging at elm around the statute, and what that's that too. It's a great question.
I know I had the same thought as like, a Barks. That... It's such a goofy thing. Right? Because his expression is very un Scrooge like And what weird, like, he's not usually
one to be self centered like that. It's it's interesting. I'm I'm sure we'll we'll mention the duck
episode at the end, but it's interesting that they chose to make that a statue of glittering bold when they adapt it rather than having Scrooge kind of like looking
self obsessed.
So we're gonna transition Al this point. To screws Nephews, Donald Huey, doing wayne Louie are in enjoying
some fishing over by the docks. And
they're they're in the process of taking of a food break. And we get this set up that the Nephews apparently are a big fan of some specific cheese that was imported all the way from Norway. And really quickly you guys I do not associate as an American.
Don't associate Norway with its cheese.
I much heard Barks back?
Okay I I know that every country has, like, it's cheese that it's famous for in Europe. And, like, if you impressed me I could probably have come up with I wouldn't have peg it specifically to Nor out. I mean like, oh, it's the scan one. Right? Because of the name, most Americans are gonna think of France when they think of cheese.
So that that that always struck me a little bit weird. Norwegian cheese. Those don't seem to go together to me. Yeah. I actually
started with this research about that because I talked about what we see here ourselves as typical reach. No. We don't actually see our help as a cheese nation. I see what you see about putting, like, the whole new Europe and like, everyone has its cheese permissions.
But
probably six or seven.
European countries that I would have named that I would have associated
first.
Exactly. So I like I had to Google black reach and cheese when it's going up. And then of course, there's an article that says like, oh, what we I actually have ever rich? Please cheese tradition. It's just not that loan out of get. But I did wanna mention the brown cheese that we do see
and it is it's goat cheese. And it's more like caramel ish. And sweet. And also, we have, like, the y'all that Michael mentioned that is like if it's famous for being like this cheese wheel, and I believe you can buy in some stores in the united states. It's not that it doesn't work. It just... I don't make the connection. Immediately. What about you Miguel? I think the reason the reason Barks think about cheese when I am hear about no because he lived in Minnesota for his mere prepared of time. And apparently, there was a little cheese
cheese instructor her, named Larson
or larson cheese. And it might be the... From there, I got this
new information about norwegian because there many
reaching immigrants moved minnesota Right. Start living there. Yeah. So they they grab their sack, their lunch sac, and Donald will notice that it feels a little bit heavier than it should, and they
discover they don't know that... Yet, that it's a lemon, but we're introduced to the landing of the title.
And and so he's a really funny little animal. Right? It's it's funny when Barks plays around with quote real animals. In his funny animal stories. But he's like very or. He's always coming in, like a fighting pose that deluxe are gonna learn he's very clever, but also very skit. And,
you know, he's eating all the cheese in the bag. And they're they're a bit curious about it so they decide they un unable
decide that they're gonna ask Uncle Scrooge
about
blaming. Him key being a a man of the world.
And you guys... I I think I could have predicted Scrooge is reaction immediately. It's it's pretty... It's it's a little silly that the Nephews
think he has any interest in, like, an animal and isn't gonna react this way. But it definitely works for the story progression. Right? Yeah. Barks us to introduce chaos into the screw office.
Right. And and that that's a great point, Miguel, because Scrooge that were set up with this nice orderly
system that Scrooge has here and and now he's just gonna throw it into array. So Scrooge does react to the way we expect him to he pretty much only ever thinks about animals as environments that want to destroy his money One of you guys mentioned them how ridiculous the idea is that this little rodents
could chew his way through the in imp
den. But Scrooge just freaks out and he he makes the situation worse by panic. This something I always tell my kids. Right? If you're If you're upset, take a moment
to make sure you stay calm because Panic can always makes the situation worse.
And Ruben, do you wanna tell us how his panic makes this situation worse? Well, he started chasing the rat as they call it around the office. And
it jumps on top of the chair, that screws previously used to stand on when hanging the on top of his statue himself and also setting up this same for equipment because it jumps on top of that chair onto to add the. The statue you and Gladstone to that statue tips over with the lemon into the into the floor, the statue breaks, and falls of it and on to the living make right. And and so we've got... We've got our setup right guys for the whole rest of the story. It's... It's going to become a chase
story. We're getting at all these little chase sequences the rest of the way. So he knows where he's going with this.
You guys this sequence
seemed to me like something that would probably work better.
Right? It's hard to depict this kind of like, frantic
motion
effectively. But does a pretty good job here, but this strikes me as like a story board where you're like, oh, this still look really good once we realize it as a car too. I agree. The the necklace itself
actually is too small to wrap around the big let head So I believe that would work better and some type animation. Yeah. There there's a little bit of cartoon and logic gets it there. What do you think we miguel? No. I really agree that this is very much an internet story, and it also becomes very clear once they get to the ship, try to catch just wrecked. Yeah. The that part is
is basically animation still.
Exactly. It's gonna be... It's gonna be that very slaps stick. So the Ducktales
Scrooge explains the importance of what he has in the locket and the fact that he can't remember one combination let alone service. Screws panic kinda scares the skit
le, the skit rodent into jumping out the window. And and at that point, they have no choice but to, you know, pursue him. And he Barks a ship with the ava evo name, the Moon golf, you know, at this point, He also...
And so, you know, the Ducktales feel like they've got him corner and they head to the docks.
But, of course,
they are just a little bit too late and and it has taken off. And Miguel, you wanna tell us about
change with the sale there? Well, screws is coming down running and then you see this sale run. It shows hey, sailor. Where that Scrooge going? And the sailor Al
transfer who knows fishing go everywhere the cactus have an next call it goes very points fish is next porch. Of
Casablanca.
Yeah. So I like the setup. Right? This the... It feels very hope list. It feels like the the saying in in English would be... It feels like a needle in a haystack.
So it it really does feel hopeless.
And so the the setup is very exciting. Next we get to, like a sequence where he charter a helicopter
but a fog Barks ends up foil him and they have to turn back. I'm not gonna go into too much detail every little bit here. Right? And and, basically, Barks is doing a really good job of of of setting up this logical
progression.
For why they're gonna end up following the le
back to its home. And so as they ponder this dilemma. The Nephews have a really good idea. Ruben, you wanna tell us their their suggestion to Scrooge. Yeah. I just have a simple idea. That just the scooter will land some place
notify every sea in the world to hold the
theirs and a Scrooge just pair like, oh, that's simple. That will. Yeah. I I really liked that because, like, sometimes in in these stories they... It it annoys me when they don't come up with the most logical
next step, that really is exactly what he should do. In this situation, I feel like. Right? It's it's a good next step. And so it leads to this passage of time where weeks later
Right, We imagine Scrooge has been been just incredibly stress over this passage of time. He gets the notification that they're done with their fishing,
and they're being held
in herring tail
Norway. And and sp does this great thing where like, he's always having the Ducktales pack up
prepared on a moment notice. I've gotta imagine guys that at some point, they just keep standing suitcases for one Scrooge is like, come on. We're getting on the plane. That reservation.
And and,
why don't you tell us about their
conversation? Oh, go ahead Ruben, you had some and... Yeah. I just wanna tell, you know, I had Al plane book. That's right. The book is called fly or pre in region and it's by kids
nordic in two thousand fourteen. And
it tells that the airplane they used to... It says it's on analog
cancellation it was produced from nineteen forty three to nineteen fifty eight and was used for cross atlantic travel
index in this
fly is written by call and clear
by or or the evaluation... The norwegian and aviation museum very cool. It's amazing how
the length that Barks went to to get his aircraft accurate.
So
Nico miguel, why don't you tell us about their approach
and just kinda your impressions of our our first glimpse of Norway and what the Ducktales talking about. Well, so do son no or the plane and then screws explained that they're holding to ship in the forge and they will board border shape and find that rats. And then one of the nephew Nephews
tell that if is still a board, and Scrooge don't expands that's tedious the crew man have seen him, and then nephews
claim that your troubles will soon be over uncle.
I don't think probably will be Al
right. And and we get them arriving at herring tale, I'm gonna guess you guys that this is a sectional place name. Oh, no. Harry is beautiful I area should go.
I interesting that hair tale is basically the same name as Colbert houston in
the special panel of the Golden Helmet with the the old viking shipping they're in her Norway. That's
use this name. It's a lovely little drawing of this fishing village. But this is
we really nailed the the western coast
looked of this place. Yeah I was gonna ask you guys because to me it looks very realistic. It looks very evo about it, but I I wouldn't know. Well. Well, I wanna say, like, from a distance, the the small village and the mountains around it. And it looks it looks pretty accurate. I clint looks like this could be like somewhere over the the west far away. Yeah. And and so our next sequence is that one that we were alluding to a little bit earlier where it's this really slaps stick
series
of them trying to catch
the le. I guess they're still calling him a rat at this point.
It's it's
it's a bunch of comic mayhem.
You know, I'm not necessarily too interested in in the specifics of these pratt falls. It's it's fun. But, again, it kind of brings me back to Donald duck finds pirate gold where, like it it really does feel a little bit like an animation story board. No one beats sparks when he's drawing, like, these naval scenes on top of shit you know, he does such great detail where on the ship.
You know, but there's pratt falls with the harpoon gun and a polly and and Scrooge getting dizzy running up on on the circular platform that I guess
more modern ships would have instead of a crow nest. And eventually,
they start to get smart because as the captain has mentioned, this rodent is is very craft. So they try to
lure him with a piece of that cheese. You know, he returns to this cheese.
One of you guys wanna tell us about the top hat sequence.
Yeah. They still call it them the rest So one of the nephew
explain that brother is really disappeared. Along the guru asks where d hide that we haven't looked then one nephew spot with lan and say that he's not in the board and anymore uncle Scrooge. There he goes. Sailing in your hats. And another Scrooge explains
that and that has cost me two dollars in nineteen ten, and this is of course, one detail that Donna rosa would later through use and the life and financial subscription deck by showing skill actually actually buying this hat in. Yeah.
It's
detail.
No
far. Yeah. So you guys this that little moment where
where the rodent is is sneaking around under the hat that feels very, like, donald Duck Cartoon to me. They're not not in the best way. It's not not my favorite sequence. But does work to get him to get him over to shore. Right? Because he's got this convenient little boat. What do you think rubin? And I agree toll because like, they're all sweating they're all looking at the
pizza cheese that are put floor and they're all all the
and all the nephews are standing with minutes rated to catch that. And then Scrooge head just come crawling or what is sliding or around along the deck? It is very donald duck part tony. To me. And it's not so much that the le is that smart but more that the other characters are being a little bit well stupid in this one. Exactly. So so the next sequence is the Ducktales going
to to follow the le And they passed by a couple of little local Barks kids.
Right? And and you guys I imagine, this is Barb wanting to give some flavor of local people. I will give you my impression as an American is that Number one, these kids do look very stereotypical typically scan
me. Number two, they're they're they're drawn kinda creepy. They are really crazy.
It's so Al it's the dollar eyes. And you wants to highlight the blue eyes
their blue iris, and therefore it's drawn the pupils and very very small. Yeah. They're very
unsettling.
Lucky. I always.
I thought that kid and I failed thinking Yeah. And bricks really could draw kids, like in the pool Barks story have kids who feel like kids to this more realistic,
kind of and genuinely Al. Yeah. Yeah.
Everything
But like to,
like they're clothing and their parents. Like in that way, that's actually accurate. Nice you talk talk about it being
the girl is wearing some kind of know the inspired clothing. And I think the boy is wearing typical fifties
small region ish clothing and both wearing boots, standing and fishing. I think that's pretty accurate. Yeah. The she and the girl is wearing this
simplify the hard on not cactus kind of and alone that's just to capital...
Yes you said needed that maybe? Yeah. Yeah. That's true. And.
So the... At least these creepy looking kids are able to finally tell us what what the rat is. That that he is Al lemon. They're like, oh, you mean that lending with the lock we did see it going through the village toward the up land trail and and you know, the steaks keep going up. This is becoming more and more like a needle in a hay tax scenario. And as the docks get into the village, we get a predictable, but very cool sequence where each of them thinks he has found the le
because what what they're seeing is one of these
migrations
or
as I read someone referred to it, It's not so much a migration, but a
dispersed. The the animals are being just dispersed because of, like, food pressure is what really happens.
But whatever you call it, it is one of these great lemons on the move.
Events.
And and the Inducks,
you know, they have to like. They're looking checking for line kits on all of these le and it's seeming more and more hopeless and one of them...
One of them angrily bites Donald finger, and then and then he gets
swarmed. It's it's a fun panel. It's a good... It's what we wanna see happen to Donald. I'm sorry donald. This. It's very accurate as well because lending are famous
because or their fan for being angry. And there's yeah little myth that I can explode with anger and just flat all lower.
Not through that. They it has been the.
But
compared to, like,
both creditors and also skiing norwegian skin and hiking
migrations up in the mountains. So I believe some people have been bitten or probably many people have done
by by while hiking in the summertime time the.
Yeah. They
they might be small, but They have they're ferocious.
So, yeah, it seems like a good choice for the story. Ruben, do you wanna tell us about the Nephew little d tour?
I just want to highlight
panel where the kids are pointing to watch the city. So first, I just wanna ask you Barks, what do you think about the scandinavian architecture here? This scan
architecture... I get a good look at it mostly from that
panel with the two kids pointing toward that plan trail. I'm.
Right. I mean, first off, it looks very
picturesque.
I noticed that a lot of the houses seem to have, like, pretty steep gable roofs for for snow. I assume.
Yeah. There's nothing about it. That's standing out as being... It it kinda looks generic northern Western
European me. There's nothing about it. That looks like, I would be able to identify it. Al Norwegian. I find it kind of more German looking in some ways. So I like this little detail that for said with the stay and state church
dragon heads or brothers spikes that he has added on the rooftop sir? To... I guess
guess Huey,
mistakenly thought this was a very normal norwegian way to decorate rates the rooftop. Yeah. I think that's great. Still is a Barks word Barks
phrase. It's a great catch.
But I just wanna say that to me, it also just feels like this generic
European type. It's it looks more like dutch and twists and German to me than actually scandinavia. But the... I I can't do you kind forgive it because I can see how americans would find it hard to differentiate
different
architecture type I I think he's made a good effort for at least. Yeah. If it it's okay. So why don't you tell us about the little d tour? Al the nephew take. I will
that they've been searching for a long time, So they wanna... What that you says, let's find the store where we can buy some of that you cheese. And then they see that little store which by the way, that's accurate or reaching Barks architecture right there.
Where I sell that cheese, that is called large,
or large cheese and.
Just like the point out Barks really went through great lengths and is written sign in the region. Exactly only made one little mistake with Al drop because was or now larson
it's just written in one word and working in the in norwegian. Not mushrooms.
That's true. And I also go inside that cheese store, and we could also mention that.
Inside the cheese store, I... There are more no norwegian Barks. There are two piles of cheese that says no
That would be a north cheese. I don't know that one. And close to the viewer, there are also two packages of app. Tools that would be coke cheese. I believe it's the problem cheese maybe. And also I see that was
a my edition they called red
behind the
the goat cheese. That looks like some sort of
or maybe Iceberg and they see that big pile of or the big kind they call it of a whole cape of that type of cheese they like very much. So that buy that for for almost nothing because the guy who owns this he expects the will eat up in store time one of the you say. So they run away with this big problem. That I love so much, and that will be their food for the rest of me week maybe.
Yeah. That would... That much cheese makes my stomach hurt. Although, I I do love me a good goat cheese.
But I I really like I like their very clever solution, right? How to keep it safe. That they suspend it hanging in mid air from a a telephone wire. Which, of course, is gonna become very important. Also like the covers.
With the new rules he wrote it into
different ways. Both in one word, new, and you also used it with
with the hyphen just to be sure that Huey, at least one of them most the correct spelling. Right. And, you know,
it's worth really highlighting that it's cool that he got that right. Because, like, he didn't have Google translate.
The way that I did. So he had to go to some effort to to figure that out. Right? And on some of his stories, Huey, he uses kinda like native lingo for some characters and another stories. He like goes to more pains to get it right. So he obviously was interested in having this be at least a little bit like a travel lobby.
So as the nephews
recon
with their uncles, you know, Scrooge is telling them to come on that they're heading up towards that up lens trail, and they're pondering
how they are seeing more and more le.
As they go get along, and they encounter a local that tells them you haven't seen anything. Yeah. Wait until you get up on the farmland land above very ominous.
And, you know, this is one of those cases where I don't have to like think about how the characters can all speak to them in English because, like, most Norwegian
speak very good English. Well, thank you.
So also I just want to notice that the the guy informed them about this. I believe you may be escaping or running away from towel, but it looks like that it's it's a great accurate
representation of an norwegian hike Alright. So you guys were we're gradually getting to the, like, really big
anticipated sequence here. It's it's easy to imagine that this is what Barks really wanted to lead up to. The whole time I I think in a lot of these stories. He has a a moment
that he's really starting with. Right? Because the Nephews are gonna see these trails of of le
converging.
And
one of them ominous
says there must be a big band of them where all these runs of le get together. And as they crest this hill part, we see this. And it's a it's a very cool
extremely memorable
splash panel. We see what seems to be millions
you know, this this might be that exploration for their exploration of what does a billion of something look like
Moving
across the side
like a blanket.
And and as a reader we're thinking, wow. We're we're thinking they're... They must be eating everything in their path. But most of all, we're thinking about the impossibility
the en normally
of this task of finding this one lemon in that teaming mass
and knowing
what is about we're we're gonna find out what is about to come. Thoughts you guys? Well, if cob didn't have to that billion bottle caps in Al
sure they get that. Huge hair.
Right. Absolutely. It's a great flash panel left. I probably saw this splash panel
way before I read the store. Because was published in some.
Talk about oh, the norwegian Barks story. Ninth great. I love it. And also you further there miguel. We chatted the for the podcast and you're talked about about some coloring
where the not norwegian
whether of the west coast is accurate and harry actually
grew of a big pile of wind and
and clouds and that's again, glitch for
the western Norway
western norwegian climate. I just like to point out that the example you've been mentioned with the the caller is the Gladstone,
Album
no norwegian sky is pretty gray and, yeah, that's very accurate for the best western cons that's inside of Norway. This always raining there
Nice. Also, I would just like to add that I exactly we
Barks that this probably is like I believe Barks and many of these stories have this like panel like it wants to visualize and often the of page slash panel. And I'll just love the idea of thinking about how Barks come up with this idea. Yeah. You can't
you can't identify it on every story. But there's definitely a handful of them where like Oh, that... That's what you wanted to do here. What do you think we can? Yeah. I think Ports really did a good job here, this especially family. We certainly got some help from National geographic because in August nineteen
fifty four, there was article particular about
describing a American
and taking a sale tour from post to Bargain And
I was
nineteen fifty four
the national Geographic Magazine also has some picture from lisa, where there was this rates alan and picture of where. Of a man looking out Al least view, and you can see that a picture was played Al huge role and it's inspiring Barks for his panel. Yeah. Thanks for earth that. We'll we'll make sure to put that up
on the Facebook page for sure. It's a it's a great panel. It's one his most iconic I would say for a reason, it's a probably a big part of why people remember this story fondly on a.
And also I also like how we see the Inducks from the back camry we like units from the same view as the Inducks. Definitely agree. It's a great perspective shot. That choice he makes there is is excellent.
And I really like the sequence that follows. Right? The the sequence that follows is is just really about the futility of what they're trying to do. It's about Barks,
surrounding them
with all of these,
like, mindless, the ram paging le.
It's about Scrooge just bearing, you know, there's a moment where donald
votes that they just give up because it's a lost cause. There's a funny Al little bit where he provides all the votes by saying, I I I.
And and we get to see Scrooge looking both, like, it's it's both funny, but it's also very sad as he's
commenting that he can't give up. He'd sit penn lists and starving outside the door is safe with two hundred and fifty
fabulous trillion dollars
inside that couldn't touch. Yeah. I also likes
with at that's Scrooge is not invisible. He has this breakdown on that makes him view.
It's not always on top of things. Right.
That's a really good thing Barks there. Definitely it. To me it evo the moment in horse rash. Story. We're just basically saying I I can't give up. I have no choice. I I nothing.
Otherwise. Because this He is his fortune basic. And, you know, this sequence is so cool. The le are like this rolling wave that that's basically eating everything in their path
they pass another person
fleeing with a chest of whatever world
he could get and and the states go up here because they've never really had the chance to, like, learn about Le. And so Scrooge asks,
mister what causes this flood of le. Do you want it ruben do you wanna share his response? I can I can do bit reach and accent actually?
This go for it. So he he asked you know, mister her, what causes is this flood of le? Says Scrooge.
No.
We just get out way every few years they leave their homes and start watching Al your
migration, maybe they're be
which, Maybe they're only looking for more and different food. They more everything in their involved awesome. They're do the go. They keep going until they reach this team. And not even that stops the the plug of the clips into the rails and swim
bone Severino goes back to the mountains.
So it's a great setup of what the steaks are, even if it's definitely playing into this, you know, myth. Even if even if none of that true. The fact that there... His lock is on Al le.
It's
it's still an impossible task base And and I like the desperation over the next couple of pages. The dots are trying all these last ditch
attempts
And
I I love this sequence. And for whatever reason even though this is very slap stick. It just works for me so much better than the ship stuff. Maybe it's because of the urgency, maybe it's because of all the le.
I I can't place it. But but I love it. Right? The they're, like, building these walls, what do you think rubin? Yeah. And also it feels way more dramatic now because you can really see how, like they see the serious
and to see how how the task is because there was only that one learning on the ship that I need to catch and what's this
mouse type of thumb. But there it is more hard like like even in the haystack and they and it's a moving haystack. And
if the haystack
reaches the ocean, they'll never see it again. And also like, Scrooge tests and what the ritter it thinks it's like this is truly a nightmare. There Barks so many
I have to check out each one but are so many and they're moving so fast
So it's really just that and it's section nightmare. The experiences says. Yeah. That... That's the word for it. Right? It's hopeless.
And really feel the clock is ticking. Right. There this great sense of urgency.
The the lam keep devour everything that the Ducktales are trying to do to help. Right? As they go to get a view up up a tall tree,
they they they devour it down, essentially,
likewise a hay stack and nephew goes to look up there.
They try to build walls
to stop them. You guys I really like these panels where they're just, like, hopeless
trying to bat them backwards
with switches with branches.
And we see them plunging into the seat. We see the inevitable
thing happen.
I like that we do see them attempting to swim, you know? So there's none of this, like, they're they're not trying to commit suicide or anything like that. But but they are this un unstoppable
force And
after hours past, you see
screws, just kind of pitiful
half hearted
looking at the last few str wars
as they pass.
And Miguel, do you wanna tell us about the
splash the mini splash panel that expands the page at the bottom. Scrooge door we're overlooking this the ocean and looks so waste and all this naked clips and the sea goes flying and don't just say their gone on.
The last of the millions has gone over the clips.
And Scrooge
say yes. And the last of my has come with them. This a great panel. It makes him you. It makes the reader just so, I this Yeah. It's very Barks it it feels it's devastating. Right? And the way their shadows
are are
being cast now gives us the idea that time is asked and
everything that that works really well. Box was really
informed of you from of using these shadows to really drive on the point of hopelessness. So we also use starting home world man.
Just lost this fortune to the bagel boys.
Just before it gets that right Id. But Harry, he doesn't get any right And how to save his fortune he's through the last and then screwed
I will bear my property like a mom. I will be brave in the face of disaster. I won't cry and then he just boils down to the ground and starts sobbing and holding and don't stay this standard.
Not much that is.
It's it's a good comic be. It's pretty predictable, but but it's it's very funny. And sp just looks very different seated here and And then Ruben, do you wanna tell us about how the nephews
decide to cheer him up and and what they discover? Yeah. They just...
The letters, I just suddenly remember that that the cheese they're hanging from the phone wire. So they go get that to Up
chairs and man that I most to remember the Federal Lil
or something dollars, more than a decent cheese. So they're hoping it's still there And when they come there, they are shocked to see that it's a big hole in the chase, and it's also a airway way build up sticks. That's leaning up from the ground up to it. So when they come closer, and I see the how is about the size of a living and the left other that response yes.
Lending... There's only one living in the world smart enough to figure out this their setup up. So they look inside and they see that exact living with the login around it the view don't see it. But is the... But one of the left tells the viewer the other,
of course, that his name there, And he's just been eating so much they can't get out of that hole he just and can tell but. You guys this part works, I think fabulous.
This is such a great solution. It's it's
super unlikely, it's super coincidental
that there's something very funny about the idea of this Clever little room and
the the Clever Little rodent eating his way into being too big to escape. I I like this element of the story a lot. We don't usually see the Nephews have the w
exclamation I don't think. Right? I think that's mostly a donald thing. That baby. I don't know. I won't fat check yet. But And also...
About something we don't see nephew due to often but when I discovered this, one of the nephews gels Barks Scrooge, and it runs towards this location.
And I believe that is you read us. It says stop. Wait. Let's tell him just yet because if we work this so right, we may be able to get a rich reward we're finding the log So actually try to up trick Scrooge
giving them some... But maybe they get some reaches from this. And they other... And yeah. How does the other that he respond? It's it's a funny gag. It's so funny. It's a funny line. He says we're we're only Inducks, not magicians, but I'm with you.
So I like that too. Yeah. You're right. We don't usually see them be a little bit greedy. But on the other hand, they... As far as I concerned, they definitely
deserve a rich reward here. Kinda reminds me of
horse
story right where they're going to some length to make sure that they can collect their wages.
Yeah. True. This this time non Scrooge not even paying them thirty cents an hour. They're not any payments.
Yeah. We haven't heard it. I think we can imagine
maybe there too... They they feel too guilty to... I guess it's probably contingent. His... Their wages are gonna be contingent on him getting into that safe, obviously.
So
the the story is then I can include. And what looks like a a relatively
nice... I guess it's not a restaurant. It must be like the the dining room of the in that they're standing at. And they've set up that cheese. And, you know, Donald is looking really cheerful.
He may or may not be in on what the nephews have planned,
but he at least looks excited to to be sitting down and ready to go home Scrooge is just looking desolate and the nephews are looking very, like, right and and sure of themselves because of what they've got planned. And and so as they prepare to dig into that cheese, they they start to kinda talk up a deal
asking
him if you were to... If if we were to suddenly find your lock for you, how big a reward would you give us? And fridge kind of gestures that he would give them a chunk of gold three feet around and six inches
thick. And the Net Barks satisfied they've heard enough
so they do their big reveal.
They flip over the cheese with has, like, a little trap door that they seem to have blocked the the le in there with. And they reveal him
and he is
still just incredibly full. I I imagine the inside of that cheese would be pretty gross by that point, guys. Yeah. Problem probably.
I I know.
Also,
the purpose is I think bubbles so thinking that is working.
Yeah. That's great. He's got a little burp sound effect, but only inside his own little le head.
And and he looks very funny and Scrooge of course, is delighted and he calls out the title.
The le with the locket
And Let living with my.
Yes. Excuse me. Not quite the title. The landing with my lock
And and that that is our ending. We get a brief little comic cap.
Mi miguel, you wanna tell us about the the nephews
getting their reward. Yeah. So uncle Scrooge gets well again and the boys get their reward. Unless the Barks is boarding the home board
Line. You didn't carry a big wheel of cheese. And one of the nephews with annual faces. At cheese. That's the reward. Right on just like on Scrooge promise It's three feet around and six inches six. And is gold
all the way through caller that is. And one of them is... One of them is saying it,
What what of them are saying you'd like long.
Yeah. Not. And one of them just find money Yeah Yeah. And find it funny is actually the one who
at least in my conversation.
The one time that funny is the one that wasn't in on the idea in the first place or Al least wasn't with baggage. Right. Yeah. They they all have this kind of air of
expiration. Like, what are you gonna do? That's our uncle Scrooge.
Exactly. You guys this the ending doesn't really work that well for me. It's it's a silly
thing to say, you know, gold is is clearly not cheese. Cheese is not gold.
I get what he's going for there. But I don't know. I don't think it's the most successful
gag that he's ever end with. Kind cheesy.
Whatever it really is.
It's a cheesy joke.
But but...
Like mark, can you please add the sign anything music right after life.
You know the the the actual
ending. The little construction
of
of how they find the le. I do find that very satisfying.
I do enjoy the way it wraps up. Otherwise, I I just prefer not to do dwell on this
silly little gag that doesn't live up to a lot of his efforts for me. But
but but that's that's the I with the lock at you guys. I I think we covered the story really nicely. And and now, you know, we can kinda talk about what what
how
how do we receive this story? What do you guys think did you enjoy? Do you think it was a good representation of Norway? I mean, that's not obviously the most important. Thing. But what do you think Ruben? Well, as I said earlier, it's like it's true Barks
Norway they're in the first place. I love that thought. And this but and the story itself, it's a fun idea.
My love like they're chasing like this animal that is
Al lot many aspects of it. I love how like that the of it is Scrooge having it's big fortune not but that they can't reach. It knows where it and everyone knows where it is, but no one can enter. That's what in danger hair. I like that ninety end. Like the idea that they're chasing like it's animal,
which has, like, the key to this great great amount but wealth
So that'll of course, I like the fact that there are in More. So I I like kinda know like the panel about
know this flash panel, the great one but letting submitting Al a carpet. But just the store itself, it's it's okay. When you see Al the whole thing it's it's okay. It's a pretty good Barks story but not I'm on the greatest than might opinion. No. We could surely just swap out
the text some other characters and the store still kind of work. You just
have something else than the lock combination from Scrooge just have a letter or a
code or something and you could use Mickey or some other characters
I think it's a fine story. It's not not as strong Al the eight previous sample Scrooge ventures. It's fun. And this, of course, very cool that I go to Norway.
Yeah. For sure. I I think I largely agree with you guys, you know, it's a very good very enjoy
even very memorable
story. It's gonna suffer a little bit compared to some of the recent ones just because they were so good. Right? Because, like, this... And they... And they had deeper Scrooge
themes.
Only a poor man and back to the Al can even the horse rather story and control Al. They like really had something to say. They had some big ideas in them. And there's nothing wrong with the fact that this one doesn't. It's just a good solid Scrooge adventure.
And we're gonna get a lot of those. But like thinking about it alongside the... This group of the first ten Scrooge stories that I'm I'm choosing to do that because it's... It makes for a good podcast. I think this one is is like, kinda and middle of the road
as far as the other adventure stories go. Right? I... Just for pure Adventure, nothing touches
secret of Lan.
That's just the the... To me, that's the best of the adventure stories
in this early cohort.
And like, I think it's probably a little bit better. I enjoy it a lot more than, like, the mysterious stone ray, which is probably for me the weakest of them.
Likewise, I like it a little bit better than I enjoyed the fabulous
philosopher
stone. But I don't know if it quite holds up to, like the seven cities of S,
which just was
really twisty, and turn
and and really memorable as far as and pure adventure stories go. But but for a lot of the reasons that you mentioned,
I I love the... I love the kind of needle and the haystack stack ass expect of it. I love the feeling of despair. And I love what they did with the le
himself
with his journey and and how it eventually
resolved and wrapped up. I think I think it's a good
standard Barks adventure that
is remembered fondly
for reason. Definitely and ask some great visuals as well like that most of the big
panel with living moving as of carpet. That's we'll make it really like
memorable I to say more. Yeah. That's something.
And I think I never get that and I have one le
having to find in that big pile of fleming. I find that very remember. Yeah. The the story has a great hook. First. Sure. Yeah.
So, you know, I've compared it a little bit to the other stories from this era. But let's go ahead and check him on what the community
actually thinks about this one by looking at Inducks,
you know, the site where people can vote on on what they think.
About these stories, and this one gets a very respectable rating as of of today, it's got a seven point nine out of ten, which makes it good for number fifty one out of all the, like, forty two thousand or so Disney stories that are rated. So I mean, that that kind tracks for me. Right? Because it's people I think have a lot of goodwill for this story because it is an early Scrooge
adventure.
And it just has such a strong memorable
hook. It's a very famous story. So I think it's gonna naturally
stand out. I might not rank it white that high myself,
but I I don't think that's like, out of bounds. I don't think that's off too too far off track. What you guys think? No. I... Out of the first ten years adventures, I would probably rank this either
last or second last
the the fabulous philosophy Gladstone is of course, very great fresh and story, but I I think that one also is kind of weaker on dates
previous stories. I personally like to mister Stone Ray. But of course, none of them really are quite up there with the secret of Ot land or back to the clone or They're just They just kind of go the little extra mile
Yeah. Yeah. I yeah I think it's a strong story
it's good
I really like that Barks sent to. As I previously said the he sent
Norway when it was still in his golden and age when it comes to character drawing. So that's circle.
You know, it's interesting
that
as of this point, is it's he hasn't really gone to Europe that much.
At this point in the Ducktales adventures. It's it's in these first few stories he's gonna start Scrooge stories. He's gonna start exploring that a little bit more.
But yeah, it till, like, castle secret and danger to skies. And then for a long time that was not really much in Europe, which which I find interesting.
So you guys... Let's talk a little bit about other, like, references and adaptations.
We had alluded to this being
used as one of the episodes of duck
I think did did we all rewatch the episode? Yeah. I worked with yesterday.
I see but before what recording. Yeah. I got to... Rewatch it this morning.
And and I have been revisiting at least some brief scenes of some of these episodes as they have corresponding ones for the stories. Like, I watched a little bit of back to the lawn. I can I watched some of the for t la? And I not this episode is actually pretty strong compared to those.
I don't I don't know what you guys think, but it's called... It's called Scrooge
pet So, you know, he they change it a little bit. But but they change it in a way that actually Barks for me rather than just doing a straight up Al expectation.
The kids wanna get screwed to pat. And as mentioned, it ends up being kind of a list full reminder of glittering gold because that's the statute that the lock goes on. And he's relieved when it doesn't shatter. So I I liked it. I don't always love the the original app so the way that I did as a kid, but I found that one really enjoyable.
What do you think Ruben? Well, it's a pretty good episode, and it's a pretty good rotation of the story it's not accurate because the change some bits. Moved back and forth. Of course, we use large pad and credit instead of donald. And it's Al complete link different character. But I think it's a decent since Episode. And also I like the idea how to introduce the in another way because they're still at the harbor when they are introduced to the learning, but let's they have like
a different motivation of it. And I I will say it's better. Because it isn't
Al lot the our Barks. But it it's pretty good. Let's say
the alive is so that's pretty much can't I'd say Al least the story wise is pretty much the story for them to start from dot. But this it's more
adaptation. The pull it in another way. What did you think we miguel? Oh, as a ruben said they he still not way to
introduce the lending and it just don't send me that that's pretty similar to hold the priority and the pixel lite Barks was introduced. They can't yeah kinda use that one for lam. That's done. That's honestly, I I found the introduction of the lam more believable in the cartoon. I... I'm not saying it's better. But I did find it more believable.
It definitely did not treat Norway as respectfully as a Barks.
No way.
Pretty pretty silly stereo
of, yes. They call it no way instead of Norway, which makes for a couple of silly yeah. And all the people run their own. They run around and leather the ro and and... Yeah. And they speak very
where the we're reaching us kinda made think about the x files episode where better or in Norway. Yeah. I haven't seen that one myself. I know you guys talked about... But apparently a pretty cri version. Yeah. That's and also, I know the because they're like. Because I remember it's more being a German accent probably because a wearing leather.
And again, the architecture is like his mickey town, so switzerland meets switzerland lamp.
I'll tell you.
Go ahead. No. I just wanna say that.
But if they're more pulling it than like this,
swedish chef type of talking. So Yeah. It is like
I see that this swedish is Jeff already where started this
probably for whatever I know it didn't start it. But it's like this. That's what...
It's like this cultural
agreement and how the scanner made stock.
But, of course, I'm not talking about since they're just talking
words within in that in that type of...
Yeah. They're they're pulling up pulling the
around see. Yeah. And they're doing like the the try to, like, because I've heard that the norwegian of canadians, it's sounds like we're singing when we're
talking, and that's probably what we're trying takes. Yeah. On the hold, though, it's a pretty successful at episode as far as the handful of Barks
Ducktales
that they did. I think it might be one of the best. Yeah. I'll have to think about that. Think the land beneath the ground optic adaptation might be my favorite of them. But...
Yeah. The one pretty solid. Let's see.
I'm not aware of any other major sql that any other Comics creators did to this. I think Rosa might have snuck a Cameo
in his like, Olympic story, there was, like, a little lemon cameo or something in that one, but but just an off hand thing.
Yeah. Let's see. And you guys any any other thoughts anything else you wanted to highlight before we transition to favorite panels and and wrap things up. Yeah. I would just like to mention that the period when Barks was making lending documents
Since he wanted to visualize this a billion of something.
That would end up giving in... Giving him quite a headache. He wife Gary Williams and sometimes to get married in July. And they're have to go on six week holiday. And when the day for leaving was approaching guys still missed much a bunch of linking.
Especially on le So this become kind of a joke about among their friends and neighbors. Would I get to start finished before they went on their holiday?
So Get told
story roughly like this. When we finally have finished
that dun
lending
story. We just showed it Hooray and one of the neighbors come running and ask if you had finished and be answered Yes. We are done.
So
rest out with this getting the story done and in know... In a sense you can perhaps feel this urgency
for Barks to get done with the story that it kinda got himself in stick bid. He had to draw his.
Yeah. Thanks for sharing that. That's a a dynamic to. I think I saw that a long time ago, and I didn't encounter it in in we
reading and researching for this episode Barks off and he you gotta imagine that he off has this thought of, like, why did I make him so rich
and he's he's always kind of exploring ways to draw few of the actual coins in those bin scenes, but make it look as convincing as possible. Because he really does. He sets himself up sometimes for drawing all these millions of coins and bottle caps and le and jewels
sometimes. So... Yeah. That's that's funny thing to think about. Any any other thoughts have just one little more story that
in the eight region eighty character and a friend, he sent a letter Barks were told him all good this norwegian story was, and they wondered if he... They received Norway. Something Barks sadly haven't. So The same is... I
with mail and when it arrived
Barks place, it was
on the soft it was apparently tasty and there was... Is there that they sent them? They go both. Yeah. The goat jeez. But there was a picture. There was a picture of a rain there on the package. So Bark thought it was rain cheese. And I don't think you learned into until many years later that there is no such thing as rain.
That's funny. I mean, they're mammals so you you can milk them. So some... Someone must have made it at some point, but clearly, it's not something that's like in wide beige. Right? It's probably gonna be some person in the chrome that tell them.
Oh, there is right cheese sprite. Right. Awesome. Well you guys... We we definitely covered a lot of the great panels.
In this story. There are some really wonderful
splash panels.
Are there any any that you'd like to kinda go back two or other panels that you'd like to highlight as a favorite or notable panel? Yeah. I just wanna tell that it's this... It's kinda interesting to see the panel where the download and nephews are actually packing for the visit. Because and that's kinda like some behind the scenes for me, it's like it's behind the scenes type of thing. But we don't see enough that they're actually pack packing. It's like Severino one of the Inducks going to the toilet that we never see.
So and I'm not sure if I actually would see that, but
method like one of the things Severino see, and I love seeing it. I can't look it sometimes. Yeah.
Adds to the the storytelling. It should be done rough actually Also I love the sequence where
they're running after landing on the boat or the ship. And
the learning is running not top and Arp. And is climbing after it, and it's climbing on the front of the arp and the landing just jumps off an up the leader that suits the Barks with donald on. And I think that's great comedy actually. And also it is it feels like.
Like
probably something you would like to see. You would likely see in
on the cartoons, but also thank you to work here. And also, Scrooge notices is the that was shooting into the...
This sky and is looking at an
saying,
it was looking at the angle, and it says there go trying to get out of his share of the work.
Yeah. I think that's a great punch line as well. That is a great line. Yeah. You're right. Good. Good call on that one. How about come? Well, there is two parts there would like to mention, and the first one is the the fourth panel on page one. We're on the.
And the only way to open the door is by working the combination of seven locks.
I just low expression here and that that panel was also used as this
picture you could buy, which was signed by Barks. If I remember correctly, they made like not a little graph, but something similar
collectible. Neat The other part like is when Scrooge just trying to corner the landing up in the rigging. It's It's a silver little part of it. But I just think it's nicely drawn and also light our sutra has cut on this green gloves and then I think is gonna fix the landing this time but then it gets this. Yeah. It's definitely a fun sequence. I I
criticized being a little Gladstone, but it is fun. Yeah, Ruben. I also just quickly want to add I every time the learning is biting. One of.
Yeah. I think it's hilarious and it's
correctly wrong and Also also like to see the village of Ducktales
from distance, I'd say.
Yeah. Because it's we we can see the mountains and the norwegian village looks accurate. And looks cozy.
And it looks like I loves saying there's village surrounded by the mountains And embassy. Yeah. It's a great scene. It does look very appealing. I'll just mention too, I really like the panel where they present the le Scrooge at first. And he just screens. A ran a horrible money chewing rat that that cracks me up along with his expression. And then from
reminds me of that in the
the story where it's Al about rats being in the bin that's
the last
before it tells Scrooge, she has to mail this pillow Right. To the
work over screw chair. Scrooge prescription one thing. What you I doing? Oh you'll you'll see it because I just had to tell you that are red the bin.
Yeah. Makeup. I just realized that the openings dashboard also can seen as a symbol way of Scrooge looking himself. I talked london. Right.
Yeah. And we can absolutely literally. It's the last time he's gonna see the money that's in there.
For many many weeks, which... Let's see. What does that remind me? You should take that... Yeah. I think it's in the mini mystery. When Yeah. You yeah. Taking a buzz the last you'll see his money.
The other panel that I really liked was just that one that I've mentioned where he's laying on the wall, kind of four lonely picking at them. And he's he's all but given up. That's a Yeah. It's a great one. Alright. Well, you guys I think we did this story some real justice.
But I
really appreciate you guys joining me, to to talk about this fun one.
Al mentioned, why don't you guys
share where people can find you online?
Ruben. Yeah.
On on
Instagram on and Facebook currently. Both of them my pages.
That'll will be my part.
Anxious that I do mind. I did conduct things, but I also do some other things. I do some graphic design work
some of my old heart that is
It's very much inspired by the tech universe, but it's... Yeah. And
American and European comic books and let me come name, it's in region or tiny,
which means Al groups. That's my name draws and it's
spelled o l s r u d t e t m e r on both Facebook and.
Right on. Yeah. That... Again.
It's it's a really cool logo
that you did
kinda album cover for the podcast. Turned out great. And Miguel. Well, I publish most of my drawings and...
A Facebook page to named the Mi H tiny it, which means michael Drawings And that's
m I k k e l h a g e m s
t e g n I n g e r.
Yeah. So check check out their pages, listeners,
and we really appreciate you giving... Giving the podcast to listen. You can check out Barcodes remarks on the same socials on Facebook and Instagram.
And I'll of course, link you guys on those as well. So, yeah.
Thank you again, listeners, and and be sure to join us next time around
when we get to cover
the last of the first ten stories,
which is the fabulous
philosophers
stone.
And you guys have been closing out the episodes
by lately.
By
having someone read the last panel.
So Mi miguel, why don't you close it out for us by just reading? You have the English there. Right? Yeah. Yeah. And it's gold all the way through. Caller that is. Awesome.
Thank you guys so much. No worries, I love bidding amr morgan and it's great Talking dex with you guys. Thank for having. Thank you for having me on work and I'm looking forward to listen to the all their all episodes will will come.
Absolutely.