We can have
Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer an artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comments of all time. Join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Welcome back to Barks remarks. I'm mark Sever a Grown man who enjoys Inducks con,
and I'm pleased to be joined by a new guest this time,
to discuss this classic uncle Scrooge adventure
we're gonna be talking about the fabulous
philosopher
stone. But before we do that, I wanna introduce my new guests Dan Cunningham.
Welcome dan.
Hey, Mark. Thanks so much for having me. I appreciate it. Yeah. It's it's great to have you here. You know. Dan had had reached out
when when you listened to the podcast, you had some really
great and insightful things to say, and
You know, we had some good conversations and and then needed did some really thoughtful promotion for me on Instagram, and and I'm I'm definitely.
Definitely
susceptible to flatter. So
Aren't all.
Yeah. So I... It's it's great to have you here tell tell us a little bit about your
your... Your history with the dot com and and what you do. Sure. Well, I am a professional
artist in illustrator and designer.
And I grew up reading the du com, the Disney comics all all in imprint of comics, but the Barks work always spoke to me from a very young age
and whatever was available at the time because
when I was a really young kid, they weren't easy to find. But when you could find them,
especially when you could find Barks. That was a really... That was a special one you held on to when you re reread. And I've always
used his work as a basis for my own creativity,
as well as that higher
standard of just because these are talking animals, doesn't mean you should be talking down to children. You should challenge them. You should send them to an encyclopedia back then and Barks had such a high level quality and everything he did even the artwork. You could see... If it was well disney these comics and stories, you know, you could have had about four different orders in that any of those issues, and Barks was always the stand out. So
I eventually learned his name and so much about him. The timing of my life was fort two and that around the time that was at eleven or twelve. That's when I know the rainbow began publishing the Carl library, the three of volume sets. So I was able to learn more about Barks and every Christmas, there was one of those sets under the tree and it was a really... That was very special.
Down the line though, I was able to meet Carl had an event in Orlando at Walt Disney World, and that was very special too. And Something I'd mentioned to you when we first spoke is I'm very happy to report that Carl was exactly what you wanted him to be. He was just this he was a very warm very kind grand Grandfather type. And as gracious as you could have imagined, if not more so, he was very eight Al ninety
three years old, I guess, at that point. We was absent... Yeah. He he... But he was absolutely...
He was very taken with the turnout of people. The line of people Al that we're waiting to see him in particular, which was really great.
But going back, I really was taken with your concept for the podcast as well as the delivery of it. And that's why I've been, you know, I've been trying to put the word out on Twitter and on Instagram and really get because I do follow a lot of people who are not involved in the comics, but also people who just enjoy them that are Disney fans at large, but now they have been exposed to the actual stories. Thanks to... You know, thanks to the current Ducktales that just concluded a few a year ago, I guess, and so much of the graphics reprint
people are really
discovering Pearl Barks where they're red Barks and both are tremendous. It's exactly the kind of thing I I'd like to promote because I want more and more people to find out about these stories. And if you like Ducktales, well, hey, this is where it came from. This is the Genesis
Yeah. Absolutely.
I feel, you know, similarly, like, I... A big part of this podcast is just because I really want I really wanna take the stories seriously.
I I enjoy looking at them from a storytelling
perspective. I like to look at them from just the cultural background that they came from and I I really feel like you get that. You know, and I appreciate that. I I think a lot of people enjoy it in that. Sense. But, you know, that... That's my aim. I wanna look... I wanna look at the stories for from kind of all of those different dimensions.
And and it's so neat to get to connect to with people over the course of doing this who had the opportunity
to encounter Barks himself. Do you Do you wanna share any any other impressions that you might remember from from the encounter? You know, it was one of these at that time, they were doing a Does disneyland convention official out conventions. Mh.
So I I was there at the previous night they had that night club Place Island, and I was going to school in Sara.
We all drove back at gosh. I don't know. We got back at five in the morning, but I had seen the literature at pleasure Island that this is happening tomorrow and look who's gonna be here. And I had to just kind of, like, negotiate myself. He's ninety three. I don't know when I'm ever gonna get this chance get. Right. I drove. I filled up think. A drove back and I got in line and, you know, fueled by Caffeine, but it was absolutely worth it. And it was only... Again, it was only about, you know, was about a minute and a half two minutes because there was a lot of people. I was fortunate to get a photo with him. And again, I just said, you know, I said, you know, you're we're so instrumental to what it was I wanna do wanted to do the way I tend to view so much of the world. And just the idea of his notion of discovery because it's in all the books, you know, whether it's someone who's resistant to change or to expanding their minds or you have a junior wood truck notion of world is your playground in the world is full of curiosity like Scrooge too. And there's... You know... And as I as I go on in life, I embrace that even more. And I really... I credit Carl for really giving me a good gosh, what's the word, a good moral barometer. You know? I I feel very much the same way. You know, I feel like I got a lot of my my curiosity. Mh from reading these con. And and it's a it's a good thing to consider, you know, with this specific story that we're reading because it's so...
It is such a like journey of Discovery. Like, you were alluding to there. That's and there's Al resistance to it. Right. Yeah. It's a very... It's a very dog
story. It's a very
this one's a lot of fun. I'll I'll kinda open up off the bat and share that. You know, it's not. It's never been one of my favorites, but it's kind of a good like second or third tier just like a very enjoyable
Scrooge adventure.
I do remember reading it, you know, a lot as a kid. My my copy of Uncle sp two fifty three where I read it the first time is is definitely
definitely showing its love. Yes. Yes. And it... But it's it's worth going back to because so much of the... Especially the first half or the first act I suppose you know, you had mentioned in the Severino cities
show a few weeks ago. The impact that that story in particular had on George Lucas Steven S. The first half of the fabulous philosophers Gladstone kind of lives that way too. Or if you think of the Indiana Jones films and the the map with the timeline and plate... That... That's really the first half. I mean, they are globe t in this one. And it's... It makes it even more fun because sometimes they'll have one destination and get there. Sometimes it's a little bit of a.
This one, they just, you know, it's it's a series of seemingly dead ends. And they really... You know, they... Like, the... I tell you this is one of those stories where the passports really came in handy. Right. Yeah. I think that I think that the the aspect of this one that I found the most memorable
was that the was the journey. Right
When when the docs arrive, it's it's it's very cool part of the story. It's a neat element. There's a reason that he memorial it in, like, his paintings. Right
But it really is that, like, I'm reminded of the movie parity. Which is the movie where they parity that they called it traveling by map?
Oh.
George of the jungle. Gotcha yes. Someone else did it too, but you're right. They didn't georgia to the jungle. Right. Right. I'm I'm sure... It's too good of a trope to pass. So. But absolutely. But yeah The house, there's a room to it. Yeah. You know? Yeah. For sure. That that's what really stuck in my mind. So let let's let's talk about a little bit of the background of the story and kind of what it what it came out of, because I think there is a lot to say about So... Right Right off the bat, I love... I love the title. I love that it's got the modify
fabulous
mh. Al philosopher Gladstone.
Had a publication date of June of nineteen
fifty five. Mh. And, you know, it's kind of a big deal issue for my own per we're in uncle Scrooge
ten.
We've we've made it into the double digits and
so Dan, just for the sake of the podcast, I have chosen to really think about those first ten Scrooge stories as their own units. Yes. For no other reason then, you know, round numbers are interesting.
But but I like to think about, you know, how how do those first ten
stories kinda kinda hold up. How do they stack up against each other? And maybe we can kinda put a pin in that and just talk about that after we sure talk about the story. I I will tell you something that surprised me. I always check in on how many times stories been reprinted in the United States. Mh. And counting,
its original
publication Inducks ten. This has only been printed eight times.
That's surprising. Yeah. Because I feel like this is a pretty iconic one. It's pretty famous. It's pretty well known. There's there's no real, like, culturally and sensitive
aspects that would like, make it Severino to reprint. So No No. There's no real restriction and it's twenty... What is twenty four pages so it would fit in a book with ads. That is surprising because yeah exactly the initial Gladstone run didn't do it. I imagine they had it slated. They they I know they couldn't fit everything.
You know, right. They... You know, which which was actually nice because they they did space things out. You know, you mentioned that. I I remember when I was
reading one of the stories a while ago. I I came across this great letter message from the editor.
From those early days of Gladstone where they talked about how they've been getting a lot of... You know, they were... The tone was still... We're so excited to have gotten this license
because of course, the the folks Al glad were basically a bunch of fans. Yes. Who acquired the license very probably. Yes. And they ran this letter saying that they were getting all these letters to the editor telling them to to only print the Barks and Gottfredson and stuff.
And, you know, reasonably, their their position
was that, you know, they they don't wanna run out of those stories. They really wanna highlight
stories from new creators like Don Rosa, and William Van Horn, and the focus Al what was then called.
Mh.
And to make the case, they they brought out the big Guns they had Carl Bark
himself run a risk response. That's right. I remember this yeah. I I think he said they're running it, you know, they're gonna run out like ans of picnic, I think. Yeah. He a good matter of. I forget that precise where wording, but... But I think you got it. That's pretty much it. And and it definitely had his his tone, which Mh. As you point out, he's he's just so care or carl was sharp to the very end. You know, there's act... There's a letter out there. I I think it's a it's that one website which is a beautiful resource c Barks dot d dk. Yeah. Great resource. It's I mean... Just
y'all, oh my gosh. But there's... Things I, you know, things I either forgot or never knew They even have
one of the last letters to his fans like, at the very end. And it's... You could tell it with him, you could tell from the from phrasing from the wording. You know, Didn't... It wasn't necessarily clever or snappy, but he was being scientific about his diagnosis.
At ninety nine years old. And... But but, you know, he he was very... I... I'm not trying to make an statement. Honestly, one of the sharpest lines of the twentieth century really.
That's what
that's what everyone, you know,
patrick block. Huey, you such a fun.
Tried to talk with. He he loves to recount how he had to, like, move quickly to keep up with him well, in until his nineties. That's wonderful.
It's it's great. It's it's it's great to, like, really celebrate him and his worth. So let's see. You did mention that it's a it's... I was gonna say short, but really twenty four pages is is gonna end up being pretty average length for Inducks adventure her stories once he once he stops doing the thirty two pager.
Background Trivia and and kind of like the culture control background. There's there's a pretty good amount there. You had talked about how this is like one of the Inducks most traveling in their stories.
I got that in my notes too and what it reminded me of that the two stories that featured already in the podcast this was very reminiscent to me of guild man. Yes.
You know, at the end, where they're in this kind of like
mad
dash
across countries and state lines, and they don't know where it's gonna take them next.
You know, the... I didn't even consider that. There's very similar beats to both stories.
Right. Yeah. It takes place in, like, a different
phase act of the story.
And and then I also found a little bit reminiscent of dangerous to disguise, you know, that one have
it's a lot more tense, of course. And the steaks are a lot higher, but That's a very unique one. Yeah. Right. And these too kind of singular early among his stories are really, like, focused on Europe. Mh.
It's always strapped me as a a little bit odd because I... I've been... One of the fun little side projects I'm doing with the podcast is
maintaining the the adventure map I call it that people can see I'll post... I post on Facebook u And as I cover the stories every month or so I'll go in and and put the little pins where the doctor
wow
And and it... It's it's been a little bit odd to see the lack of attention that Barks pays to Europe
compared to, like, South America
and
South Asia and Yeah. Right. That's that's true. I I imagine it's just the fact that certain counselors Barks places like Africa or, you know, with the Amazon this you know, the the sedan, they're this more exotic. They're more right. You know? He he's definitely
interested in
Discovery.
Yep. Right. Like, I know world is. Yeah. Now, you know, in a couple of years years, once you get it to the sixties, you're gonna have to push that and map back and start getting it to the galaxy.
Yeah. It's true. Once he gets into his sci mode. Yep. Google Maps doesn't really accommodate that. So that's right. I don't I don't know how to how to handle that, but
let Al alone land beneath the ground. That's right.
To me, this story is kind of like all about the the joy or or the importance of of research. And the first panel it'll straight that beautifully.
Right. There's screws. I mean, you you have... And for some reason, some very nicely rendered volumes on that on that table
But, yeah, it's just... It's... That... You know, when when he's not conducting business when he's not swimming and money, Scrooge just looking for the next thing to make pile bigger. Couple of stories start like that with him going through.
Studying parchment, studying older books, And I believe I believe that this is the first time. I think that's right. And it's very much... It very it's very
reminiscent of some of the things would do twenty years later. Don't out of the lighting It's really a a... It's a really gorgeous panel just for for something as simple as shifting through both your knowledge. And so to me, it's it's notable that this this is like one of the archetypes screwed stories, right where he's doing research that launches him on a treasure hunt. Mh. And and this really is the first one at least to the best of my memory. You know, I recently covered the seven cities of S, which I
identified as the first sort of pure treasure hunt Yep. But but even in that one, he kinda stumbles into it He isn't set out on a treasure hunt.
Right. This is the one where he's, you know, first, we we see him right at the he's like, dogg
following these bread crumbs.
Yeah. You're right. So, Dan, I'm thinking that there's kind of the the other sort of background thing to talk about is is like the greek mythology of it all. Got some. But there's a lot of that. So maybe we can kinda integrate it as we talk about the recording itself.
The the only thing that I did wanna cover the four we transition into talking about the story itself. Is is my little moment to to panda to our international listeners.
I I shared a couple of titles from around the world with you, each have two of them. And,
you know, this one, it has such an iconic title, and it's so important to express, you know, the token,
the the philosophers Gladstone
that it really it had to be a straight up translation. Yeah. It's... It's it's very direct, you know, where others can really kinda take a weird serve of Right. But this this item is just such a famous piece of history and mythology. Right? The stone that turns all metals to gold,
that... Yeah. Everyone's got a term for it. So, Dan, why don't she hit us with
with one of yours?
Sure. The German title, and I'm gonna
I'm going to take on an vacation, so no offense to our friends from foreign Lands.
So the German title the fabulous flu for stone. Is there stein rice? Yeah. I'll buy that. And like we said, it's straight up translation. I will. I'll do Sweden.
And and the philosopher stone is translated as Devices
stan. Mh. And the next one would be Italy
and that is also very direct
Very nice. Alright. And then in Spain, it was published as
and
del.
So that's on in search of the salon numbers stone as... It's just about.
Alright. So let's Let's do this. I think the only thing we should just kinda mention is, you know, the Flu Gladstone
as a concept, I think most people
today know it from Harry potter because the Right original book and the film around most of the world was Harry Potter, and the Philosophers Gladstone, the first book. And the real thing is that it was
partially
true to what Barks had put into the story we're about to discuss where it was a
compound sometimes gel, sometimes the powder sometimes a vessel.
Sometimes they fused stone that would turn base metals into gold, but the larger
part of the philosopher stone that Barks did not touch upon it was it was reported to be an eli that would grant good health if not pure Al. And that maybe wouldn't have fit into the narrative of this story or a twenty four page length. But for the sake of the Barks story,
it's really turning metals into gold, which is the only thing that would have interest screwed.
Bright. Yeah. Exactly. These are good points to make. This is something that's really cast along shadow and pop culture.
So
let's let's dive in. We're gonna we're gonna talk about the the philosophers stone So we're gonna we're gonna go ahead and summarize this we're gonna alternate pages
and
just take a little bit of time to comment on it. And, you know, you you'd already mentioned how
how interesting this kind of opening panel. We get a a nearly...
We get a half page
slash panel of of Scrooge doing some
research.
Again, this is like the first time that he's really
kind of
proactively
doing some treasure hunting Al to to my recollection.
And
Barb has this
just really nice setup up in the narrator box. Some very, like, floor language talking about that he's about to be sent on a f
quest for gold to the very secret court of Buy gone pagan kings.
And and we just see Scrooge
kind of reading through these old tones
pondering
how he
has figured out how he can make gold out of these other base metals
and talking and reading about an Al
have always liked the word Al
Who's succeeded in his quest for for, you know, turning these metals gold. And we get this great panel dan
Barks often and we'll do these panels we're where sp is kind of overcome
by, like,
by greed and was the potential of a new fortune
rise. And and he's surrounded by dollar signs, but he just he cramp more in around him than I've I've ever seen before. This one's a little over the top. You know, that panel was I used to work in animation or galleries.
Salesperson. And that panel that... They actually did a ceramic tile of that very panel. That one. Without the without the the dialogue, but they did that one because it's the dollar signs and look at that tongue hanging out. That's, you know, that he's he's really like those those gears are really turning in its head this time. It's a really eye catching panel. And I and I just... I like the the dialogue, the the monologue log
balloon there where where it just says history doesn't know what the became of him referring to the Al worst his fabulous invention. But I think I have guessed so that's just a little bit of hand waving that's gonna launch us in and any calls donald over, and he tells him that he's on on the trail of the philosophers.
No. We get to our next page, it's really just a touch more of x physician and Donald kind of breaks down,
again, not not pan to the audience, but just breaking down what Al is do and in this case, turn into gold and, you know, really A is, you know, what you reconsider transportation today. It's the changing of the structure of one thing another. And they're going through the text, but screwed reveals that they actually
produced a mother of gold. I'm gonna read that fourth panel right here. And again, this is Al.
Do you think? I think it's... I think it's au.
Let's it's... Okay. That sounds a little more gruesome. Right? Right. So Austin denise the need fused four metals into a ball of mother of gold. He actually made a philosopher stone. And a get wouldn't concept that in the service of this story, that stone, if it comes into contact,
with the base metal will turn it to gold automatically So very similar to king Midas only strictly for Metals.
So we think. Right. However, Donald then says you think you know where that ball is today and Scrooge is absolutely a billion. He says not exactly. But I know where it was eight hundred and forty five years ago, And then that next panel is it doo.
Has donald it's just leaning against the the office wall, is canned, and he's saying eight hundred and forty five years and you want me to help you to find words gone since and the word, the number eight hundred and forty five is pounding out of the side of his head. But Scrooge to assures that it's not gonna be that hard. So go get the kids and or off to the Black forest of Germany. Yeah. Dan, I I love this page. Right? It... This is such a great bark touch. You know, donald staggered panel. And and just the little
inclusion of the the the number
right the the years, it's
it's it's very
unique. I don't think most artist most comic bug artist would include attached like that. So so what's your... Are you reading
like the original or a fan graft... I have a digital
graphics
on my tablet right now. So I... I'm I'm going off my the the issue that I read all the time as a kid, which is the Disney comics reprint And
they chose to update the year in that reprint. So that it actually says eight hundred and eighty one. Oh, so they made it contemporary to nineteen ninety, I guess? Or... Yeah. It's not one not unusual, I I can't think of many other reprint. Yeah. And I thought it was odd. So we're we're gonna launch as you say, right into
the black forest. And and as is the case with a lot of these
stories where the Inducks were gonna travel somewhere
barb
chooses to show us the cruise over. He really likes his scenes he likes drawing ships
and and vessels.
And we get to see it's also a good
opportunity to kind of let the Inducks sit back and and for screws to give a little bit more background.
You know, Donald is reading a book and route and he talks about, you know, os
philosopher for stones supposedly
disappeared in Palestine
and, you know, they're... I don't think there would have been anything
controversial at the time of publication about using that term. For that area of the world, and Scrooge gets off a nice line in response. He says that he's not going to where it
here, but rather to where it reappear. Right? So the the rest of of the first act of the story is basically gonna be following this really
exciting trail. And and so Scrooge goes on to talk about a later book that he read, detailing the journey of a night from the crew Crusade that stopped at this castle they're destin too and apparently paid for his lodging with a curious yellowstone stone found in Palestine.
So, you know, the Ducktales have a really good lead. And there's a quick illusion, the the the... His grand nephew say that if you do find that stone, there will be no limit. To the amount of gold you can have. And
we also get this little brief view of of a passenger
on on the ship, and we can we can come back to him. Because every time I read it, I I end up backtracking anyway. Mh.
Happened to me.
So the dumps do arrive at the castle. So it's... It's a it's a nice little panel, but It's too bad. It's not a larger panel. Because we been no
You know what it is, though. You you look at this page, the the the view of the ship from the different angles to close ups, the long shots and the castle. This page is such a beautiful example of
exposition
without being boring. Yeah. Because they really unravel a lot and he even touches back to stuff from page one,
and the economy of storytelling here, is wonderful. Because sometimes it's easier to just cut to a location. You have two... You have two frames on a boat, and then you get to the location. In this case, there was more to explain because we're gonna kinda hit the ground running in terms of the search. So now this sets things up really nice. Yeah. You're absolutely right. It's a great point Dan because this story really does, it opens up with almost three full pages of exposition. And page one
bark me Scrooge do the thinking. Right? And then and then he changes this up. He keeps it interesting.
Page two is basically
Scrooge and donald now talking to each other. And page three continues the
exposition but it takes place on this boat, which gives you another
totally different background
and a different dynamic. He keeps bringing in new characters. So that it's a great point you made about about that economy of storytelling.
Go ahead. Tell us about the cas. Right? So now we're already inside the castle. Very
shades of digital downs by the way. Yeah. Or there's a lot of similar,
you know, brick Gladstone work. But they're already... They got their magnifying glasses out and they're exploring And luckily,
one of the nephews
sounds a stone table, and they are flex gold. Not only that, screwed comes up to inspect he said sure enough gold dust and flakes of hammered goal, and it's not gold from old coins either it's too pure. So they know they're already a little... The trail just got a little hotter. Right. And they start poking around a bit. And what is
normally a trope and a lot of,
you know, and you know, media movies, monster movies,
where you have something hidden with a secret
stone or a secret secret hide away, Day Barks
was so wonderful in this He explains why because Scrooge taps on the wall the listened for a hollow Gladstone, he says since they were no sage in those days, He must have hidden it in a secret niche in the masonry. And, again, it's like you could have had that old gag where someone leans against the stone and it's loose or it would have
fallen on Donald foot and you get... Right. Yeah Tantrum. No. It's just... Barks had screwed explain it because it's a very logical thing for that time because there would have been no padlock
and kiwi removed the Gladstone,
and he said there's something glittering inside And the coloring, I have the stone
wall is a very pale blue, but the interior is a is a bit of yellow. So it's actually... It's it's a it's a bit gil. So
Yeah.
Down this. Yeah. I see that's the... That's why, like, the coloring doesn't make a difference sometimes. It really does. Yeah. Again, Dan a a really good summary of just the importance of, like, this story feels earned. Right? Because he's always... It's not happens. Dance. He's using his knowledge. Huey, going back to the research that he and later the nephews will have done Even Donald is, like we see him res researching on the ship. But I found this part. I really enjoyed this part, and and it is kind of like a classic, right? Finding something
secret away in and behind an old stone. But the way that the way that Barks handles it here, you know, where where the Ducktales have the lead So they you you could imagine
overlooking these just tiny
little flex of gold. Right? So I I found it very believable
and a very, like, exciting when the dots did find something. It does it seemed reasonable that something that You know, a castle is such an ancient building that it could be there. So this this has been a bit of missed action though because on the next page. And again, it's it's great pacing. We we have to turn the page to see what's in it. And and Scrooge screws
disappointment, it's just some guild parchment.
And Scrooge is able to re latin in this story. So he
he saw once he reads it. It's that fourth panel on this page with him just w is just pretty great.
He he cries out the stones gone
the guy that lived in this room was a scholar and he took it to Rome to show its magic to the emperor. And so the doctor, you know, they this feels like a dead end and screw even makes the fit full decision to just put the parchment back in the compartment
for some other sucker to find. And and we sense that they're about to give up. But as the ducks
leave the castle. They encounter this very funny looking little gentleman.
And and gentlemen is the only
term to use. Right? Because he's very dapper.
He's like, interestingly he's about as tall as the docks. Barks doesn't usually make the
dog characters that are like this shit. They're usually more of a human scale, but here
he has kind this funny tech Severino one or brothers look to him does yeah. That's a good point. He does kinda look very av s. He has human ears,
but a dog knows
his ball he wears this time comic tiny little. I don't know if that's a derby or or what So. He... He's very funny looking and very distinct. And...
Unless you have any comments about this page, how much you tell us about him? Yeah. And, you know, just from that they he he kinda passes them buying
you know, gives him a Al it keeps going and the Inducks seemed to
recognize him from somewhere. And one of the Nephew you says he was on the ship coming over here, it's odd that we would meet him here and further
investigation following him and they realized that he's looking around the castle the same way, we did and uncle Scrooge appears around the stonewall wall corner, and he gets gold Flakes. He's on the trail of the Philosophers Gladstone
too. And this just re energizes screws to
reinstate the search,
and they book the next trip to Rome, and they're already on the and again, back to economy of storytelling. Scrooge we're going a rome no matter how slim the chances are, I can't let anybody else beat me to that fabulous rock, and then boom next panel. The ancient Roach To rome skirt the
C. So they're already there. This starts the series of wild goose chase, slash dead ends slash possible leads, and we're really rolling now and they arrive at a sea port and a record keeper has some old roman parchment scrolls and does a bit of
research says that the sc passed through one day in the year, one thousand one hundred and ten carrying a yellow stone wrapped in many layers of cloth So now, we suddenly have a new more recent lead to get this chase moving forward. And there's a lot of nice little moments in here. I think the the little
road kind of that skirt to see, the Ducktales and a taxi, and it's actually really nice little moan because there's a
man selling wears with burrow. Right. Behind them. And it's just... And there's way back in the
far background on the horizon. There is a crop of trees. But there's a small steep kicking out because if you are in Rome, yeah, there's gonna be a lot of cathedrals. Be a lot of churches. So that's that's a nice little touch there as well. Oh, yeah. Definitely feels very,
you know, coastal meta.
Yeah. This page is pretty interesting. Right? Because like I mentioned
once you read that he was on the ship coming over, the reader like has to go back. You have to... Yeah. You have to you have to go back and then you were like, he's the he's kind of against the railing, but he's there. Right. And and he's drawn. I he's not colored accepting kind of like shadow mh at least in mind. So
it really...
It does a nice job. I guess this would be Barks working in tandem with whoever is doing the coloring decisions.
The readers
should be gloss over him the first time and kinda realized he was there with hindsight inside, which is it... It's an exciting interactive way to read it. And then, you know, I think that's why he looks so goofy. We needed the nephews tat to We needed him to stand out enough for the Ducktales to kinda be like, hey,
I that. Yeah. He has to be memorable. And then I really liked that
Scrooge wants to continue this adventure, basically out of...
Out of just that sense of not wanting to be one up. Right. It's kinda like shades of the second richest Inducks or something. That's right. So as you mentioned, they get this next lead and and, you know,
maybe they gave up initially a little bit too quickly because they did at least have the scholars name that they could consult. Mh.
And so this guy in
outside of Rome, I guess, on the
Coast,
discovers that this scholar was
attacked south of the Wall City wall by Su sicilian pirates.
Who took his magic stone and sail away. And this is just gonna be this recurring motif where, you know, the Ducktales learn about the next step,
the next leg of the journey, they they have some great reaction shots here they all give these great bones And and then on their way out, they're gonna keep encountering
this this little beard to dude and get re energized. And so they they take their leads to sicily
where Scrooge
irritates the historian by asking where was the hang out? Of Pirates in the year eleven ten. I I like the guys
I like the guy's response. The questions people ask. I'll look it up. It's so wonderful. And it's it's another one of those kind of, like, Barks drawing like, an administrative type. And this this... I... That that clerk, it he looks so friend. Just look at those eyebrow wrinkles above his eyes, it's such a it's again, it's just it's such a perfect expression for someone being asked such a weird question. Right. And yet he's dedicated. He's gonna do it. Mh.
So the clerk does
give them a
a little bit of exposition and it directs them to a cave on the North coast of Sicily. Sure enough. They find some gold flakes
along with arabic riding on the wall.
Screws once again, being very well red was able to translate this, and this time, the writing on the wall said that the pirate colony failed for Damascus
to take a yellow yellow
Gladstone or their Kale.
So once again, the while goose chase is reinstated. Into its third leg and on the way out, guess who's rolling into the cave.
It's the little guy and with his usual Al sanitation of Good afternoon gentlemen.
Yeah. This time screw just not gonna be his gorgeous and he just fits fires what's good about it because he knows he's getting dog. Right. This this then we now get into the high level passport stamping, next panel, Damascus,
where revealed there's no record that party ever arrived. Why not try bad dad, next external bad debt. No record or your party here. But in those days, travelers often stop on the island of Creek. And, again, you have two very
dig dignified federal types.
Who are going through the records.
However, in damascus bag debt, you can see the architecture is different and you you see the
the dome doorways
in damascus. And in bad, you see the hand carved
detailed
pillar and the the sunken window. With the very flying patching. So it even the desk, if you look... If... On that bag dead panel, look at the look at the fill look at the design on the edge of the desk. That is a lot of detail to wanna put into one panel, but Barks went ahead and did it. Like that one, you can really you really look into it like dude there's a lot happening in that panel, but it gives you a sense of a different place. That's why he did it. Yeah. Absolutely. It's it's all very lovingly drawn. We're
this this one feels like like a tourist tourist story. Right? We're getting this like really nice tour of basically
much of the ancient roman Empire. That's you're right. You know, we're going from from Germany
to the Western
Mediterranean
to the eastern
Mediterranean and and into the the portion in the Middle East where where Roam
or the Roman
ruled. And and so we basically hit our dead end in cr where the records kind of run out and the Ducktales are mirroring.
And we get this neat moment where they they observed that they're
friend with the chin shrub.
I love I love that they call him that
has has also come to a dead end too. And we know
Prior to that, Damascus bad, the same
interaction happened. Good afternoon gentlemen and happened there too, but we don't need to see that. We can guess that that was gonna repeat itself after the third time. Absolutely.
He faces this so well.
He he conditions us. To know what's going on. And and the Inducks throw his greeting back at him Donald says afternoons.
Sir and he's very dignified so he ind says you flatter it gentlemen. And so basically, we come to the part of the story where the wood chuck step in and and save the day. Right? Because the docs are waiting for their boat home. And
Gui doing Louie. They've got that great child like wood check
curiosity.
They want to read about where they are in Cr.
It's not because they're trying to look for a lead. This is just what they like to do and and they discover by reading that cr was in fact, the headquarters of those race pirates.
And
the... This is the part where Barks is gonna kind of mix
mixed history with fan c with Legend. They go on to talk about how the pirates had a regular
city in a great case called the lab.
And and this is something that Bark just did so well. You know, when he... When he be through these fantastical elements in, with just enough historical details like in the seven cities of Ebola, to to just give it just enough of a
of reality. It's it's the story within the story.
And Right. It's it's... Again, it's just it's just enough exposition to get you where you need to go. Right. And their uncles are skeptical
because the labyrinth is, you know, only A myth his screwed says, and and Donald slips in the min tire was supposed to have lived in the labyrinth lived in the labyrinth. He was only a myth too. And we we get kind of bark Al little bit of hand waving about how if it's in the junior would check guide book, it must be true. To the
and and...
You know, we've seen that enough that it's one of Barks own like
specific tropes.
So so I feel like it's an earned a bit of hand waving. No. Absolutely.
And again, it's one of these, you know, we're especially with the Wood fix stuff is concerned. I mean, the the word I always like to use is Noble because that's what they are. They're always they're never... The the kids, especially under, you know, wood truck rules They never deviate eight, they'll never be rat, you know, like they would have been in the forties.
Right. No. They they... They... And this is this is one of those stories where that transition is going on already where Donald and screws eventually become the guys who get carried away and the kids become the ones who bail them out. Yeah. And that that will that will kind of happen here in a couple of pages.
Right. For sure. And if you... But you have a trope like that, a tiny little book that has just about all the information in the world You can't not use it. I mean, that's pretty that's a pretty... That's a pretty valuable one. So you have to use these things again with some economy. You have to know where and when to utilize these things. Right. By the next page, Donald already
kinda had it, and he says, now we're expected to look into a cave that never could have been and sort of confronts the kids.
About the Min,
and the kids say they haven't even read that far. Who was the V? And again, this is Donald. This is Barks just giving you enough exposition
that really just brings into the conversation without appointing at you explaining donald tell him it's a legendary
that was locked in the cave a half man and a half volt and the ancient world was scared stiff of him and the kids are intrigued. Screwed then, again, rings in the story within the story of d,
how he went into the cave to to slay the mini military and found his way out of the labyrinth by following a thread, which a girl Aria had given him So in two and a half panels, You got the entire Greek story. Yeah. Where... Again, had this been brought up in the first three pages where there was enough exposition, it would have seen rather pointless. Right. But now it would have overloaded yeah that position. Right. So we... It's just... It's... Again, this is a this is sort of building blocks. And basically, the boys point out that the labyrinth is near the ruins of the Palace of King Min and it was destroyed... It was covered by an earthquake. But they're right there may as well go take a look for. And there's one interesting thing if you look at that third row where Donald says well, it just goes to show you how wild those myths were. Look at the fact that it's two panels, but it's actually one. There's a divider, but that little walk away? Continues on panel two. So. It's just... It's one one long pane the Cartridge panel.
But he broke it into too. Maybe just for the sake of it being interesting or maybe to get the boys a little more close up. But I... That's kind of an interesting factor. That's something he didn't really do that often. Night. Huey, that's a great thing to point out. I need to make a point of kinda highlighting that when I share, like, panels
this. On on Facebook or instagram. I I think it probably makes it more readable. Yeah. I think to
remove that that that it's too many
characters
and too many words to share one panel. And there isn't many... There isn't a reason to have a long panel Right.
So, you know, the docs excited that they've got this new lead and they go to explore these ruins.
And they discover that the language that's on the walls there is is un trans.
And they encounter their with security friend again and he is totally s. You know, he's made it this far as well. But he he's finally beat and so he
Scrooge this time, which is him... Good afternoon, sir. He just says good afternoon and goodbye. He's finally broken his procedure. Right. And and this leaves the Inducks
free to, you know, search Al their hearts content can. And and this is where the nephews
slide in and it and say that they've just translated the writing, of course, with the help of the guide book. And and they point out the section
under the wall. Under a tumbled wall where the entrance to the labyrinth is. Now I always did think Dan that this was a little bit of an an Al una assuming
spot for, like, the Mighty labyrinth, you know, that didn't look like something that would maybe hold up
for
the better part of a thousand years.
But but not a big deal.
And and so we get another cool ci silhouette panel as the duct can... You know, they they work to uncover the entrance.
Through the night trying to be... You know, screw has an interesting thing here he says, he says move these rocks quietly. We don't want
service
to know what we're up a little y ish. Yeah. Because so to bits, it's a yi term that's like to kinda like Fetch. Right? Oh, no. It's like... No. I think kim it's just like I I think it's more like Nosy. It's more like yeah. You know. Someone who's knows around the It was it's an odd choice, I think of term. All I can think of is it kinda sounded like whisk too. Yeah. Anyway... So, you know, they do finally
uncover the entrance
and with Lantern turnaround off. They they enter, and we get this pretty cool
splash panel here dan of the of the main entrance to the cavern. What do you think of that? I think it's a beautiful reveal because, you know, you have that. You have that inlay panel where Donald is holding Al the lantern high, and then the next, you know, practically full slash page. You just... You're basically turning the camera one eighty and you're seeing the Inducks from the back now and you're seeing what they see. And it's a... You know, again, it's it's it's pretty indicative of what all those. Because I've been to, you know, some of these different caves at least in the Continental Us, like in Colorado and
other areas, and that rock work is not unfamiliar to me. It does look like that when you go. And you go far enough down, you know, right lag tight, like it... It... You know, it does look sign sort of cartoony, but if you go down, far enough, it does start to look like that. That this labyrinth because there's gonna be all these holes, all these different entry ways, these cri cross paths.
So it's pretty intimidating. Yeah. I agree. And
intimidating is the word for it. Yeah. So tell us about deeper in. So off they go, and the first thing to do is decide which have to take because there's so many openings.
And
one of the nephews Donald claims, I'm getting scared. One of the nephew says, well, what do you think Dc felt when he came in here and they have lanterns.
Dc didn't even have that much. So screwed just kinda takes command and starts going through one passage
and he immediately runs out. He's there. Don't switch which is the street and and a and a Scrooge will put together. Don't let him really likes that that terms. That's a that's that came up a lot. Yeah. And so he didn't and Scrooge just runs right out there, and Donald kinda follow suits, the Nephews of course being me being the being Most bra take their lanterns and look through the entry way. And in this case, it's the min.
However, it's just to statue, it's not an actual mythological creature, but screwed just kicking in with his lantern and wouldn't have been able to tell that because the men tire is pretty men Yeah. It's it's pretty cool looking. It's it's very
intimidating. It's one of the few times where we get... Let me ask you, Dan. You're you're reading a reproduction the original. What color is the min tire? In this kit now the one you're reading, I think he's stone color. Right? He's gold. Oh, he's gold. Okay. Okay. And this one, he he has a... The the the head the horns and the cow are brown, what a steer or bull would have. The rest of it is flush colored, which surprise me because I had seen another... I think gold key... The one I read years ago as a kid, the gold here. I think it was just a Gladstone color. That's the one I remember.
One of those times where the coloring is is an important decision. Right? Because, like, as a kid when I read this?
It always seemed to me like the vacation is that once upon a time the min was real and and may have been termed to gold
To that of first.
Because that's how he shines. But but that doesn't seem to be what what's implied based on the original color itself. Right. And again, that's
sometimes the communication wasn't always there like you I or Barks would sometimes write a note and blue pencil that wouldn't be reproduce saying.
But in this case, the interesting thing here though is that we're an Uncle Scrooge number ten in Uncle.
Number twelve will be the golden fleece. Right. And that's where pathology, greek mythology takes front center. Stay. Yeah He's got a pretty good run of it. Yeah it's there's a lot happening here. I'm guessing part of that is because now that he's rolling with this, he needs to start looking up treasures to for Inducks to seek out. Sure. Yeah. The interesting choice here is that the minute military is statue when you get to the golden fleece, No. You you may just encounter some real mythological creatures and then some... Yeah. And and I'll tell you, Dan, this this part always let me down just a little bit. Right. Like especially based on on this cover right part. You know, I'm promised to minute.
Mh.
It it it feels a little bit like check offs gone not actually going off. Right.
So
I'm okay with it now. But I do remember as a child being a little bit less down that that Al cool of a thing. As the legendary min tire is just there for this one admittedly cool looking panel and then really is not an element to the story at all. It's not visited. No. It's not revisited. It's not even used as a device after the fact, which is interesting. Right. Yeah. But that's it one and done. So you know, I'm gonna Al gloss over a little bit. The their their trip travels through the
labyrinth because they they go back in
They encounter
some some gold relics that really seem to be evidence
of those pirates using the philosophy for stone. There's an exciting little bit where Scrooge almost rush in
past the golden door, but the nephews no enough that it's a trap and and they they make it through.
Tell us stan unless you have a comment on this page. Tell us about the the drone room. Or or whatever this underground temple is. Yeah. No. I mean, the nice thing about this page is that you kinda see that trail leading towards the throwing room and you can see that like,
they they... You know, I think he says it looks like stuff, the pirate dropped and they... As they fled from the cave when the earthquake struck. Again, very practical. It makes good sense because at some point, even a pirate running for his life. He's not gonna have to... He's not gonna handle everything. He's gonna drop some stuff. He's gonna drop some dead weight in order to, you know, hopefully survive.
Right. Tied up that loose and there pretty nicely. Exactly
hot hole. But they do raise the truck door and they enter the thrown room of king,
and there is... Looks like, you know, again, people kinda left there in a hurry. So it turns out to be an underground temple, and there is all kinds of intricate design, sooner. If you look at the thrown. It actually has... It's it's... It has a bison bowl like mo down the feet Barks hoo, and there is a... There's ones on the
on the top of the throat. So that's a nice touch. It's great. And, again, bet this there's shades of seven cities here where they're just finding drugs of jewels and precious precious. Yeah.
And it's very similar to of those scenes where they're just putting their hands and shifting through it, like, like, kids in in a in Al sandbox. Right. It's some nice wish fulfillment in here. So, you know, the these couple of pages are basically about them kinda ba
in and appreciating this treasure
and continuing to look for the stone and, you know, Scrooge assumes that it must have, like, a very special place like an alter that he's prying open.
And one in the nephews
spots a very una assuming
stone that a pirate and a big hurry might have dropped and
that's kind of a cli shade a moment, but it it makes for a really cool scene where Scrooge
dismiss it as rubble
toss it over his shoulder,
and it lands on their lantern turn rendering it immediately into gold. Let me ask you, and the version you have what color is the stone?
So the stone is brownish.
It is. Okay. Not early nineties prints Okay. And this one, they actually have it as as a gold stone, which I I would've think it again, it should've have been more, you know, trunks get worse. Absolutely
fit with
with the Nephews
like Yeah with it kinda being hidden. So that that's that's a better
coloring. I I guess, it goes both ways. Right? Yeah. But again, I... It's all, you know, subjective, but you think you just for it to be inspector with brown or a grayish. Right. Brand. For sure. So that... You said it hits the lantern and boy, it is the the the tin part of the lantern turned to gold and guess who just absolutely
loses his ever le in mind. Screws runs up and starts kissing the stone because he's found the philosophers phone, and he actually says he starts eve rocking back and forth kissing it. Mine online, the most valuable gizmo and history. It's a great That's a hilarious panel. It really good. And again, it's just... But you... That's that that's that ever just that bridal joy that, like he gets you know, we've seen it, you know, and in a few different occasions.
Yeah. So he only has dime on them, so he can't... He wants to have fun start turning stuff in the gold, but they realized they believe. We got, you know, they need to get out of the labyrinth Donald
kinda reverts back to his usual cell where he's loaded himself up with
jewelry and jewels and a giant urn
full of
pearls.
And he's like, yeah, you found what you came for, Let's go. And the Nephews immediately just... And again, this is the nobility. This is that switching of rolls from Garden
voice.
Put those jewels back on Ka macdonald, they belong to the creation government, not us, which gives Scrooge pause that the stone possibly does belong to the government as well. Right.
Yeah. So so on the next page, we basically have these two problems
to solve to resolve and and Barks
wraps him up pretty quickly. He's he's more interested in kind of covering these potential plot than he is in some other stories. Yep.
His Scrooge just says that he's gonna file a claim for it first thing in the morning, and and then he can use it all he likes. And And, you know, it's a little bit of hand waving, but it's it's just enough for a comment book.
And then the next problem is that the adult dot have realized that they have done... They have done the exact thing that the labyrinth is notorious for is they've been basically
swallowed up by its it's
it's maze of passages and they they realized that they were careless.
That they could wander out for years
and
and we get this moment of the Nephews looking very pride
saying don't worry. We will get you out. There any... They're in unanimous stride, which is such Al funny way to go. It's really cute. And and they explained that they basically did exactly what Pcs did and un roll the thread
behind
And
and we get this neat little moment of reflection between Donald and Sp, wondering what they would do without the kids and their with chat guide book. It's a very brisk
at it feels to me dan
This is occurring to me just as I speak. All of the sort of danger
in this one. They they just end up getting... They they really don't come too much. No. They resolved themselves. Yeah. They was all very quickly very neatly. This one's not really about the payroll. It's really about the journey journey.
And and if you were like me, you know,
a kid in the nineties,
eleven year ten or eleven year old my first read this one. Like, really
disappointed that there's not this min encounter mh.
Hey I guess it's understandable why this was never like an all time favorite of mine because I wasn't really appreciating what it was going for. Right. No. I understand. But at the same time, it's
It's it's the it's the discovery and the romance of loss civilizations,
the potential of a,
anything else that And the, you know, just that just the notion of traveling that much to find such an unusual object. There's a... There's there's too many attractive components to this.
That. Oh, yeah. Yeah. Got you going back to reading it again. Where I'm sure there was... But there's just so much... There's so many layers to this. And, again, you eat even just in the labyrinth alone, I mean, just to just the depth and the succulent of the the the treasure and the gift the different passageway ways. It really... It's so... It's it's such a
safest kind of a notion. Right. And and the way that he leaves it in so nice see with the the quote real myth. Mh. You know,
it's it's a really cool
interaction.
Yeah. With
with legend. Absolutely. And this next sequence is really cool too. So we
we wipe over to the next day at the hotel, and Uncle Scrooge
has Gladstone and he's gonna use it.
And probably does the ever.
So the iron bed, the water taps and the sink, the bathtub
and
donald and the boys are watching this finally Donald has to kinda take a take a little bit of control. He said, you better be careful how much how do you make so much gold right here? So someone's gonna get wise to you? And then one of the nephews says, yeah, that little guy with a spade whisk for instance. Scrooge. She just... You're just just enjoying himself too much she says have. Fully on him he's gone away talking himself by now. But we on there last time, we see guess who's down in the lobby. So he didn't quite give up either. Yeah. He you know what, Dan this this is
really reminding me of another Barks sequence.
In the minds of king solomon that this exact story beat happens near the end after they're a great discovery,
screws gets careless
Al right. The Nephews kind of chi him shouldn't we cover up the the entrance
to this temple full of fabulous treasure, and he dismiss them. I wind is gonna... Is gonna come come up. It's... It was too engaged in the the victory. Right.
So we... I like that we get whisk
perspective here. He's sitting there pondering, you know, try trying to figure out they've had luck. And
he sees that their tray and the silver of of their tea has been turned to gold,
which he just in a very une assuming way calls very
suspicious.
And as if he needed as if he needed a more approved, he identifies Scrooge is fat buttons
cain tip, and
are are both gold now and his pocket is sag
suspiciously. And and as he puts
two and two and two and two together,
He beck Scrooge, and the nephews jumped him,
demanding that he explained him himself Yeah. It's a... And that... Again, it's if you if you don't look at ahead, you didn't see that one coming. Like, there's some really... It Again, not no... Again, just seeing this guy kinda like encounter them coming and going. Now you have a little bit of an insight, but it's still not clear.
Is it's not really Al antagonist. He's not arrival.
Right. Like, the... What's the... You know, because, again, he's too goofy to be like a sp. Yeah. Miss Necessarily. Yeah. So we can tell that that he's not a classic villain. We just we can't quite place them. Right. And finally, the nephews get them upstairs into a utility closet, and they start to... They they kind of release at least his
facing this mouth from the table cloth or the sheet that they wrapped in. And he says I must stop that duck let me go. And we that's use does a very...
This is this one where he's kinda confronting mister She says why any he sticks is turnout out. Yeah. You really see uncle donald than that one. You really see that donald Ducktales defiance and that one right of it Al.
Yeah. Where the where the nephews user aren't usually that had doesn't have that much B.
But...
And basically, mister Wi
reveals his
true identity he is most mattress face of the international Money Council. And they are tracking the Philosopher Gladstone as well. The main reason being is the
overuse of the philosopher stone would destroy the value of all the world's goals. Coins. He says all the world's gold coins, but all the gold in the world naturally.
Right. And if that's if the sticks aren't high in enough there, he then adds as they leave the hotel to try and find donald the Scrooge, there's another reason we must get the stone away from your uncle soon and the kids say why The f from the stone will turn him to gold if he handles it long enough. So now we see that he's actually
something of the savior on two different levels here.
So your master face is actually an Ally.
There's a lot to take in on this page. It is a lot of.
Yeah. This story is just full of exposition. Mh. It it suffers a little for it, but but not not as much as it would in another
artist hand. I think so too. Here look like we start... They capture him first panel. Bottom, he's already got them in his good graces. They're their way to find them they're out of the.
So... Yeah. They're motion... Move the action is moving. I think some artist would have kinda just had them standing there with their hand out talking would have been very dull. It's like, a couple thoughts on this page,
bark
around this time was very interested in these sort of economic
monetary lessons Yep. He only takes a panel here. To talk about, you know, this sort of supply and demand and what a real philosopher versus stone would actually do.
I found that kind of interesting that, you know, under a different
circumstance, I could see him, like, going a totally different direction and really examining that idea and it has More of a dis situation for sure. Oh, just just... It's interesting that it was such a timely thing to be
thinking about fishing. Right? And and
nuclear fish is just one of those, like
explanatory things that that Al account for anything around this time. Yeah. I died that had to be in every every every other day that had to be vision and fusion had to be in the headlines every other right. Constantly.
So I I'll I do really like the snap sequence. It's one of the more urgent things. The Barks is done. I love these three panels that drove the nephews all disco
frantically, like bumping it into each other. Thinking about where uncle Scrooge could get metal fast. And we get this kind of
echo of the the previous
you know, journey that had all these different legs
throughout these different countries. But just within within the city that they're in where they They start out at the iron works. They go to the hardware markets.
And again, it accelerates
no sign of him at the silver smith's or the tin makers
and kind of in the background, the Nephews, they've been so frantic that eventually a kind of registers that wait a minute. On Scrooge wouldn't by metal. He goes somewhere he could get it. Free. And and as soon as they stop and really think about it,
consider the way they've been doing this whole story, the solution presents itself, they they need to find the junk.
Right? And then, you know, you realize too, like, you know, the kids are panicked and they're following
your mattress face because he's leading the charge but he doesn't really understand Scrooge my Ducktales, so he wouldn't. Right. And so naturally, the kids are gonna be the one. And you can see that moment of revelation. That's where that's what this is where Barks solidifies every characters personality. This is one of those moments where it's like No. The kids know enough how their uncles are. You know, respectively and together. I don't know if anyone would do it as debt as Barks did right Yeah. No one would have the pacing. Mh. Guys.
We got another great sequence here to wrap it up dan.
So donald and Scrooge.
Well, first of all, the kids are right because that's exactly where they are Junk.
So Donald Scrooge there, and
is just ecstatic and in a rare moment of drag gratitude for his nephew. He says I'll make you a president of a gold bicycle, and donald
gets on it, but the back back of it is crunch up and missing. You said, well, you might have found one with two wheels.
So it doesn't matter because Scrooge is just going hog wild, gold washing machine, and old automobile,
and he's absolutely just... He's he's just... He he's absolutely thrilled with the prospect of this new To Gizmo as he called it. And Donald finally takes a good look and this is uncle Scrooge. Isaac is returning Al lemon color. Screws says they are it must be gold fever, and he also mentioned that the stiffness and his joints are getting worse so we can see that the efficacy,
the stone is already taking root. It's... Might be working faster than any of us thought. And Right. And I had neglected to mention on the previous page that that that, you know, they they remember that screws have been complaining about feeling that stiff joints. Yeah. So... And again, that that there's a nice, you know, inter of that. On your page, this one here at the junkyard,
Scrooge,
like, slightly pale yellow and eyes? Yeah. The the colors done a very good job of of doing just like this suggest and. Oh.
Yeah turning goal. The the the original... The gold key had it.
This one doesn't. At least the digital version does. Just realized that now. So Donald is trying to course to leave and what what happens next. Yeah. We get
we get Scrooge is just having too much fun. He he refuses to leave until he's turned everything in the place.
To gold, and we get one more instance of the nephews tackling someone
as as they cry out, including yourself. Drop that right. And and then the story wraps up pretty brisk here. A narrator box does a lot of the heavy lifting and just saying that Scrooge is saved in the nick of time,
but, of course, has to give up as wonderful for philosophers stone, and all the gold he's made, and he eats a little bit of crow as monte mass mattress face points out that look at what he gets back his healthy color as he holds up Al, like, a junk piece of mirror for him to look at. Boy. These three panels dan
where Scrooge
is just so ticked off at losing
the best toy ever had. I'm almost reminded of the screws from Mickey Christmas Carol or something. Yeah is about to say fair mountain like that early fair.
Just that hunch over g the cane, like... And he was just... And and
three panels before, he was absolutely
buick and tall. I kid again. You know? Right. And the story wraps up with the it's it's a fun little gag. I wouldn't say it's the the strongest cap or ever.
But
screws just pondering on the boat right back if if I had been turned to gold,
keep the moan, the fact that he could have sold his whisk whispers for five dollars piece every time he's shaved
dog on the dog on luck.
It's is cute as I read it out loud, but it always struck me as, like,
it's kind of an average ending. Yeah. I... You know, I think the the only thing that could heightened this...
And I mean slightly is you know, besides the eyes, if those let up here, if you could see the feathers start to turn a a light gold color just you could see it would actually be taking further effect. Just to height the fact that it was a real threat. I think that might have been interesting But the one panel I have to say, the the healthy color panel key not just face is holding the mirror. Look at how there's no clear definition that mirror. You just get enough. It's a different... It's not the same angle. It's more of a front view. And they color it just slightly. I that's that... Even as a kid that one always stood out to me. It's like, she, looks like a real reflection. It really does. Where so many people would You know what? Some... I I would say a lesser artist would have just done the mirror image of that profile right been right. You know? It even looks like like the junkyard mirror that it is. Exactly. But... And again, that's that's what Barks did where a lot of other people wouldn't have A lot of other people a lot of other artists wouldn't have taken to care. That's why all this, all of that work just gets reprinted over and over again and deserves where so many others might only see one or two printing, you know, over the course of seventy years. Right. Yeah. And and so That that is the fabulous
Gladstone.
I think we did a really nice job of covering that. I really appreciate your insight here, Dan. So I know... I know you really enjoy this one. Right? What are what are kinda of year overall
thoughts and impressions?
I think it's, you know, it's one of those going back to what you said before we started. You're gonna talk about the first ten issues.
I think it's a great character study where If you look at only a portal man, you kinda... That's where prior to that. It was always ten page stories or Christmas for Shack and
screwed kinda like lived up to his name say he was a little bit... He was sometimes a little bit more of a foe to his nephews.
Right. But over the course of time, he kind of, like became more integrated with them became more familiar
And when you get to this point, you get to that fam familiar
familiarity level where again, the kids know No uncle Scrooge wouldn't go buy a new metal even though he has the lost for stone he's gonna go we can get it for free. They already know there... And they look out for each other, which is nice day This this... Again, one thing I've said in the past, which I think people don't always ways acknowledge. Like, you you look at our cast here. It's three generations of a family. And there's always, you know, within generations, you're gonna have you gonna have similarities, but you're gonna have those differences
of of behavior of someone being more stuck in a previous someone who's very much in the moment Donald and the kids who are maybe be a combination of both and looking towards the future. So I think
this is one of those stories where the cast
with with where the Ducktales really worked together as a team where before they were things were a little bit more loose. And I like that a lot. Because even back to the cloud dyke, you know, they
led Scrooge
compete with Gold, they really want you... Because they even said, like leave the old lady alone. We don't need to do this. But they... You know, but screws was actually a noble individual at the end. But the same thing where the horse rad story, you know, that's one of those things where they kinda came together. So did this this isn't... This is really a one of the last pieces of the puzzle where everyone's inter walking and, like, the the Treasure hunt formula really becomes established here. And that's the thing I like about that story. Even though your mattress space is not a heavy so.
He's not a b to tag. He's not a big boy. He's not a common gold. He... He's an area. And again going back to what we said before, like, that's why he kinda looks like a, like a tech Severino character. You know, he's supposed to look a little He doesn't have to be men. He's just had to be mysterious, which is exactly what he was. Yeah. I I like this.
I I kinda like this weird little era here because I've already
already recorded
episodes for the next two adventure stories.
Which are the great steamboat race and rich rich
everywhere, both the number eleven.
And So we've got three stories in a row
that don't really have a bad guy. And it's kinda refreshing to see that. I I like that. I I will love a good bad guy Barks has done some great,
but...
But this an interesting little run. When you do things like that, then when the eagles return. It's even more rewarding.
Right. You know, or or others.
Again, halfway through, you really couldn't predict with the outcome of the story would... Yeah. You're right. This one's very unpredictable. It's it's very much all about the journey it's all about the the twists and terms that are both literal
in the labyrinth and fig
in just the con of it. So you know, I... I've already alluded to the fact that this is like
it's... It's not fair to say that this isn't a favor of mine because, like, and do really like this. I read it a lot as a kid. I mean, I I remember every story view this in a way that I don't remember some of the ones that I haven't revisited that much. So I do really like this one and boy every time I really dive deep into a story for one of these so I find so much to appreciate about it. And this one is Oh fine, you know. It's it's much like Kirby Barks.
It's... Every time you go back, if it's been a couple of years, you know, you you getting your eye, your your your perception changes, your world view changes, your knowledge changes.
And I find that I appreciate. I went for a good... I don't know, ten years I really didn't read any of them. Just be... I deliberately to keep a distance
and then when I came back, I was like it's better than I remember. Yeah. It's very rewarding to reread them at, like, different phases of your life too because some phones are that way, you know, Yeah. And and I I think about the fact that Bark was... You know, he was no spring chicken
when he started writing these. This was like a a several careers into it for him. So... That's right. He would have been in his mid fifties at this when he did this one.
So so that was his perspective of. And and it's it's interesting to... Like you said, It's been it's been a pretty good span since I was really
obsessively
re reread and reread these and, you know, that's kinda of part of this podcast is it's been... It's really been since, like, college
before college since I was really in that kind of mode of sure. It was something I did everyday for a couple about. So... So it's really fun to appreciate how he integrated myth and legend and history and and great storytelling.
I really like this one. There are just a couple of things that kinda keep it from
that sort of that all time great sure.
Classic classic story. But it's a very worthwhile very fun story.
And I also think you what we said it earlier is that, you know, I I think, you know, whether it was something he had seen in
book or Geo national geographic. I think he was looking into mythology anyway. And my guess, knowing how he thought processing was he knew what the golden fleece story was gonna be. To have some large looming mythological creatures there. It didn't make sense to do it here if he knew what was gonna be coming. Yeah.
So he might have been avoiding duplication. Right. Taking a different approach with that one. Mh.
There would be some similarities.
Right. So why don't we check in with
kind of the community consensus? I'm sure you know that I like to use Inducks Yep. As a resource. So great. It's a great website with a lot of it. Al lot of great information about stories and, of course, people can vote on their feelings about them. And in the case of this story,
this one as of today, has a rating of seven point nine,
which is good for number fifty three out of all forty two or so thousand
stories.
Okay. That are
reviewed on Inducks. So, you know, it's it's a classic Scrooge adventure
top almost fifty, that seems about right to me. Yep. Absolutely.
I mentioned how I've been really thinking about those first ten screws adventures.
Mh. You know, this one it it it's the case, I think that it doesn't really stack up next to most of the other stories in that first run of ten. Mh But for my part, I think the only one I I would rank it above might be the mysterious stone ray, which doesn't really do it for me.
That one's what... That's the first like real sci five type. Yeah. Story. And that's why it doesn't fit... It feels like it comes later. Yeah. Yeah That's that's probably... That's a good point that I probably should've mentioned that podcast. But...
Yes. I and I'm probably... I might also put this a little bit above the le with the lock. Mh.
But... But definitely, I I I would probably put all the others
even a horse rat story as much as I'm not a a relative fan of that one. Mh. That... I mean, that one just... The horse
has a lot of mood
to it. So
as far as as a bit more reflecting, you know, you you had sent me a nice
couple of images from Barks. Two coil paintings for this one.
I was vaguely familiar with the second of them. Mh. You wanna tell us about the contrast between the two? Yeah. So the first one, I love that first oil painting. I think it might be one of my...
There's so many gray ones. So favorite might might not be accurate. But I I I really like. Oh, absolutely but, again, this then that's that's kind of answering the wish fulfillment of your reading it as a kid because The first one was when in seventies Barks was doing these fan commission paintings, and it's called K the Men, and this is basically the quest for the flu Gladstone.
Except in this case, the Min is a real living creature, and he has a sword. He's she's ready to go.
Even with the, like, giant lots of hair between the horns, which almost reminiscent of Mad they're almost strip like, and it's interesting that Barks chose to for trey him as a real creature. I almost wonder if... Because this was commissioned by a collector,
seventy five, they paid two thousand six hundred and fifty for Bo to do it. I almost wonder if the collector didn't request such a thing. It's very possible that they did. Yeah. It seems likely. But there's there's some beautiful
details with the treasure.
And if you look on the left side the above, the nephew with the the torch, there's a release
sculpture of the
and a young woman kind of in Al embrace It's all... You know, for I don't think the comics at the time would let that one go. It's a little...
It's it's a little suggested to the... I think it refers to the myth. Right of the of the of birth. Right I can't... I can't think of her name no. But the queen was apparently very
taken Yeah. By by by a bowl. And and I guess, you know, I do try to keep these family friendly so we'll we out of that
interesting.
No. Yeah Yeah. And and this one is cool, but I I was invert them in my head. Because I definitely saw the other one. First. It's the one from the
early nineties that would have been, you know, the same year that my rep. Right. Exactly
Actually if you bought this lift graphic came with a copy of that comic. They that. You know? And so this was the last original
oil painting Barks did for another rainbow. This is kind of around the time that that the they they... The Gladstone
had print had and didn't just need taken over com extend. This is the last original work that he did for another rainbow. And this is basically the thrown room of King min
maybe even amplify. It's a little more ornate nate. There's a lot of blue. And the reason there's a lot of blue is to, I can complement and to amplify the fact that the stone, which is a stone color. In this in this painting, the stone turn the lantern
gold. And if... Look... Just look even if you eliminate color for a minute. Look at how it's laid out and look how Barks framed everything even the sword on the bottom right, which is pointing to the lantern. Like, you can't miss what the what the goal of this this image is, it's So... Yeah. This this really wonderful
oil painting
probably...
It probably would be in my top handful of course sure. Pay.
I do like to mention other media, you know, if there have been any follow ups. And,
you know, Rosa did... Don Rosa did a lot of sea pulls and follow ups. To Barks stories. In this case, he didn't do a direct
sequel to this one, but he
reused Mo our mattress face. Al very good effect I thought too. Yeah. Yeah.
He used him in his stories the crown of the crusader kings and the old Castle other secret. And I agree. He fit... He fit in with those stories. And he also... Again, he seems to be aligned his proportionately, but he wound being an Ally. Yet again, and the philosopher Gladstone kinda made this guest appearance that really
works so well. In
a letter from home. Yeah. I'll have to reread. I haven't haven't
revisited some of those. So I'm looking forward to doing that. Soon. And as far as the Ducktales series go, to my
recollection, they never
adapted this. In either of the
in other of the series. No. I don't think it was even referenced, you know? Right. But but there is a brief homage.
There there... It is referenced briefly because they
they briefly
doing on homage and the title sequence
to the earlier oil painting, actually.
Yeah. The the backdrop for the... For that first one right with the the the treasurer behind the grate there. Right.
And I think that's it and the in the opening credits, I think it's that gold dragon that... What's his name. I think they named him after the French word struggle Scrooge actually.
Oh, yeah. That's fine.
So I I think we have a lot great commentary on this one. And we we definitely covered some great panels.
Are there any panel sequences that you'd like to highlight
for, like, favorite panels that we didn't didn't really give enough attention to. I think, you know, the
the exceptional... You know, even on that first page will dollar signs. I think a lot of people are gonna point to the labyrinth.
Yeah. You know, my.
Yeah. But it's... But it's a great choice, frankly. But I would say as well, you know, that it's really more of the aspect of it. It's that little reflection in the mirror... Or. Yeah. It's such a nice... It's such a nice little moment and what's your mattress space is so pleased.
You can see it in his face.
Yeah. But really anything in the junkyard, you look look rubbish, like virtually
he went for it, and it it didn't have to be his detailed as this, but I do like... I do like a lot of that. It's interesting. That... Actually, it's interesting in the last act like, you know, it didn't even have to be in cr. Everything after the hotel, it could be Ducktales. That's you really don't get a sense of it being somewhere else. Right. No. I I think that's a good choice that that those panels you mentioned.
For my part, I I can't help but notice how great all of the panels that show Scrooge
being, like really emotional. Yeah. More. There's a lot of those just him w
or him like grim.
And the
poses are just
unstoppable. I mean.
Right.
I mean, it's it's really the heart of these stories.
Mh. And
perspective. The the stories were always written, but from the drawing style around this I was really just unbelievable. Yeah. Well, Dan, this has been an absolute pleasure. I really appreciate you joining me.
I'm I'm excited to have you back for some others. Yeah. Absolutely. And, again, thank you for the opportunity. I really adore the story and I'm glad to
let you go through with you. And also, you know, by the way, if you wanna surprise, that issue of local Scrooge you have there? U. Yeah. The with. I do indeed. Oh. Why you go and back, look at the letters page. No. Yeah. Are you Are I'm in here? I think that's the one. I I think at one time, and I think it's that one. Right? Yeah. The letters is in a weird
place in this one. Hey. Look at that. I calling with them.
I at New York wow.
I used july. Yeah.
I had fun when I came to the issue for only a poor man.
I I got... I was in the Glad stone two
letters to the editor for that one. So I I I had got a kick out of revisiting that oh that's great. I... That was a bit... That was a double issue. I remember that one. Yeah. Yeah. I was like good.
Well, it's it's looks like a good... It's good call or so So I'll I'll definitely take a look at it.
But there's no insight in there. It's just a it's a fifteen year old kid just shooting it mouth off. Project... But there's a that's a nice little tangent for us. Right. Oh, it's it's delightful.
So I I hope I hope listeners have enjoyed this I hope they'll check us out on the various socials, Barks remarks is on Facebook and Instagram.
And
I
look forward to having people back for as I mentioned I've already got an episode in the can for the great steamboat race.
Dan, I had mentioned I had read read the panel, but it's my shift for closing them out now. Do you wanna read the last at least
at least the last word balloon to close it account. And all how fitting. Yeah.
Dog on the dogg on unlucky.
Awesome. Thanks again, Dan. I'll thanks. Thanks again. I will talk to you soon. Take care.