We can have
Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer an artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comments of all time. Join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks. Welcome come back to Barks remarks, I'm Mark Sever, a grown man who enjoys dot comics, and I am joined by a returning guest host. I've got warren harm here. Warren could you
reintroduce yourself and let us know if you've ever had the pleasure of being on a river boat. Well, thanks, Mark. Great to be back
with this story. This is a is a kind a childhood memory that I cherish in for a few reasons, I live in the state where the Mississippi River comes from. So that that that means a lot. And up here in Minnesota. But but long time Barks collector
and comic fan, really everything Barks. And, yeah, that's the steamboat River boat connection here. There's a wonderful little River town called Red Wing, Minnesota where they have a tourist
boat
that
you can jump on in the summer and and la go down the Mississippi, and it's really a lot of fun to do that. So it it it's around a lake that actually is embedded in the river called Lake pep,
and it's just a wonderful experience But I thing, the most memorable
and I believe it is still a steamboat,
listeners will correct me, but I think the Mark twain at Disney disneyland, is is something that I
have been on many times because every time I go to the park out Anaheim, I love a ride around in the Barks on the market. Yeah. That's that's true. I never really thought about it, but I guess I guess, technically, it is it is a genuine
a bonafide river steamboat belt. Is this yeah? Yeah. So I've gotten to... I've gotten to be on a
a river boat on the Mississippi. My cousin had a Mississippi had a New Orleans wedding
and part of the festivities
included
a reception on a river boat closing down the Mississippi, which was just just big spectacular great experience. Yeah it's a romantic adventure. No no question and and imagine back to the the nineteenth century payday when they were they were the a a a major form of transportation. Yeah. Yeah. For sure. And and steamboat boats and the Mississippi river, you know, they've figure,
they figure in a really important way into the Barks and the Ducktales stories. Right? Because I shouldn't bear the lead here. We're we're gonna be talking today about the great
steamboat
race.
And and Barks really...
His imagination was really fired.
These these steamboat boats by these boats.
Well, there's no question that and I really believe he was
fired is is a great word. He he his is fired. So coal fired. Right right. And he he just... Just really re and looking back in history and Know, we'll do a little research.
We'll do a little bit of historical perspective here as well. But, yeah. This is kind of a Al almost a love story with the river. Kinda like Barks Wayne. You got Barks has the same kind of romantic notion about the river and the racing and the old salt. Right. Yeah. The Mississippi is an important piece of American.
And and one way or another, it just really figures in Scrooge
backstory.
Yeah. Rx sparks has gone back to this a couple of times and and when Don Rosa,
picked up those stories, he added his own flare. It's it's a really great setting. For these stories. So let's see. The the great steamboat race was published Inducks
Scrooge number eleven, and that was back in the cover date was September of nineteen fifty five. Right? This is a pretty john
short little Barks of a story worn. Sixteen pages. What what do you think? I like it. I
as much as I love getting into a a a a twenty eight or a thirty two page story.
The sixteen pages seem to deliver a lot of action in a short amount of time and get right to the point with with one strong story that thread. And and, you know, you can really deviate too far from from the plot, and you have to stay with it. All the way to the end but. I I like it. It's a nice... It's a it's a pe
story length for me. Yeah. I mean, I like it two. Sometimes it's... I... It's nice to see what he can do at different lengths. You know, I I didn't check for sure, but I'm pretty sure that a part from
the fire bug
and
Adam Bomb, Donald Adam bomb, this is the shortest adventure length story we've done so far. Yeah And when I created the podcast, I I didn't start out doing the ten pager kind of pivoted to do... Give those their own little
sub brand. But I I had to think about which stories I wanted to cover. Right? And and, you know, this one was paired Inducks Scrooge number eleven, along with another sixteen pager. And we could talk about both of those, but you know, to me it's important that each of these episodes really
gives these adventure stories there like full do. They're they're they're full focus. So that's that's how I wanna do it. You know, This one's gonna be a little bit more of a shorter yeah. Short. And it stands on its own really well. It is as an adventure story
with a competitive race with the callback to history with intriguing character
in in Horseshoe hog. I mean, it really does have a lot of fun stuff. Yeah. This is a memorable one. I'll I'll admit that this has never been, like one of my all time favorites.
I do find it very enjoyable, but, like I realized going back to it that I I hadn't
reread this one to the way that it it wasn't burned into my memory. But like some of them were I generally remembered all of the story beats.
Right? There there are the occasional
stories that I revisit, and I... I'm like, I'm surprised that I don't I don't remember certain parts of them, but And then there are those where I just like, I I might as well not re reread it Remember so well. And this one, you know, I I remembered it in general, I remembered general, like, architecture of the storage Didn't remember the specific needs.
So that it'll be fun to to revisit this one.
I didn't mention
the number of reprint. This one for whatever reason hasn't been reprinted Al often. And it only as nine
American
reprint total. And, you know,
we we always... We like to mention
titles
from around the world.
I took a quick peru of this one and generally seems like most publishers have gone with a pretty straightforward
translation and So I'll just mention one that I liked from Spain, which was
And me see c p. The rule in the Mississippi. I like that one. And then later on, again, in Spain, it was locked around I got the.
Gotcha I think is just the great steam race.
So that that's fun. Am I correct to assume that the steamboat is truly Al American
invention it is? Isn't it it Fulton? Yeah. I think that's right. I don't I don't have open in front of me or anything
I believe it is. And I believe that's the of the attracted meter this story was the origin on the Mississippi the history. I know, like I said earlier, I'm I'm in Minnesota where the this be river Barks and I've been on it many times and different parts of it. But also the history and the just Scrooge competitive nature comes out in this. This is this is the fun part. And you can't forget the boys, they they are in my opinion and the stars of the story they save the day as usual. Yeah. It's true. They're pretty important here. I think you're right. This one feels like more American.
Than most of the adventure stories that we've seen so far and, like, the uncle Scrooge run of Comics
we're we're finally out of the, like single digits we're we're pretty thoroughly into this run of uncle Scrooge con here. And and so, you know, I guess Barks is willing to play a little bit with his format here, which is why we get this
sixteen pager. What do you say warren? You're ready to dive into it? Let's go well let's get on that the on that steamboat and go on that race. Yeah. Let's do. Let's get our tickets punched.
The great steamboat race. Opens up you know, it's striking me worrying that this is one of the handful
of early uncle Scrooge, Barks
stories that does not open with him in the Bin. He's not in the money bin. He's he's pushing this southern gentleman out of his office, but, yeah, your right at that it doesn't start that way. Yeah. You're right. So we've got Scrooge in his private office and he is giving the rush to a character that we're gonna learn is named Horseshoe
Hog.
Bark Loves that.
Yeah. And they're basically in the middle of this like, long doing argument,
right? Where the the the other docks donald and the Nephews are walking up and their they're kinda serving as the audience surrogate, and they listen to
hog who's kind of ranting about a hassle between the two of them, him and screws that's been going on for eighty five years and it needs to be settled. And hog is very determined to keep pest
screwed
until he is willing to to do it. And he's really...
Yeah. I use the portrait of a dapper southern gentleman. Yes. Yes. He's got the Goatee, the mustache. He's dressed with the best and the tie and the hat.
But every
image of horseshoe hog and this first page is one of frustration and anger. And so you don't know where this character development is gonna... Is gonna go. But Scrooge is not letting him gap his way at all. Right. And and he uses this expression that I don't I don't think you really hear these days. He calls him a dog and the manager
because he says, he allude to this prize, which is a place called corn
Gables. He says, you don't seem to want corn pony gables. Yet You won't let me have it. You're just a dog and the manager. Were you familiar with that? You know. I am? I was not familiar with that. I looked it up
and
essentially, it means that you don't wanna give someone something that you also own, but you really don't care about very much. And it's yeah Yeah, it seems like it's one of those old sayings that that was probably in in common par.
A few decades ago and is just falling out of favor, but that's pretty... That's a pretty useful expression and it's exactly what I thought it was from context. Mh.
So warren before we kinda did on to the next page
I like...
I'm really intrigued by the character
of horse too hot. I I find it really kind of refreshing that he is not a villain. No. He's Al.
He's someone who if when you look at Scrooge,
family history as we move back in time, his ancestors, horseshoe,
kinda grew up with fruit and sisters and it it it it really brings another
level of of interest to the whole Ducktales universe into the whole to the whole.
So he's not he's not.
Someone who wants to strike a deal with his his old nemesis, and maybe is too strong work. I mean their adverse serial, but like, there's they're they're in competition,
but but they're they're Severino like really... He... He's not villainous. He's not scheming. He kinda reminds me of some of the later
competitions that you'll see in some of the, like, nineteenth sixties
screwed stories, you know, some of those like ty
competitions.
That don't have later. But, yeah. But yeah. I find that refresh no I do too. But Scrooge isn't having any of it. He's happy making money and horseshoe hog is just... Yeah. Inducks is only interested in making money he says, Right. And and you can tell that hog is like, he... He's clearly written as being very rich, but he's not like, rich for the sake of being rich like mortgages. We're gonna see him willing to, like... Right.
Spend money to get things done. He... He's an interesting
contrast. It's kind of a shame that he doesn't really here
other than Inducks, some sequel stories like as his Suzanne ancestor. Mh. So, you know, getting further into the story, so Scrooge is is basically
relating to Donald and and Inducks
doo Louis. What the whole story right? And he explains that he and hog were locked in this competition. They they had their their ancestors.
Their ancestors sounds like really old. They're their uncles have had a race that they never finished
to determine the ownership of this place corn pound gables, and he shows him a helpful picture of it, and it's a beautiful old southern mansion as Donald
characterize it. And so you wanna tell us what Scrooge
sp about eighteen seventy? Well, yeah. They were they were the River captain Horseshoe uncle was Parker hog, and his boat was called the River bell and Scrooge
leaning back in his chair is just finally remembering that his uncle was captain Pothole Mc, and his boat was the Stern wheeler cotton queen, so
again, it took me back to eighteen Severino, so I did a little research, and sure enough The great steamboat race of eighteen seventy actually did exist.
Nice.
Between the Natchez and the Robert y lee, and it really did take place on the Mississippi in that year. So I have to believe that was Barks as inspiration for this week. Yeah. Absolutely.
Right? Because he he
identifies the racist
starting
in natchez, which I guess must be taken from that. That's it good to catch. I didn't.
And so that's just a little bit of his
perspective.
When you look at the year eighteen seventy or five years after the civil war America needed healing,
everyone in America and the press picked up on this great race of eighteen seventy, and it just marble America. Now the steamboat
Al a mode of transportation was coming to the end. What was taking over the train, the locomotive. And that's what it was gonna, you know, connect the to two halves of the country East West. So
this was sort of the last
for the steamboat,
and they lasted a few years later, but that race that famous race between the net and the Robert y lee, what really took America by storm and I think it was just so filled with American and his history and so American in its iconic nature Barks could not resist by creating his own little
floor. I I love it. Yeah. That's awesome. Thanks so much for sharing that one. That's a great catch. So, you know, I I like this. The the Ducktales are really
intrigued by screws
recount this, and they're, like, encouraging him to to tell them the rest of the story yeah. And and things kinda switch to a halt because Scrooge says that there is no more story. The the race had this really noble end. Where neither of the boats reached the finish line because the cotton queen hit a snag and the river bell. Blew her boilers and and in the flash panel. We see that they were in really close proximity to each other. Oh again this doesn't seem to be like usually if Barks goes into a flash like this in, like
the horse rad story, it's gonna be because of, like, some kind of sabotage or something. But but now that That doesn't seem to be the case. And so Screws says that, you know, the boats are still there and that horse shoes proposal
is that the boats be raised and they've brace them all over again because they've inherited these claims and ends hog thinks that that's the only sporting way to settle who's property is. And a warren and this seems really fitting right? Because it seems like what a stereotypical
quote southern gentleman
would would propose. Or at least our our cultural
idea of what he would or a fair wear race
winner take Al in this case, cor Gables. And and then I had to kinda think a little bit about that original deal that their uncle uncles made that they both own the claim and therefore
we go back to that dog in the nature.
Right. Like
couldn't Scrooge
just just give it to him if he doesn't want it? Exactly. But, of course, Scrooge Mc doc never never gives anything away for free. That's absolutely
correct. But don the boys are not very intrigued and
the boys get all excited here, you know, what, what what a great prize this mansion and the Southern man. Why don't you erase Al Scrooge? They're just absolutely
convinced that he needs to follow through on this. But Scrooge won't have it. Right. Right. And and they kinda plant this little seed. Right? Well Scrooge is like ranting about how
expensive this whole process would be They're talking about how create would be if he could live there like a real southern gentleman if he wanted to race. And and it kinda gets into Scrooge
head, you know? And on the next page, he's kinda doing that like far away
day dreaming, look. Bark is a really nice job Al training this. And and so he
he does. He
visualize he thinks about corn Gables Okay. So Warren this this this is the part of the story that I find a little bit uncomfortable.
Okay.
I'm just gonna read
what Scrooge is thinking to himself. He keep ponder thinking it would be kinda nice to be a southern gentleman. I could wear a big hat and grow go he. And he kind of pictures himself looking a little bit almost, you know, colonel sanders ish. Yeah That type. Right. He says I can see myself now sitting on the veranda Al cor phone Gables, sipping soda and listening to the cotton picker
str their band.
Yeah. That's where it takes a turn. So, I mean, here's the thing. Right? Like, This is this is
a like fund
reminiscent of the
plantation
ethos. And and I'm sure there a regular
nerves who are like, oh oh Barks is gonna go off on one of his, like,
socially conscious tangent I I don't really beg
for doing this. Like, it it looks to a lot of people,
it feels weird and gross.
Today to kind of like look back with fondness
on on this whole sort of plantation
style. Right? People now. Nowadays, you'll see people like, having plantation weddings and when that comes out later, they get... They tend to get a lot of trouble us because we realized what the plantation was built on, Right? It it was built on slavery.
And and there's nothing about that here directly, you know, it's not meant to evo that. It's just it's just unavoidable.
Yeah. You Yeah. It's what it is. I understand and and no no. You're you're there's certainly no rant here. I I I think there's a there's a a recall of a time when
I I guess I do take issue with the term cotton picker, but that's,
you know, there's so much slang that comes out of that as you know.
But his reminiscent with his eyes close is one of of the the sweet south and the music of the salt than that that time. So, yeah, I guess
today doesn't hold up.
But back then that's what the... That's what the were. Right. Well, there was like, a whole... I mean, it was
extremely popular in the forties and fifties.
To like, even even the yankee would, they kind of bought into this. Right? The south really sold itself. This this sort of lifestyle after the civil war. It was like this effort to kinda reclaim their heritage away from slavery. It was a bit of a sn ring, but, like, people loved films like
like gone with the winds and song of the south, and there was just this kind of mythology.
So I'm not trying to pick on Barks, like, because
everyone did this, but it does look weird to see Scrooge
imagining himself as essentially
Al plantation on.
Plantation owner. And that don't forget that Huey, Hollywood musical called Show boat, That was all about the salt and and that the same error. But but I, you know, I had another
context on this page, I love it Now Scrooge just Barks and his money then on his on his money having this sort day dream and and... But the idea is now getting into do his head that he can't He cannot
not compete with court with the horseshoe. Right. It it kinda reminds me of that moment and back to the dyke where he kind of like is rem reminiscent, and then he all of a sudden demands to Donald. You know, we going on a journey once he remembered. Because he does the same thing here
except
He'll, it'll be a moment before he tells Donald about it. That's. He ends up calling horse shoe hog, and he does this kinda like funny little bit of turn about. Right. He was the one dragging his feet, but now we get the funny comment beat where he he says you can't start until tomorrow while the stalling. You go a chicken or something?
A course, you called him chicken earlier and not he's turning the tables on and I love right. And and so basically,
the Inducks are off. Scrooge
sc does what he usually does with his nephews he ram rides them into joining along another adventure slash treasure hunt slash competition. And he thinks that he has got Al leg up because, you know, he... He's ready to get started on a nice fast plain, and he's... He explains to them on the plane that he's kinda changed
the the rules.
We proposed the rules change. What does he
suggested now? Yeah. He was able to convince or sure that they... Instead of starting the race over from the original starting line or origin that they're gonna start the boat right from where they are.
You know, and race to the end of the from there. So
they thought that was a good idea. It means that whoever gets his boat out of the mud and get it going first
is that much ahead of the other guy? Right. And I really like this aspect of the story from a story
perspective because it adds a whole new dimension to it, you know? It doesn't...
Well like I said earlier, it moves it along it gets you right in the thick of the race right from the beginning instead of having to right deal panels that take you back. So I think it's a wonderful wonderful story point. Yeah. I agree. It's very zip.
And so we we see the Ducktales on their plane, and they are
overtake by, like, a supersonic jet. And
and in a steward, I would usually say flight attendant, but she is definitely coded one of those nineteen fifties, very elegant very attractive steward.
Yeah.
Explains to him that it's a rich Sports Inducks jet racing plain
and we learn the predictable it's horseshoe hog bound of Mississippi at seven hundred miles an hour. So, you know, Scrooge, we... Screws gets that moment where he gets kinda knocked off his perch. I like that we hear we hear Horseshoe su hog referred to Al the Rich sports. You know, and puts him in that class, so he's got money. We know that. He can afford this jet this very very futuristic looking
I don't know if this is about the time that Chuck Yea broke the sound barrier, but pretty close.
Like that.
And he's going at seven hundred miles an hour. So I love Al Scrooge just collapses, and you have that wonderful thought bubble coin with the wings flying away.
Yeah And you know, it makes me think that it would be fun to have brought Hog Barks for more of these encounters because, like, the that sort of character
pathology was not really in Scrooge just like, staple of
or foil. Right? It does... It brings a bit of a new dimension.
So when the docs arrive at natchez,
is Scrooge is really deflate, but he... He's got the old sunk cost fallacy on his mind. Right? When the other Inducks proposed giving up, He's like, I spent a dime for the charts. So we've we've got to get on with it now. It's a great reaction from Donald. There just yeah.
Yeah
they're on the next panel. They're they're they're on the Mississippi and they come up on the cotton queen and all you can see are the stacks the the stacks from the ship
above the the water line.
Not figure how they're gonna raise it. Yeah. This is This is the part where the other docs learned that Scrooge sk doesn't really have any idea for it. That's what he brought them along for. That's why You're there. Yeah.
But fortunately, he's got, you know, his
ex wood shots along with him.
But but before the wood get, we'll get their bright ideas we get to see hog lifting his boat with a couple of crane Barks. What what do you think warren of that That's, like,
wide panel that full with panel of the... Yeah. This The our work here is just stunning I think. I think this is where where where Barks really have fun with with not only the history and and bra is bode but capturing what they might look like after being down in the water for over eighty years and just the... I just love the landscape the birds, the water, the was camp he does his referred for grounding in this panel too. I always like that. And and but no he's using technology. He's showing... And... And I I made a note here that that Barks is the just quintessential teacher. He is teaching history every story almost. And this one has so many facts that he'll point out about how to raise and how to restore and and and... Well, we'll get into the story, but this is the the teacher Barks that I think I was fascinated with his a young boy when I read these stories just to learn more about it. Yeah. It does feel very, like, realistic the mechanics of of all this. Yeah
So, you know, the the...
One of his nephews tells him you better stop pinching pennies here worrying about dimes.
Or you're gonna lose the race. And so we get this very, like, important line for the rest of the story where he admits. I guess you're right. But brother, corn pound gables better be worth this money or four bright young Ducktales are gonna have to scatter in Al directions.
Yeah.
A physical of cash that he's kinda going through as well. Right. And eventually,
the the Nephews bust out there wood got I book. And they they propose they can get the
the ship raised for a thousand bucks
Yeah. Which is only
one of the bills in the in the handful of cash. I just I love that. Yeah. That's true. And warren...
Do you wanna tell us about
what they come back with. Well, yeah. They, you know, they're looking over at Horseshoe and his very expensive looking creams and they're they're absolutely
there's a better way to raise boats in their Wood chuck guide book. So they go off Scrooge just
creating a worry circle in in the grass there had his own little like a portable worrisome room groove
Huey, does.
Any he sees he looks off and sees horseshoe making
pretty good progress when the Ducktales the boys and Donald come back
with a little barge and where's the fancy equipment, There's there's nothing that he thought they would bring back and he says, we've got it on Scrooge, two thousand old entered inner tubes and six miles of bailing wire and this is the the ingenuity that they found by looking through their Guide book. Again. The boys...
The resource this is unbelievable here. Right. And so what do we get here warren we get another
Boat raising see.
It's not Ping pot bowls this time. No No. It
it's tubes and diving gear and the boys,
are now instructing uncle Scrooge as to how they're going to raise this boat. He would Huey, is gonna go down
with air hoses and inflate all the tubes And Dewey and Louie are going to go down and start wrapping the deck with all the the bailing wire. Scrooge just gonna stay on there and his job is to cast off when the cotton queen comes up under the the force of these these boots. But, yeah. This is the... This isn't the first time we've seen this Barks. Right. He he did this several years back
in a pretty famous story called the Sunken yacht it was one of the first ten pager that I covered. Yeah. And this was featured and... This was one... That was one of the, like, Barks and pop culture moments. Right? Because they talked about in popular. Mechanics and on myth busters on the discovery channel and so on. And and it's interesting that this other boat raising technique gets gloss over because I guess Ping polls ping pong balls fire the imagination a little more and and some I'm not actually
did it. That's three years later. So, you know, I like this... What I like about the sequence here, Warren is that, like, clog
crew, they're they're kinda smuggling watching on. But, again, like, h himself is never
this. I know
there's Just in it. For the race, you know? He is. And is looking on and kinda mild amazement.
And he knows something that the cotton queen was cypress so she'll have a bottom, but only if her nails have rusted away. But look at the look in here his eyes. He's he's looking in in kind of competitive
admiration is the already say? Right. And and he is taking his time because he doesn't think much of their their tech needs. That's
But
but again, there's no, like, efforts to sabotage or anything like this.
I did look it up. Apparently Cypress is a very good wood to survive under underwater for a while. So... Good. I think Barks annuity was talking about and we do eventually get a pretty great splash panel
where this, like, jury
boat does rise with a with a pretty john t blur sound effect. And it's a very cool panel. We seldom them see half page splash panels of this detail in any of the Ducktales stories. So again, I think I'm I'm really attracted to these great None, there's there's not a spoken word in them. Just... It's this story that now it's up and now the race must begin, and I just... I just love this. Right. Boy Bark just he loves
to draw boats.
She boats and ringing,
mass Al every every
opportunity he can. You know so the Inducks could continue to secure it. We get a great little comic beef here where yeah. Rising boat has
stuff screwed on his little ski boat because you forgot to cast off. That's a great comic bit. And, again, the artwork work here is just fascinating every every
line of wires is drawn to detail. And... Yeah. And if you look carefully, it is every line of wire is holding down
in inner tube, and it's just... It's got all of the
underwater Lg and c wait or whatever you wanna call that. That would have been down there. I just did just really a beautiful
beautiful panel And so the next sequence is gonna basically be all about the Ducktales efforts
inside the interior of the newly raised ship. Trying to clean it up trying to get it shipped shape. There's there's some really funny common beads here where Scrooge gets covered in a pile of cat.
Yeah.
Are you a catfish fan, warren? Well, I love eating catfish. I have right. And that's what I'm Al. Yeah I I actually... I've haven't caught, but...
But I literally like cat good. So if you live near the Mississippi in in the Southern states, Catfish is always on the menu. Yeah. It's easy to get... When I visit my my folks and arkansas,
it's easy to get cats fish. Does does Catfish
on the menu extend
that high up the Mississippi? Only on rare occasions. I'd say probably past Saint. Louis, you aren't gonna find it very much. Yeah. It's probably not much of a yankee thing. But I
Barks is technique care of teaching, you know, the brass doesn't rust. So the the the the cotton queens engine our brass. And then, of course, he opens it up, and then that's when the cap is running, but I can... I just... I'm just fascinated by the detail of everything from the, you know the prep... Prepping it and getting it all set Yeah. And I mean, we've got a little bit of hand waving. It's it's awfully easy to get this
old sunken River boat in running shape. But Bet it's like
logic approach. Oh, I'll buy it for this story. Yeah. Yeah. Likewise.
And and then we get kind of the last important element of the story
introduced. Do you wanna tell us about Scrooge allergy here? Yeah. This is where we are see a kind of a late story running gag here. He
he'll see if there's anything aboard that they can burn for fuel and he finds these barrels
is Hickory, not... It says no hickory nuts. Nothing but these barrels of crust m molasses or something, and then he starts sneezing. And this is, you know, really a funny sequence here because that one seen on that page where he sneezes any Barks into the barrel with this eyeglasses and this hat flying off is just really wonderful. Yeah. The fun one. But but but sort of his allergies and the must smell don't go together. And he's not he's not Al it very well here, but we see this a time and again throughout the story here. Right. And he allude to being allergic the must smells
like like the bottom of his money bin. Yeah. I yeah. And and these barrels end up being pitch, which is a perfect fuel. Mh. And
I think at the end of this page, hog notices that they're firing up their boilers, and he's despair because, you know, his crew is telling them they're not ready. They they've gotta a finish bolt the engines in their hold.
And and so the Ducktales they get off to an early lead. I do Like Barks does this this really funny thing that he likes to do where... It almost doesn't matter
who gets off to a quicker start because he's gonna
he's gonna throw all these little random obstacles
that's just gonna keep turning the tide of of who's ahead in the competition. So that you you can't... It just makes it so unpredictable. It's very Barks to me. I like it a lot. Back and forth, and I don't know if the rule of three applies here, but I think it might bump they'll go back and forth, you know, two or three, four times before We have an outcome here. Yeah. They keep exchanging the lead and and we get the the the running bit where screw ends up sneezing through his river chart.
They end up, they end up losing some time to go back for it. And even though they even know they find the the missing map and, you know, the map that blew out from the sneeze, they put it back and then of course... Well, that that that map was from eighteen Severino.
So
Right. It leads them to a dead and channel. And we get... We get one of Barks
classic Scrooge is so cheap
gag. You wanna tell us I... Well, he says, look, it it only cost to dime the new ones dog on it. It it would cost me a whole dollar. And just
classic.
It it is classic. I'm I'm sure it's a little bit eye rolling, but
but those of us who love the Scrooge stories love this this kind of thing. I I really like the bit of writing a little bit a few panels back to her
points out that the boiler is leaking badly and he asks Louis if the
guide book says what to do about boilers in that condition and Louis just just proactively
it says to jump overboard and swim for your life.
Tables within my grass.
But. That is a great, and I'm sorry. I missed that earlier. But, yeah, I kinda skipped over that to get to the fives. I love that. That that's one of my favorite bits of writing. One my favorite gag
so the the race kinda
continues.
I guess really, it just gets underway because the the docks have to... They have to turn all the way back basically to where they began. Because with this achievements.
Yeah. Yep. And Hog is the hog and the his river bell have just finally gotten underway. And at this point, the Ducktales have totally run out of pitch. That's right. Yeah. It rip up the cabins and the deck nails, the sun's dried them enough to burden them by now. You know, And so now there... The the desperation is really kicked in because, again, horseshoe is taking over the lead. So what a fix were in, but he starts sneezing again and the course he rips the the wheel right off of the the boat. Right. He ends up wearing the ships wheel and the do do the kind kind of predictable thing where they use the wood of the boat, it cell for fuel. And Hog points out that, you know, the lighter the boat gets the faster she goes
So he switches, he orders them to give it full throttle,
and what happens when I give it full throttle. Oh, I'm fortunately,
horseshoe logs boat,
basically just basically splits in half.
He knew that the new engine was too powerful for this old rotten
Serves says one of the deck.
Never mind the race isn't over, Not until the cotton queen reaches the finish line at the end of the boy up head. Yeah. So we've got this great... Again, this is very Barks. Right? Where where a race is gonna
come down to this kind of pathetic, like,
staggering to the end conclusion.
Yeah. I got a sense that the Cotton queen is just drifting right now. Right. Right. It's very pathetic. They're both basically coming to a halt right before the finish line. What it it.
Yeah.
Yeah, just twenty feet away, and and the Inducks run out of wood and and then and then Barb
got c for a warranty and tell us about how the running gag comes back into play. Well, now this sneezing couldn't happen at a better time because is is Scrooge kind of gears up for that big sneeze from his allergic reaction to must places. It pushes that final two pushes him right over the finish line. And then we see this this horrible rec of ship make it and, of course they all they're all happy. And we... It takes us right to corn home Gables Barks take us home. Right. Yeah. I I love that. Right? He sneeze is right into the paddle wheel. It's totally cartoon logic.
Yeah. Yep. And and as you mentioned, the Ducktales
they are victoria since Scrooge does win the full title to corn Gables,
and he approaches it in a very excited manner saying he can't wait to move in and become a southern gentleman.
And and I I don't like these moments where characters are kind of proposing to like, abandoned, what makes them them. I think that's probably one of the things I didn't like this
about this is a kid. I just I want screws to always be like, because rich tay himself. But Right. But anyways it's he has to be excited for the sake of this final gag
where where he opens the door, and the the mansion is looking
extremely.
He He comments kind of off offhand but, yes. It it does smell a bit
must.
And how does it wrap up or? Well, we thought that we saw the final sneeze but not quite... This this sneeze breaks down the entire corn phone Gables mansion
and then he races off after the Inducks
basically.
Right. It it feels like that last niece should've have been the really big, like, comic cap
finale of that, that running gag but Barks gets in another great one here. He does. And it it really ends with a callback. To that panel where he says, you know, this mansion better be all it's crap up to be your I'm gonna chase you off into the four foreclosure.
Yeah. It
There it is. Warren. This is like a john t brisk b story.
It's very satisfying. Right? Yeah. I mean, we we get to meet
this non villainous
adversary who seems to be a a a fair sport, the southern gentleman and Horseshoe Hog.
I agree. I wish I could have seen him in other stories. But if we get Al little taste of the Mississippi and Al little bit of history with steamboat and the romance of that era. And the racing, and we now know that it was tied to an actual lace in eighteen seventy.
But just a nice little Ducktales. Yeah. Yeah. I I think so. It's it's never... It's never been one of my favorite as I mentioned, but it is like a very satisfying
tight little story that the steaks are much lower and most of the stories
from from the Scrooge adventures around this era. I mean, he's not gonna fortune here. This is not losing a fortune it's about gaining a house that he's interested in perhaps moving to. And I never... I never thought of him a abandoning Duck and the money bin. I always I kinda looked at this as a summer vacation home that he would wanna go visit, I and I could buy that. Sure. I could see that. I could also see on getting, like, incredibly bored after like two days and.
And abandoned cor Pound Gables
Can I say it by the way that the name of that mansion is outstanding? Yeah. But what do you would what you hear the word corn phone? What is that say? I mean, corn pound is just one of those, like, very stereotypical,
like, Uber
American south things to say. We we talk about, like, the southern accent, literally being corn phones. Oh yeah. We. Baby. Yeah. It's very funny.
There's some sharp writing in this one. It's always
great to keep him drawing
vessel. He's just
So you you can tell the the joy that that it brings him to to t boats. I think drawing the boats and they and a wonderful half page splash panel with the the boat surfacing to the kind queen coming up is just brilliant and again, it it reinforces what you just said. He loves
drawing these these vessels. And
and it loves the Ducktales these these, but I would call American adventures. You know. Right. Their whole... Yeah. This is one of the stories that really points out that despite being like a scottish Inducks. Scrooge is, like profoundly America Yeah. And I think we're we're hitting a stride here and and other stories after fifty five where I think Scrooge
we can talk about this, but might be at the peak of his of his character development now. He's he's getting there. He's maybe not quite, but he's we're seeing some of these other family
history
memories come back. We're seeing some of these wonderful adventures that are have within the country, not necessarily in in Ducktales.
But, yeah. I I I... We're really kind of seeing screws now kinda fully developed your Yeah. I I think to my eye, he is basically
fully developed. Okay. At this point.
I mean, that's just where I am. I don't I don't think there's much more evolution left in the character, but I'll be interesting to pay attention to is as we continue to go along. Yeah. I think you're right. I think I think he's about as far as you're gonna go, but this... But probably peaked in the in that fifty two a fifty five time period. Right.
So let's talk about the critical
consensus
on this one One because index.
Index which, of course, is the site where users can rank and vote on the stories. And, you know, it's not gas or anything, but it does give us a pretty good idea of what the community thinks about it. So out of ten, this one gets a seven point seven.
Which is good for number one hundred and thirty nine. Out all forty two thousand or so stories that are ranked on Inducks. So that's like a a very well ranked story
for Barks.
It is... I would say kind of pretty good. So this is a pretty average story among Barks adventure stories. It's still, like, it's still is is considered great, compared to most, you know, other created. I think that's about right. I think this... I personally think this is a pretty average story. But again, it's not one that I read early on, so it does have, like an Al hold for me. Sounds like you'd probably rank it as kind of a personal favorite. Maybe it's got a bit of an nostalgic. I think that is nostalgic part is what what I I talked about first. And also aligns with another
important piece of Disney history. If you think about the release date of this in September of nineteen fifty five. I would imagine that Barks wrote this earlier that year. Is that correct? Oh, yeah. I think so. Let's see. This one was written
in February.
Fifty five. So while February of fifty five, remember
Disneyland was being built at the time And so we have that Disneyland built in one year and one day. And and
and and so Barks certainly working
as an artist in Southern California knew about this and adventure, this is this venture. And and I think the whole eighteen seventy steamboat race plus There was no secret that the Mark twain, the Disney steamboat at Disneyland was going to launch on July seventeenth nineteen fifty five, There's Al these wonderful which I like is sort of the the historical
placement of where these events occurred. And those this story was timed, I think really nice to the opening of Disneyland. Yeah, that's a good point. I'm glad you pointed that out. And and, you know, really, it's it's hard to
remember about like, the Barks twain stories they figured
so prominently. I mean, they're they still do. Right? It's he's he's a great American story but I I definitely feel like in the fifties, those were a lot more salient
Al time. Yeah. And I also think this story
as I read it again
for the first time in a long time, and I really I get brought Barks memories, which is kinda what I'm talking about. I think it would have been a great animated cartoon. I really think this would have a great card too and it right at the Huey, day of Donald Barks in the fifties too. But it it didn't. And and I think it's placement in in sort of that index universe is is very fair. I think it say, it's it better than I would call a better than typical story. Sure. Yeah. I won't argue. This would this this seems right for
for
animated
adaptation. You know, you mentioned
Disneyland. We we
we should not fail to point out the
the other
Karl Barks
river
race
story, right, which was in the
the the weird uncle Scrooge coast to Land. Yeah. I have that original del too, and you've got the the great reprint there.
Yeah. What was that Right. Called again. And and that was called. I think that's called the
fantastic river rate. There you go. And that literally was meant to celebrate.
Disney disneyland.
Yeah. So, yeah. Like, Barks did
he did a couple of great
river race stories. That one's a little bit odd a little bit unique but that is still a great read.
And
yeah, very memorable.
Let's talk about kind of the legacy of this story. More, I would say that this one really has kind of a big after life for, like, a a little sixteen page are you know? Mh. I think so. So this
story
despite being
again, pretty john tea.
This this ended up being a a huge part of the Barks.
For Dawn roses
big project, the life and times of Scrooge dot a lot of his, like, second chapter, the master of the Mississippi
story was based on the events from this Scrooge
recollection,
and also that other river boat story, the fantastic river race.
But arose that took a lot from from those
to to develop. Gross other artists who who followed in this these footsteps really did
pay homage to the to the Boat story here. And I think, you know, this is the basis. This was the groundwork. The set the set the stage. And, again, I just... I would say it's because it's a great American adventure. And it stands to reason that people would be nostalgic for this earlier time. And American history in the post work here. I agree. The the last thing I'll mention as far as adaptations is that this story did get a a pretty
brief
sort of Ducktales.
I that... Okay. Yeah. What one of the episodes from the first run of the series dime enough for luck. It's kind of like it's meant to be sort of recount how Scrooge made his fortune and and got his number one dime. I would say it is not one of the series best episodes. But the the the little brief sequence that adapts this. Is this... It's probably the strongest part of the story. And, you know, it it literally does name check corn pound Gables. Well, it does.
Yeah. Then I did actually become a bit of an animated film.
Yeah. I it wouldn't it would definitely wouldn't leave you satisfied.
Okay. But but it was cool to see it. You know, that they've been that weird early nineties animated way, the boats, like, are moving on nash. Shirley. Oh Barks hated.
But anyway,
gotta mention it. Yeah. No no oil paintings that I'm aware of or
or anything. For this. No. So...
Yeah. You know, it's a short story, so there may not be as much to say about it. But it's definitely a fun one I am pleased to have revisit.
Yeah. It was fun. I... Again, the the the splash panel there that we talked about very memorable.
The artwork on the river, the the
attention to detail
of the steamboat
and their their structure, and even they're rebuilding
He he didn't cut corners there. And and then, of course, he knows has a beautiful... It's a wonderful story. He knows how to add those gigs, the the sneezing of Scrooge
and establishing that wonderful
rivalry read between him and this new great new character horseshoe hog. Right. For sure.
You wanna hit us with the one or two favorite panels that we didn't mention?
Yeah.
Sure.
Well, I think when I look back at memorable panels,
I I I'll repeat again that that the the the clean coming up above surfacing is is wonderful.
I do really like the the joke... The the the sneeze of Scrooge just going back into that barrel of pitch. I think that a wonderful piece of our work. I get I love it when he exaggerate that the form of of of the the Inducks. Those are those are fun. Yeah. That's an excellent one. And and as you say, there's a few of them that are pretty obvious. So I I'll go to a couple of less obvious ones. Yeah. Would get like the one where one of the nephews is lever himself against the machinery of the engine as they get it started. I think that just looks really neat. He's like full on horizontal
And then I I like Scrooge under the pile of cash fish. And you mentioned the Nephews and the the one shot of of... I can't remember which Nephew it was.
Oh, he's in the office at the beginning of the story. And it's it's the nephew leaning on a cane like a little southern gentleman. That is cute. That's that's cute. I I love to see him up there. Excellent.
Well, warren, thank you so much for joining me for this office so.
I hope people
know where to find this at this point. We've got Barks remarks on a couple of the socials Facebook and Al
Instagram, and
please join us next time as we get to cover the second story in this
issue of uncle Scrooge, riches, riches,
everywhere. Warren, can you hit us with the dialogue and the final panel? Absolutely.
And so, you rattle heads and your romantic ideas about the old soul. Wait till I catch you, Awesome. Thanks for... Thanks again, Warren. Thank you, Mark.