We can have
Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer an artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comments of all time. Join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks. Welcome back to Barks remarks. I'm Mark Sever a Grown man who enjoys Inducks comics. I Al joined once again by Warren, Warren, could you
reintroduce
yourself and I've had you on a lot. What thing. Let me ask you. Who is your favorite Barks side character? Oh my side character. Villain or side character
or... I have a soft spot for gyro Gu. I really do. His solo stories with helper are some of the most invent, humorous,
big just a a breath of fresh here for me. A solid choice. I'll I have to have you on for the eventual
Ji short stories.
Episode.
Deaf. Yeah. I've been doing this for a while. I'm a long time Barks collector and comic fan and Barks fan. So... Yeah. Yeah. And and today, we get to talk about a very fun story
We're talking about riches, riches,
everywhere. And I'm pretending that we're not recording this immediately after the...
It's it's fellow comic book may in uncle Scrooge number eleven. Right? This is a pretty unique issue. It had two sixteen
pager.
So I I wanna keep them their own episodes though.
Give them both their due. We we're... We've
recorded
the great steamboat race, and now we've moved on to rich rich everywhere. Which one's your favorite of those two one? Boy. I
how I wasn't ready for that, But I will say
the memories of steamboat rates, the great steamboat race probably
I remember more, I had not Red bridges rich everywhere a lot before this. Maybe once and so revisiting that story and how it reminded me of another
story that we'll talk about and was it... But... Yeah, I think great steamboat race. Right on. Yeah. I had it... I had a feeling you might. Right? And and for very understandable reason,
I think steamboat race probably
is technically the better story I just... I really like this one. I feel like it backs above its
above its weight. Right?
Good point, I think it does too there's a lack of found in this story that that I that that that kind of recalls
why I recall some memories of some other stories. We'll we'll get into them as we walk through it. But it's it's it's classic in every way because you got the boys and die I'm so fascinated Al at dead Scrooge as well. Yeah. So rich rich
everywhere. But again, just like like in our last
episode. This one was released Al a cover date of September of nineteen fifty five, where still an uncle Scrooge eleven just like steamboat raised. This one has only been reprinted nine times.
Okay. And just like that b john t story, you've got it. Quick little sixteen
page adventure. Absolutely. This is...
Kind what I would call the Treasure hunt adventure.
Yeah. This is like
the the kind of like. Really focused on Scrooge is a great prospect.
Right. And we've seen this, like, Al alluded to, of course, and back to the Blonde and only Al man, but, like, this this makes him out to be more than just an argo.
Right? He's more than just, like looking for gold or or or the copper that's briefly alluded to and poor old man.
But this really adds to his leg.
Legend his mythos and and in a very funny brisk.
It does. It does it. It shows he's the expert at doing this. And I think this is a
another classic story. What you said it well
where we see En Scrooge Al the expert
really, does this prospect in his deep down inside of him is gonna come out in this story and and his expertise is just marble
the the nephew is just marble at it. Right. So let me pan very briefly to the international audience
Yeah. I was looking at a couple of international titles.
I like the first one from France where it's La
the.
So that seems to be... I'm gonna risk it and not look up the translation that. It's the Ducktales family,
I'm not sure if exploit is
exploits as in minds or
explored. I'm thinking that's minds, the desert.
Yeah. That would make sense. And then
later on in France, it was
Rei
call pew.
But again, it's a pretty direct translation. It's just kinda has a great sound to. Right? I like it as riches and even more rich
I I like that one why. You said well, yeah. Well, if as long as as you don't speak French, I.
And then speaking of the title, the fun thing about it is that it's a pretty neat classical
illusion
Rich rich everywhere is...
It it has to be intended to be a reference to the old samuel c
poem, the rim of the ancient mariner
with the the lyric water water
everywhere and
area dropped to drink or not a drop to drink.
I don't remember exactly how it goes. But it's cool poem
and it was very memorable
put to music
by my favorite heavy metal band, so I'm I'm just gonna
insert a couple a few brief seconds of that
a very few brief seconds of that into the podcast here. Because I don't want any copyright bots to to strike me down. But
here it is. A little little bit of the poem
set to some
great heavy metal courtesy of iron maiden.
That the title is based off of.
And look at that, I just succeeded in
getting my love for duck com and iron maiden in the same podcast. So only.
That's right. So when you and I both found this one reminiscent of a of a past
great story, the magic hour hourglass.
Did, we did. That to trip out to the desert and the...
Yeah. The the quest for water. I I don't know. It's a it's an interesting tail in that respect. It bark it fun one. Visited it a little bit. Yeah. I'll tell you when when I was a kid reading this, and this was somewhat of an early Barks story for me, so it might be a little bit of a nostalgic favorite.
I was obsessed with geology and minerals
So this one really rubbed to me right. Are you ready to to dive right into this? I am, and I'll I'll share that vaccination with with minerals and and and rocks and gems. I I I remember as a twelve year old somehow, I got this... It was a cardboard box with every kind of
mineral
stone on it, and it was all there was copper there was led, and I just... I had it on my dresser in my room, and I just fascinated by kids can look at that kind of thing for.
Same thing. It was it was paid. It was glued onto to the board with a little... This is what it is. They there were eight or ten or twelve of them in there, and I just... Yeah. I think I yeah you know, who... What what young boy or girl didn't wanna go out and fix four. I I think I think you may have figured out some grand gifts.
Here you go.
Alright. So rich rich everywhere. We we mentioned the last episode that unusually,
we did not start out in the Money Bin. And and we are back to it. Right? Barks is signaling
signaling
screws wealth to us. And and this is a storytelling device that he'll use frequently somewhat frequently where he is
his grand nephews with tales of his ex exploits. It is tell us again Scrooge how you how you made all of this money
and he is
kinda of below
he is po
about how he made it with a pick and shovel. And usually,
he talks about the
a wide variety of adventurous things. You know, me...
Maybe Huey, would typically mention being on the river boat or a cowboy.
But we're focused on prospecting
today. Yes. So so he's talking about digging all kinds of minerals out of all kinds of hard grounds.
And Donald comes in.
We got this fun little back ground image of him on that first splash panel warren where he's
Al the money in a bull, or I I really like that. Oh, I I love these old buddy such. They're just grand and you you get to see a little bit of what the top of the money bid might look like as well. But... Yeah. Oh, yeah. Yeah. This is great. Great poetry by Scrooge there too. It is. All all of his poses are great.
And Donald mentions
he he he wishes that Scrooge would share some of his secrets because as it turns out, the have a prospecting
trip plan for neck week.
And and screw propose, you know, why not take me long
but
Donald has kinda learned from experience.
And what does he tell us on the next page? Well, Donald says, although, I don't while you log. You'd expect to keep all of everything that we find. And
oh, without me along, you'd likely find nothing.
So it's...
You know, he he wants Scrooge advice and he wants his ideas, but he does not want him to go along with him. Right. But but Scrooge does cut them what he
characterized this a very generous deal
where he would... They would get to keep one dollar out of every hundred dollars worth of minerals.
That's that's wonderful.
Donald gets off one of the lines of the
stories saying one percent. I can see that you didn't make all of your wealth with a pic and shovel.
But you know what Warren, that's a honestly a pretty great deal. Right? Like... Yeah. Because Scrooge is... I mean, he's he's pretty sure I higher. So,
you know,
one percent of a million bucks is is still something. Yeah. And Donald has a bit of a change of hard. And he is convinced and the boys are now
very excited as they jump up well he wants to go anywhere in the world. Yeah, does it really matter where it is. Right. And and this is the big hook of the story. Right? Yeah. Scrooge
is so confident in his ability to find well. That he says that he can find some kind of rich minerals
anywhere he happens to be as he leans on a globe and And and... Okay. So the nephews... They call out the title, we get a title on the call. Yeah. Yeah. Which as rich everywhere.
And they get off a great choke. Why not start looking right here?
It's joking that they'll gladly take one percent of the wealth in the bit. I I like that That was was genuinely funny. I thought. It was hit threw me it wasn't oh, that is really clever. You know, Barks had this
insight where all the boys have to do say. But, we found it and there it is. They they they're wealthy for the rest of their lives and.
Scrooge know the money bin is out of bounds for prospect.
No no more funny remarks. I can almost see Scrooge telling Barks that. I know. And I I love his, like,
expression as he colds them.
Oh, yeah. Put at donald in the background.
Right. Donald is genuinely muse. So warren, we we get one of my favorite
adventure tropes here. We get a globe spin. Yeah. I love it. I love it when Tv characters or common characters
spin the globe and randomly points.
And and that's again, the hook of the story he'll go anywhere to prospect and his finger
lights down on a place away out in the desert of Australia.
I'm like he's he's surprised, but come on. Where were you expecting could have been even worse. I was wondering out Scrooge it could've have been... Well, look Al you take the globe spin in like of the North, the the Ducktales Landed in north of Alaska in the in those sea. So no. I think this globe been has actually landed them on land and Australia. It's it it seems realistic to me, but he's like, oh,
he's he's regretting it immediately. Right And I mean
australia
the expensive of getting there. Maybe that's it. Sure. Sure. But it is famously the side of a couple of gold rashes
Sure.
And so this is our first time to my knowledge heading
returning to Australia. After the early Donald duck venture
adventure down under. Yeah. Mh.
But but this one we're gonna be in the out outback.
Entirely in the outback the whole time,
I guess they land at Sydney briefly. But
right they they, you know, they get there, they take a
a boat to arrive, and we transition pretty quickly to an out fitter where he gets ready for their trek into the Outback. And warren, why don't you tell us about this kind of unusual
sequence that sets.
Yeah. Strangers.
This this was this was interesting, again, reading the story for the first time in a long time.
Kinda said, okay. Here we go. First of all, the the narrative panel that explains the uncle Scrooge should never brag in front of strangers. And, of course, he's in Sydney. They're strangers everywhere. But we see this sort of
Shadow of two two men who are definitely speaking in an Australian dialect.
Hear that bigger I do and I say, bloke make. So just strike. He's the fed Scrooge Actually. So they know who he is. They
converse with each other to tag along after him to see what he can dig up
let them find us a fortune to speak a hunter so we know it's bigger and hunter. So as they head of it, it has shades of the beagle boys, but not quite. That's how I kind of saw these two characters. We don't know what they look like though. And then right that's the interesting
Barks
introduction of what
could be very villainous this characters here. Right. They're they're definitely coded as very sinister.
Yeah.
And and it's very intriguing.
And it's interesting because, you know, they are gonna end up not being villainous.
Why no.
Yeah.
It it's kind of an odd... It's kind of an odd on characters to thing. And I... You know, we we just earlier, we talked about the great steamboat race, which again has this like, add serial conflict
against a character
who is not a vi. So I find it interesting that he did two of these around the same time that ended up in the in the same issue. Yeah. That's a really good point. And I again maybe it's another way to keep a sixteen page story moving, but
but this one took me by surprise because we don't see them for a while.
Right.
So so the next sequence is basically gonna be the docs out in the out outback.
And and like a lot of these desert set stories, there's gonna be a big
preoccupation with water and staying hydrated.
You know, you and I had recently covered the seven cities of
I
I'm always feeling thirsty on behalf of the characters when I read these stories warren. I always have my water with me because I do do. Yeah. Yeah. No. But they're there they... So such it's an important part of survival in in Barks world that he's Inducks on these adventures and these are the simple things that they can use to survive. And sometimes they they've ignore it. Right
And so, you know, basically, I I like this next sequence, but it's it's not all that interest. It's it's really designed to set up. The fact that Scrooge just determined to get out to this
location
to prove his point
and things kinda start to go aw. He accidentally
swings into a big part of their water supply damaging, and it can team.
The nephews point out that technically he's missed the site. There's a quick gag about compass is not working half of the the greater is a the pickaxe for a Compass. Yep. Yeah. It's pretty funny.
It.
Mh It does move quickly here and and Scrooge the... This rock that
that he strikes
and crowns himself ends up being pure lead, which is kind of our first hint of the little...
What's the word? Is it just his kind of uncanny ability that we're gonna see later. Yeah. You wanna say luck, but it's probably a little bit more than that with Scrooge
yielding the pic because
led is the first level of of mineral that he finds here. Right. And and and, you know, that's classically one of the well anyway. So
Donald is really eager that Scrooge has proved as point by finding that and he wants to hike Barks
civilization.
But it turns out there in a bit of trouble because of losing that water
Yeah. Yeah. When the pickaxe hit to canteen,
they're out of water and the nephews on the the the next page or just basically saying we have to refill them And the junior would check
we learned about to read signs that aren't nailed on posts and such as animal tracks and going in a certain direction. So they're they're trying to be resourceful here as Uncle which is kinda coming out of his days here. Right. And and they lead the Ducktales to a water hole. Yeah.
And and this is gonna be where we spend much of the rest of this brief story. It's a it's a neat little location.
It got, some wildlife,
some ding and kangaroo.
And and the kangaroo are drawn pretty much the same as he drew them back. Can adventure down under pretty much. And and you know, the dots feel a lot better, especially
Scrooge
with some water
side, you know, it's a safe supply of water. And so he's elected that he's gonna do some real cross expecting. You wanna tell us about the Sequence or this is funny. So in this wild place, we could make a fabulous of strike. He's pretty confident Now, again, that you said refreshed... And he here this this laughing this calling and he turns around and that's enough of your remarks. You k K burrows and he pitches the lead... I believe it's the led that he found earlier.
It it.
It cuts the trees down the three birds kinda jump up in the air. But he hits this in in in the Graphics book it's kind of a green layer looks like green layer of of rock. And as it crashes into the rocket it reveals a silver
vein and that is what He found next is sober right. And and that basically
sets the tone worn for a lot of the rest of the story. He's he's is going to
kind of casually
or half hazard
uncover a lot of different minerals. Yeah. And And when they set up beside a part of the cliff that is easy digging,
Scrooge
instruct Donald to kinda chip off some of the, like, very una assuming stones that he's
dug up and tell us about what Donald finds. Well that finds it that the underneath on the the yellow or that blows, it's uranium. So where he He he says, okay. Well, Sober is okay but we can do better. And now he's discovered uranium is the next stone. Yeah. Sunday stack up this big pile of uranium or which quote is worth more than gold these days and unfortunately, I think that was probably true.
There's a fun little bit where the Nephews here. They jump for joy and say, ma'am, and Ser, Scrooge screwed is the greatest prospect or it ever shook a shovel. It's a little corny, but it's fun.
And then they have this little... It's called a skin. Right I wasn't sure what that was. And they but they did bring one along because they're prospecting and they wanted to find out what they would find. The Rich. I think we... There's a pretty famous ten pager or with a sent liter too. Was all shit later. Okay. And I think that's yeah. That's fine. Oh, I've always mentally read that. But they're in us
they're look new. Can I ask you were you concerned about the Inducks and their exposure to this uranium? And no. I didn't think of that.
I mean, I I looked it up. I I was. Apparently, uranium or is not, like, radioactive to the point where it's gonna... Oh, okay. Good. So So I was worried on their behalf. But apparently, you you can you can hold up some uranium or and be just fine. Alright. To hear that alright. So I'm I'm you know, this is kind of a cheesy bit. Like so the Ducktales
gather
this big pile
And as they're debating, how to get it back to
civilization,
they noticed
some track leading to this water hole and they and they identify that two men have been camp out. And as you mentioned warren, we haven't really thought about what hunter and dinner in a couple of pages.
Yeah. Yeah. And screws is
despair that, you know, they've got these claim jumpers to deal with, who are who are a very mean lot.
Mh.
And I don't know. This this is, like, I guess it wasn't
maybe this horrible cli at the time,
but I I just can't take this trope serious. Right? Putting anything in a kangaroo pouch.
This is the Nephews plan. And then we've seen this in a million pieces of media across the years. Sure.
There's a great bit in the Simpsons,
Warren where one of the
homer or and Barks in there go to Australia. So they try to do this. Yeah. Like, yeah. It's a lot stick here than the cartoons show you.
Yeah. Well of the simpsons. I love it. Yeah. No. I said it it it is far fetched and... But you gotta get the or out of there or you gotta get the uranium out of there. And, yeah. The nephews
again, tend to have the answer.
Yeah. It's classic cartoon line. If they're they're gonna load up for... They're gonna load up the kangaroo pouches and and, you know, let them take it to wherever they're headed and and when when the older Inducks point out, how how are they gonna get it out that nephews say, well, we're gonna still away in their pal. Right.
And I guess they're smaller than, like, the average Huey,. So maybe it's not as unrealistic as all that. I
I had a tough time buying the fact that out of these wild ding and kangaroo that the the the boys are that confident that they've made pets out of most. Oh, yeah. You're right. I've I skipped past that. They've kind of mentioned we've made pets of most of them There's a little bit of hand waving here. It's... Got lot of it. Yeah. This is the ce part of the story.
It it works part logic wise. But but I do like this bit one, the part that causes all the trouble. Right? Is that
the older Ducktales
observe the kangaroo leaving so that they know which way to to take off and you wanna tell us their their kinda guide... They're way finding
Yeah. They're way finding
mechanism are these two
very long looking trees that are standing out. They're definitely in the path of the of the departing Kangaroo
So
he's hoping that those two threes they they stand in the line, and that will be easy to remember. Is in the morning, Al we have to do is we'll pass those two trays and keep moving. We can't miss that then we see the two trees stand up, and this is where immediately say, okay. This is gotta be bigger and hunter. Right?
Because they start talking to each other. Yeah, that the base glow like they swallow Jack enter. And so they know they've got something
but they still are kind of ominous figures here. So what do they do? Well, they decide to look like...
I think innocently trying to find out where they went. I don't know and this is what kinda confused me, Mark. I wasn't quite sure if they were intentionally
repositioning
to
to screw up Scrooge. I don't think so. No. They they don't know that they're... That the trees are Barks They
and everything out. The only thing they don't know is exactly where his quote glory is. They don't Know the exact location
of the uranium mine and they want to get a better glimpse of it and and at this point, we think they wanna jump the claim. But, of course, we're gonna learn later that they're just trying to state their own yeah
legitimately.
Yeah. Yeah. We've got to locate his digging and we don't dare go into his camp snoop around. He could plot us. I didn't know what that meant got us, or did they mean spot? I I
I... It must be an Australian term. I yeah. I... I'm I imagine that my reference like a pot shot, but maybe it is us
pacific
Al slam. He calls them the the tree blinds then to a different location because that's what they intended it to be. Right. But anyways, so So, yeah, they they move just to get their... To get a better view. And of of course,
this causes Inducks to, like, doubt their sanity.
And
as they wake up in the morning, they're kinda standing there and they they end up going the totally wrong way. They head out to the... They they don't go south as they should. And as they walk past the tree blinds,
one of the So called claim jumpers
has, like, a question mark balloon. Yeah. Wondering, you know, why they've gone off in a different direction.
Yeah. So they
looks like
the the Nephews have camped out now. They've made it to a destination, but they can't find donald and Scrooge they they haul they call out to them. Right. Because they've returned
they've returned. Yeah. And that's when we start hearing again, these
from these two men. Now I'll be honest with you, Mark. When I saw these two men, there's no tree they're not in Silhouette.
It took me a while to kinda say, oh, these are those guys. Maybe them just slow slow on this story, but it took me a while to thread it all together it... That not too long. Maybe a couple of panels in. But It's it's a very jarring. Right? Yeah I guess that's why I'm saying it. It'd be it they that's not at all, like the silhouette seams that we saw earlier.
Right. So Barks has done all this coding. Right? Very overt. He's used all these, like, very specific storytelling
techniques like showing them in silhouette, not not letting us see them showing them whispering and skull king Every
storytelling
indication that he's used is that these guys are bad news. Right. And then, as you say when they show up they're looking very baby face
very jane,
and they just saw to write up and introduce themselves as prospect
that just state to claim and and it it is jarring. And like, I will say I I don't think it really works. No I don't either. And I wanted because the editors maybe gotten this one or Barks just decided to to do it but it it's very... I don't think this is any kind of editorial interference, you know? Because, like, through the rest of the story, they are the point I think there's a little bit of a jump don't judge a book by its cover except it's like on the readers.
But I will say I don't think it's as much as I enjoy this story, I don't think this little turn is that six successful because there's no interaction
between the characters,
there... It's it is it's weird
and it it doesn't match like, the usual storytelling rhythm that you would expect from this. So I I suspect that a lot of other people
have probably found this jarring and confusing.
Because of that coding?
Yeah. I don't feel alone then, but and it wasn't until the last panel of that page.
That we really understand when he uses the word... The name dick. So we go all, okay. These are those two because the the baby faced nature of them, the the sweater, the the what they're wearing and it and they're pleasant. They're those are like some of the friend looking characters the Barks has ever draw. So does it work for me? Man, it it threw me off. Let's put it that way. Yeah. I I definitely... So I think that if this story had another six to eight pages.
Yeah. It probably could have made for, like, a good sort of reveal or turn
and I still really like this story. But I I... It is jarring.
But but I like their role and the rest of this story. Right? The
they're gonna they're gonna kind of figure out oh no. We've inadvertently
you know, the the the, the Nephews mentioned that how can our uncles have gotten lost, All they had to do was walk and align with those trees. And, you know, even here the story is so short that it's missing the panel that I feel like it needs where the Nephew turns around. And goes, hey, those trees were right there. Where you know, everything is just a little bit compressed. Yeah. But basically,
did earn hunter figure out that they've inadvertently caused this disaster
And now they have to go off. They all have to go off and try and rescue the docks. And and and we lose they lose their trail and a desert sands
storm. And so the rest have to like, fan out and and call out for them but but now we come into the sequence of the story that it is my favorite, and that I think is
extremely
successful. More. Yeah. This. Yeah. This is where the they start looking for water. Right. Because Donald screws don't have enough water. They had counted on meeting the boys much quicker than they than they are.
So after
a hot night,
into a hot day, Scrooge is digging, looking for water. And this is... This is the magic hour hourglass. Sequence. Right? It almost... It it almost mirrors it beautifully. Yeah. Where it right. Discover that the first strike is gold, biggest nuggets I ever saw
You looks sent them for Alarm. Oh, you can't drink, go. Look at that look on Donald face eyes have closed just desperate
on the luck.
Dot god the luck. So he toss it. Right? So It's it's a little bit different
than
magic
glass just because it doesn't have kind of that moral realistic element. That's.
But you still have these Ducktales who are desperate for water and and Scrooge like un uncanny
is basically kicking in here. And
we're gonna get this sequence that where it's repeated
where
every time he digs a
quote mine looking for water, it's gonna end up first, it's copper,
which would render the water un dr if even if it was there, And then well we're on. But then they look... They dig into something
into clay and they see something shining like ice, but it's diamonds.
And again, it it just keeps going.
Donald.
It's just is plastic there. And then the narrative box for the next three or four panels is another dry hole. And another So after diamonds, it's platinum
than nickel than ten.
And and Barks
accelerate
Yeah. The. Right? It it takes
two panels to find the copper
and then the diamonds. And then each Each subsequent one gets one panel and Bark keeps it varied and interesting. Right? This is his genius. He does. Yeah.
And and, you know, but when once we get bored of this we switch gears what well, before we get bored of of this
sort of gag. We switched gears and Donald is like, hey, you are the problem. You you bring this bad luck finding well. So he blind folds him. And Dawn I'll just gonna hit the next spot. That's a nice story took her here. Nice.
And then even while blind folded warren, what what happens?
Well,
Scrooge uncanny ability as a
is even
elevated with his ability to listen now what? He says I can hear something ge
underwater or the underground, it's water. Sure enough. I hear it too. So they both have their heads to the ground and they say start striking
and not admitted to soon, and they're both look at static that you see the kids and the
coming over the... Right. It's it's a perfect
transition. We're not gonna see them discover. That water. Yeah.
We we... The story is gonna wrap up and the one of the nephews,
Dewey is gonna find them
and and it's just in the nick of time, he's able to give him a drink of what what the older dots are excited to realize is orange shoes. Have where'd to get that.
Yeah. Because they've been the civilization.
He says we got it from a store in the town where the kangaroo left took us.
Warren this this this is like pitch perfect. Here. I'm just gonna read I'm just gonna read it as written. And the man and the man at the asset office where we left the oa said, you must be the greatest prospect that ever lived and a be drag Donald domestically says, there's no doubt about that, dewey. Look at what he finds.
Blind folded even. A
confounded oil well.
We see the gi
that liquid turning out to, of course, not be water and a totally should
embarrassed looking sp. And you got the pick pickaxe on one side of the the ge pool and you've got his top hat on the other side. It's really a nicely framed piece of art right there. I think. Yeah. But I love that. I think the think it's it's very poetic. It's it doesn't reach the heights again of the magic hour hourglass the degradation that they're going through and that, but the steaks are a little bit lower too. And tell us how how I wraps up one Well, they they they've got... They they were able to drink the orange juice and they're they're refreshed, but so Al well that ends well, the ducks and their prospect friends, now their friends hike back to safety. I love with Donald here after boys. Well never again ask uncle Scrooge, How he made his money. We won't donald. It's just it's great. Right.
Yeah. I like that closing line. He might wanna go prospecting.
And if he does tell him we won't go, not even for one percent of what he can find.
This a great ending.
Again, and shades of magic glass, but not so much. I just love the... I think my favorite page had to be that that where they discovered all those
for nickel to tip to aluminum and donald saying you're slipping uncle screws. I mean, That's just classic. Yeah. I I think that's un question the best part. And and it's it's the point of the story. Right? It's... I think this is probably one of those stories that he kind of wrote backwards. Right? Like,
maybe he was even thinking about magic hour hourglass and that great sequence. I I mean, he should rightfully be proud of it Like, magic glass is not one of my all time favorites, but I I do think that that ending is as good as anything he's ever done.
And so, you know, now he's got Scrooge as more as something
a little different and wouldn't it be funny if Scrooge were looking for water desperately, but all he could, you know, Donald is encountering found riches in that one. But now Scrooge is mining for richards. Right. Right. So I mean, we we acknowledge that this one is an uneven story.
It it even has a couple of issues,
but I I also just I really enjoy it. Maybe it's a nostalgic favor for me. I even like the the... That weird aspect where they turn out to be nice guys.
The prospect
I just wish he had gotten to kinda develop it better over the course of, yeah, a few more pages made. I totally agree. I like the fact that they're good guys. I like the fact that they're helping the nephews and and helping donald and Scrooge. I'd like the fact that they kinda disappear at the end of the story.
And donald Scrooge take over, which makes sense because you've gotta a wrap it.
But was jarring. I think that's the best thing you could say it just threw me off, and I I didn't care for that as much. But I I if I think back to Barks and but I can only imagine him saying that this is just a vehicle. So a vehicle to get from point eight to point b, and we don't have time for a lot of dillon and stealing. So let's just make sure they're good guys, they're gonna be helpful and get to that ending. So I... Yeah. I don't know. It's about the only thing I can arise here. Yeah. I mean, the point of this one the meat of this one is the comme sequence at the end and it is
kind of establishing Scrooge screws is this over the top rate prospect.
Yeah. So
so let's talk about, you know, the with the community and and how they feel about this one.
Four for a pretty early
screws story. You know, we're still in uncle Scrooge.
Number eleven. This one's not really that highly disregard. It gets a seven point four on Inducks
which, of course is the the site where anyone can create an account and vote on the stories.
That's good for number three hundred for number three hundred and sixty six out of all forty two some thousand
stories.
So, you know, it's it's not the highest for an early uncle Scrooge Barks story but compared to other non Barks It's still still very well.
Kind of considering it against the other
Scrooge
stories or the other Barks adventure stories this one is just kind of like a a typical average Barks story. Okay.
This is at the low end of that kind of those kind of average
bark stories.
You know, this one didn't really have anything
It's it's it's like a snack not a full meal. Right? So he didn't he never
revisited this for, like, an oil painting or Al lit or anything like that.
But Would say it's a big kind of, like,
inspiring
or a a a guides stone for what the care... Who the character
is. Going down the road. And then just, you know, by the nature of what this story is, there's not really been any kind of a sequel that I'm aware of
or any kind of a follow. So any
final thoughts or favorite panels that you'd like to highlight lauren? First of all, I think the book is... The this story is book ended by three opening great pages and closes with three great pages. I know that's I don't wanna say that the the the central part of the story isn't is great but I don't think it's as memorable. I love I love the opening splash panel. It's just another great money been shot in Scrooge.
Confidence and his
you know, opening statement about being the clever prospect that ever lived
or picked under a pebble. I think that's great. I love the globe spin and that that trope that you you see often and where he lands and then it takes us into
the middle part of the story. But then the ending
wandering wondering through the desert
striking all of these minerals and
to me is is the is the the the last three pages are just classic
that's what I'm gonna say. Yeah. I think that your point about how it's kind of book ended by greatness is very fair. Got kind of a weak middle.
But, yeah, great opening is closing. And you you hit some pretty good panels there for me, the the winners are basically,
you know, once we're at the end of the story and donald and Scrooge are on their own desperately digging for water.
All of those reaction faces that they make are are just the best. I especially, like Scrooge
embarrassed grim. As the oil Al is for revealed. I think that one is the a confounded oil well panel is is is fantastic. I also love Barks
detail on just,
you know, going through the wind and the sand.
He does a really nice job with with the forms of of duct of the Ducktales as they as they, you know, are venturing off into the desert. Really Yeah. Sorry yeah. The outback looks really nice. Maybe not quite as nice as an
adventure down under, but it's for nice. But... Yeah. Excellent. Well, thank you for joining me on this B one warren.
These. I really appreciate it. It was fun. It was fun to revisit
the story. I I don't have the memory of it that I have maybe some of the other stories, but there were some some
reminders of of other stories in here, like You said, we talked about the magic hour hourglass and the globe spinning from my favorite like of the North. I I kinda love that. So it was great to revisit this again into
to work it a... Work through it with you. Thank you. Bye. Well, I hope listeners will join us again next
episode should be a very fun one. Get to cover the golden fleece.
Which should be very easy to talk about. And check us out on our socials,
Barks remarks, Facebook,
and Instagram. And, you know, I already mentioned
I already covered that last bit of dialogue, so that's it from us, and we'll see you next time.