We can have
Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer an artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comments of all time. Join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks. Welcome back to Barks remarks. I'm Mark Sever a grown who enjoys dot com. I've got a returning guest host with me.
Awesome in. Do you wanna introduce yourself and
could you also tell us if you you like, so many kids had a greek pathology phase? Sure.
Austin, Kelly. Yeah. I've been on here a couple of times. It's always a pleasure because, of course, there's nothing better in the world than talking about a good Donald doctor or Uncle Scrooge, Comic Barks story. Greek mythology, I was never
big into it, but I remember a kid thinking like, wow. This is... Like, some of it gets really scary. You know? I remember the one story about the guy who has to push the rock up the hill for, like, all eternity. You know what I'm talking about? Oh, yeah. Sis.
Mh. Yeah. Says.
So I was vaguely familiar with all of it, but it wasn't until I gotten into the Carl Barks comics and I really started to, like, properly educate myself on that sort of stuff, you know or, you know? Yeah. Mean, Barks.
Not that's one of the great things that a lot of people like about Barks is that he really touches a lot on myths from a lot of different cultures. Al lot of those greek mists have really perm pop culture. I myself
definitely had my, like, greek mythology phase where I was totally fascinated with it probably around fifth grader. So my my school, you know, we we had a big unit on it.
I'm talking, of course, about Greek mythology because
today's story that we get to discuss is the Ta
Bonkers
very weird Uncle Scrooge adventure
the golden
fleece. Yeah. And
I I don't know, Austin I'm pretty... I'm pretty excited about this when I feel like this one looms large in Carl Barks pant of stories. Yeah. I I agree that it is very weird.
I hadn't read it in a long time, but my I was reading it for this recording,
you know, that first half is very
big on thrilled and its action and I was really into it. But the whole thing came up halfway about the taste testing, and I was like, this is getting super bizarre. You know, which is good because that's, you know, what call Barks does, but it just got very weird, but it is a good kind of weird. And this is also... I think the second Barks story I ever read after the nice. Ground. So it is sort of an nostalgic one as well. Yeah. This is like a nostalgic favorite of mine.
It it was... I read it in Gladstone album series. And I just... I tended to read those over and over because, like, I I I didn't put those in boxes, you know, They're too big for boxes. So they were out on the shelf, and they were presented so nicely.
So so I really read this one quite a bit. And and like I said, I was I was into this story. I was this is one of the times that I actually knew about kind of the the myth and the background of it before
reading the Barks story. Usually, I... It was the other way around. But have you ever seen the the Ray harry house the old stop motion Jason in the Argo? That's pretty famous? I actually haven't. Sounds very interesting. Yes. It's a great one. It's one of the most famous of those like old stop motion monster movies. It has a pretty famous scene with these skeletons
rising from the ground,
and and he... If if you are a stop motion, but which I I am of a fan of stop motion animation
Jason the is like one of the all time great. Harry Has
animated a hydro
with all of its heads interacting.
It's it's really incredible.
Sounds yes.
So so, yeah, I'd I'd
I was familiar with the story. Of course, they take liberties with it in the movie. And and Barks is gonna take a lot of liberty.
With the story of the Golden fleece. Do you think Austin, do you do you have enough of an idea of the contours of the old myth to like? Sum it up or would you rather I do it?
Probably best you do it. I have kind of a basic understanding, but Yeah. Not I I say I've got a a pretty room rudimentary understanding of it myself. But, like, basically, the golden fleece is this mythical.
Hide of a golden Ram, a magical ram, and it's what... It's what Jason and his argo were going off on a on a quest to what was, like, described Al the ends of the earth in their in their famous ship, the argo.
And then there's a lot of extra details about
mid... He he needs a woman named Adi india
Mid who helps him
obtain the fleas through some sub Huey,
It is it's a pretty gruesome
story. As you mentioned, a lot of the old greek myths are are pretty pretty chilly. There's some nightmare item. Yeah. I was looking into the, you know, the original story with the argo and everything.
And I was surprised because it is very peculiar. And, of course, As we said, Barks takes a ton of those liberty sort of to make it kid friendly because after all uncle Scrooge was for, like, a younger audience, but it is still very interesting to see the direction he takes it in and course, the first half, a lot of it is directly based on that original myth and it kinda gets
progressively weirder, which is very cool. Right.
Yeah. The this one
I think this one stands out for its odd. In a lot of ways.
Let's see. Let's I'm gonna cover some of the kind of background
around the original printing of it. So the golden fleece thing was originally published
I had a covered date of December of fifty five, but I think it was actually early fifty six.
So so we're into, like, the second half of the fifties
at this point, Austin.
And it feels
to me like, kind of a transitional story. Do you do you know, like, Barks of the sixties I feel like he got a little bit deaf here in general,
a little bit more screw with some of the stories. So this this kind of almost feels like the start of that to me? Yeah. And in a sense it's like almost like he ran the well drive, like, really nice original
sort of more straightforward
mystery adventures, like the four color Mcdonald's, like Old castle Secret and goes to the G. But like, later on, he sorta of uses the silliness...
I don't wanna say crutch because that has a negative connotation. But, like, just to give the stories an interesting kick, Right? And it's sort of starts with golden fleece and, you know, land beneath the ground, and that kinda spirals into
later on stuff like the the postman man's story, which everyone hates from the gold.
Right. Yeah. He's definitely gonna get into some like pretty kinda concepts.
In in this upcoming run of stories nowadays that he's out of kinda of the first ten issues
of uncle Scrooge, because because we're in
number twelve is our issue number here. And
I... Oh, so I guess general correct here. I had mentioned in a previous
episode that the Secret of Al
was
Barks last thirty two pager it is actually this one. I was let us by the fact that
if you look it up, Wikipedia tells you that this one was thirty one pages
that's because, like, they cut out a panel in the original
because they wanted to squeeze in the dell pledge to parents or the Dell promise to parents, I guess, which is like their old, you know, don't come after us Comic book Authority
attempt to remain family friendly. Sure. Because they, of course, they didn't have like that. Common book authority seal of approval on the cover that everyone else had at the time. Right.
And and this one's got twelve reprint, which is a pretty good number of them.
Did you happen to come across some of the
information Austin about Barks being asked to Gladstone this one down a little bit. Yeah. I found a little interesting
fact about some panels
halfway through the story when
Donald and screws get captured by the la. Him having to red draw some of the panels because they originally suggested what the editors called in Insanity. Right. Sound like, really interesting. And, of course, like, I'm sure you know about changing the name of the herpes to the large. Yes. Exactly. Why are we calling them? The Barks
Austin
instead of
instead of as in the Greek miss. The the herpes piece are the the bird like women creatures that that men... So they jimenez a man named Fin
in the original
myth.
They're like his punishment. But why are we calling them lowercase keys instead?
As far as I could tell, I think what Barks said was Harp had, like, a really bad
connotation. And what Barks called a street walker, which I'm pretty sure of prostitute. Right? So... Yes. You know. Yeah, Barks actual quote is pretty good because it sounds very like Barks. He said, I almost had to eat those thirty two pages of drawings. It seems that Harp is an disputed nic nickname for a street walker, I managed to reset... To save the story by ren.
Them lowercase keys instead. And and you know, the name is is is pretty important and and it's important that he was able to come up with something
for the little gimmick that he's gonna use later on.
Yeah. So, like, we could we could spend a lot of time kinda of recount the old miss and and what he based it on. But but it's pretty famous, and I think I think most people will have at least like a passing
familiarity with it. So
why don't I mention a few of the international titles
and and then we can launch into the story. It's itself. Sounds good. Yeah. So I guess the thing with a story like this. Is that
it's it's based on this myth that is super super famous. So in general, people translating it for publication
in other countries,
they all came up with the same title. It's it's all called, you know, and the golden fleece. Or in search of the golden and fleece, which means, of course that they'd kinda miss out on the neat little pun in English that you get from the story the Golden flee
because, of course, to to fleece someone is to, like, trick them or to
to rip someone off. So it's a really... It's a great Barks title. But it's pretty dine when you translate it. So I pulled out
Brazilian Portuguese.
It is Uv
Del,
which is gluten fleece.
And then Finland,
I've I've been avoiding Finland for a while, so I thought I'd cycled back around to It is
Cool.
Which...
So this was interesting. When I plugged it in, Austin to Google translate, it gave me the golden holly.
But I'm I'm gonna guess. That's just Google translate having a hard time with finish.
Yeah. Sounds like that. I'm sure it's the golden fleece. And then I will finish with France
where it is love Al the
door and that is in search of the gold fleece.
Alright. So let's see. Any anything else you wanna cover you wanted dimension before we launch into the story Austin?
Probably not. I kinda like that all the the titles are just kind of the same general thing. But I do feel like I should probably just point out that today, I'm using my copy of screws number twelve, which is nice. To go Is Corey. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. And I'm that's in the error when
Barks had all of these neat
adventure stories, these iconic adventure stories with these, like, really
anonymous gag titles or tag covers.
Yeah. It's very weird because he could have done a lot of more interesting stuff with the covers than just know. Scrooge having a time glass filled with gold coins, but, you know... Right. And I I... I've I've never, like, really read any reason why I think this was Al last dictate tape. But my my assumption is that they liked the idea of having these covers that could kinda match for any story that they could reviews as they want it Sure. Yeah. Alright. So let's see. We're we're still pretty early into the Scrooge series.
And And I guess it's it's interesting to me Austin that he...
In the first, like, run of uncle Scrooge stories, you know, he seems to have really been thinking about how he can use his new character, you know, Str likes to go on treasure hunts.
Sp is worried about his money.
We had some of the kind of reflective stories that kind of built up Scrooge
methodology. And and by this point, you know, we're back in Treasure hunt mode,
But it's interesting that this story is not, like...
We're into the miss and there's usually an explanation for these mythical things. But but we're really gonna land into these
mythological
creatures that are literally straight out of the mess. So I do find that interesting. And as we open, it is a classic
shot of Scrooge in his bin. We got a a half page splash panel and and he is pondering.
I imagine here, Bark is like, okay, what's what's something that rich, man might worry about. Maybe he's gonna worry about his his clothes.
Because that's what Scrooge is thinking about. He's thinking how it's odd that he's never really
had the kind of clothes that suit, a man at his station. We got a reference it's neat here to having bought his old broad cloth At a rum sale and Scotland in nineteen o two. That of course is gonna be one of those details that Don Rosa is gonna pluck out for his life and times of Scrooge series. And he kind resolves that he would like to get a special coat made to loaf around and, like, other rich man.
And he decides that he can have it fancier than average because he'll have it made of pure gold and he holds up a bar from a stack.
And I like that he mentions, it'll be cheap because he's already got the goal. Of course. Alright. What do you think austin and this feels a little bit un Scrooge
to kind of be worried about, you know, his appearance?
But...
But but I like the angle here. Yeah. I I do agree that it seems like the clothing
concern was sort of just
me and out of nowhere for this particular story. Like, I find it funny at the beginning, like, the opening line is like, nothing is topped quest for the golden coat, you know, which is like Right. Well, if it was his big question and when we heard about it and you know, earlier on.
I find it funny. He just picks up like, the bar of gold and says, yeah. I can make this into a coke. Right. If any idea how that's gonna work out. I I like to how Barks kind of
spotlight
for the reader, how strange this is gonna be. He says right off the right off the bat in the little narrator box what a strange adventure Change adventures. Know. So
next, we find Scrooge over at Ducktales,
trying to get his solid
gold coat
and I'll it wouldn't work out because it's Ducktales tells him the code gonna be cri like tin foil, which, of course Scrooge doesn't thought about. You know, we Severino these stories that Scrooge is sort of urine from money kind of overcomes him when it comes to, like, logical rational thinking, which I always find interesting. Of course Ducktales taylor name drops the golden fleece, which gets him interested. And we see kind of a shady character sitting in the background in, like, the silhouette, which is very interesting colored in purple. Scrooge just walking away Sad when he sees a big shadow following him. We get a nice chase sequence with a couple interesting poses And here's where our Scrooge rounds the corner Al he's running away, and he finds Donald just hang on on the corner. Which is nice because this little small town dynamic this mindset that Barks has that just walking around, you can run into someone you know. I find interesting, of course. Just kinda tips is little
hand and, of course, Barks in grow in a big city where something like that would never happen. Right. Yeah. It's interesting how he
introduces this quote sinister,
you know, foreign...
Yeah I think he he thinks oh, that evil looking foreigner
who is in the taylor shop I I don't think I even noticed him the first time and I had to go back and and look at it. It it's a pretty stereotype
version of, like the generic middle east.
And I think it's kinda playing on the dynamic of the very paranoid
you know, mid nineteen fifties
definitely. So basically,
you know, Scrooge is concerned that he's being per sued for this bar of gold. And and I really like this chase sequence here Austin
where Donald leaves him
down into this a call
through an abandoned factory
through a bunch of colbert pipes under fence and and then hiding into a barrel and the stick is that it's where he hides when Daisy comes after him. To mow her lawn,
And first off, it's way more trouble probably than just mowing the damn hang on. But but as a kid, I like this little, you know, path this little
escape app that you had. And we get this very, like, on settling
image at the end of the sequence where this foreigner
is literally
sniffing
around to try to find Scrooge.
It's very weird. Yeah. It's very so weird that it's very... Scrooge screws do that as well. Doesn't he have a nose for money as well? That's true. Yeah. This is
it is like Scrooge.
Everyone smell he stiff out gold, and that's what this weird foreigner is gonna do as well. But, you know, he looks so sinister.
Quote he.
He looks so sinister sir. And and his nose is so pronounced that it just looks It looks on unsettling. Mh. Yeah. Which I find very interesting. These sort of stereo there's a lot of stuff in the store that wouldn't fly as we'll see later on well. Oh, yes. They a huge number of stereo yeah in this one.
Anyway, on the next page,
the man, the mysterious figures found Scrooge under the barrel and tells me is a keen sense of smell, strong aroma of money. Which is very interesting because, of course, Donald his the bar now Scrooge just nothing on him. So, you know, like Jake's sort of up Scrooge just wondering when going on. And out of nowhere, this man pulls out a little bit of the famed Golden fleece, which of course, gets Scrooge right away, you know? He sort of falls for it... Like I was saying earlier, it's interesting that he just falls for it right away. You know, he doesn't really think too deeply, what's going on here.
You know, it's kind of urine for money takes away any sort of logical way of thinking, which I was found interesting. Right.
Yeah.
It it's... Scrooge is very credible
in a lot of this story. I guess he's prime to be fleece. As it were. And and, yeah, the the weird
foreigner starts name dropping all these things from the myth. Right? He says that he doesn't
specifically say immediately that it's from the golden fleece. But...
But he says that it came from fable.
And it... It's from the land of the sleepless
dragon and and then it kinda dawn on Scrooge, all of a sudden, and he says that could be real wool from the golden fleece.
And basically, this this mysterious guy is saying, how fortunate is that we've met and he's preparing to basically make a bargain with him for
more of the golden fleece. You know, they kinda coordinate the details of this deal whilst... Well donald is ea dropping.
And at the end of this page, Austin, we get the first
of this weirdo
tell,
right where he slips up. He says it would mean a voyage to Us, mister Mc talk but and then he,
he he come aboard the argo, and we'll talk it over with my sis. I mean brothers.
So, you know, Barks is gonna almost go overboard with this where the man keeps, like,
when we meet those siblings,
they're gonna repeatedly
almost refer to each others Al sisters
and
when they're gonna be giggling all over the place. So box is gonna practically
he's gonna practically like sign post it that
these are these weirdo are actually women.
And and then the Nephews, Huey, dewey and Louie hop upon Donald he's fine on them. And he he basically is gonna fill that in. Yeah. Donald comes around and nephews he's and he says, I've been watching Uncle Scrooge and a stranger.
A guy is trying to sell him the golden fleece, which, of course, gets the wood chuck like
super confused. You know, I go down to look at the the ship.
And of course, they show up and it's like exactly as it appeared in the book of old miss. Our book of the old miss is enough use call it, which is interesting, like, I always like the treasure on dynamic works very well because the wood shocks with this book of, like, seemingly infinite knowledge are always able to clue in as we're gonna see the reader on kind of what's going on. But, of course, like, Barks can't expect every reader to know the the Golden Flea Smith and everything behind it. Right. He has to do like this very bridged kinda cliff notes,
education even if most people are gonna know. It's a lot... It's gonna be a lot of kids first exposure. Right. Exactly. And and Barks does it very well Let you. Seemingly
just inserts it in for a page or two. Just the wood checks reading out of their old guide book and everything. So anyway, Donald and the nephews go over to the boat, and they wanna listen in ea job again. And Scrooge is on the boat, and of course, the man who's been following him says mister Meet my sis, I mean my brothers so he slips up again. And even I remember the first time I read this. Of course, I knew what was going on, but I still wasn't able to tell what was act gonna happen. I wonder people who were reading this for the first time could be able to predict, like these people that everyone is figuring our men are just gonna loft spoiler. Cool off all their clothing and just be revealed to be these creepy bird women creatures. You know? Right. Especially if you're reading it in, you know, for the first time with a cover that doesn't really
give it away, you know, that album that I read, Don Roses, does show the Barks keys on the on Don Rosa cover. But, like, it doesn't connect them to these guys. So, like, I I knew just like you. I knew something's what? Something was up. I didn't know exactly what was... You wanna read the the full panel where he says their names as,
whatever.
Sure. So, yeah. He introduces his sis brothers
as
Sang,
equal Zen,
Es said and
Y, and he mentions his own name is Al
and then another one of them mentions they are they dot I mean sons of the queen of sequel. So that's how they kind of introduce themselves and they're doing the classic. They g with the beard and and sort of you know, doing the little hand thing, rubbing the hands together. Right.
So there's there's a lot to take in here off and so, I guess first off. The dynamic is we've got shift eva looking foreigner. That... That's pretty unfortunate. It, but but it's definitely kind of a re of the time. I guess it is worth noting that they are in disguise for for what it's worth. Number two,
the the made up name, it definitely
sounds like it could be a country and it could be these, like, foreigner hundred names. You know? So this construction that Barks has come up with it it it's definitely
stereotypical, but it's also very effect And number three, this sequence is really
really creepy. Like, if I step back and remember the first time that I read this, which would have been probably Al age like nine or. I remember, like being very creeped out because they they looked they look gi
like they're planning something
horrible, you know? And right. And these like
interject, Sparks is really going overboard signal that they've got something nasty planned. Oh... I think this is a good one to kinda step out of my own head and try to remember what I was like to read it the first time. Because this is this a creepy sequence. And and basically, the dynamic of the next page is that they, you know, Scrooge in them continue to... They talk business as he says. And we see a little bit of cons
between the sons of Sea
planning to sail back to call this. So, you know, we know that they're on the up and up about at least because they're they're referencing it amongst themselves and whisper voices.
But just as they're getting ready to... We figure probably kid kidnapped Scrooge
the nephews who have been ea dropping on this business
spot this really
creepy looking
shadow. And and the Nephew just describes it as a big bird came out on deck and sauce and dart back a bird with a funny head. I don't know about you Austin, but I I really think that out of context, that shadow is freak that out of is super freaky. And you mentioned people who had read the comic originally with, like, just the gag cover having zero clue about what was really going on. I had zero clue was going on here. So, you know, for someone who might have had the rosa to cover with the, you know, the and everything you might have been able to clear yourself in, but, like, there's is not a lot of resemblance between these creepy brothers that are you know, calling screws right now in this bird shadow. So for the gag covered is very effective, you think back for Barks to, like, sort of heat readers still very much
not in the nose. That makes sense? Right You know? Yeah. I think that's a great point. So anyway, on the next page, the nephews cl donald on what's going on. Of course he says, all birds have funny heads. I I like that Al lot. That is funny. You know, Scrooge is sort of supposing some things wrong because he's not as eager to get back into it. Now the jig is really up with these guys because they're whispering behind his back and saying, love to have our rich play thing come back later. When his buying relatives aren't along to raise Cane. They figured they'll send them away. They say their fee to take him the Golden fleece is five bars of gold Scrooge. You know what I'll think about it. We go to a little bit later. Where he's walking along with the net his nephews.
And they're like, you're not really gonna sail with him or you But screws is saying, well, you know, I'll have... If I'll have to, I'm gonna go get that fabulous fleece. So it's interesting because the nephews in donald are usually up for the adventure. But here they're sort of suspecting more.
Like Donald usually not one to understand, like, the true danger of a situation. Whereas his Scrooge is. So kind of interesting to see, like, the opposite in the dynamic and, like, sort considering what's really right and what's wrong. What should they do and not. Yeah. Definitely. I think that's a good point. It... It's interesting too that, like, Scrooge is talking about how he's kinda eager for this adventure to be like, Jason
after the Golden fleece.
And and he's not usually motivated by the desire to for adventure. You know, in in these stories in Barks stories, at least duck,
the series kind of like changes that so that he just he loves the quest, but in general, I don't think that's really what he's usually about. Right. And and I'm perceiving that he's been just a little bit witch by his, like, actual
view of that golden wall. Right. Because because in the next couple of pages, they're gonna kinda
him on by showing him that. Right Awesome know to that, like, what you were saying about, I'm not being very eager for adventure. It is true that in most of the stories, the adventure isn't, like, something they choose to go on. Right? It's usually a result of some
mishap or screw up and they have to go on it to retrieve, you know, this item or this amount of money. But here they're sort of willingly throwing themselves into it and it is interesting
to see why like so eager. Yeah. Least Scrooge just. The Nephews, they're really... They're they're only interested kinda holding him back. That... That's actually what kind of annoyed me about the second duck series is that they they kinda of re con them and being like, always down for an adventure
but but like, it was really about the treasure hunt. For Scrooge. That's just my kind of side now. So, you know, basically,
the the the kids they go back to kind of
try and figure out more. You mentioned that they're the wood checks. Right? They're gonna they're gonna consult their guide book. And they're kinda remembering what they know
about the ancient
story. Think have a real eclipse notes version that says Jason was sent to fetch
the Golden fleece from the palace of Ares and.
And then they
very quickly mentioned after scatter some bird like creatures and knocking out a sleepless drag. Right. So that's gonna kinda set up the rest of the story, just that one little panel.
And then he took the fleece back to Greece and married a which named Na india.
And boy, that part of the story, the the later parts of it getting up being really sad and gruesome.
And so they they try to find out more in the guide book, and Donald Ducktales screws to his office.
And when Scrooge
unlocks his office,
he is shocked to see a Sequel Al.
Already relax at his desk.
And
and Sequel Al is being this really big weirdo though talking about how you know, this is easy for someone. I I came in through the window, a feet, which is easy for someone from August.
And basically you sense Austin
that
Al is there because he wants to real in Scrooge
he wants to hold up that fleece and kind of enchanted him by how how weird he is and
and just dang that fleece under his nose.
And and it works He gets screwed a little bit in enchanted and he gets him to follow him out of the office.
And, you know, Donald
prepares to tail after him and
You wanna tell us about what happens next or if you have any comments?
Sure. Yeah.
I just find an interesting that Donald cares this much about Scrooge. Usually. He so
Scrooge is so hard on Donald. You wouldn't think he's not gonna be
that quick to get all the help he needs from his, you know, Nephew, but apparently, he does. But anyway,
nice bit of fore foreshadowing and Donald gets hit by some
flying object that knocks him over the head and only
one black feather floating down.
You know, so we've had the strange bird light creature reference in this,
and it's all very nicely for foreshadowing wants to come. And here's that little
sort of cliff note version of the whole golden fleece thing that I was mentioning earlier, the exposition that he needs sort of that the story.
You know, Made got sore at, Jason and get back to C taking the golden police with or they say. So they sorta of run through it. She hung it in the hall of that echoes, then the bird light creatures came to live in Cold kiss and the sleepless drag and resumed his vigil.
So
you know, they kind of run through it real fast just to give you that basic understanding.
And while they're doing all of that,
sequel Al is already on the boat with sc and they're already
getting ready to sail with Donald close on their trail.
Right. Can can you tell from the text
Lost where they must have had Barks, we let it.
Bird light creatures sounds pretty awkward or funny birds or whatever. I think I think they must have been reading about herpes fees originally.
Yeah. You know, most. Because I know a lot of it had to be edited for the publications. Right.
And the nephews do get that realization or or the one who saw the the shadow says, he katz.
That's what I saw board the argo,
but but the others, you know, are skeptical still.
Sure.
And and again, all of this is deeply on unsettling.
This whole time. Right? We've got
I I think this is really exciting too, and it would be cool to have this put to screen where you see the Nephews kind of frantically learning as much as they can.
While Donald is desperately
running to the boat. You wanna keep telling us about Donald boarding the boat?
Yeah. So, of course, the they find him out, the brothers seat roles find him out. They sort of pull them on board by
came to the neck which looks super painful. They call them mister Guac face. So now the
the humiliation is really through the roof.
Anyway, Don gets pulled into the room with sc, and he's just going over his five bars of gold fee
But Donald is saying, you know, there's something fishy about this ship, and he's trying to pull him off. But as Scrooge know just of course, doesn't listen to Donald because why would you? He's pulling out as five Barks of gold,
and the brothers take the gold and throw it right mind Austin reading readings Scrooge,
word balloon there and their response because it's really well set up. Oh, sure.
Which the one in the I paid for Scrooge says I've paid. Yeah. Scrooge says, I paid for my voyage with five bars of gold.
I'm sure these men respect their obligation.
So the brothers grabs the gold they say, oh, sure. Sure. We respect it. Like this and they throw all the gold right out the window, you know, which of course, Scrooge screws like absolutely
fine.
Through your gold overboard, why? Brother say because we have no use for gold and,
and this is This is really trippy. We have no use for these garments either and we get a super creepy panel. Rather start taking off all their clothing one of them even throws away a mass. This is why really weird a mask of their face with the big nose and the beard and the mustache. And they all start un addressing and they reveal themselves as those creepy bird light creatures, the Barks keys, and this is a really weird panel.
They are,
like they look kind of the same in the face, but they have this short black hair and, like, a pony tail,
earrings,
red and yellow earrings and like, big bird feet and wings.
And, of course, you have the classic, like hat jumping off the head for Donald and Scrooge in the corner who are absolutely
terrifying. Right.
This has gotta be one of Barks best like reveal ever. Right? It it really bears repeating how on unsettling this is and and it's kicked off with that great moment where they just Al
throw screws bars of gold. Out the window. We... We as the reader knows something has gone horribly wrong when we see that, It's such a great shocking moment to us and Scrooge.
Then when they, like, dis drove that way, and then we see them, they're really meant to look like a cara of an unattractive woman too. You know, I think I think Barks is generally... It's not a kind
representation of kind of femininity throughout the rest of the story. Here. Right. Because... Because these...
I would say that they're really meant to depict kind of a like
unpleasant
s
woman who's focused on cooking and gossip and competition. And I mean, you know, their their herpes
but but the point is that they're just really their women first. That's why they've been like, giggling
we're where we are supposed to see them. Has women. Right. And it's funny you mentioned s ish woman because when I was looking into the Harp large sort of debacle, the actual definition for a Harp under Mer Webster is s woman. Right. Interesting. Right. Yeah, I wonder if it was, like, crossed wires because I've never heard of it as a reference
for a a street walker process do, but I've heard it as like an un really unpleasant woman. I'm pretty sure even in other Barks stories that someone, like uses the word hard for for a woman. And that'd be very So
that that page continues with the kids still, you know, the reader knows what's going on. But here's where the kids figured it out. They read that travelers near the region of ancient call
believe that the strange birds
sometimes called Barks keys
still live there. So I think that's our first time that we've actually seen the word Barks in this. Right? Mh.
And they go on to read that wild giggling has been heard on moon list nights in the valley of the mists and natives have found huge bird traps and their sheep folds
And then another Nephew has kind of su out the little backwards
writing
basically, the the the reversing
trick. This is a fun trope. Right? I can't remember if I had seen it coming or I knew there was something weird about those names. But he says I wrote those guy's names backward on this piece of paper and it spells Barks.
So So sea crawl, we've just learned the word Barks. So maybe we... Maybe we haven't...
We haven't figured it out. I think if Barks have gotten to use heartbeat like he wanted too, which would also look kind of like suit foreign. We might have recognized it more easily.
And they go through, and they say Ep Sang is the la agnes and Zen is La Nes and Al is Ella eli and so on. The nerve of them. Right. Yeah. I... You mentioned the sort of if you could tell whether or not that reverse same thing was coming. I certainly couldn't. I mean, I know it was one of my first Barks stories, but like the reveal of the
and the name, like, everything really floor me when I first read this one. It's a really good. It's a really well
instructed reveal. Whether you see it coming or not, I think it's got a a great impact in this story. Yeah. He he foster such a unsettling
atmosphere. All, like, in this first half. It's weird
Austin.
The
second half when you actually get there is like less on unsettling, than all the build. Right. I actually was gonna bring this up. It's in my notes but it's like I was so
disappointed upon reread because in my mind, what lasted in my memory was that first half with this great reveal and this, splash panel on fourteen of the the Barks, like flying away with the boat, which is really weird. But then we sort of file into the second half, and it's like wait a minute. This is almost like a different story, you know? Yeah. It's this weird. We're gonna enter into this weird domestic
dispute thing. Yeah. Like almost like it would have worked with daisy and, like, her friends back at home, you know? Like, Huey, know at Al. Yeah. Parts of this definitely feel like a daisy story.
Tell us about that splash panel though because it is great. Yeah. And this is a this is a very cool panel. They... The Nephews run off, of course, they realize everything.
They go down to the dock, but they see the keys in the distance. This is really cool. Above like this the moon or the sun and they're flying away with the boat attached to like, their wings. And it's all in silhouette. So it's very creepy.
Of course, one of the nephews finds a note on the side from Donald where prisoners of Barks save us, you know, and they're thinking about how to save them and one of the nephews just would cost thousands as Al as to travel a lot far. Another one says, and we're broke. The only way we can get there is to swim.
So, of course, one of them just dies in starts swimming. Hey, you wild Hiro. I didn't mean that we could swim, guys and the water says I wasn't swimming the ocean
I was diving in to see what was shining on the bottom, and it's just what I thought it was. Gold, five bars of it just waiting to be fished out of the drink. So of course this is cleverly structured by Barks so as bars Al we're thrown out, couple pages later and hour coming yeah. That's an extremely
tightly
constructed and and funny engaging seats. Yeah. I I really like it. So I I noted
Austin that when the nephews see what's happened with the Barks departing, one of them says brother, this is one time we really missed the boat. And and, you know, that's an old... That's an idiom.
That's an expression in English, and it it occurs to me, like, literally right now that I wonder if Barks decided do that because there's gonna be another idiom that's gonna be very important at the end of this story. The pulling the wall over. Over the eyes.
Yeah. Al might be interesting. You might be right on the. Okay. You know but Austin, it's weird.
That like what I think we're fifteen
pages are so into this story. We've had most of the first half and it's been entirely
confined to Inducks and this set up. He really... Lets the beginning of the story breathe. Yeah. Sorta takes his time with it. Yeah. So
we see the Nephews making their preparations to travel to c us c
and they transfer to a helicopter.
In Asia minor. So we're in, like the Turkey,
you know, the Europe and Turkey
kind of border.
And and they reference having some special weapons for battling the Le along with their junior wood checks.
And Barks kind of takes care of getting any other support. He hand waves it by saying no police will ever believe our story. And and now they head to the valley of the miss. Where the pilot says that, you know, they will be the first person in sent to enter that creepy place.
Not not our first time being in a Al of miss and A Barks
in a Barks story.
Oh, yeah.
Right. Interesting. Yeah. Barks really enjoys
like, fog as an element of mystery.
And and it works great. And we've seen it in plain awful.
Golden helmet itself, I had a great fog seen
So so here, we are in an entire value of it, and they have the pilot dropped them off near
prepared to give get dropped off near some old ruins that they see. And if give us any comments or or tell us about about Barks headquarters
Yeah. We'll jump right into the next page because this is really where it gets sort of a peculiar
but.
Very cool art wise because I really like the fog sort of background effect. We getting a couple of select panels here. U.
Anyway, we cut to Donald and Scrooge as prisoners of the Barks. They're up and like. Some very cool
tree stump like nest, that's like, way up in the sky, of course, the are flying around and, like, the classic
shaking hands and laughing and They're all happy because they're successful trip to your country to find a rich taste. They found the first sucker that fell our for our golden fleece story.
Taste or, like, what are they talking about? You know? Right.
So they're all laughing and they're very excited and Donald says I noticed that they called you taste. I hope they didn't mean that to refer to refer to your flavor. Scrooge says I noticed that they called me a sucker. I know what they mean by that. I'm glad you. I'm glad you highlighted. That's a good line. Yeah. Scrub course Scrooge is angry because there's no golden fleece. Or at least he thinks until the Barks tells him oh, yes, there is
italian right over there in the ruins of that Al, but you couldn't get to it. Even if we let you go and, of course, it's a revealed that there's a big dragon and he hiss and scares the crap out of Scrooge donald up in the Nest. They're left furious. Right.
Hey. So Austin. You... I it's just occurred to me. You're reading uncle scratch number twelve. So you've got the
kind of on panels. Don't show. Because this is the sequence where the Barks keys
he had to like, modify the lara keys
because they looked a little bit too luna. Right? Holy cow. I've never seen that before. Yeah. So the the... The glad stone for the album, I think that was the first time that they had the restored art. But it's worth seeing. It's they they do look really...
They do look insane. I don't think it's like I don't think there was any reason to censor. But... But they look.
They look.
They look. They're just... They're just like laughing at what a supper for just been. But it's really great our work.
And I I left
I love how they
they're really just delighted what a sucker they've made of him.
And so on the next page, you know, we've got Donald.
We've got Scrooge really doing and having been sucker and angry Al his predicament.
And he threatens them he says I wanna go home, Let me out of here before I forget that your ladies
and we
we get a very weird scene where one of the Barks keys puts him over her knee and span him. Like he's a naughty little boy. So, like,
we're we're kind of reference. We're kinda figuring out that, you know, they're here at their pleasure. They really are prisoners.
But they're they're always being depicted as
unpleasant ladies. You know, there's never
any more any other hint of menace other than that.
And very interesting. It's playing off like all the stereotypes like women who, like Barks, their kids and courses we're gonna see like women who are awful cooks and and women, like, all these things that are just so crazy, like it's just so shocking to read in, like, sort of modern and society, you know, and, like, all the standards have changed and stuff. Right. It's it's It's kind of a vodka of the old like cat skills canadian, you know, take my wife, please.
So, you know, the the lowercase keys tell them to sit tight until we have something ready for you to taste. And when screw asks about that, that, you know, they say, that's a secret and we get more of that
madden
tackling giggling that they're constantly doing. Right. And at this point, like this is spence and the thrill of that first half is still very
much so still there because the tasting
could be anything. Like Barks is already sort of tripped up the standards and the expectations by having this whole gang of villains being turning from men to women. So, like, you're not really sure what do expect anymore. Yeah. We're totally off balance.
Yeah. It gets very
disappointing with this whole taste reveal is just exactly what it sounds like really. I I I agree. It's it's a little... I love this story, but it it is a little bit of a lab. Yeah. Because it could be so many other things. Right? Anyway,
donald and screws are up there in the Nest in there. Thinking back to the old myth about how the Barks kept prisoners for years and every time they would sit down to eat, they would put awful tasting things on the prisoners plate. Par at putting is what screws calls one of the things being which throws him into it ti because he apparently hates par sn
which is a bizarre thing day, I suppose. Do you have any idea, Mark if that's like, part of an original myth? Like, did they actually
I I didn't look this up specifically, but I'm I'm like ninety nine percent confident that there's no mention of par sn
and in, you know, he he he's not totally off base here. Right? Because the, like, The specific part of the myth is that they had king... Oh, man. What was the King's name? I can't routine whatever. They they depicted this in the in the Ray Harry House movie too, where this king would have... In fact, they would have banquet
of wonderful
looking food. Set out for him. But every time he tried to eat it, the Barks keys would come and like
remove it and destroy it and he would have to, like, subs
off the little crumbs and remnants.
Of the food. So so they don't actually feed him grow stuff. They prevent him from eating
delightful stuff. His is how the actual myth goes. So boxes has massage it a little bit for his own and. I do like the...
This goofy
Scrooge
tray. Right? Where he hates par sn. Yeah. I don't like the rest of the the, like, cooking competition aspect of it. But but I do think it's funny that's Scrooge has this one specific
root vegetable
hayes.
Right. Just like this obscure food just shows up for no reason is like this big problem. Anyway, screws and donald while they're fret over that, the nephews have just landed and their helicopter just sort of shoots out of the scene off to the side. And
the Nephews are kind of just investigating the ruins, and we get a cool panel with the couple Barks and vans cheeses and if he's put it flying around. And they hear a couple noises over from
the echo echoes and the here. You know, that dragon and that Scrooge on we're hearing earlier, which, of course terri the nephews as well. Yeah. I like that. I like the image, a lot of their like, duck feathers, their hair standing on end.
And their fear of the dragon and then how one of them says golly. We never figured on him being still around caucus.
Again, you know, Barks is is still amp off the kind of like, un unsettling
creepy nature. It's... It's nice that this is gonna be a kind of a halloween approximate
episode because I think this is pretty appropriate for
Nice. Yeah know. That'll be fitting. So
the nephews eventually, you know, they they hide because they don't wanna be seen and all that noise.
And they get to see one of the lara keys and they kind of marvel
Al it. One of them calls Al overgrown canary. But but unfortunately, they lose side of before they can follow it back Scrooge and Donald. And I guess, here's where we get the kind of disappointing revolution Austin. Barks
transitions us to a... They're a kitchen in a clear part of the Valley where the
are cooking,
food,
and discuss
discussing how they could find a rich old duck to be their food taste.
Talking about how he must be used to only the fan
Vi
and and we we learned pretty quickly that they've had this lifelong argument over who is the best cook? And we get...
We get a little comedic reference to their recipes
being
disgusting the first of several where one of them says quit bumping my sterling arm, you've caused my towed to mar to stick to the skill.
I do like the goofy recipes,
Austin, even if I don't like the overall premise of it.
Sure. Of course. There there are a couple things to like about it, but this is where it starts to take that really weird turn into these horrifying creatures who capture people alive and take them back to their ancient ruins are now, like cooking
and, like, chatting it up, you know, which gets a
Just kinda peculiar. So anyway on the next page, we find them talking and apparently,
whoever
has the best meal, whoever Scrooge to sides is the best cook of the five there are gets to become the queen of the Barks
which, of course excites them all. Actually, one of them starts to get thinking and says, I'm gonna win that owner even if I have to cheat a little bit to do it. So they run off, she runs off sister agnes is this one and goes over to sc and gives him a bit of a business deal she puts it. She says it's agreed then that if you select my recipe is the best, I will allow you to escape from.
Screwed agrees to it, and she says besides, if you will eat all of my discs just to floor my sisters, I will grant you another favor. I'll tell you how you can bypass the sleepless dragon and make off with the golden fleece, which, of course, gets Scrooge donald very excited and sister agnes flies off. And even at this point in the story, like, I could tell what the dish was gonna be made of and
where it's gonna go from here.
Right. I mean, it's only been a couple of pages
since he name dropped.
Heating par snip. I almost... I wonder if it might have been better if he had introduced the par snip somehow in the first part of the story. First part of the story, but that might have been tricky to kinda shoot horn in.
So
pretty quickly here and we come to the food tasting ceremony portion of the story. Okay. So I... I've already made clear that I don't really like this overall premise that much. But I will admit. I do like how it actually plays out. Right? Like like it's it's very funny how we get this sequence
of the Barks keys
introducing
their their horrible dishes
Donald and Scrooge have some really
great gruesome and expressions that the terrible smells
ema from the Barks kitchen. And and so Barks fa sets per edition in front of him and lovingly
introduced is it as current Root rhubarb pull told with hurdle the milk queen sauce.
And Scrooge is face and his thought balloon
saying shutter. That... That's an awesome panel. It might be a pick of mine.
I wonder Austin if this... Like, if you have you ever gone back and, you know, seeing how the Internet will highlight?
Some of the terrible old recipes from this sarah? Mh. I wonder if that's list is, like, just making fun of some of the random
experimentation the house wise were encouraged to deal around this time.
It
that actually sounds like the best fit for it. Because otherwise, it just seems weird that there more of these offers.
Because there was a lot of weird post war
cooking
experimentation going on. Mh.
And and while Scrooge is choking this down, you know, one of them. I like that he's brisk about this. He doesn't have each one served them. He just has two of the other le
talking about their dishes, One of which is su
sour brat with vin gravy.
Then best he, no, he'll love my Barks biscuits more. And Ina nes does get to serve her famous toss tumble we'd salad with cod liver oil dressing.
And we do finally get to agnes.
Who
remembers their little deal and Scrooge acknowledges.
He is to eat all of this Dish and asked what is it? And predictably, she announces that it's par snip putting and he falls right over.
It's super predictable, but it's it's very funny. I do like it. So what which of those dishes sounds the the least horrible to you Austin?
No. It might be that tumble wheat.
No It might be the Barks biscuits. They don't sound that terrible. Yeah. I think I think it's probably gotta be one of those. I mean, I guess the person that putting on its own doesn't sound so bad.
So Just... I don't wanna be eating any of those anytime soon.
Yeah. Alright. So
a bargain is a bargain as as Barks notes in his narrator box. That's a great error box And
Scrooge does his best. He's very game. He
pant
loving it as he eats it.
And Donald gets this great on line. If this acting or for the Academy awards, you'd win every Oscar in the place
it's awesome.
And so, you know, we don't... We transition quickly. Bark doesn't bother with any ceremony here. He doesn't really care about the lara keys at this point. The the
queen Queen agnes
tells them that it's their chance to sneak away while the other girls are soaking, and she tells them that the directions,
she tells them where the tunnel
that'll take them beneath the dragon station to the open end of the hall of Echoes.
And
she tells him that the
It's at the inner end where the quote Boomerang stone reverses the echo. So they they run off, and this leaves agnes.
Kind of pondering
her now predicament
as she reflects on the fact that, you know, her sisters are gonna be really mad
when they learned that she's let the prisoner
estate. So so she decides to do... I guess, this is the fleece. I guess this is kind of one of the
double cross aspects of it. I mean, the whole thing, the tricking them here is part of it, but there's a lot of crossing and double processing. She adds one more secret to sc about the hall of that echoes. And she thinks that this trick is gonna make cry. I I hero a heroin to her sisters.
So she says because it's a dark and whining tunnel, it's you need to find your weight to the fleece by shouting
and listening for the return of the echo
and that the special word is sea crawl. And and, of course, Donald and Scrooge didn't figure out
what the nephews did. Right? So I don't know. I found the whole thing very try with agnes coming up with his plan. And going through with all this far and then Barks just having her like,
maybe I shouldn't and then bringing it in and having her sort of take it back and then having her turn on him. You know? So it all seems like Barks can try on I I agree with you. I I had pretty much the exact same impression this this part of the story. Can we can we maybe agree right now that the first half of this story is dramatically
stronger. Yeah. Than the resolution. The... I I do like the whole story on it
Even despite my criticisms here, you know?
Mh. But, like, I think the first part of is just so strong. Yeah. First part is definitely stronger. And I do think it drops off especially with the whole
unnecessary,
like, dragon sequence that we're gonna come up to Yeah. Definitely didn't have to be a full thirty two pager, but it is still a pretty good story. Right. Anyway,
you know, without thinking about it any further,
Donald and Scrooge go into the halls and they think, okay, Well, y'all seek roll into this hallway way to see what's going on. And we get nice little panel in the bottom of these old ruins. Right? Feels like very
seven cities of gold or, like,
Indiana Jones almost which I think is cool. My little.
So they get to the hallway and they yell sql sequel seat role
the wait for the echo and they put their hand in a ear. Classic, and it comes back of course, screaming Barks is la, which gets the actual Barks keys. You know, all in it ti get up. It's told Mick not trying to get the golden police to the Palace girls. I don't know how they were able to find out it was him and him trying to get the fleece right away. But
anyway, agnes is all excited so they go out in search of him and
donald this is what I really like this Donald and Scrooge trying to get out. And the
just show up with all this food.
All these, like old fruits and just start w them knot them. Just knocked them to the floor, which I just found, like, totally weird. Yeah.
It is pretty weird.
So this this previous page had one of my pep peeve Austin,
the the the trope were like someone says something backwards
So, like, if you say sea crawl backwards,
it's not gonna work like that. Right? Like, you can't just
say a word
how it's spelled. It doesn't... You know, if you actually reverse audio, so you have to, like... You have to, like, think about phonetic
how it gets reversed. So let's see. Like, if you said sea first, it it starts with an s sound and Barks keys ends with a
sound. You know what I mean? So like, at the at best, it would be like la.
So anyway, it always annoys me when people think think that it works like that. I do like...
It's it is it is very quick and can try to how how
large... The queen of the Barks keys just quickly toss off. I am the one that tricked him into this. So we could have some fun. Mh. Yeah. Go ahead. Anyway, it's all on Scrooge being bound by this. You know, food, and of course, enough user to the rescue as they always are they're running out. They have all these sort of supplies and weapons with them. And they're up on the roof of the hallways
and they're looking over and when that one nephew he goes well, would you look at that and the other one says, Barks
flying formations like dive bombers, and it's just kind of a peculiar image of, like, the Barks,
like, soaring down, like their b nineteen into, like, the.
So they have all these weapons with them and rockets
with pin wheel war, and they light them off and and sort set them out to scare the log keys, but not to hurt them because as they're gonna mention in a little bit, you can't hit a woman. Yeah.
And we're continuing
we're continuing that old trope. Right? Like, these are not monsters. They are women first, basically.
To Barks and these characters. Right. I do like... I do like that we get one more mention of par nip austin is that's one of the foods that they get dive bombed with. U nice. I actually miss that originally.
Anyway, we get a a bit of a neat little fighting sequence between the Nephews and the Barks.
And they're throwing up the the rockets to keep lighting them, but
They... The Barks pickup handful of rocks, I guess. Yeah. They boy. Are they throwing them down at the nephews or are they they just like, threatening them with... Well, I think I think they're getting ready to when when the nephews
decide they have to, you know, release their secret weapon. Oh, I I guess. It just
seems kinda weird pacing.
But, you know, anyway, you you can. You can't get angry at this part of the story for being weird
We've had a lot of weird before this.
Yeah. And to top it all with weird because I think this is super.
Super weird and super funny of course, they can't shoot rockets at ladies. So they have to pull up their super secret
web
which is tiny little
mice
on balloons. And, of course, because women are so horrified of mice the
fly away, never to be seen again. Right. He's laughing. Yeah. They give a rejoin. He he he.
It's
it's silly. This is not... I I I imagine there are a lot of readers who really like this and are still in use. A lot of old time Barks fans are probably still in use by this kind. Is doesn't really work for me that well these days. But you yeah I understand people people like this kind of thing. Yeah. I I I get it. Of course, like nineteen fifties. It was sort of a narrative drop of course, we've seem like that image in the cartoons of, like, the woman jumping on the table Al the mouse and, like, picking up the skirt and everything. But Absolutely were saying this is
one of those parts of the store it would probably not fly very well, today. It's the trope. And and sometimes tropes are just funny because they're funny, I guess. Sure. Yeah. Exactly. So, you know, we get this sequence where the the nephews finally
reveal that They've they've come along to save Donald and sp. And we get a really quick transition. There's no real reunion here.
I like that they hold up to a little woods check sign, you know, and say it's one of the Inducks
patrol of the junior with checks of the world. And,
you know, we get this moment where screwed wants to keep going
and find the
find the police by following the Al echoes, but the nephews say fo on that, they plan to use flood lights and the encompass.
And at this point, Bark needs to wrap the story up. He needs to kinda get it get it going. So there's no no more real
T prevail,
They they do. They find the fleece. It's like hanging off this pool looking wall
Scrooge
gives a great money hungry
lunch towards it. This that this is an image that he captured and in one of the oils.
That looks pretty great. Yeah. And also that Rosa captured in his his glad cover, of course. Right. Yeah. That's the second cover, I guess that Rosa did for this one. Right? Because... Yeah. Right. He did the one with the and then the one with, like, you know, the yeah one from Scrooge Adventures.
I I think I think this one is really indicative of Rosa at the earlier part of his career. I think that one's a lot. Stronger. Yeah. For sure. The the dragon in this one is shown in full and he he looks
almost plastic. Mh.
So, you know, Scrooge just, like really
ecstatic and he's kiss the the golden wool, but the dots remind and we've gotta worry about getting out of here. Let's turn around from this dead end
and Scrooge is super excited
to to, you know, see it in the light. In the daylight. And, I don't why don't you take it from here. Sure. Of course. They're are very excited, But I guess not everything has come to a resolution yet because here we come to the most peculiar
add on to the story I suppose this part that didn't have to be here and probably could have been like a separate story entirely on its own where Scrooge is excited and he's got the fleece and we're running out with it. And the nephews and donald on is trail, and they hear an e and a champ.
And turns out there's just that big dragon, which is hanging around the corner that just in engulfed Scrooge alive I suppose.
And like, here, we've got that that cool sort of thing where the the dragon was lingering through the whole story. They mentioned him at the beginning and, you know, Donald and Scrooge hurt him, and the nephews
them and when, of course, they showed up. And it didn't really play into anything. So now it's coming into play when it's like, very much so out of the readers like short term memory. So it is a cool reveal, and this is nice,
but it's largely
unnecessary as we're as we're gonna see Yeah. Yeah You know right. Probably on all counts.
You know, even the Ducktales have forgotten of about them. Donald like actually kind of four that by saying we clean for forgot about him.
And and we're immediately
reassured that Scrooge is alive because he is yelling for help from the mouth. Of the driving who's looking Al slips.
Boy Austin, this dragon and looks like such a big dope.
Looks like such a more... He looks like the Disney dragon from the reluctant dragon in the face. You looks like Al of a threat. Maybe, like, the reluctant dragon or or a little bit keeps
and
pee, it I kinda love him.
He is
So over the top weird, he has horns and he has, like, little bells that dang from them, and they see long spin tail and these weird offset legs.
And just this glazed look in his eyes. Because he is the sleepless dragon. Mh.
So, you know, we've got this... We've got a great wood check figuring things out seen here. You know, they've got to... They've got to frantically look through their guide book for some advice on how to make a drag and open his jaw. And this is one of Barks
great
things. His his great tropes, where they're, like, debating over what chat sure they should be in. Could it be on the chapter on dental work? No. It would be under lock.
No. Don't get so rattle. It'll be in the section on unusual beasts.
And they they eventually
get the
advice to dump four to ten pounds of pepper into the Dragon nose depending on size of the dragon and to make them open his mouth to sneeze.
Being out of pepper, they find the next closest thing a
bottle of mustard
that they use for pneumonia plaster.
Lost and that that seems like a treatment that's been lost to
a couple of generations back, I guess. I admit I didn't look up what the heck that is. Yeah. Neither did I I have zero idea what's going on. Yeah fine. That's fine. But this ground mustard
does the trick. They wing it right into his nostril,
and he lets loose a big
sneeze and we get this funny little gag where
an nephew you asked Was that on Scrooge screwed that was blown by and Donald says yes I heard him say that as he fast.
It was just funny nice little gag. I suppose. Yeah.
Anyway, they find screws in the corner as he was shot out of the Dragon nostril.
And they try to make a break for it with the fleece as the dragon is building up for another sneeze. So they duck into this little, like, hole in the wall I assume they found because they try to make it to the tunnel before he sneeze is. They realized it's too late so they tuck into the hole. And as the dragon and left out the sneeze,
I think it's his toes to cover up the hole, they slam against the the little hole that they came through Right of you know, one of those funny panels of just a bunch of eyes and, like, the black darkness. One of the Ducktales is he's got us trapped in a one door cubby hole. No one says, and keep us here forever. He's that mad.
Now I guess it just they turn on a light or something in the next panel because then you can see everybody
And so the point... Of course, they pull out the guide to see what's going on
how to solve the problem as they always do. And and nephew you find that the guide says to pull the wool over his eyes. And I think Scrooge speaks for me to where he says kind of vague directions. You know? Right.
Yeah. So this is what I had
referenced.
That this is like a a common thing for tricking
someone. Right? You pull the wall over someone's eyes. And
it is vague, but the nephews know immediately.
What it means to do. And and they grab the fleece from a reluctant Scrooge promising to bring it back. I like this scene a lot, but it it is admittedly a little con contract. Right? Because the dragon is covering the whole they've got to one... One of the nephews uses gotta tickle him to distract while the other sneaks out, I'm like, okay. Well, maybe if you can sneak out, you and figure out something. But... But anyway, this is this ends up being the best way. He he scales his weird backbone
puts the golden fleece over the dragon eyes and the dragon, I guess were meant to think he's so focused on why
the
captive tops that he somehow doesn't notice. And the narrator box tells us that for the first time in Eon, the sleep dragon
can't see.
Because it seems like I guess were meant to see that he doesn't really have eyelids.
The coloring that I've got here has his eyes is very reddish. I don't know if the original coloring showed it that way
He his eyes in the the original just like, the classic black pupil and then, like, the white.
Yeah. So that's kind of a nice touch that the Gladstone.
Color.
I bet it was Susan Day beach.
No. It's Mike Mc mccormick. Apparently. Well that was a cool choice. Right? Because, like, that that seems like something that would go along with him being the sleep was dragon. But
anyway,
we can guess what happens here. He finally does off he gets a really
satisfying looking sleep and the Ducktales. We get one panel where the duct say fair well to the lara keys and they're gas cookbook.
Has Scrooge sets.
Yeah know.
I'm wasn't very sure what happened to that least They put over his eyes. Did they just keep it there and they had enough left?
I mean, my my read is that, like,
his... He needed that naps so much that even when they took it away, he probably
stay asleep. But I but I guess there's a reason that Barks doesn't show it to us because maybe you can't. It was too hard to show the mechanics of a so gloss over. Something like that. You know. So Why don't you take us home. So, of course, Scrooge is all happy. Goodbye to that old broad call cloth coat that I bought in Scotland in nineteen o two. As soon as I have my new gold coat made from this release, I'll throw this old thread bear rag in the trash can. So we fast forward a little bit to
one month later. Their back home Inducks burgers is and air elevator box puts it and the nephews are Al excited because the golden code is coming back from the taylor today,
and they go over to the office
that I guess to Inducks building and Scrooge isn't in there. So
they kinda around the corner. He's here in the Alley, and they see him putting his old code in the trash can until they talk to him and they realized he's not putting it in, he's taking it out.
Because Scrooge screws puts it This dogg on glittering Golden
Macintosh is the coldest contraption I ever had on my back.
Forest Nephew just kinda laugh Al that as we close out the story. So I guess the whole journey was for not then. Right. I I love the ending. I think as far as, like gag endings to adventure stories go, that... That's one of Barks best.
Like, it's it's such a great little bit of poetic. You know, we've gone to all this effort, and that that thing. It's, like, be careful what you wish for. Right? That thing that he wanted the whole time
was not gonna do it for him So... Mh. So I I think... I think it's a great ending. I love the image of him looking
upset in his shiny
glittering
new code. What about you? Yeah. I I mean, I didn't think about it like that when I first read, but I do, like, sort of the careful what you wish for that you mentioned. I didn't think about it like that. And, of course, like, if you think about it in, like, sort of an adventure comedy story,
there's not much better for an ending you can do than just like a funny gag. I suppose.
So even if it's not like fully satisfactory, it is kind of all you he could work with here. So... Yeah. Right. We have... We had to see the codes.
Right? We had... We got all this build up. We have see outcome.
We had him go to the trouble or that nice taylor went to the trouble explaining why a real go gold coat wouldn't work. So So, yeah, that that ending, I find very satisfying.
How about the overall
story and I and I know that you and I have talked kind of through
what we think about it. But any any other thoughts, anything you wanna add to Yeah. I know we were both
pretty critical with that weird
second half there. But it is still very good. Still one of the greatest.
And that first half is really good like one of the all time grades.
So yeah, very entertaining some great art. Couple great gag. So, yeah, Definitely a great Scrooge story. Yeah. I'm I'm right there with you, you know, the the lead up to to what happens, the the way the adventure sets off is like this.
Real masterpiece
of
creepy
atmospheric
unsettling setup
And it and take this turn once they actually get there that I'm not Huey, satisfied with flat. But on the whole, I still really like this one. I love how he kind of integrates all this
stuff from the quote actual
myth in a way that's that really works within the Ducktales Universe, I think
I like Scrooge just motivation here. I like the idea of of, you know, the richest man in the world looking for
something that is both a trophy
and just a way to wear some some clothes that really fit him.
I like all the sort of junior wood checks elements of this. You mentioned that it's kind of maybe packed full of one monster too many. And... And like I agree with you, the dragon is a little bit tacked on, but he's so goofy and he's so funny.
And it kinda struck me that it's... It's like the Greek miss. You know, When they go through, it's like monster after monster.
In
It's like monster after monster
in so many of those stories. So
it is
maybe one element too many, and some of the Barks stuff might be a little bit rushed, but... But I also think it kind of fits within, like, the framework
of it.
Sure.
Yeah. I I suppose I was a little critical of the dragon because, like, I've been doing a lot of reading of like,
classic literature
lately like novels like American and British novel. So, like, I've been very critical of the overall structure of a story. So, like, to see the dragon and thrown in when I was re reread it for the recording, like everything was perfectly resolved by the end. And then just the drag and showed up and I was like, what the hell going on, you know?
I... Yeah. I don't think you're off based. I mean, I think it's... I think it's totally fair Criticism He's definitely a little bit tacked on. I just... I just... I find him such an dear goof ball.
I agree. I I I actually forgot he was as cool as he wants. He's a cool drag and is what he is. He's not very threatening, but he's a gold dragon. Yeah. He's got a very weird character care design. Honestly, his character design is kinda like nothing
else that Barks is done.
Yeah.
Totally. And then, you know, the the, like,
The whole thing has this very retro grade
attitude
towards women
that obviously does not work well these days. But but if you
if you just kind of consume it as an artifact of its time, I'm never gonna like that stuff because it's always... It always feels a little bit lazy.
But but I I get where he's coming from. There there's are still some fun elements
there
in, like, the over the top, cooking dishes, you know? I think there's definitely a little element of maybe bark still being bitter at his...
You know, he's in his third and and
successful marriage now, but I understand that his previous marriage ended pretty poorly. So it it almost feels like an ex wife story or something.
Yeah. No kidding. Actually. That makes a lot of Severino.
Looking at this story and when it was written. Right.
So let's talk a little bit about the general consensus.
This this is a famous Barks story. This is probably like when people talk about Uncle Scrooge
and Carl stories. People probably mentioned this in the first five or ten. I'm guessing. So so it has a very high rating on Inducks, not like an all time, but
you know, in in one of those upper tiers.
It is as of when I looked, it was number forty six
out of all forty two thousand or so stories
good for number seven...
Excuse me. Good for a seven point nine
rating.
Alec like I have a lot of nostalgic
you know, love for this one even if I have a couple problems with it. So, like, despite the flies, the the things that were so well. I think that's... I think that's a pretty fair rating.
Yeah. I I agree eight out at ten is is is pretty solid.
I know people on Inducks who generally
rank bark stories are more forgiven than like, you and I might be who are talking about it. For like, an hour and a half for a podcast.
Right. Home.
But no eight auto of attendant is a good place to put it. I mean any stories like classic. Oh, go ahead.
I was just gonna say, of course, it's like an actual treasure hunt, which if you think about it, Barks didn't do as many as those. I think that was sort of wise because of Rosa.
I think there only, like, seven actual Barks hunts for, like you know, like a treasure, like some gold things. So Yeah. You know, Treasure hunts among Barks fans are
a odd item. So naturally the leasing is sort of a a big one. Yeah. That's true That's a good point. The actual treasure items were gonna be iconic. I have to do a tally for the Pop and podcast because that's that's something I Severino thought about.
Yeah. So people really like this one. Ducktales, of course, popularized the treasure hunt
and and Ducktales
did adapt this one. This was one of the, like, twenty or so
stories that Ducktales did a pretty straight up adaptation of. Had did you get to see it by chance?
I actually did not. I don't think I did.
So I don't know. I don't think that they did one for the second series
but for the first series, it was
done, and and it was titled the golden fleece exactly like it and I have to say, it was a pretty strong adaptation. It was kind of a launch pad episode, you know, launch pad instead of Donald.
They they briefly shoe horn Ludwig Von drake.
Makes one of... I don't know if he ever appeared
in any other episodes, but he's like launch pads psychiatrist,
and launch Pat is worried having these
hallucinations because he saw the the Barks keys
So they don't really do any of that sort of mysterious setup. But there's, again, this sort of cooking
competition elements
and they wanna feed him to the dragon at the end. But... But, like, when I watched the le with the lock
adaptation
recently
and back to the Al. I thought those were
much weaker as far as Barks at. Expectations stuff. So I, you know, I I don't love most of the original Ducktales apps this this was a pretty good one.
I think that one of the Barks keys was voice by June four a who is always.
Always great to hear. That's very interesting. I I didn't I didn't fact check that. I'm just talking by my reception. So I wrong. But... Yeah. Yeah. This is not one that ever had.
As far as I know, there was never, like, Rosa didn't do, like any kind of a sequel. He gave so many of the iconic stories
the sql treatment.
But it was a little element of the, like, story called rightful owners by
what's that guy's name who did the video game
One weren't inspector.
Oh, yes. Right. He had a big a big story a few years ago, or I think this was involved. And then... And I think Romano spa used the Barks keys again for some story that I've never read. Oh, Wow.
I'll have to look into it that. I don't remember that. Yeah. And and as far as oil paintings, you know, Bark did do two oils for this one. One of them with the moment where they find the golden fleece. That's a very cool
oil or Lit or whatever.
And then another one called menace from the miss, which focuses on
one of the s lara keys, which
You know, there they're such a gruesome subject
for an oil. It's it's a fun one, but I like the other one better.
Mh.
Yeah. His oil are always a a treat deal again?
Yes. Definitely.
Let's see. I
think. I think that I got to say pretty much everything that I wanted to about this one austin. And do you have any other
thoughts or comments or reflections?
I would say it's a... Not. I would say you covered it pretty well. It's a it's a pretty solid story. Even if we both had our a bit. I think it's still one of my favorites is for for that first half, especially. Right. Yeah. Definitely.
Well
I I really appreciate you joining me for this
episode.
Tom.
Let's see. Our... People can check us out Barks remarks is on the usual socials. We got a Facebook presence and
Instagram, and
the next time around for the adventure links stories. We get to cover
the very last of the Donald Inducks
Adventures,
the secret of H,
And Austin, I have... You already... I think you already highlighted the last bit of dialogue for us, but that's how I've been closing out the episodes. The last couple of months. Do you mind reading that last panel again?
Sure.
This dog on glittering Bold And macintosh is the coldest can trap I ever had on my back. Excellent.
Thanks so much, Austin.
Anytime. Yeah? Alright. I think that was great. I that went really well. Yeah. That was nice.
Thank you, and I will let you get to the rest of year your afternoon and evening.
Cool. Yeah. I appreciate it. Take care, Austin. Thanks. You too. I'll see around.