We can have
Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer an artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comments of all time. Join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks. Welcome back to Barks remarks. I'm mark Sever a Grown man who loves dot com,
and I love talking about them with the long time friends and and new friends that I've met in the course of doing this podcast. And I'm delighted
to have a couple of my returning guest hosts
to discuss
today's
story, which is the secret of Honda,
or Hon.
I guess, I guess we can we can discuss that. But
let me
introduce
my guest are Warren Harmon and Sarah, Santiago.
Warren, I think I think you've just done some some traveling in the area. When introduced yourself and tell us about that? Yeah. Mark, hey, Sarah. Yeah. I've just got back from a three week adventure to Par peru and
Ecuador.
And
the Islands, the Amazon Rainforest, and probably one of my most memorable times was much picchu to up in Andy Mountains that couldn't help but channel donald and the nephews from lost in The Andy. So I was
have a having a lot of fun there. Lots of great photos lots of great memories and you got some great Barks locations in
that there. I did. I was
happy to share it with the Barks community, the fan community and had a couple of figurines that I I post in some great locations,
especially the the sacred Valley in my two picchu. It was was a lot of fun. That's that's really cute. I'm glad to talk about this story since I just returned. Excellent.
And sarah, what do you think? Are we talking about.
So I read it in... Like, in an American English accent first, and I thought it was him Honda.
And then I thought about it and decided to go with
Because the rules in Spanish, if it ends in an o or an a or an n, the syllable that is stressed is the one before the last And... And of course, going by the proper Spanish rules, we we'd have to O omit h and go on, I guess. But no.
On Nor eureka. Yes. That's right. Yeah. Yeah. And.
It seemed to also be a evo, not just Doris but Costa rica. Right. I think that's right. It's one of Barks fun a ama names.
On du and costa to Rica. And just as a refresher, you guys have been on together frequently. Warren, you are my long time
Barks fan and collector, and Sarah, I have you on to give kind of a newbie
perspective because you haven't read these stories.
Before. So okay. I, of course, I'm a long time fan. And and this this story, the secret of,
It is one that I I didn't really read that much. You know? And in fact, it has all these elements where in my mind when I thought back on it. I I I feel like I kinda mis mismatched it with a bunch of other Barks stories
I kinda have trouble separating it from, like, moments from oh from the gil man
or
maybe
from
the pixelated
pair,
what else, a couple of the stories that take place in the African jungle
So
right off the bat, feel like this is not necessarily the most memorable
of of Bark adventure stories. It also it has some
I I think you guys this one has some problems.
To it in in a few in a few respects.
Yeah. I agree, Mark. I I think I think this one...
Barks was not at the top of this form here.
Also I don't think he his research... Well, I I'm not gonna blame on research. I'm just gonna blame on ignorance and and just of his choices of language. But... But again, given the times and this time in his life, I mean, he's fifty six years old. He's got ten years before he stops drawing for the comics and to begin his other career.
I I just these just it it... It's less of a story that I wanted to be. Yeah. What what do you think? What are your kind of initial thoughts Sarah?
Well, I
came up with a drinking game.
Yeah. So I used to do a podcast called educating key where we would introduce each other. Very much like you do, mark. To me.
Two
franchises shows, comics,
books, movies that we love, but somebody else has not seen. And we came up with drinking game rules for everything.
That we talked about and mine was take a drink every time there's a word or concept that's totally degrading to indigenous people. But you have to do it with, like, the lowest alcohol content beer
or you will just be wasted and, like, need to go to the hospital
Right.
Right. It's is has to be for alcohol point.
And and, you know, the... You're absolutely right. This one is This one is pretty insensitive. That the thing is the the thing that frustrate me. Right? We... We've had these conversations about some of these
challenging moments
before stuff that has aged very poorly stuff that is sensitive I always go out of my way to, like, observe that, yes. This was very common. These were very common depictions
at the time, you would see this sort of stuff in comics
and and in other elements of pop culture, obviously,
on the other hand, there there are people who got it and closer to right even back then. But for me, you guys the really frustrating thing is we we we don't get like the flip side of it at least being a really good story with these, like, really unfortunate elements Right? Like looking back at a story like Voodoo Do? It has these awful stereotypes
and and really
poorly age depictions, but it's like it's a thrilling
dread Inducks
adventure.
Like it's really engaging. I I mean, say what you will about the insensitive moments.
It's it's just a great yarn, and maybe a better comparison might be the guild man. Right? Because, like, the guild man is... I I think you could probably argue warren that this this is kind of like a soft remake of the guild man because it kinda shares some elements And a golden man has some of this same, like savage native tropes,
but I I it's not quite as bad and it's also, like in the service of a really engaging really siding adventure. Yeah. I I I read a that did compare it a bit to the gil man and and other
depictions of other characters in the story to other more classic stories. But, yeah. This one, I I just had had a problem very much like you did mark that that not only is the the language and sensitive in many parts and the thoughts and the agreeing by the Nephews and Donald and and sort of carrying forward
that that depiction
negative
stereotype type. It just wasn't wasn't a classic story. It's it's he's, you know, you mentioned pixelated parent. You mentioned, and I I I mentioned earlier when we when we were just kind planning to show that that there were, you know, other, like, trail of the unicorn and and others that have native indigenous
depictions like of the north with the the es, you know, tribes.
And yet, that they seem to redeem themselves a little bit and it was light and, we kinda forgave that, but one, I don't know. I have a a tough time. Yeah. I I think... So so all of us
we're we're kind of on the same page. Which means I definitely wanna go out of my way to find the things that I do like about this one because there there are a lot of great things about it. A media mediocre bark story is still, you know, the the reason for this podcast is that he's he's a super superior
ko creator. So there there's a lot of brilliant stuff in here. It's just on the whole, I don't find this to be the strongest Barks story, and it's not just because of the, like,
Savage,
poorly,
native stuff. Like. That definitely pulls it down further. But right. Alright. So a little bit of background
before we go into it.
This one is one of our relatively
rare
donald dot comic
stories. There are not a lot of them that we cover that have appeared in the Donald Inducks line of Comics.
I think the last one was Triple treat. Mh. And this one appeared in donald dot number forty six. It was published in March of fifty six. And warren I saw that he created it back in September of fifty four, which seems like an unusually long gap he couldn't I I didn't Google around too much, but I couldn't figure out a reason for that unusual
delay. Maybe some listener can fill me in if anyone knows about that. I was unaware of that. That... That's interesting. Perhaps the editors hung on to it and wanted to find a a vehicle for it. And and it's interesting as a as a collector of the adventure stories and the four color stories, which is what I primary...
Primarily collect. I didn't really get into the donald dot com. So I discovered this and that ten volume hard cover ct Al, the Carl Barks library where I'm I'm reading it in black and white. I do have the glad edition, but I couldn't find it I I searched for this one. So it probably doesn't have as many reprint. So would that be a fair statement? Yeah. It's got kind of a low average number. This one's got
ten printing
including the original. I actually do happen to have the very original dow printing which is unusual for me because like it would have... It would been my third
instance of owning the story because I had the, like, album version that was collected with the guild man,
and the the really nice
nicely drawn covered by Don Rosa.
For donald duck adventure number twenty one. I really do like that. That cover. And so, yeah. I don't I can't can't remember why as was a, like, thirteen year old I went out in my way. It was probably a a pretty pricey Barks issue for me to try to own.
Let's see. This is a twenty four pager, which
is shorter than his long adventure stories, but is about about the average length going forward for a lot of his adventures I guess it's worth noting that we're like, we're kind of outside now that period that fans generally consider Barks golden age quote on unquote. Most people would say that kinda went to how do you think warren roughly, like nineteen fifty three, maybe fifty four or So... In terms of when when he kinda started departing from that Golden era? Yeah. Went and it. I No. I would would definitely classify as golden era as that forty eight forty nine
two fifty three.
He's he's I think he's either reaching for story ideas that he's perhaps explored before and trying different angles.
Looking at how these characters can evolve and maybe they don't need to evolve. I don't know. And and and we'll comment on it later, but the artwork work here, the character drawings Barks
sub par in my opinion, and we can talk about a few panels when we get there. Sure. Yeah. I mean, that's not to say he doesn't still have brilliant stories in him because there gonna be some all time classics
coming up.
But but I feel like his his most memorable stories starting now are gonna be... The ones where he... He went a little bit out there. You know, I just put out the issue for
for the gold and flee,
which I think has its problems, but you can't deny that it's like just a wildly invent Yeah and super memorable
story. Yeah. Whereas, like, I'm just hard pressed to remember this one. So I don't really have a lot of other Barks round aside from what we already talked about how we've got a fun
Sarah, what's the term? I'm trying to remember
oh, a Port tow. Right? That's what Hon
Would be call a port where you smash two words together like that. I'm visualizing this being in I think they that they do points vaguely to that Central America
near like Panama Costa Rica. So I think that's where we're gonna be in this. Yeah. So before before we plan into the story itself, We do have a couple of titles from around the world. And guys we don't need to dwell on this one too long because most of these titles are a pretty straightforward
translation of the English title.
But it's fun to mention some of the local equivalent. Right? Since we take place
in Central
South Ish America.
Sarah, do you wanna share with us the Spanish and and Mexico title? Yeah. For once they were the same, they're not always the same. Correct??
That's right. This one is Al.
I've messed up myself.
And messed up my own rules.
It's it's not the kind of word shape you would really get that often in Spanish.
It's not. I I think that... I'm I did apply on Eureka
rules to it. But I could also easily see that there being an accent
to intentionally change
the stress. Right. Yeah. So it's just that straightforward secret of. What about you weren't? I think I gave you another local. Yeah. I think it gave me Brazil, which courses is Portuguese and and the translation that I have is
So it's very
so similar
and not a stretch from the actual title. Right. And then the only one that kinda stood out to me as interesting is the the French one, which seems like it's really trying to sell the story you guys. It's called let
The amazing
Expedition.
So that said, let's let's do this. Let's plow into the story. Alright. So the secret of
Opens up and warren... And right away I'm kinda reminded of the opening of the guild man. Right? We've got we've got Donald and
his nephews approaching Scrooge,
hot hands kinda interestingly. Mh.
Looking very respectful.
And and screws is indicating to a map of central and south America. Kinda like Donald
standing in front of that map at the beginning of the guild man. It's first. Yeah. Yeah. And and, you know, this is some effective signaling about the story. It's a good way to set up the plot. Scrooge is explaining to the the dot it has a job for them that will take them down the to tropical.
And and he goes on to a explain that he's lost a mail plane that crashed at a spot marked x on the map and there to go and recover some valuable
papers.
So right right off the bat, it doesn't feel like this is the most
inspired treasure or not. Right? We're after, like, deeds
papers,
documents,
they may be important, but they're not like it's it's not
the gil man and the the Magenta stamp. It's not
square eggs in play awful. It is. It's not it's not that exciting. It's. Basically
it's it's it's Scrooge just business portfolio. You know, It it that it was on this plane for whatever reason, and it's not a rare, unique treasure And... But he seems to be pretty Al, and this is, you know, with screw. Jeez he's they're happy throughout this entire
first page
until, of course, we see the first
a mention of, you know, who the is yeah. Yeah. So...
Unfortunate.
On the first page, it almost feels like It's it's... On the first couple of pages, there are
uncomfortable
number of mentions
of words like un eyes and savages.
Almost like
like, he's just going out of his way. To use these terms more than you might have to. You know, the the dots are immediately like questioning him. That is the un civilized Barks
that you're pointing at. And and they're
they're commenting that they're worried about this. And it goes on to the next page where Scrooge is trying to convince them that the indians of the area are quote as peaceful as kittens. But then the Nephews chime in, and I think you mentioned this warren and they're weirdly agreeable
about the the
characterization
Yeah. There's that you Sarah? They're not defending the ind folks. They're not there they're they're they're actually agreeing and saying that even read about them in school, which is
I don't know. You know? Right.
And and I guess I had the thought that, like, Barks is very flexible with Donald Right? He needs him to be an every man character,
he's also very flexible with the, like, the local peoples in these stories. Because sometimes he wants them to be a little more sophisticated,
more less objection. And then sometimes they he just needs the savage trail. Yeah. So,
Sarah, do you mind telling us how
Scrooge
does end up convincing the He offers them a reward of five thousand dollars.
So if you tack on a a zero for inflation from the fifties today. That's about fifty thousand dollars. Yeah. That bad. Doesn't it seem un
for screws to offer that much money to his nephews when he's been able to get them to go for far less to far more regions stuff the world. Yeah. It's not the most consistent. But and then he he get... He gets a little extra neat into to Donald. Right. By.
Taking advantage of Donald Jealous is glad stone to spur competition. Right. And
and he does it. He just says I imagine cousin Glad gander or would jump at the chance to win this five thousand dollar reward. This feels kinda like dashed off. It's it's not it's not the most developed men
way of bringing Gladstone stone into the story, I feel like. I mean, why not just offer it to Gladstone in the first place? Yeah. Yeah. That's true. There's no Probably do it for cheaper because Gladstone luck would have helped them along the way. Right.
Yeah. I guess there's the argument that, you know, Gladstone
luck. He... Maybe he just doesn't wanna mess with that. Mh.
But So so Warren,
how does Scrooge kinda set them off on the job? Well, it actually pulls out a map that the injured pilot from the plane that crashed
apparently, they're sent or he drew it, but got it to uncle Scrooge. So that he could show him a map of the location
and donald in the nephews now are kind of looking at that in it's sixty miles
of long hiking, which I'm very. I I get three miles of very long hiking in the Gala silence.
So I can imagine the terrain that they're talking six team miles of jungle hiking. It sounds like it could take... It could take weeks. It would it should take weeks. Let me tell you. And and they ponder the fact that with the kind of reward money they're looking at,
they could hire a helicopter and Yeah. And immediately screwed shuts them down. Right? He he tells them this is where where it his face kind of breaks and shows a little bit of nervous nest. And this is the big, like, I guess this is the secret
of.
We're gonna be set up for this, like, native super superstition But as of now, all we know is that there are things that the natives are super stitch about and it's gonna be safe for the walk And so we kinda
transition to the part where Gladstone
comes into the story and the docks are like talking about the full
story. I'm not gonna keep saying savages. The Ducktales keep saying it. I'll just... I'll call them native.
Cure on out. I've been calling the locals Sure. Locals. Yeah. That's that things like the best... Right. Because even native definitely has, like, the feel of...
It's it's a very loaded word as you say. So yeah. So, you know, they they eventually Scrooge
indicates that yes, the natives get particularly
mad about flying machines. We'll learn more about that later.
And and the docks The Ducktales are like kind of... They're doing in their good luck. They can't believe how lucky they've been. You guys this sounds like a a tremendous amount of work for me. I it never felt to me like, it's got an adequate payday at the end. But honestly, like, people die in those jungles. This this always rang a little bit false to me.
But of course, the mention of how lucky they are is is gonna be set up. Right? Sarah? Well, right. Because then
glad stones look benefits him and he happens upon them.
Kind of just is their thinking like, no. There's bound to be a joker in the deal someplace. Like, they're like, this is too good to be true. And then, of course, Gladstone shows up. Right. So we get kind of the predictable we're glad stone
sussex out immediately that they've got this map and
he's thinking to himself. This is a a chance to show them up that with his luck, he can figure out how to get whatever a kind of treasure they're looking They're looking for.
And the Ducktales really should know better. I feel like. But they kinda talk themselves into
trying to
best glad.
Do you wanna tell us one about what their their strategy is Yeah. They're... Well, first of all, the the treasure map
is is quite revealing and the Barks glad got his eyes on on some treasure. But
now that the map is sort of out there and they're aware of it, the best way to outlet
Glad stone is to memorize the map. So he'll never get his hands on it and eventually, just destroy the map. So they study the map for as it says here for many minutes, Every river and Valley and mountain must be sharp on our minds they say. So I... And they all do a good job of that. And then, of course, he rips it up into very tiny pieces and throws it over the bridge. Into the river. Okay. So this is where I start to
anticipate like I I'm like, okay. I've fried enough of these I know it's gonna happen.
Something always goes wrong. A problem always comes up that the kids then have to solve because Donald just is too emotional to do it, but my prediction was completely off. Right? Like, I thought he was setting them up for
forgetting. Like... Right? Like
not
understanding the map as well as they thought they would. And then Glad stone somehow would have found the map and rest keep them. That it doesn't happen that way. I could... I could definitely see that. That does seem like a a kind of templates.
Response to it. So, yeah, I think that's totally... I like that you're kind of getting yourself into that Barks mindset there.
But, of course, it is another bark trope that glad
lock is just gonna intervene And you guys this is kind of fun. Right What happens is that Gladstone goes down to kind of ponder things and the, like, little eddie, the little whirlpool pool of water. Ends up arranging these pieces for him.
It's it's not the most invent
depiction of the gander lock
And it's kinda of fun. It reminds me of the imp
drive in hitch crackers guidance here. Right. If it didn't feel like look so much is.
Right. Because because it's just over the top, how unlikely that would be.
So So glad.
Like... How it's gonna say, I was just gonna say Barks and Sarah, that not only is this highly highly improbable look but not only does the the the pieces of the map actually re assemble into the map, but right under glad stones b at the.
I think come on. I I I had a a tough time buying that. But again, this is an extraordinarily lucky duct and
and Gladstone dead
of that. And he doesn't... I've never thought of him as a lucky duck. I've never thought of him as a lucky duck. Like like... Well, he technically a gander. Right? Yeah. That's true.
That's But that's like
lucky stuff. It's an
right right
you want that's that might well have been how Barks came up with the the game for sure. That's adorable.
Thanks for helping me make that connection warrant.
I didn't mean to, but you're very welcome. And and should be noted that Gladstone doesn't have the time really to study yet. But but again, his crash is locked... His luck is his crutch. I'm the next sequence, it's it's kind neat It's basically
all about the nephews
trying to get there as quickly as humanly
possible.
And so we see all these modes of
transportation, like really...
That they're racing on this, the fastest
steam,
a banana train headed for the interior, and there's a reference to Donald giving the engineer eighty
to break the speed record.
Sarah, what's the
strategy for the for getting the most out of the donkey keeps.
They
suspend a mad bumblebee
behind each donkey.
I love the artwork and that.
I love that that
there's nothing
that Barks tells us about how donald caught the has been storing and transporting the b. He just somehow has a little cage with a little b.
And ties it to Al little doll too. Yeah.
One, I like the art here a lot, but but it's specifically the background art, because as you note, some of some of the figure are is maybe not his strong.
I'm glad you brought that up. I'm I'm actually quite disappointed in the depiction of Gladstone and even though even donald that the nephews look almost like they used to, but I I see these rounder figures and shorter beak, I know that that glass speak shortened from forty nine to to fifty four, but I it it just looks like he drew these more quickly.
But, yes, I can't and I could go on about little little things, but I think the background art here, starting with that Al wonderful shot of donald and the boys on the steam and then that shot of the steam and the trains and this huge sort of semi splash panel with the bridge. That's just classic Barks in the hip. Putting the condo in there with the question mark is a nice little bag is. And that condo is a bird of Northern South America.
And did you see any? Oh, we did. We saw one one condo
fly over the Amazon rainforest. And it was quite fascinating. It was... Our guides were telling us their look at these cause over here, look at these parents over here look Al and four different species of monkeys. It was incredible. But anyway, I especially love and and condo. We have...
Yeah. We have the Us
baby
here in Pitt pittsburgh. Okay. And they have a couple of condo. And I always love to look at them. Brenda, my wife and I did see an Andy and Pandora in captivity
in Cusco up in the Indian mountains that was quite amazing. So we did see one up close. Nice.
So there something else. Yeah. And like you say, this is a really cool splash panel. I like this sequence
of them kind of racing Al mail but it also, like, it kinda soften the impact of how dangerous
this journey could be because he's just playing it for gag here. Right? He's only playing it for laugh. So we're not worried about them. On this rick bridge or or on that, like, perilous trained. Where the are being lifted off the tracks Al no about that.
Warren, you wanna tell us about what greet them upon their arrival at Chi.
Right. Right there, they're they're in a hurry to get there. They think they're actually miles and miles. Like had Al Gladstone.
Sure enough he's enjoying a fruit drink at a at a vendor, stand in fifty nine or whatever. And
that's Gladstone luck came through again and of course, Donald just livid. Right. And and the nephews give him the wise council to, like, stay out of sight
but he just immediately ignores that. Right. He he reveals himself
and you guys I'm not even that interested in in how Gladstone got there that fast. It's it's not it's not really that interesting. He basically met a guy who a rich local who sees him as a good luck charm, and he's just been hanging out. And and we kinda switch over to this glad stone segment while the the docs are doing at him beating beating them there, and he's just kinda trying to su out more details about their their shared pursuit. Why didn't they take a plane like theft out like bad storytelling to me. Like, he's so in service
to Gladstone beating him that they are like, oh, we're gonna get a helicopter.
And then they take, like, a boat and then don't please. Yeah. They don't even bother with a plain.
To get the bulk of the diff
you didn't have radar artwork work though, Sarah Come on. Yeah.
They could've have flown over it.
Al plain?
Yeah. It's it's you're right. It's a plot hole. I also... I kinda gloss over it, but I... It occurred to me that You know, Donald is stew. I spend weeks getting here by the fastest means I could find. And you hop down here in Gladstone says four hours. It was a jet plain. That doesn't... The math doesn't work out there. Like, even a little bit. So. My my I flew to
Lima Peru from Atlanta, and it was six and a half hours. So no. That doesn't quite work. Right. We we even if we don't know exactly where Inducks
is. Like
Soda. So we know that. But But I mean, he's he never really like officially...
Yeah. Yeah. That seems like a stretch.
And and so when we switch to Gladstone
point of view, he's kinda disappointed because I he he apparently didn't expect them this soon and he had to pretend he didn't even know why they're there.
So he starts to race off. But then we encounter
the gentleman
that he has apparently met and been hanging out with. Sarah, you wanna... You wanna tell us about Don't pedro? No alberto seems like he's kid kidnapping Gladstone.
Linked twice if you're okay glad still.
Can get with hospitality.
Yeah. But he doesn't
let him leave. He's like, oh, you can't leave we have to have a party Oh, you can't leave now after the party. We have to have a raffle,
like it mean that guy. Not a good guy. He's got a very friendly bearing, but you're right. He's
he's very
enthusiastic.
Just there. Barks
Do you remember a time Mark when you've seen Gladstone stone rest for such a long time where is is luck has to wait. I'm I'm trying to wonder what what other style. You know, I don't specific. I I think there's definitely been moments like this. But... But you another out of character moment like, are out of just bad storytelling, like,
Gladstone
doesn't worry and Gladstone doesn't get, like, tripped up and have things happen against as well. Right.
Or usually, he's thinks to himself. He actively thinks, oh, my luck is is working in some mysterious way here. But but it takes until it's gonna take... Like you said, it's a pretty good chunk of time lauren before he's realize why is locked is supposedly taking them here.
Keeping in there. And and meanwhile, the docs are making some good progress
And Barb,
Barks does a nice job here, I think of, like, showing
how it's kind of this perilous
journey.
Right? He shows them swinging kinda like tarzan and to
to confuse Gladstone trail him. And And then then there's a neat sequence where they're crossing this, like, crocodile and infested
river
but
but there's a good gag where the Nephews asked if it's a Creek that he previously
referred to any he or if it's a river,
previously
referred to, but he says, no, this is only a creek that flows into it.
And and that's where Don Rosa
you know, made the... He he use this panel to inspire him to make part of the cool cover that I do really like for this one that he did decades. Later. You guys I do really also like the couple of panels that show the Inducks on the next page kind of evading, some wildlife life. Mh. The Ducktales look a little bit out of scale compared to those arm ill
and and like, the jaguar.
But in a way that to me feels like oh in this
jungle that's, you know, incredibly dangerous. I kept thinking about you talking about his Love for national Geographic these felt very inspired by National Geographic. Yeah. Yeah. I have no doubt that these are right out of it. It's it's really cool. Especially those arm in demos. I really like that. That I mentioned of them. Yeah. The realism of the of the images is is great mixed with the comic characters. And And and again, I I think just the the background art here is absolutely pure Barks genius. And then, of course, they they come to that that river. Which is white and shallow. Yeah. And and this, this is my favorite part of the story. I do. You you too. I love... I love this historic tables,
see cats. I've never heard of them, and it's so invent and I wonder if bark... Barks created it, but did he research This is great. What do you think? It it is great and I've gotta tell you I... When I came to this part, I was like, oh, that's right. This is the story where the... Where he used the store tables. Because I I remembered
did he also use them in so far and no Safari later on. I feel like he might have used them in two stories. But anyway, I had I did not remember that they came from this one at least initially. And I got so excited. I was like, I'm doing this podcast where my stick is that I gotta go going in dive into all the details of this. So I'm gonna look up, you know, where your store tables come from? Because it's such a specific and evo name. Huey, couldn't I couldn't find anything you guys. I don't know that they're even a real thing.
I think he might have just made them up for this.
I just looked up store tables and all I found was like, side tables with really skinny legs. Right.
Right. It's like lines of of furniture. Right? Some of which I'm sure my wife would really like in our entry way.
But, like I I was a little bit a little bit bummed to realize that store tables are not a thing. Maybe maybe, again, a listener can point out to me that oh, these were widely used in whatever country, but
But anyway, it is very invent. Right? The idea here is that because the... The river is so shallow,
it's that, like, it's too shallow for them to cross safely and a boat and and so they have to use these complementary
pairs of very high tables that they fashion out of local
branches and stuff and they
they place one in front of the other and transfer themselves, and there's applies to cross. It's really cool. I love it. Yeah. I've never heard of them but, like, we all agree. It it... I think this is Pure Barks imagination. Kind of
reinventing that giant walking through the river on with these... What I look like stair steps or flip footsteps. Inducks.
I think one of the that says is just like walking. And that's when it just dawned on me how they do it and yeah. The most invent creative part of the entire story. Are these?
We shu table ahead while we stand on table b then we step ahead on table a and move up table b. Yep. And, of course, the boys came up with it, and it came from their wood truck guy.
Yeah. Yes Oh basically
Take tune year wood shocks. It looks like a small book for so much knowledge doesn't. Yeah. And then so the the docks make it across the river, and they're very celebratory
saying that they're gonna
Gladstone
for the first time and their lives. And that that feels like the signal.
Right? The narrator or signal that it's gonna go poorly for them now.
They
see the pilot's marker, which is gonna lead them to the rep. And do you wanna tell us
warren about the raffle?
He the raffle back in Chi?
Right. So now the Gladstone still looks rejected and here the the don and deputies are so close to that plane. But back there. Al last we have everyone here for the raffle is done Pedro.
And
glad just looks so rejected. But then what is the prize? Well, we don't know what the price is But Gladstone does. And his eyes widened and he says, well, polish, my papa and eye eyeballs, I do want to win that and Well, we'll see. I I really like that line. I do and it's a neat. It's a neat little bit of entry, you know, readers with a good memory code. Can probably guess when it is. But I don't think I saw it coming as as a ten year old or whatever. Mh. I didn't see it coming as a forty three year olds. Yeah. There you go.
You guys... I'm gonna break for just a moment to mention that the fact that Gladstone has just been been sitting back there the whole time. This makes it feel like the story is almost one of those airport layover stories.
Right? Like, it's it's so easy for Gladstone to do the thing Right he what that he's about to do to just kinda pair in to the story that some of that is what makes the the weight of the story less impactful for me. Yeah. There are very few moments where you actually do see during the the with the the heart of the story we're glad and donald actually do interact until the end. And it's right. So there is... Yeah yeah. Yeah. Yeah So the the Ducktales now, they know that they're really close to the wreckage
and and we get a little reminder of the locals
as one of the Nephews
says, aren't they gonna hear us coming?
And Donald like, no. We'll sneak up on the plane quietly.
And
as they arrive near where the they expect the plane to be, they hear some sounds.
And Sarah, do you wanna tell us about the sequence
They discover Gladstone
already going through a bunch of papers and throw them around like they're useless.
And and this kind of, like, Beg
disbelief to me too. Right? Gladstone
expects to find a treasure
So he's like just tossed out all these papers, but it seems reasonable that these papers could be what he's looking for. Mh. I I think so... I felt like that was pretty credible if he didn't really like, investigate what the papers were. Right? Like, if you just go with and and you have it in your brain
that you're going to find something, and then you don't find that thing It
Sure. You can... Yeah. It's believable that he was so upset by that that he did investigate what he did have. Right. Because he has been following what he believes to be a treasure map, but then on the next page, he's gonna specifically reference some old deeds and stuff. And I'm like, okay. That mean deeds, those are inherently valuable.
I mean, we are
millennials
who
only just by the skin of our teeth were able to afford our own homes. So maybe
more valuable than a dentist to us. But not to Gladstone.
To Al oil will. Yeah. Yeah.
He tells them his story about how he got there before them. What what is it? Sarah?
He got a helicopter ride.
Right. That was the very? The very thing that Scrooge warned them against
Glad wasn't there to hear. So when he heard that there was a helicopter ride available
he took... He took it when he on the raffle. Right. You want one ticket out of ten thousand other tickets. So, again, it's a very... We're kind of returned to the incredible Gladstone luck.
The story. And and this is a pretty tense part of the story Right? Because the Ducktales
look genuinely fearful
and they're tearing through the local jungle as Gladstone
explains I threw out some papers. Well and such Right.
Black. Come on glad. When I emptied the pilot's duff bag, and and, you know, this this sets up the Ducktales racing to find the papers
while they hear... They describe them as Indian war drums. That's an old an old trope. So they know that the danger is approaching.
I I looked up... I tried to look up whether or not central American, indigenous people's used
some kind of four. I I only just briefly lift up couldn't find anything.
But what I could find was, like a link to the, like, Us army five and drum core as if, like, board drums were dis stink,
like, not white thing. Like, you'll have your symptoms. Like, don't other people for using drums in their military exercises is that not men in the... Right. Exactly. And this is just coded.
Yeah. And and so we kinda get the natural
resolution to this, where Gladstone
realizes that he's got them
he's... He's got them to write.
They need to get the to recover these documents fast. So they can rely on his luck. And they do make the deal with him for for half of that fat reward. Warren you wanna tell us about Glad stone recovering them. Yeah. I I find this to be
more unbelievable than luck. But anyway, he
and I'm sure just a few minutes is able to... After promising to use his luck, he proves that he does have the ability by just simply reaching into a tree and pulling out two fat envelopes and grabbing the third one from a monkey, and that's it. That's all of it. All them
is all bundled up in three bundles. I I thought that... It blew away, I I was having trouble with this, but I think Barks needed to continue this story pretty quickly. Now he's doing his page count. He goes well, I think I'd better wrap this up. That's me guys. Yep. Done We get a little transition where says one minute later. So he probably got a couple more of those really unlikely things, but it's all very... It's like kinda per.
Right? He doesn't even... He doesn't even do like three of them and then a a really funny one. It's Yeah. You know, he doesn't do that kinda rule of three or anything where maybe one of them would have floated under Donald hat or something like that.
It's just the monkey holding one... That's not really much of a gas. That have.
Yeah. And and so to me, it didn't occur to me that it was kind of
lazy storytelling.
What it did for me was serve to prove the point that Donald Jealous just got in the way of an easy time. They It could've had glad don't help all along. Because all he had to do was, like, grab an envelope from Mom monkey and reach into a tree.
Right. I think the idea here is the only glad to like, this is
an impossible task for a regular person. But bet you're right, he coulda cut he could've cut Gladstone in back and chi an, he should've have known that Jig was up But, of course, we we like to see this play out. This is yeah. This is the story the Barks wants to tell. Right. The cap to all of this is that they finally got it now they can dash out on glad stones
helicopter
and this infuriating
relation
tells them that he doesn't have any helicopter that went back to Chi.
It was a one way ride a one way ride. Who ends a one way ride into the jungle.
And why would ten thousand people who live there want to do that? That's what I'm trying
out.
Right. Right. Yeah. Except maybe he bargain for, like a a different. Maybe it's supposed to just be an excursion
around. And he was like, not drop me off here. My luck... My luck will take me home.
And so, you know, the the Ducktales sen
flee here, but Glad stone never has to worry.
Do you wanna do you wanna read... Tell me about Glad stones pen?
Interaction here. Gladstone,
like,
why would I run? Like, they're gonna be my friends.
Yeah. What does he think to himself? He he's reaching up to some
grapes
that. Of course, they're growing in the Central American jungle.
And he says they looked like a bunch of squares when my pilot was their rock piece and this helicopter coming out. Like a rock tv. Take a drink.
Let's
some American
Native American
drives here. Right. This is definitely
an ugly American
stereotype here. Barks is like, poking. Just a tiny bit of fun at that. But but mostly,
they're just the danger here. Yeah. He absolutely has no idea that there could be any danger until
his hat gets
smeared to a tree.
Right. And and to be fair, you know,
contacted tribes in this area, can be very dangerous to outsiders. And I would be to
rightfully be left alone. It it is kinda cool the moment that they capture Gladstone
as he holds out his hands
and they spear through his sleeves
as a way of kind of carrying him
by by two two of the locals. But, again, they're just a threat And now Gladstone is in danger,
and and the Ducktales have to have this, like, moral
dilemma.
What do you think more about the moral dilemma here? Well, they know the the more the dilemma here mean, they they know that these
indigenous people of that that have captured Gladstone on did not see them. So Donald, Donald is saying well them, we can escape We can get out of here. Go home, let glad,
luck his weight out of this. Well, the nephews
are... No you can't do that. And then the dilemma is we have to say them he's a horrible jam In a way they're telling him he's family. And and that's how I saw it the that first panel of that next page. And most reaction is quite classic. The sticks come he knows that Gladstone still them, but we've got to throw that chance away. And I love find. Probably my favorite line life can be very un kind Yeah. Has five can be very. Un kind. I think be what's the story here.
Right. I thought it was a really good
characterization. That they were like, yeah, We could leave him
because we know he has the luck, but we're gonna take the
compassionate route and go ahead and we'll rescue him. And they. Talk donald into being more compassionate. And They're the same joel on his shoulder.
Right? Right, which he needs all of the time. Right. Because he knows, but he has to have it told.
What do you guys think of their the local city? That's quite beautiful
but... I'd look at it as a a temple as something that was built by the indigenous people
for their home. And there's their social
gathering spot. And it's really nice. Right? Yep panel. Yeah. It it looks I mean, it has the mark of a great civilization, not quote savages.
Yeah. The way Barks is, like, showing it here, it's very permanent.
It looks like great a great empire life the Al it doesn't... To me, it doesn't really evo Al tech, but but like, it it's very permanent. It doesn't look specifically my end or ast tech or anything
that we're
familiar with. But it does
evo their, you know, create stone buildings that are... Obviously, they're still there that right that have stood the test of time because they were so permanent Right. Yeah and it's got this mix of, like, permanent stone, temple, like buildings as you say warren and then like, batch hut.
It looks cool. It's it's nice art. So you guys this next sequence,
I don't wanna delve too much into it. But the this this is basically the classic,
like,
trope.
Of
a group of European
land in an indigenous
society and they're mistaken
Al got.
Right? This is apparently a big part of what led to to ruin in the Caribbean
for the Barks when Columbus sara arrived they're genuinely
have been myths like this. And time miss and stuff that that
invaders have taken advantage of and and here
the Ducktales, the the big secret of,
the big reveal
Warren you wanna tell us about their their statue.
Yes. As they peer over the wall and they see guards with spears,
it's
it's certainly
apparent to the Nephew and donald that it's gonna take something to get their cousin out of trouble. They see this quite striking statue with a...
I'm gonna call it kind of a helicopter
haircut.
Kind of kind of a helicopter blade with like wings
wings or something above above this very
almost grow and scary kind of face. Which immediately,
they say it looks like a helicopter. I saw that right away
so they could reinforce that
is this this cross wings on his head are the sort of the...
What they see it, then, of course, it's in the wood check manual there as well. They Right. The the picture writing says that he is
brew
their spirit of deeds,
He flew down with those strange wings long ago and captured two, their god of good.
So now we've got a little backstory
about brew into
and they kind of on on on unravel from there. It kind of reveals itself. Right. So Sarah, this was your first time reading this. Did you pretty much Did this kinda clue you in for the rest of the story once you saw
the helicopter looking statue, and then we're gonna we're gonna see that the other good God or Spirit it's variable
is it to the God of Good eating who looks like Donald
didn't think he looked like Donald. I went straight,
assuming that Gladstone
good luck made it so that the god looked like him. It didn't occur to me that they would try to send Donald in first. Right. But that that that seems reasonable to me. But... But you've you got the scope of the story here that this is why we understand them to, like, freak out when they see helicopters.
Not that you guys see the multiple blades, I guess, on Al helicopter when it's in motion. To me it looks like
Venus store. Like, it looked like he had some kind of a plant growing out of his head and I have to read the words. To understand what was going on, but then, then I understood. Okay. So so you guys, they do the predictable thing. Here. They're they're going to their big plan is to disguise Donald as the God of eating.
The kids have him memorized
warren
some of the the character work here, you're right. I'm noticing as I look at, like, the nephews here. It is not his best r.
As they're explaining the plan.
I even wonder almost if it was retry, Jeez. Awesome hey, it's hard to say, but I I I I... Yeah. You've kind of echoed what I said earlier about the drawing looks looks a little bit more, like, dial it in phone in.
But yeah. Or so who knows. So their plan is to...
Is for Donald to walk in out ten
memorized words
I'll I'll say the words. Go guys. This is this is, like, this is... I'm annoyed even the say the words. This is the savage trope, right? Where we just make up language. And and this has been done by thousands of artists and riders over the years. So donald supposed to say arm two sc stew, which means roll out.
Roll out red carpet, two back in town, and gl gl means I'll explain later and then
k clock bus could do.
Means release prisoner,
him good gander from Mel egg.
Sarah, what do you what do you think about this stuff translating
to bad
dramatically bad English. Does that does that bother you a little? I it is in my notes that They they... They had... But even when they were like, speaking English for our benefit, it was some kind of offensive pigeon in English. Right. As if
They can't just like beak words,
Right, which is what languages are. If you translate, if you translate something into English, you are not supposed to like give it a a savage pigeon
overlay. And and I know I understand this is the trope where this describing them as savages is the whole time, it's what he's looking for. But
it hasn't aged well to yeah to to be generous.
I will say this. I agree with hug you, but I have to say that Al clock boost could do the what it means had me roaring laughing. I was laughing because kim good gander from Mel egg. I just... I don't know where he got that. Even if he said he is a good gander from a mel egg, that is reaching far into where he came. I just... I I I roar. I just... That's funny. I did... I agree with what the sentiment yeah But it was silly. It's it is kind of, like funny. Why would he why would they be saying mel?
Exactly? Or can...
Yeah. There's no gander in Central America as far as I know, maybe there... Right. Right. And and then why would you translate an idiom, like, roll out the rad car? Right. Right. So it it's It's just it's kind of la
silly.
Least
it. That but is silly. I won't read too much into it. And so initially, this big
does work but
the natives are a little bit smarter than that. The the locals are a little bit smarter than that. They
to verify
that he is the real
I saw someone commented
online that it looks like the words spirit had been kind of
replaced there. That it's probably god. You know, when the nephews are looking in through that brush.
But they're probably both referred to as gods. Anyway, to what what do they wanna do, Sarah to prove that it's really him?
They want him to try on a gold crown. That is taken from the statue. Yeah. It's the old Cinderella bed. Right?
Sure. So that's
So it doesn't work. They they clock donald as the imp.
And the nephews
come up with a really hasty plan here Warren you wanna tell us about it. Hasty and very clever. So They reach for some
a Al slingshot and a good hard stone, the panel reveals that
this note wrapped around as Gladstone has hit Gladstone stone in the back of the head well. He's kind horribly chain
by the neck to a pole. Right And then, of course, he's reading it and
mum these words, and then he just ends up and does mum the statement
choose clumps too and it worked. So I'll go ahead and kind of
Yeah. Now it's now it's glad stones turn to try the ru.
And we get... We get a fun little, I guess this little perspective switch to the nephews
is kinda cute. Right? We see through their eyes. They're very suspense
if it's gonna work
One of them is covering their eyes afraid to look. The other reassure reassured them. And indeed, the crown fits
the locals are celebrating that he is the real chew
and the Nephews
craft
look and say, hopefully, he remembers the rest of the instructions.
Sarah, do you wanna tell us about the next part of the instructions?
Gladstone says look
scrub off thumb, and then he has a little thought bubble that it's very handy for us readers.
That says the kid's note said that that means
everybody go into the jungle fetch game for big fees
Right. And so that does it The Ducktales.
The docs plus gander are able to
escape. And
they're kind of, like, as they walk back towards the coast or wherever, Donald is venting about how
great Now Glad stone has half of our reward money and that that crown, which is gonna be really valuable.
Of course,
large
steel, the breakfast they've stolen and that that price was start to fit.
And then... But but we do get... We do get so warren, we've noted that sometimes the duct come out ahead, sometimes glad stone comes out ahead on these stories.
Tell us about the outcome with this one. Well, glad still didn't quite come out ahead although he used his head
he had to give back the reward money to pay for our our tip that saved his scalp and then explained to donald that the crown only fit because when they use the slingshot with the rack, it took good aim, so that would create kind of this big nut in the back of his head, that would be the only reason this crown stayed on. And look, what he says, the goose egg is starting to un swell at last and of, of course, the last panel. Go ahead.
Right. Yeah. It's it's it's a clever bit. Do bit. Yeah. It's a it's a funny bit. Yeah. So Glad stone gonna have to, like, pay someone now to remove the crown.
And and they're all gonna break even, I guess.
It's a lot of trouble to have gone through for all banking even. Yeah.
That's it. So, yeah, you guys... That is the secret of Honda
We... None of us were very kind to it. But maybe we can each say something that we did enjoy. About this story.
Warren, do you wanna go first? What what was your favorite aspect of it? Well, I I think I some of the Carl Barks is invent,
the Barks tables in the middle of the story.
Just added to the whole tracking through the jungle.
And the artwork work in the jungle, the background artwork some of the splash panels were pretty memorable.
And and again, the nephews
kinda came through and save the day. It's it's something he likes to repeat. But I think as a story,
I will say what I said earlier, the the first half goes very slow for me just as a story and and not even factoring in some of the language choices and some of the depiction that we talked about. It just really felt that he was trying to put into a twenty four page story. That's me. And then Al the the the last part became more of a comedy
and
it kinda picked up the pace a little bit
in the last month five or six pages actually
we're a little bit more entertaining that terrific, but but a little bit more entertaining. So... And I love travel stories that take the Inducks out of America and bring them to foreign countries. This one just didn't have the charm and the romance of some of the others. Yeah. Alright. That's fair. It's it's a re tread in a lot of ways. He's you know, I'm I'm kind of collecting on the Barks remarks
map where the docs have been. And if you look at it, they've they've kind of been to the area Al lot. So I don't know that he's really bringing much new to the table on. Right. But what not use sarah, your overall thoughts, and if you can start If if you can start with something nice. I like the jaguar.
I love cats. I love big cats,
And so, of course, I was like, okay.
When they were going through the series
with encountering all of the crocodile dials and our materials and jaguar and junk. Sure. My overall thoughts are
that it it didn't age well. I... I mean, not a lot of them do.
Some of them are spectacular, but so many are not
in that respect. And it didn't... Like you were saying, it didn't even have, like, a good story to to redeem it in some other way. I tend to dislike Donald Jealousy
and, like, kind of dis emotional maturity. Anyway... I know you know you hate it when people just don't talk to each other. Too. Right. And I... And I don't I don't understand
look. I don't understand Glad stone and his self awareness about the luck.
I would just be like, I would find it more believable if he didn't had any have any idea about the left because right that kind of an x journal
assessment,
cube, he doesn't know any different because he's never not been like this. So why does he call it let Why doesn't he just say like, oh, why don't you guys have this? So, like, Gladstone,
Hai doesn't make sense to me? That either? I mean, he he he'll make more sense to you, I think, if you if you think of him as
exclusively
foil for Dawn. Right Right. He has only meant to H Donald
insecurities about himself. But I hate donald his security.
Sure. I I get it.
Yeah. So that's the...
And and remember too that bark
himself. Kate flat stuff. Right? Like, this is his own creation. He did not... He he... With Scrooge, he saw a lot to redeem.
In Scrooge and he developed him into a a more fully fleshed out character
still has his problematic elements, but there's a lot to like about him. Barks
has never like been like, oh, let me give Gladstone his wine and give him these these elements no. He's just Huey,
just exists to be an an ear attendant for non. Saying that though Mark, I will say there was an element I said it earlier about Gladstone in the story. There was a little bit more of a character study than in the past. There was this moment...
Several pages actually were glad still Glad luck didn't reveal itself. And what it did it revealed it in the big way. But when Don pedro and his his is gathering was keeping him captive, this sort of accidental
kidnapping. Right. I I I felt that we we looked a little bit more into a little bit more into
where
glad is a character
maybe struggles with where the next lucky break will come. And there was just a little bit more of that humanity... And then maybe that's too strong of a word. But so I thought that maybe
Carl was giving
Glad a bit more of the stage in the story
I mean we see a lot more of his, like, interior
monologue
than we usually do. For Sure. I I do feel like it is it is Gladstone at his most glad stone in this story. My my...
I guess, what is this? It's like the rose and Thorn thing Right? My my rose for this story is that I do love the store table bit. And I like a lot of the version through the jungle. I I don't think it's like an outright bad story. It's just so bland. In a lot of ways and and uni inspiring, that, like, there are there are Barks stories that are technically maybe bigger mis hires
or failures
that I I actually like better even if they're not technically as good of a story. This one is just really pedestrian really boring in some regards.
Boring is too too harsh. It's it's just it's not Al it's siding. It's not as engaging as a lot of recent
stories that I've been covering. You know?
I was just gonna say it makes you wonder how excited by Scott about the assignment or about this particular story. And maybe that's why It's on the editors desk for a month, you know could be yeah. It just... It feels a little bit. It feels a little bit half hard. Yeah. So when when we look, this is gonna be an interesting one. Right? Because we all feel pretty harsh about this one. So how about the community?
If we check in with Inducks,
you will find that the canadian she likes this pretty well. You know, it's not it's not a favorite of theirs. But
when you look at the voting Inducks, as of today it as a seven point six.
Which is good for number one hundred and ninety eight of all the forty three some thousand stories on Inducks
because I am such an excessive, you know, I I kinda broke out the adventure stories into their tiers
into different, like, groups and if you look at this one it lands in the tier of stories that I described as, like typical Barks, right, the average Barks story. And And within that group, it's in the upper half of the average Barks story. So roughly in the fiftieth
percentile
of of Barks,
specific stories, which I think is very very generous
for this one. I I'm trying to remember
stories that I've enjoyed less than this one that I've covered so far on the podcast, and I think the only ones that come to mind would be like,
volcano Valley. And...
That one though, I kind of loved to hate. Sure. So it had... It it just had him acting
so terribly, I found it hilarious.
Mh. So it had that going for it. This one I didn't hate that much. Right. It it was
I really dislike Volcano Valley. It's one of my least favorite Barks stories,
but it's definitely more interest then this one. And then like, too many pets, but that's not really fair because that's barely even Barks. He, you know, he finished that assignment
maybe, oh, I guess in darkest Africa.
That one was... Or that was similarly a bit fun fire. I think I even liked land of the tote pulls better than this one. I was gonna bring that one up. I think land the tote poles
parallel this a little bit. Yeah. I found it more interesting
than Right. Story. And I'm I'm Al little surprised by the community rating on as well. And not just because of the story, and I'll say it again. I think the artwork... I I think Barks is entering the last ten years of his career with the comics and and I just don't think he's in there... With the exception of a few of the stories that are coming up, I just don't think Huey, as as inspired as he was during we called that golden era. Yeah. Warren, you and I had... We've gotten beyond with Patrick Block before. One of the great Inducks artists, which has been awesome. Yeah I he... I can't remember when, but he's talked at length about, like, Barks. Had some point here Barks
switch to the type of paper
or the type of pencil he used.
Does that sound familiar? I don't remember him saying that that might the part of the reason, but he I wonder if it was Henri who... I... I've got... I've been, like, really fortunate to get to talk to a number of the Artist. I a couple of them
have mentioned to me it might have been
Someone had educated me about, like, one of the the ways that he switched using
to a different pencil for a while, and that impacted his art for a span of time. Yeah. Forgive me previous gas for
for forgetting who told me that. But... But that's it's neat to see maybe this is part of that So anyway,
One, I'm not aware of any,
like, sql
or
oil painting things lit those that you did for this one. No Barks paintings on this one. I've.
You've already mentioned the the the Rosa cover. Yeah. It's the cool one. And he did that But other than that, there early hasn't been much more. And I I didn't... I didn't check to see if there was a duck
adaptation. I don't remember this whenever occurring.
Ever carrying in any episode of got. I don't think this one really
had much of a, you know, after Al life or impact.
Do you guys have any favorite panels that we should mention that we didn't get to? Sarah, you don't. I I do like I do like when the Gladstone gets carried away by those spears even though it's a a an uncomfortable moment
and and I always appreciate that store table moment where they're surrounded by the crocodile dials from that
perspective kind of looking up. I think the bridge with the donkey with the Bee behind on the tail was memorable. And there's that one panel that we're
Gladstone
discovers the
the prize. And Oh, yeah. He's kinda.
He says his line in beam actually has little shades of what I would call the classic forty nine nineteen fifty glad stone with the longer beak. Other than that, glad Stones
characterization is is to me pretty bland. Yeah. Those are some good panels. Excellent.
Any closing thoughts sarah? No. And connected it all my notes. Yeah. I'm good. I think I got to say what I wanted to say. How about you were? No. Thanks for revisiting the story with us, and I think it's great that we all see the flaws I think that just shows in any artist doesn't have his his best day all the time. And and now I don't know how Barks felt about it. No. Nothing else to say other than I look forward to the next time we all gather. Right. For sure. And and if you listen
if you do feel strongly about this one feel free to reach out and and yell at me.
Yell Al us and let us know why. Differences of opinion are are totally fine. You can reach out We are... We have a presence on the socials, Barks remarks is on Facebook and
Instagram. And
So you guys for... I I always mention what we're coming out with next. This is a little bit of a tricky one because I I don't usually say what's coming next for the ten page podcast.
I usually stick with the adventure stories, but this is kind of a weird one because the next
episode we do is pretty special. I'm gonna be covering the riddle of the red hat
Oh is is famously
Carl Barks is only Mickey mouse story. Well, that will be good. Yeah. And we're doing that in time for
Nikki birthday on November eighteenth.
Yeah timing it for that.
And then I've I've got a
episode coming out for Thanksgiving with a couple of things thanksgiving stories.
Soon and so the next proper duck adventure story that we're gonna be doing is is gonna be a real doo.
It is going to be the land beneath the ground.
Which I'm very excited to cover Sarah, you might know that one It's from the duck openings sequence when he's in the Mine going beneath the ground. Does that sound familiar? They meet the the the weird little characters
that create earth earthquake.
Oh
as I always wanted to meet them.
It is an exciting one. Especially as a somebody who went to school for radiology. Those features have been very interesting to me. They would be. Alright. Sarah, do you mind
reading the the last panel to close us out? And by the time he's paid somebody to cut that jagged thing off his neck, we'll all just about break even on this trip Awesome.
Thank you guys. You you have been good gander from mel eggs, and I appreciate.
God.