Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Ducktales and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comics of all time. Join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical contacts and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks. Welcome back to Barks remarks. I'm Mark Sever at grown man who loves dot comics, and I have such a full house today. I am so excited about this episode you guys. I have...
It feels like I have half of the Disney Dutch comics.
Community here.
Because I Al joined today by three great Dutch artist.
Who who have all worked in Disney comics
and and we were here. This is really fitting because we're gonna be talking about a very ledge and dairy Carl Barks Story. We get to cover the land beneath the ground. And and you guys... This one is this one is really special to me. I imagine it's special to a lot of people. But before we get into it, we got we got a few introductions to go through. So I'm gonna go out alphabetically, but I'll mention I am joined today by Tim Barks, Henri, Hood house and Al Hem.
So let's see. Why don't you guys tell me? Tell me a little bit about yourself as as a fan and comic book contributor. And
and And tell me either tell me if you have ever been on an earthquake or whether you would be a terry or a firm.
How how about you tim? Well, my name is did my
disney need doug artist, and I grew up with the with bark stories and also mouse
stories. So
Hang marcel that is. So I've been a fan on my life. Don't think I've ever been in an earthquake meeting.
But I did wake up once when there was suddenly a crack in our ceiling. So there might have been one. And I'd probably be a terry because sometimes I do wear both ties.
Excellent.
Alright. How about you same question, Henri?
Right. Right. Introducing my, please.
Challenge I'm also... A disney artist. Also draw bunch our stuff in called So been Disney comic and pretty much my whole life. I mean, probably since page four or something. Group Barks and also my.
Making him feel old for happening.
I have been in earthquake once, and we didn't realize until the next day or something because I was actually in in Japan standing in the waiting line for splash mountain and business.
In turkey care this and the whole floor was sway really slowly and the lamb moving, and we were noticing it. I wonder if that's the construction of the building or and nobody was responding to whatsoever because jeff before so used to it. And on the way home, the metro,
said that it was cancelled to earthquake. And we still can't and realize it. Then the next day people oh, did you you know
that's hilarious. How about it? Which which... Which which ball person would you be? I would say for least, I'm not mixing them up that is
because
a little better I'm just rolling Al along not being strong, I guess.
So the fermi are the the press. And the carries are the rollers. Oh. So we have two
ruined my reputation as support team.
Okay. Excuse me that I normally
the but exactly. And they... And they have a a pretty goofy fun name and Dutch. We'll get to that.
And and then M High,
It's such a pleasure to have you on. I I am I am so excited to get to have a a Disney master
join the show because you you are a legendary Dutch artist, and and and you are my first guess that has one of the fan graphics
Disney masters
stories release.
So, you know, I'm sure that I'm sure that Dutch listeners
have a lot of your work. But if if Americans wanna pick up your work in addition to many of the issues, the Barks issues that you've been published and you you have this great fan graphics volume called
scandal on the App
Express. So forgive me for for rambling on tech can you tell us about your involvement with the comics and growing up as a Barks fan? If you if you've been into bark for a long time, Yes. Actually, I
I got to know Barks when I was six and I was completely
mesmerizing by the story
that there is if I start
talking about this subject because it's it's... It is so
imprinted in my
memories as a child, and it also... It was a hard time for me as a child child and and the the world of callbacks Barks was really
something I could step into and I I I I really thought Duck Bergen and every person there was real actually, and was dreaming about this. I was sure that this really existed. And,
yeah, Well, it's a long story. I
rediscovered it
way later and I I started
reading
everything
all the Barks
stories and it was... Yeah. I I just want it to be a comic artist.
And... Yeah. That's that's the thing.
That's that's what happened. I looked myself up for a year in my house in my apartment and I
because I I didn't
draw that much
in my younger years, and then I just practiced
practice prices
over and over.
Again, hands feeds,
beak, all all these things. And after a year, I send something to the dot magazine and they were... Yeah. They liked it and they wanted to... Let me try stuff. So I did. And then I remember the moment that I that I was rolling back from
the the the building where where they... Where I was sort of accepted as a as an artist. And rolling back to the station on my roller blades, and I was just lying. So... Yeah. And there Al start and I. So still... I'm very passionate about Barks and the whole universe Barks. That's wonderful. And it must have been such a thrill to get to following Barks foot footsteps And and it's very apparent, right? Looking at your art that you are very inspired by the duct man. Seems like you and the other dutch artist really have, like, model what you do on a very specific era of of Barks
work. Right? Because you guys tends to like the stuff in the late kind of the late forties. Right? Is would... Is that what you would say? Yes. Maybe in terms of Barks style. But the
are a much broader part of course. Yeah. Mh. Right. The stories tend to be a little more contemporary temporary. Right? And and Bark did that. He he was riding modern stuff at the time. And you... I wouldn't say you guys have like hospitalized writing in that error or anything. Because a lot of them have very modern touch.
But it it's it's very clear to see the the inspiration that you've taken from Barks
and and have some great work of your own. So I'm just I'm delighted to get to talk to you. I'm I'm delighted to hear all of your perspectives on the art and the writing and this great story. Oh, really quickly, now, how about you would... Have you... Do you have any earthquake experience?
Yeah?
No. Absolutely
not. Another guy. No. I've never been aware of
earthquake happening. I know that's
want to place somewhere in the netherlands in So nineteenth. Yeah. I really.
And myself.
Yeah. Well, I didn't notice it and... Yeah. I think... Yeah. It's I would also I would love to roll roll around and, you know, launch myself from a hillside. So Yes. I would go for for that one. Alright. So far or three for three. And and I've I've gotta say, I think I'm gonna make it unanimous. Right? Because it's just
so much more
imaginative.
It's so much more appealing even though these guys are technically slamming themselves into these fillers and it looks pretty painful whereas the fermi are pushing, It's just not as it's not as iconic it.
One is more useful than the.
So very briefly I could go on for a long time, but I I grew up in California. I grew up in the San Francisco Bay Area, so I've been in many many quick.
Including a pretty famous one Loma Pre one in nineteen eighty nine that that made made some international news And, you know, it's just part of our like,
education is learning how to how having earthquake drills constantly. So like, earthquakes were always in the background when I grew up and so this story seemed like such a natural thing to me to think about
to speculate on the cause of earthquakes. And
yeah curious about you guys because we Al at this story when we were very young and in my case. I don't remember something like that, but often you will read something in the economic and then think the world works like that because she just didn't... Actually learn about the real version or do you recall, like, how you thought or earthquakes were made or how if Barks? Well, I read the story points. Late.
And I think I already
knew what was happening in a real earthquakes, Not not really
thinking that it was of these guys. Not little men not right.
It's it's a great question though, En Because
kids Barks so, you know, that's that's the way that kids are. I know for my part, we got so much education we learned about earthquakes.
So much that, like, even even when I read this, I think I would been
seven or eight I'm thinking. I knew. Oh, that's not right? It's caused by fault lines and so on and so forth. I knew a lot about the science of it just because they hardest. What about Ut tim and Henri? I think I might have been Al gullible as the thing this was really.
Had been big imagination. Is a.
Yeah.
This was probably more plausible to me because I could see it. They tried because of the drawings. But that's the thing. The eggs in this one are spectacular, and Barb does such an amazing bit of world building that it just it feels so plausible. Just feels right. Yeah. I you enrique. It's
every other the story that he really manages to bring something completely
insane
it's unbelievable. You just buy it and also all the studio scientific
stuff he explains. Yeah. Yeah. With me... Now I... So I don't don't remember when I learned that stuff, but I always love outside of Comme. I didn't really like reading fiction and love reading non fiction books just learning about everything. So I also don't really remember them, and I didn't really know kind of about some earthquakes work. But yeah, upgrades, we're not a thing we deal with here really. Right. But but this is actually a really good tradition, you know, bark like concept here of creatures
underneath the ground. There's a long tradition of this in human history of different
cultures having this kind of like myth. I read a little article that said,
it started out. Would you believe that giant snakes Ducktales, catfish fish, or spiders? Live underneath the ground, and it is their movements that create birth earthquakes. Maybe you wouldn't, but your ancestors did. So usually, there was this idea that there was something alive and large and restless down there. That might be causing beads. It's just such an animating concept.
But honestly, the real
explanation is also pretty wild.
Yeah. It's pretty crazy too that the whole
stuff.
Yeah. Yeah. Absolutely.
Guys. Why don't I count talk a little bit about the background of the the story and its publications so that we can get into the real meat the content of it pretty quickly.
Land beneath the ground was first publish in the the cover date was January of nineteen fifty six, and it was first printed uncle Scrooge number third team. This one has had a lot of printing.
It's worth saying that you guys this is a super famous Coral Barks story. This is arguably
one of his most famous ones. It's gotta be up there in the top five or so. Even if it's not like his highest rated story. It has such a big and invent concept,
you know, that that saw some wide release and the Ducktales up. So that, like, if you've heard about Carl Barks. Chances are really good you know about this story. As I've been doing the podcast and I have people sometimes
message me about maybe being interested in joining it. This is the story that by far the most people have been interested in joining me to host. Like this, this is a this is a fan favorite. As far as the page length, that's where it gets a little bit murky. Right? Because this was had this had a little bit of a weird Genesis, a a little bit of a weird birth to get to publication. I've mentioned this before and it's not... Ultimately that interesting, but there was a period of time where Western Publishing figured out that they could get a better rate, a better mailing rate for subscribers. If they followed this weird post office rule that a a publication had to have two separate characters in it qualify. So Barks was made to, like, cut pages out of stories occasionally so that he could fit a second story usually about chi Gear in it. And as a result, this one started out at thirty two pages but for its first printing, it ended up having twenty seven pages
and then a number of panels and pages ended up being
stored. And so I think the current length is something like twenty nine and a half pages or something like that. I'm I'm not too interested in getting, like, every little detail of that right you guys, but I think the important thing to know is that there's still a little bit of this that's technically missing. Barks made sure to pull out stuff that wouldn't affect the flow of the story too much. Hopefully. I... This is also one of the earliest Barks stories I read.
So I phone memories of it, but one of the pages there was the most iconic to me that I... That stuck out the the most. So I only found out I only found out just yesterday
that the page was missed... That's one of the pages I was missing and Al be early printing. So it's one that Barks actually decided to cut out himself that the it was less
important.
And then there's there's even one panel that he had used Al like a little bridging panel that now gets excluded from the publication because it doesn't really make sense with some of the stored art. Again, we might mention those when we get to it. I'm I'm not there's so much to this story that I I don't wanna dwell on kinda of that little inside based fall behind the scenes stuff. Alright. So I always
enjoy checking in on some of the international
story Ducktales, you know, because these are so popular
around the world. Here we are in the states and in Netherlands talking about it. So So we're... I think we should each take on and everyone who's willing should mention one of the titles from around the world. So I can't resist this to you guys. I've got I've got three people, three dutch artist from Netherlands here. I should be the one to do the dutch title because that's funny to me. You you guys are gonna either
praise me or or laugh
lia Al me.
I am gonna say this is
Ti land under the Ar. The land under the earth. Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. It's not too bad. It sounded like something from.
Okay. Yeah. So let's let's hear from You now. You're gonna... You're gonna give us French.
Let me the by boom. I'm might translate to. It's it's sort of a...
How do you say on automatically pay?
It's... Yeah. So it is the cracks the do bada boom. Did produce that sounds by. I'm actually curious and is what the actual characters are called. So that is the character names. In French
clock bada boom.
Yeah. So they just named after the the something makes It is.
I... I think that's the only
one that uses the name of the terry and the Fermi. In the title
which got me curious about the terry and the fermi in in other languages. But but go ahead, Henri, what... Which one do you wanna do?
Let me see. Finish.
Yeah.
See oh. I'm sorry. My friends from finland.
My or something like got which I have absolutely know. I
speak because spinach and
yeah I think that you guys... Most of the titles are a pretty direct translation of something like the land, the ground. And and that one that you just read Henri is the underground world. How about you tim, you wanna do one?
I actually really like Brazil if you're down for that.
Can you guess what that translates to? The makers of
Earthquakes. Yeah. The makers are the manufacturers. Yeah. Yeah. So that that's a lot of fun.
They're mostly straightforward, but but always interesting. Yeah. I've got I've got some other trivia and stuff you guys, but... But I can kind of integrate it as we do the story itself. You guys ready to plow into this? Yeah. Mh. Alright. So again
right. Oh, real really quickly. I should mention that the name of the creatures that the dutch are gonna encounter this.
It's a really fun ton. On on a latin term. The term Terra firm is like solid ground. So that's why these these characters are called the Terry and The fermi.
And I did look it up to see in other languages, but just in the interest of time, I'll bypass that. So boy, right away, this first page, you guys, the land beneath the ground, it is a stun of of an introductory paid. There is nothing
that
significant or that stands out too much on the opening page, but it does such a
spectacular job of setting up this story and intriguing the reader and really signaling what uncle Scrooge is about and what motivates him. Barb opens it up with the great narrator box that says Uncle screws just rock Al high above the clouds and dive deep beneath the seas, but never as he had a stranger adventure than that, which is about to default him, deep within the earth it cell and we encounter Scrooge basically in full bore worry mode. He's reading the paper about terrible,
quick thinking about other recent earthquakes, we see him pacing in his weary room, and and he is worried about the predictable thing that a quick might strike here Inducks
and destroy his money then. And boy you guys... It it is great.
It is fantastic how the reader is being drawn into this story. It's got this
beautiful.
He's using black has a sort of threatening
force
that... Well, it already Inducks
introduces you into his his dark
fears and it's so beautiful. It's... I think it's the most outstanding panel in the whole story actually.
So you mean that fourth panel
Or you have that one as well. But it this first stage and already in the opening
splash
yeah. That's a great point. There's all this, like, menace. Looming over this representing screws is worried, and you're right, that that's splash panel, it's hard to argue with. What do you guys think? I also really liked the little boat. I have the third book for the left. I mean, it never stood out to me before, but it's like
one of the
areas of for me
Yeah It is. You guys I think it's a little... I think it represents like a it's it's a little morning.
Like Al boy morning.
Right. Like it it it's it represents him morning for the oil wells that have gone to put
nice. Those ledger, but it does have that dual purpose of made sensing at the bow tide,
and then it also
serves the additional purpose of evo, you know, drilling
beneath the ground before we even know about. I I love... I mean, the the second panel course it Al concept at the february worry room areas but I in the fourth panel to how the the... There's this looming black sky
over the Money, but also the hands off sign being bigger than the actual title of the building is city funny. It is really funny. And the worry room always cracks me up and his little line in there only last week a quick in bo swallow to Castor oil factories.
That's how hilarious. And and you guys the fortune that he is
describing. This is one of the running gag, right, where he's always gonna
label his fortune as a different value in my head growing up as a kid. This was the like official number of of his fortune for me. And I memorized this the kid So can you say memory?
I I can't anymore. No. But I'm gonna read it all out loud because this number makes me so happy.
He says five billion Qui
Up
and passive
fantastic trillion dollars is worth trying to say. So great. So
The next sequence is basically about Scrooge heading to
commission scientists.
To see what can be done to protect his fortune and when he encounters Donald on the way,
Donald points out that they can only make educated guesses so he suggests what screws is ultimately gonna do, which is to dig this spiraling tunnel beneath has been to inspect for worrying
weaknesses.
Yeah something I I left which accepts stalls very une uneducated
opinion in here. This is like
dog comes to perform with an Id idea and all screws says okay. Yeah. I just buys it's from a nephew for some reason, but one the coincidence steps that donald is walking there.
Yeah just buy it and
drives it. And we get the first... We get a mention of a crack which is gonna be a word that haunt Scrooge later on. So the next sequence, you know, it sees Scrooge
play out that plan. We this really cool cross section panel of
ex waiters digging that tunnel beneath his been. And and even though it's just like
laborers,
Barks makes it a pretty exciting sequence. We see the form and weeks later we see the form and say we're two miles down mister Mc and have found nothing, but solid rock and, you know, Scrooge won't be stopped. He tells him to keep digging. And they get four miles down and still no sign of a fisher or hollow. And Tim, do you wanna tell us about what happens
eventually.
Suddenly one day
the men are all leaving the chef was wild. It's hurry. And
they come out in the fried because they hold through the top of a mammoth hole and they heard voices. A great moment. Right? Like this feels before you know what about rest of the story this feels so eerie. I'd I just love it. It sets... It sets this up so well, and then they referenced that hold that my be as big as the inside of the whole world. Yeah. We're is feels skeptical.
Yeah. Scrooge is always
skeptical. But but because these experts have been scared off, you know, the Inducks are gonna have to mount Al Expedition
using a min. This is a great... This is gonna be a great Mine sequence. And
so the Ducktales get all packed up and and prepped to go down there and donald comments that they've got everything but Al observer. And asks, who's gonna go down for you? And we get this funny little
exchange. Do you wanna tell us about it Henri about how he him into it? Yeah. He's here here Al I owe you for fifty cents that borrowed in nineteen fifty, and it down interested now amounts to five hundred. So if I'm not wrong, he he through this story in nineteen fifty ninety six five, I think so that's a pretty bad
yeah. And and this hasn't been too long again since there is a similar concept in secret of Atlanta. So I just like to imagine Screws with this, like, file full of Donald Io used to to cash. Also would be better borrowing
anywhere else from
anyone out.
So, you know, Donald is rope into it.
I think this is one of those sequences that Barb had cut out for pacing because he thought it It not too important.
And and he's gonna go down with sc. And as they get ready to go down, the Ducktales start to notice something odd around the excavation side. You wanna tell us about what they notice, now? Yeah. This...
Yeah. What is this? Rocks or weird bowls of we don't know why it is exactly, but they they... Especially with the the coloring, they
looks somewhat shiny
and
colorful flow as well by the way. But,
obviously,
Scrooge is not
impressed. He says, I guess it's not important.
I didn't see them, but Barks.
Thing last one.
Right.
And and you guys this is one of the weird things about the story. Right? The rocks are always the quote rocks are always colored.
So colorful. And there's there definitely exists colorful rocks in nature. But they they really stand out. So this is a little bit of that comic book logic that I think we have to get past. Yeah. I was actually curious about but the caller speak because. I was wondering if
Barks would have called them if they would be just gray. Mh. But I doing some faint studies, and he also make be colorful so... Yeah. I wondered I wondered about that myself.
About what he might have, you know, originally intended.
I think there's one
sketch he did that does have a colorful terry or firm if I remember right? So and he has a drawing that has a colorful one, but I don't I think he did it a lot later. So I don't know if he just accepted that, you know, the colors But I wish I could've have... I wish I could have read his mind and, you know,
confirmed whether he intended them to be all like gray and brown. And and when I grew up with one of the... And in the dutch one, I grew up with they were either purplish or orange, but it was also only the thirties... The there were one color and the furnace for.
Interesting.
I mean, I think I think it's a big part of the appeal of this story. Frankly.
They just... They look so interesting. But it is definitely silly that the duct don't inspect these a little bit closer.
Because
all all of a sudden,
the my cart is going to wrench loose from the cable and Scrooge Donald gonna roll down that shaft
that, you know, four mile deep, not long but deep shaft.
Because someone has pulled the cable pin. So this is pretty dramatic, pretty serious, and the kids have to also out
an expedition now to rest to them, and they set they set it for automatic release and the same thing happens to them. Some joker has pulled the same cable pen trip on the nephews as well. Yeah. Well, it's weird that they're they're talking about the joker because I was reading the dutch
translation, and they... There is was also some help lag or pricing.
But it's so weird because a joker, why would he why would a joker play with the Doctors
lives? Yeah. I don't know.
That was for me to weird moments somehow. Right. Yeah. Yeah. I think it fits with the ominous tone of the story that you are identifying at the beginning. Right? Because it is Like you said, this this likely would kill them. Yeah.
Wonder how long the chef must be incredibly long.
Yeah. Absolutely.
I did look up a little bit about, like, the the longest that people have drilled down into the earth and it is... There there's is a hole that was drilled not for people to, like actually travel down. But the longest, the deepest that people have gone is
a little over twelve kilometers, which is about eight miles.
D... And no one has gone anything closer than that. About two miles is like a a mind
drill that a drilled mine. So anyway, the the next sequence
is basically
the Nephews racing down
out of control, but but Dave thought had. Tim, do you wanna tell us about their preparation?
Well they say...
They're getting speed like a hard and
another one of you said this time to play our little joke. Worst smart, we brought along poles to jam the wheels in case anything went wrong. And they call out to the invisible joker, like, put that in your invisible pipes is focus.
I like it. That's cute. Yeah. So they slow themselves down to the hole that the ex
clearly busted through when they saw this giant cavern.
There's this great ominous
shot where they... I say shot. But a panel where they kinda peer into the darkness and and dope. They're.
It is And what I love about
that
speaking sequences is that the little dogs
well, one of the Ducktales holding
the others
by their tail. Yeah. And it's so sweet. And
I don't know. I I love that little panel. Yeah. Shows that their care for each other and it's it's it's just beautiful. It is. Yeah. It's a nice touch and that there is so sync. Yeah. Yes. And I just love the neck... Panel on the next page. Yeah. Why don't you tell us
Yes. Yeah. Just...
Yeah words really it does so much with Al little one. He really makes years of black and on the next stage the panel see silhouette of the nephews
with some of the camera around and surrounded by some of the light that they still have around, but it's really tiny on the battle. So they're really being swallowed up by black. They're looking... Even though it's a small panel and we're looking into this is black and you already to get the feeling of how massive
and trading the case underneath must.
Isn't that wonderful. What a great piece of perspective. And and we we feel like we're underground for most of the rest of this story it really does feel like that.
So the Nephews, you know, they call out as the first step for their uncles to see if they're all right And and all they here are some,
which at least proves that it's got a bottom sides. Al they go to get some flares in the mining car, they discover that it's being pulled back up the track buy somebody,
those invisible joker,
possibly.
And and, you know, there's no evidence of them of anyone except for more of those goofy round rocks, and just in that moment, the Nephews
here some voices just like the digger her. You know nephews eventually
ne the story for us.
Especially when they're they say garden, how did they get her?
Right. But in a very, like, natural
way. Yeah. How about it now, do you wanna tell us about what happens to the nephews as they're appearing into the cavern? Yes. Well, then you see this beautiful shot of you... These huge Well, these Barks are
in front of us and they're rolling a high speed towards the the small tiny and vulnerable
nephews
and
it's... And then they
sm
because
that's
see written there as me
into the darkness.
And in this darkness day, for the one of the nephews
feel like a Ducktales in a bowling.
Imagine just saying that we're you're bigger one is.
That was scary.
Right.
It's a little silly they're They're na
themselves as they follow along
that they talk about flying through space and then landing on a sla surface and going over
over some slick moss.
You guys it always bothered me in the printing that I have that the Terry and Fermi
that hit them don't match their colors. I always want them to be color coordinated.
Mh. Oh, yeah. I see the in the in the new well which is yours is the old colors in the... We... We're looking at several of economics at the same time as the Right. Graphics one, which is the old colors that think
Does that color match them? Oh, it's a green blue and orange ish, but they do go much shift. Oh, okay. Well, that's good.
Right. So Tim, do you wanna... Do you wanna tell us about what they see as they slide down? To the bottom of this ramp. Yeah. They they see, like the sun of the Matte March hair, and they they they common like it's really scene from us in one wonderland. You see these huge fillers of holding the surface of the earth and this is really awe inspiring world really when she creates there's all these little Barks lying near the three docks. Yeah. And then longer you look the more of them you see Yeah. Everywhere
in the distance, There's this tiny little thoughts and it's yeah. Make it it's it is an amazing panel. This is gotta be one of Barks most iconic panels this first view of what we're gonna learn is Terry Fermi. I I love it. I mean, as a kid, I was just
enchanted
by this. And and so the the docks... The Nephews,
they kinda orient themselves and then they hear their uncles. Their voices coming from beyond a crooked pillar and
Henri, this is this is the scene that you really like. To right where they encounter or tell us about what they encounter. Yeah. Well, I mean...
But I when I was Severino this was like the funniest thing to.
Yeah. So so they're Scrooge and Al there are in a mine
writing in in Al loop loop basically.
And they say stop this loop and create before we get cor. Think it is your nice serious travel. You don't call this serious.
So they say we hit this work or like a run market that been looping at the loop here for forty minutes slowing that sounds pretty terrible.
I figure about new increase. I love that comment of Scrooge this is noon on Thursday.
Why don't she keep telling us about that sequence and how they stop Alright. So at the end of the page, just still going. So the nephews for tell amount and how to break just like david with using a panel of the side of cart however, Al they Scrooge although, something's wrong. I just fall they just fall straight down. It's golden and nephew saying you kidding are your bright Id Okay we know that you would stop the car top of the? It's it's a great such fun lipstick sequence.
Definitely.
Yeah. It's a great comic be And and that was one of the another of the moments that was, like, stripped out. And I I I totally understand why. But it's also the mind code thing such Al almost overview overused stroke, but, of course, one only has to be the first line. Very read about my Barks. Also, probably, I think the year before, I read this I went to
for the first time And lost different amounts and so much when I was six years old, so of course, I right. Yeah. And the mine part
is pretty iconic. I gotta think that some of that must have come from this story. So you guys this next sequence is pretty packed. Right? This is gonna be our introduction to the to the Den of Terry Fermi.
They kind of... They take some time to marvel at this huge tavern. Donald is boggling Al how thick the
the pillars are and screws, you know, comments, they'd better be. They're all that's holding up my money bin.
Donald Ponder that there must be some some kind of creatures living down here. And the Nephews point out that they've heard their voices
but they still think that it's gotta be these invisible people.
As they inspect the land, they they discover more, they see these little hats. These very smooth and worn paths, and they ponder what sort of creatures have made them because they haven't left any kind of a footprint And then we... The reader gets the surprise of... Yes it's not too much of a surprise. Right? Because, like, the... Barks has been signaling. Pretty loudly that these rocks are important
Huey, have favorite
rocks and boat letters about eighty five times
Right.
Right. But it's still... It's such a delight to see it plays Al to see it play out. Because we see these word balloons come from the rocks. Saying, they think we should make tracks we
track
what with? And let's see. Who who have I not
thrown it to in a little while. Tell me about screws and encounter with the firm.
Well, a screws
walks over to the bunch of the the Barks and on the rocks, I should say. And then if you still say, we think it's a invisible man.
Won't find anything. But screws says maybe not, but I'm getting suspicious of these rocks. And this rock is wearing a neck time
this is especially Yes.
Yeah.
Right. He just he rolls it over a little bit and Now we see it all bald up. And and
I I love screws line. You guys as he like wrench cane inside the neck tie tells him get up there and give an account of yourself, you ball up hu
and now, you wanna tell us how the creature greet him? Yes. He says howdy partner. Welcome to Terry for me. And he's very...
Yeah. He's
really inviting screws there. Is...
Yeah. Yeah. These these baldwin up bugs this despite being very secretive.
Once they Al themselves, they're very friendly. We were
there adorable. They have these, like big sn that kind of are like duck bills, but not quite
They have no feet. They're just balls at the bottom they're kinda shaped like a good or a base. And
it's so funny to see them all emerging once once the secret is out. And and when Scrooge asks what sort of creature are you? He says fermi. Shu partner, you sure ain't been around.
So
you guys this really kinda reminds me of, like, playing off.
Right? Where we have this like, secretive race of funny,
not so threatening weird creatures that have their, like, kind of odd lingo and and speak acts scented English. Yeah. And I... By the way, I love the one on the left the squishy the squishy on.
Shows the motion too of I I just kinda like, Oh, yeah. Fully brown software, but is the sender cute. Barks must had a blast drawing these guys. You guys are all artists here. What do you think of the the character design on these these creatures. Yeah they're there... Yeah. They're so nice to to look at and
yeah. Super we're funny and cute.
Super cute. And it's a simple. So you guys, at this point, the story is really picking up and we're starting to learn a lot about terry For. And I'm I'm gonna rattle off a couple of things that way you learn. Right? We... They're they're pretty important. They give a little bit of color to this It's it's always a shame to me that we don't get more because this is such a fascinating little
civilization that Barks creates but but we learned that the Severino extends
all around the world,
we learned that the way Barks app gives us a justification for them
speaking English by saying that they they pick up radio waves
through, like, j germanium or and you place this like cookie little
very funny commercial jingle, which is why they all look talk like, nineteen fifties movie cowboys.
I like to imagine that maybe the ones under Latin America talk like Tele o.
And.
We we eventually
learn, and it's... And it's very funny the moment we learn. We we discover Henri why don't you tell us about what's
what the purpose...
The meaning of life is for being a terry Scrooge
ass?
You know, what do you do? What does your work? Are you minors or farmers or what? We don't work. We just have a game that we played. Every and every thirty to devote his whole life to getting a shape for game. Forget sake what you do in this game? We have to say it altogether, and I guess We may
week what
what a great panel. Is so funny you guys seeing that
see uncle
collapse like that. Go ahead. Keep telling us about the demonstration En Rico. Also these they're pretty perfect.
See, this is how we do. Many millions of us for me squeezed into the karim beneath the press like this, and they... I'll press to together no Barks and place snap ups snap off of giant piece rock. Lift it up like this. It's a very good show for Al says. But I'm afraid Scrooge has missed that. He's painted better way one of my things.
That that... All of the dialogue on the... This couple of pages so snappy And I like... I like the moment
when the nephews talk about how they'll tell grandma all about that place this place when we get home, then they kinda shutter if we get home. Yeah. That only takes a dark turn. Yeah. Yes. Right. And and these the... It's worth saying these guys are not managed thing at all. They're just... They're these weird goof balls. I. But I mean so are another ground their cart is gone.
Do you guys think about the fact that every terri and every fermi spends his whole life? They're they're all male. They're all quoted is a extremely new. Not. Yeah. No really follow. I think if if we would've written the comment nowadays, you would have just used day just similar day because I think they're supposed to be kind of gender. But, I mean, traditionally,
back in the day... I need still two wings. If the default is just meals. I guess supposed to be.
You
you could ask yourself how they reproduce and
yeah. Without any females, we you could. Yeah. We just probably smash their together.
Might. Well that's with a lot of these these economics. Like, that's the thing of Al these characters. So, like, of course, I'm was a little girl reading this, but they're all basically again on this but because the default mail. They're all representatives as me what I think. If I would read write this today, I would just use in English. That's a nice thing. You can just use the word
Right. Which which just covers any any random gender I know and you just say they. When it dutch it we really work. So... Right. I and I think you're right. There is that sort of male default from this sarah, but but these guys are more aggressively male than most of the like creatures because they're wearing like the little sign.
The four in hand versus bow ties is mail a tire.
Yeah. And they're they're all, like this competitive
strength and vi. It is a very male coded thing. I... Yeah. I'm I I I don't even think Barks thought about it. It's just it's basically just the the default especially in the fifties. So meeting it as a kid. I I really didn't think about it. Yeah. Mean, neither.
They just need, like, tender to me. But I mean, you just right mail. But... I mean, I also... I'd also notice it now when I draw a character, I have a character that doesn't look specifically female so people just assume it's the huge mail. But that's just because it's it's you're that's how traditionally the the default is in especially old going so that's how I learned completely because I read this.
So and, you know, Barks sets up this, like, so society pretty pretty well. Like, we we learn a lot about it considering how few pages were actually
down there. But I I like how he teaches us in that demonstration about the fur kinda show off And then in the next sequence, we're gonna also see the terry but varies in a little bit keep it interesting.
He shows us this little, like, school of terry learning about how to how to roll the themselves into the pillars. And I've gotta say are we all in agreement that the way the Terry make their earthquakes by smashing, rolling and then smashing into the pill pillars It's just much much more engaging. Much more interesting. Right? Definitely.
Just don't tell the furnace
Right. It's officially much more impressive fun. Right. Yes. I mean, I like that little
contrast, how there's the two kinds of these goof balls. But... Yeah. So the docs watch a...
They watch this school in action, and they see the the little tiny Terry crying when the news when the news radio
broadcast
talks about Al slight quick. Just jolt a small section
of Duck. No. It's the the normal various and there's for were kicking enough yet. I he gets crying baby.
Oh, yeah. Yeah. It... It's alright. They're adorable. Who wants to talk about the Bow ties and four in enhanced sequence. It's such a... It's such a bonkers
weird
detail and it's so funny. It it's delayed. Hold me. Now, do you wanna tell us? Yeah. What's what shall I say?
It's such a tiny...
Yeah. Difference between the two. It's almost
ridiculous.
So how do your guys know terry from Fermi,
but that's easy?
We terry wear bow ties. And ref where for enhance.
Am I weird for finding this so funny you guys... No. I'm pretty sure. That's normal. Yes
speak concept. And I
gets ridiculous and that's why it's memorable
it is. It's incredibly memorable. I love that this is the important fact that the the kids want to write in for their your wood guide puppy. Yes
So you guys the next sequences where it starts to get serious. Right? The do have had some time to.
We feel like they're just kind of processing their off right now. But the narrator Barks tells us that they're soon gonna find cause for real worry Tim, do you wanna give us kind of an overview about what is this event that's about top Well, which is the
rom in the distance and
Barks remarks but it sounds like a million bowling Barks.
And one of the
and front
says, it is a million Barks. They
they've come rolling from both our corners of the earth to try for the trophy and Scrooge
it turns around the trophy trophy. This this something I should be I should know about. And
well, the trophy is the the symbol of the earthquake championship.
One of the terry says. Come on, will show it to you. And so it's actually this is like this story how they have these these competitions
for earthquake and making earthquakes in in the past. And, yeah, The... They have this trophy for it. And the last time
was a few years ago and they lifted the floor of the wearing c seven feet. I I love how the fermi is bragging about the devastation. Of the earthquake
and Scrooge just just glaring at him never nevermind the gory details.
It cracks me up the way he's like, pointing up and spinning his fermi finger
talking about how it rolled up a tidal wave that flooded half the basement in Pa Pa. I love all these little geographic details that Barks is bringing up throughout the story too. I also like how
screws
in this last panel of the that other page, how he's already sensing
but he's it's about a trophy, but he already senses
that there is something
really wrong about that. Yeah. Got this, you know, our normal
almost
ability to know when there's trouble add.
Good worrying.
Yeah. Yeah. This whole... This whole story is about him worrying and being paranoid, and now he's this detail is, like, flashing to him. Henry Enrique, do you wanna tell us about how they got that that this trophy. Let's see. It tunnel down for a crack that the terry opened up in greece in the years here crazy.
Scrooge once again. Thanks. And something I... What I really like here in the in also in the next few pages, basically, I mean Barks is running a lot of detail, but it's only so much he can do so he really uses the dialogue and and the dialogue Barks too to really give you the the size... An idea of the size So... Because they keep mentioning how millions of them are coming in every few minutes and our millions come from and these wet land and the great hollow of so many soon see for hours and hours. Right.
Yeah
Al feels like faint too now. As an nephew will looks to today annoyed.
Right. Yeah. You're right.
It.
He does a great job of making this feel like really epic.
Feels I mean, we got the world cup just starting as of recording this. It did feels like the world cup plus or or times ten. Yeah. They think we look really closely at the... When all the there firm come in. They speak different languages
done. Right. Right. He uses is kinda little gibberish Scrooge to represent languages from from around the world. I love that it just takes the mention now of a crack for screws to just faint.
Completely.
All love our in the panel august where they're all rolling in that they're... They say they're stacking themselves ninety deep at the double
you could just barely see it under the dialogue box that there's this whole gigantic wall.
Yeah.
Service
way it's colored in some of the comments you can barely see that it's that it's secured. That it's... Yeah. Exactly.
So, you know, and we learn the specifics of this year's event is that they're going to strike at the the giant pillar that is the main support for Duck. Right? So so Scrooge is like utter paranoia
his worry. It is... It has a reason behind it. You know, whether he was justified and having these paranoid fears or not, for the sake of storytelling telling, it
it was meredith. So so at this point in the story, you know, the Inducks really, like, they have to decide what are they gonna do? And Donald is all for getting out of there that they've got to save themselves. You know, so he whispers to the Inducks. And we do have one... I guess it's firm. Right? Because that looks like a four hand.
Fern over here them talking about, you know, getting up to the surface. And warning people to flee. But the firm don't like react the way, you know, we would expect them to because this one is saying that because of the moss slide that the Inducks came down on, it's too slick for them to get back up without any help. So, you know, they've basically got time to bargain with the Inducks for their silence. So it kinda like diffuse is some of the tension of of meeting Barks doesn't need the fermi to be a threat yet. Right? That's pretty important. He needs the dust to kinda be able to have the run of it.
But but it... The threat still kind of lu.
And I like that he's he's thinking about this. He's trying to keep it sensible.
And love little detail on this page where that
the nephew
is whispering and Al us whispering with Scrooge doesn't Barks the whisper, which is why he's being overheard. Right.
Right. And and that's part of why the fermi is not worried because he here Scrooge saying no one would believe us. If we told them about this insurance. Yeah. So so that's always it's interesting with me with Call how some... So I'm saying it's risk whispering what you see is that the speech bubble instead of
having a a a normal line that has a dotted line and somehow you know that it's screen. Yeah. Instantly. It's it's the great comics
toolbox the you guys are... I'm sure all familiar with. Absolutely.
Right.
So Scrooge kinda steps on the Barks a little bit. He's like, no. You know, I've got a better idea. And, of course, he's motivated by wanting to save his money.
He decides that he wants to appeal to their quote,
sporting fancy.
This is a really fun sequence.
You guys it's really funny, but I might... So so basically, in short, the gist of it is that Scrooge convince is donald that he should challenge
the champion
roller to a bumping
contest to to see if they will call off the earthquake.
And we get this great build up where Donald stands across from the champion roller. And
and they goes exactly as well for Donald as you would expect. He gets catapult
as the nephew... As one of the nephews who's mentioned
halfway in China, which is where he has to swim back
from this big lake gru Al the way. Or donald
But you you you you say he's
he's he's convincing donald. But the way he's is convincing Donald is Well, basically struggling.
It's dragging him to the to the guy and forcing
to to do something donald really doesn't feel like Dude really does.
Yeah. It's a very funny. It's james. It's so funny. Seeing donald with the Scrooge cain dang yeah.
No. No. No.
I love the double actually try.
Yeah. I.
I I guess there there is, like, maybe a small moment where you think maybe he's got this because he rolls up and. Been.
Then no. It's it's donald
thing.
And and then as Donald is gru and swimming the whole way back
shares his backup plan, which is to just swipe the con found trophy so they have nothing to
nothing to compete for And I love that one of the nephews is just like I didn't you go with that in the first place instead making him swim halfway back from China.
For donald peppers
be that he came off pretty good my pretty well
considering.
Yeah. Tim, do you wanna tell us about how the Ducktales
launch into this next
attempt to forest Al games.
Well, donald,
again it says,
he wants the appeal is sporting fancy. So
he he begins
challenging one of the
one of the fur. And
I mad at you mouse eating bold bearings. Champion terry just smack me two miles, but the for doesn't lift the can bug me off this rock. And the the the firm is for me, it takes a challenge. And he says, also the firm is our lift there's not sm. But I can roll hard enough to flatten the likes of you. And
as he rolls the towards, Donald, He says, happy landing busted.
But then that that'll just... He jumps up in the nick time and he wins Yeah. I like that sequence a lot. It's neat seeing donald
turned the tables after he's just gotten, you know, smack around I really like is insult as well. The the Moss eating bolt.
Oh, yeah. Yeah. I wonder if that is like, a a real detail or just an insult right? Because we don't learn a lot about these
these creatures. Maybe that's what they need it's not know either.
And this doesn't thought that they couldn't get any more wacky.
Do you wanna tell us about messages.
This this sequence is great. And. You wanna tell us about the tel sequence as as well as that fermi rolls clear over into a third valley Yeah. So donald is only important is successful with Terry for and this way of sending messages
and to defer me,
He says, I've sugar clicks glimpse, those that's were fixing to sweat the trophy. A tell and alarm two to have partners. They
inflate himself
to a giant ball. And the message is have earlier, and the story that they're rubbery also
the seems.
And it just inflate himself and uses cell as a massive
drum.
This is so silly.
It. So was a real specific message It's like... Yeah. Love it just goes like, bamboo boom
a message the Barks. That's it's still the trophy and they're racing bullshit. Yeah. This this part always cracks me up it it's very funny.
It's very silly. If it had come earlier in the story, it might have been too silly. But at this point, we know that these creatures are just profoundly ridiculous. Do you guys remember another an earlier Barks story where he had a character do this? Not to put you guys on the spot, but what this swamp? So? No. Wait. Yep. It's it's mystery of the swamp where the the measles.
Very the.
He he doesn't exactly do the same thing, but but he's like a he's a swell. Right. Right.
Dutch name. So
I think over a lot of these three, I'm I'm now I'm curious that Al have to look up what I.
What is it diesel and and dutch? I?
So this next sequence is basically the pursuit. Sequence. Right? We we get to the part where the Ducktales are at that moss slide area. And
just like you know, just like they figured, the Inducks can't easily
get up this Moss Hill. So this is gonna be one of the big problems that they have to pass near the end.
I guess we get a couple of panels that were cut here. We'll have to opt include these when I shared it on Facebook, but he just excise the a little bit of this
escape sequence out. Yeah. Love how the next sequence...
Because they're being... They're being chased and they have to... The the nephews are gonna look in there in their guide book for a.
So it's both... I love it it's both really tense and really silly. Mh. These These guide book sequences are always so funny to to have Barks like take them through the... Right where where they're like, look in the chapter on vegetable forms No. There'd be an instructions for grasping
slick object objects.
And there's a whole page on catching greased pigs,
but to
Now do you wanna tell us what they
eventually planned on?
Yes. Because then, finally, they they find
under the, yeah. On the title or, yeah, the chapter the desperate
dilemma,
it says when you can't climb over an obstacle go under it And so they decide to do, donald lifts up as part of the moss
slightly
slippery
slow thing. I'll be dug and this moss lifts up like a blanket and the ground beneath is rough revel.
You know.
Like a perfect square it gets listed. Yeah Right. We can crawl up the slide under the mouse, like mole. Come on. And there they go over the most and they managed to... Yeah. To
scroll the
the, yeah, the goof bulls.
Yes. That's a good thing. That is a good name for them.
But Scrooge starts to lag behind You wanna tell us why Henri? Well, he lives find well my mole don't, I high silk cats and he makes the... We we don't know it yet, but the beautiful... Or is it a dreadful mistake is good thing. He throws away is hat down down towards the case.
So you can speed it. Yeah. As a reader, I always
always feel a little conflicted when I see something
iconic. About a character being given up. Right? Even if Barks is just gonna, like etch sketch this
out the next issue, I'm like, no. It's.
The worst it's the card. I everyone possible.
With the well with Donald head, I feel like he has a eight hundred of the consumer.
Right. But Scrooge is clearly more more more special.
And I like the sequence a lot. I can I can really imagine this having like a sterling score and being very exciting because we've got, like, millions of fe being pushed up behind
or an army affirm being pushed up to boost them behind as the Inducks crawl up, and the fermi are giving these these goof balls are sports fans basically? Right? They're like
I don't know. They're almost soccer hoo or something. Yeah. This is something gets scary.
Right. And then they're doing this goofy year.
One more shu Raw raw, and we'll roll into the shaft
charge
it's a very classic you know, like an archaic sounding cheer
and the docks parallel it with a clever bit of riding where it's one more inch will be over the top and and the nephew you say one more inch.
I like. At least that's how I imagine
the nation going. And And finally, the Ducktales make it, and and they seem to be free because once they're in the shaft, they can run up hill faster than the Tires and f can roll up. So it's it's a nice moment where we breathe for a little bit
before
before we flash back to the teri and front any comments you guys. Yeah. Well, it's it's especially beautiful.
Well, the the way these these these creatures are being...
Yeah. How they're drawn with their
disappointment, at this disappointment
on their faces it's just.
It's
these these little mouse
and these eyes...
Does bust is the master of with the, you know, expressions of whatever kind of
emotions and this is brilliant.
It definitely is. Because all they are is balls with faces basically, and he's making them so expressive. Yes. It's so funny.
Now we're onto to one of the other most memorable
pages.
I I would feel the one... The other one that's stuck out in my memory really a lot but so great. Yeah. I'm sure that this page lands in a lot of people's memories. I why introduce it and then you can tell us about Henri.
Basically,
you know, the the... They they rally a little bit. The carries and fermi, and they decide that now they have
like a meaningful
reason to make an earthquake because they've gotta try and shake the Inducks out of the shop So they're going to get all they're gonna work together to create the biggest
earthquake. In history. Are you guys the details of this earthquake are so great. You wanna do you wanna tell us some of Henri? Yeah. First of all to here is big where just lock
individual phase
take characters.
U. Yeah. The the is new and and the firm is he to stock has never had it hooked up. So let's see where on the left, we have a three upside down. And we have a trim where one half is upside down half.
We have some fancy hotel. The the the guy the hotel was holding up for two life.
And we have some buildings that are just playing for a year. And an actual ship on top of the bridge.
Saturday.
Well, I guess it's the best. Yeah.
It's easy.
Great panel of this guy in above. Yeah.
And I just want I love the dialogue the cards with it too. So it's hard to say which is the worst the bouncing. And you see this this guy with stolen in the water except the water and him and sober or flying not do both the bathtub or the rake,
which is get super.
Very terrible.
Dreadful.
But... Yeah. And it's so nice because the the water is still
you know, it's it's it still has the form of the bathtub.
Yeah. So it's... It must have been a such a crazy balance
that that there was not even time for waves
to,
you know, to come into
exist Yeah. The other one was mortgage japan so great
Way.
Yeah. And so I like.
I just... I really like that the different parts of the earthquake are like
identifiable
as Terry or Fermi cost. You know? Right
Yeah. It's a
different budget earthquakes we get. Yeah And something I love with the sequence in the next few panels is now Al the current hs and doctor is so silly. So you don't really have to worry about all the millions of people who are dead or.
Ignore. Let's just assume that everybody's yes. Right. Because we're figuring, you know, the one that I was in was, like a six point nine, and that that's pretty bad. I think the San Francisco earthquake was, like a seven point nine
but it's a long with scale, I think.
This is gotta be like a nine or a ten where we're figuring. So, you know, that burgers is is gonna have a really bad day here. But we got some
would be a horrific event, but the way he he presents it, you you're not you don't have to worry about. Right Actually we've got labels falling off with cans. We've got the pink being shaking off of the grocery store. And it's also... It's also imagine
and this whole stories, but also just just the the little details of what happens to the buildings is also silly and original.
Right.
Yeah. Tim, any
any
detail that you especially from the? For some reason, uncle screw ends up with the true head
And I think that's really funny. It happen off crime camera, I think or must might have been one of the most panel.
Why you see him before that... But it just... It's just there It's just suddenly on his head, and it's like, yeah. This one the things I would probably do. Well, maybe that's what he did. Maybe he put it on, so he couldn't investigate the whole it.
Right. I definitely imagine that it happened in the course of of the earth earthquake. Trying to hold on the room gonna put this jar.
Seriously.
Right.
So so the the first earthquake settles and the fermi... The terri and firm they realized that they haven't, you know, shaking the docks out yet. So they they give it to them again.
Even worse than the first one, and we get this great moment. This is why Barks must have done that little bit of slap stick, having Scrooge head
You wanna to tell us
what what he says, So he says, I wish I could see my money bin has made out. Yeah. Well, we see these
these guys
not very cute anymore
Mh. As we already found that. And
Donald, we're getting a another shaking This one is worth than the first one says you. My skin failed. I've been now. I've been an old junk.
And I love the reading this course dutch that Joe doesn't work work. So wasn't that name Right.
Right as the nephew pulls the the ancient
jug off of his edits. It's the goofy you've been of it's
they say home never looked so good and and Scrooge situations he could see his money bit probably
is head covered. Right. And now we come to the part of the story in the course of this the second awful
earthquake, it is the exact
calamity that screwed feared and now has inadvertently
caused
because his whole money been bounces
towards the shop
And and the narrator box tells us. At this moment, the fur give with everything
they've got and in a very unlikely,
but but wonderful cartoon slaps panel. The the floor of the band breaks open and all of his money pores down the shaft into Terry for me. What do you guys think of this panel? Well, I must say I'm a little bit disappointed
because
this could have been and maybe this is for my sort of yeah R I. Mh. Is could have been so much more dramatic.
Really five if I would have drawn this one I I would have at least Yeah. Let the the the the money
draw lots of coins
everywhere all around, but more... I would've chosen different perspective, more from... I don't know. The the money really falling down towards the viewer more You know what I mean? Absolutely.
That's a great take. Yeah. I was live at this disappointed. I thought yeah.
Have done it this week. Yeah. Maybe maybe I wonder if he chose to make it more funny. Because it's a really funny panel now. And it... So the different angle it would be more... Then it would be more like
kind of traffic. Yeah. I'm more like the demo we're like in only a bright, which is really yeah dramatic moment and here. It's silly too because the buildings are flying any the air letters are enough the money business. So we really place it more funny than dramatically. Yeah. It was still. Yeah. I
something with the perspective as well. It looks like the the money been... Yeah. It's is tiny little. It's also does one one, which is not
dramatically
which is literally the sound effect that you make in English when like others a fall. Well
nice.
Right.
But but basically, so so basically, mount h you're you're telling him step it up a little bit, Karl Barks.
Yeah. I'm so sorry. Yeah I have feel so seriously, I feel like
Box... It's like I'm am nothing
compared to him of course. And
I love this, but
sometimes and especially, you know, in the in the in twenties.
In these later years, I'm
to this
critical
more critical upon his...
Yeah. The ways he's drawing especially course the deduct themselves. And... Yeah.
Working about their own coverage. Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. So I'm I'm I'm really
he he is the greatest
and he will ever be the greatest. Well, and he was his own he was also a huge credit of his own work. Right? He he talked openly about things that he was disappointed by. But
I think it's totally reasonable
to look at these stories critically. Right? I mentioned,
I I don't have the discerning artist by the eye that you guys have, but sometimes I will notice panels where Like oh that's drawn a little bit off. Right? U. He had so many stories that it's easy to imagine that maybe we're we're getting close to the end of this one and he just wants to wrap it up. Or maybe like Henri said he wanted have a little more of a slaps stick tone. Yeah. What where I do think it works, is that it's a very big
broad moment that that is dramatic and it you know, we feel for Scrooge here. He
he sees his life's work going down the drain basically.
And and it's very fun. But but also very effect. Yeah. I I do really feel it's mostly played as fine, especially because in the in the next few pounds especially the first one on the next page. Duck discussed utterly ruined, but it looks so.
It's.
And just if you think about it it's just horrible
Right.
Those is also has to go Scrooge usual. So it's it's not very... It isn't played very dramatically Al all really silly. Right. Tonal, this is gonna stay fairly light, and it's gonna get resolved so quickly here. And honestly, this might be my own criticism of the story is that it's all... It's it's very brisk brisk, how how quickly this product many bark stories sometimes the ending really... Yeah Al comes at there was fun
exactly. Although I want... I'm not sure if it's because of that worry. If it's I mean, he also likes the stories to be great tight so mh course, now, we are reading the the version that's longer than what he intended after had to treatments itself. Right.
So we do get a little quick callback to the first uncle Scrooge
Solo story. I'm only a poor man. He just spares, and Donald tries to point out that he could just send buckets down to haul it up, but but at this point after living through their earthquakes, he is too afraid. More afraid of the earthquake than he even wants his money back.
Might be a bit of a stretch. But I mean, all change mind soon enough push sure anyway. Right. So so this next sequence here is takes us back to Terry for me. Do you wanna tell us about Tim about
about the problem that they have to deal with now? So
the there in the firm are like what is the stuff that came pouring on the chef? Maybe it's something that old my Inducks and down an exchange for a trophy. If it is, it must be money. I heard broadcast saying he has tons of this stuff.
They they were like, oh, yeah. Stan this stuff. And the nerve of sending this down an exchange for.
Right. They they're quickly like, oh, it must be garbage basically.
I mean, to them, it is anyway. Try to keep it away on that radio program. So they're they're really insulted. Right. It looks so installed.
Yeah. And and of course, being
being sports hoo, they're gonna turn this into into a competition is how they wanna resolve it. They they want to have a contest to see... See about getting rid of the stuff and
Henry, do you wanna tell us about a new trophy? Yeah. So this Terry or for me, I cannot.
It's
this is tearing on the old crowd
for and For the new term, is proposing the si cat deal Inducks
they're programming along and this automated service much better in the old twenty.
Because now it's it's also the trophy Al also part of that invention, I guess.
Right. But, yes, they're making the have the new truth so the games will go on right. But now... And and what I like here is it now now there's actually a really nice huge for the the work pushing specifically
because now they they can send all the money back up the shaft, and there's a good explanation for.
Yeah. That's right. Even if even if the fermi method is is a little bit less like enchanting,
than the terry, it definitely comes in handy for for the narrative here. It's also nice tight little, like, I like that structure of the story, right, where Scrooge is forced to discard his hat, and and that's all it took. To give them a new. And so you guys the story wraps up very
quickly here.
We get another rumble up the shaft and Scrooge here's before anyone else that the jingle of his money. And,
I guess we're we're meant to believe that basically every dime of it
right Barks to the bin, which is it's it's a neat Gladstone car ish drawing, I think they are of the Bin.
Around
stuff to stuff to bursting.
We're just hanging out.
Yes.
And... He's basking in his money and and in the very next panel, the fermi
have sent up a massive earth in plug that that completely blocks up the hole with a big chunk.
And and the one of the nephews has just common the terry Fermi
must not have liked the stuff. And upon the whole plug Donald says, wow, and they must not have liked us either.
And so
although Inducks is completely ruined, but
Right.
Right. And no one can probably prove that I I mean, I guess everyone knows about Scrooge
excavation. So he'll... I I guess it'll keep his construction businesses
very busy.
So
right.
Who wants to take us home with this goofy little
sort of anti
sure ending.
Yeah. Well, so Uncle Scrooge gets its money back and things are again as they were as we know. By now. So there's uv telling Scrooge that there is a professor from the university. Here to ceo On recruit. Cinnamon
Scrooge says,
enthusiastically, yeah, we see this
University man sitting in front of the Scrooge. I just want to assure you, mister Mc that there will be no more earth earthquakes for many many years. The pressure is off. Where post causes
earthquakes professor,
Scrooge asks is man why a gas that builds up in fishers and the earth shrinks and then the last very last panel. He sure range been around as a partners.
So this is, of course, I
I say it verizon? Callback?
Yeah. Yeah.
To what...
What what this guy told
screws before the bugs not
having been around. Right a florida. Yeah. There's also a detail that's missing in the dutch one, the fact that they both have different dialects. That one uses, like, cowboys speak in the other one. As a Boston
the is boston actions that's missing, of course, in transmission. It's it's funny. I such a epic story and and with fridge.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. It's a very goofy slaps ending for... But it's. It's a nice closure.
Yeah Now. I do too. It works for me. It's it's a odd in a wink, and it's obviously meant to be a wink at the audience even if we see the Inducks
silhouette there.
Wow. So you guys... That that is that is the story. That is land beneath the ground. I am totally interested in hearing your overall thoughts on it. I don't I don't know if I would go it, like, one of the best or most epic economics ever but of Barks, but just the it's so memorable and so imaginative and I think that's why I really stuck out me. It's not the one that I've read that's often it's...
Agent come up because this so much fun and yeah know, it's it's both... I mean, it's it's also a little exciting thing that mostly is really funny and these characters is just... So much imagination in there and course I read it when I was so young so to when you're so young everything is new to you, but There's so many, yeah know, this phone memories stuff this is so well and crazy. I've said it in in previous,
because before the whole concept of Scrooge, of course, also insane.
Well it's just...
I love that I got to grow up with something. So imagine it Right do. Yes. Well, I for me this story is...
It's a brilliant story. I love it. I love the drawings. I love the jokes. I love the dialogues
and still for me, the problem in this story is I need horizon. I need air. And for me, this is
a little bit, you know, I don't know. I miss... I miss... I don't know. The horizon.
It's is that like class
t this this lost to for me. This that's the point of it too. Course is the point of it. But, yeah, that plays Al role in my... Yeah in my feeling about.
So
yeah, this is why I always
when I was creating this story.
I always have this this same feeling of let's get out of this place. It's
I don't know.
Well. Yeah.
Yeah. Because this that is the notable thing about this story is that it all takes place underground. And a cavern that so huge that it it might as well have a horizon. But I need see where you're coming from. Yeah. But you know, also
there's nothing going on there. There is not eve... Yeah. There's moss. Okay.
Would I need a tree or add bird or something? You know, and that's like I already said. It's it... That's
somewhat
makes me so I love the story, but
it's not one of... It's not one of my favorites.
No one you like to get lost in basically Yeah.
Right. Yeah. That's that's great to hear. That's that's really in thing.
Successful this and with how if it makes feel Like
very
that's Barks. And manages to give me that
feeling of close to pho. And that's, of course, it's brilliant. Yeah. It definitely sticks with you. What about you, tim? Well, for me, I As a child, I really like this story,
especially the the the build to the... The the mystery part of it. It's always what I really like about Barks economics, like, it always sets of these great questions and then things that are a bit off. And we you get this
reveal after the build is is just was great
kid. Yeah. So you big thing anthony You love that I read when it was young, but I was also so I'm gonna don't remember. I don't remember not knowing this story. So I don't know what it's like to discover to that's... Because they're still where your great Barks coins that I have yet to read. So I can't wait to find out.
Although, a lot of it, of course has been spoiled million that's
sure. I again again imagine what it it must be so great to read this story for first time I have no idea what's gonna happen. Yeah. There's a handful of stories where I think it's important if you're revisiting them to try to put yourself into that mindset of reading it for the first time. Yeah. You know, the golden helmet
and this one, like, this is... I think this blew my mind is a kid.
I think for me, this coincided with... I I think it was about the same age I saw the Ducktales version of it and those two things together, they were awesome to me. Yeah. I so... Yeah. Why don't we hold, I definitely wanna cover the dot towels one. I usually do, like, a little other media sequence.
Right. But sure. But, yeah, that's... I mean, they I would have read it around the same time I saw that as well. Alright. And what I wanted to say was when I... Because I've read it every few years, but when I was with this
visiting it to us and, but it's interesting I am I'm... Of course, I'm big coming on paper, and I always really I love with com how the whole page is also part of design, But lately have also been
reading and digital using an app where you zoom in on the channel. And I noticed that reading the pages that way. It's like you're experience
experiencing it really differently again, especially the the panels where the nephews go down to Severino when you really go panel by panel zoomed. It's so
cinematic and it really hits home and the way I originally read the call and I'm not sure if it's the same for you tim but... Yeah. Yeah. The in the netherlands and then in the nineties,
they didn't published Barks that often in the magazine because it's mostly new material, but they would sometimes include special, like, mini mini booklet. So in two parts, this is one of the first ones I had. So in two parts that have this come and a separate booklet, but it's only half the size of the normal So it's actually Al tiny it's still... Especially with the seven one, I remember being so impressed by so even at this tiny ninety size. But yeah here... If you digital copies of comments or already try if you just have a paper one. Just try really going panel by panel and it's almost like... We it in a really different way. Yeah. Seeing the page as a whole. But that's why I love with Com because you're when you're drawing a page... The the whole page is like a composition. And... But every gun is also it's own... And it makes me wonder how this one might have been affected by the, you know, the removal of those panels. Because it it would throw off the pacing of. That's...
It's also a thing and Barks that guess to where. And I think it's like an it it was impacting most of the story where you often would end a page with a cliff thing actually I really want to turn the page. If you pay attention to it dude he really does live a lot. Yes. Right. So Al little mystery at the end of the page, Huey, can be something silly too, but something that makes you want to go and I wonder when when these comments get cut up that sometimes it it gets ruined because then there a half page with shelf around and.
I would be curious to see how it was originally. But it is. At least he got this story up himself and you got to add in little things to make the story flow better again. So... Right. As for my part, I I love this story. I think what you said Henri about you know, it may not be technically perfect, but it's just it's so audacious.
The whole concept of it is so arresting
and in en to me that even if it has a few flaws and faults around the edges,
This is just such a a stunning concept.
I think there is a a reason why this one stands out to so many people as, like, their favorite or or the Barks story or the comic book that they remember
more than all the others because it's just got so much
absorbing
imagery. You know, just looking at those pillars
and the
thousands of little fur and terry rolling around. I'd I never get tired of this one. Thinking back to it. This might be like the one that I reread, you know, the most as a kid because I just... I found it so fascinating and so fun
and so absorbing. I I love this one so much. I I always think it's a shame how brief, like, how little time we actually spend with the terry and fur,
and it's kind of a shame that Barks never went back and revisited them. But, you know, that's not his style. That wasn't his agenda. He he had he had had his fill of time to me a different part of the fun too because it's really... Like, will be really fun to write more with these characters, but that that's why it's nice because he left enough... Left enough space for everybody to imagine
their own fuel fill in their own ideas of... Yeah. Where it's like So... Yes.
Right. Yes. Well, that's actually what I find a little bit disappointing
sometimes that some artist...
Some artist tends to
fill up the gap the gaps that's
Barks left open, and that can be...
I don't know
you would prefer these stories to kind of stand, I think, as their own testament.
Right have have that miss stick rather than trying to tell every little detail around I'm guessing
I already enjoyed reading when people make their take on it, but then I do see it as there. It's their version. Right. Right. Not Cat.
Yeah. Because I I didn't hear like I do enjoy seeing what people then come up with how they imagine.
How for their imagination and they make follow ups, but then I do see it as like this their version and everybody can fit own through.
Yeah. That's that's a couple of different philosophies.
I understand why why you guys feel that Yeah. Yeah. For me, the Barks
universe is sort of sacred
I and I think that quite maybe so seriously.
This, for example, this story is so it feels so good to just they it depends the story it ends there that the... Everything we know about these creatures and that's perfect.
Right that. Yeah. It's it's a very tight story. I think you're right. It doesn't need more. Let's... I... I'm gonna hold off on the critical consensus to because that feels like a good segue to like other
media. Right? Like like you mentioned it's actually surprising to me that as famous as this story is, there haven't been that many people that have done their own take on it. I did see that there was a very fun William van Horn follow where he used it Terry or affirm, I can't remember.
I... But I really enjoyed reread it. It was in this issue with this just really gorgeous classic cover.
Poor covering.
And and it was fun, but it didn't like it had a terry or a firm at the surface.
And it it it wasn't very ambitious.
Right. It wasn't trying
to tell, like land before time...
Land beneath the grounds. To
or anything like that.
It it was it was story art in everything by Van Horn.
And was called Cr Comforts. And I I really liked it. I thought founded it a delightful but All follow And then like, even Don Rosa was more restrained, I think. Because he'd never did like a big follow to this one. He had them cameo
in that center of the earth story, but he never like, tried to do a sequel to this one or... Yeah. The with since there. So... It did. Yeah. And It was
to bus if I said story
Right. But but again, it wasn't like trying to do land beneath the ground too or anything. So I like that. You mentioned the duck
episode. I'm I'm gonna
I'm gonna have a hot take. I think that duck tells episode is one of the best ones of the series. And one of their best ever Barks Al adaptation Oh, I do agree.
Yeah. That's as well. Yeah. It's it's more... I I watched... It was coincidence I watched it maybe two months ago. And we watched it. And yeah. It's it's one of the best doctors that makes for great episode and great animation though.
I have know, it's just it's always going to be a Al let down converter Exactly. It's it's nothing compared to the comment. But as far as, like, the the animated show goes, it's it's definitely a high point Boy, I remembered every word of it too once I started
to rewatch it. Yeah. Was it is interesting to see also how because, of course, in a twenty minute episode and animation budget is Al and endless they staff to make certain. Yeah. Got some changes And month in our phone really...
So one thing they did is that they basically
put the for to together. They're still the two separate types, but they only do the rolling. And know yeah. Actually already mentioned, there's is no time course all isn't in there, which is the main reason. Right. Right. I didn't know like that
because of the in there to gifts
areas all But at least they like ji rowe instead of, like, fe and cra or something.
More Barks in than normal. But one lady... I would have to much it again because it's it's been like, two months, but
They... I think they really follow one of... They make one of the the little... The baby. The firm
a main character so they really come, but doctors bring more kids, so it kind of makes sense that they they make... There's also like less less time to spend with the dairy for, so maybe you don't getting time to see how like they are. So I think that's decided like one of the baby characters as... They give them a bigger role, so you kind of have a way to relate to Dare. But it's interesting that they tell a bit of the story more from the side of that character. Yeah. I I liked it. I thought it worked. And and all the Mine Barks stuff was great. And it's one of the most foundation course. Yeah. It's one of the more iconic sequences from the opening of the show where he grabs hat coming down in the the My during the famous theme song. I would say that stands in contrast to the two thousand seventeen version of Ducktales. I I was I was pretty upset at the little ts.
Yeah. I don't think you're it now. But No. No. I've I've not seen But no that's.
They they call the title. The the first one, the original is called Earth earthquake, and in this one, it's called the tear of the terra.
It's if they're bought, it's a real tease because, of course, you're going to think. Yeah. Right. The show is not I don't think it's really angry of people or that's definitely not english
trying to have it both ways, I think. It's fine would make the Barks references
without really doing it.
Yeah. There was... Well, I mean,
I haven't seen enough of the.
I've I feel like it's a it's a good show by itself, but because they reference Barks are making references rather than capturing the spirit of Barks if you actually really to like Barks I'm sure there's also Barks expensive like the new show but for me that was the issue that it doesn't... It references it, but then it doesn't capture your the the I way early essence of it. So... It doesn't do anything with it. There was really no point. That's the thing. So they have they make an episode where that's called the
and the the I would say they kind of Cameo, but they basically play no role. It's so.
Like what. You see think you see them all the way at the end for, like a little bit, too Right.
Yeah.
I I I won't dwell on it, but I did wanna mention that a terra firm is is
a boss in one of the levels in the old school Ducktales video game. So that's fun. Let's go ahead and and transition to the community consensus so we can get on route it up. Yeah. This one more thing I should mention though because that's something we found up kind of recently, but of course, I'm not from the Us, but for serious
until recently had all these disney stores. And the ones in the ninth we said
several different types of decorations and one of the ones that was across several stores was disney afternoon themes and one of the displays was a pretty big statue we were seen from Earthquake. So I can... I'll send you the pictures of it up on until
know we're still around. I'm so glad you mentioned that. That was one of the stores that was near my house. Yeah. There's a few of them around the country that this these sculpture. So the
good Ducktales is a sculpture
third
and
nice sculpture too. It's
I imagine for a lot of people. Even if they've never seen that bills with net or never
economic but they if they've seen the store in in their mall for thirty years that that they know it from there. Right. It was very lucky.
So So it sounds like we all think very highly of this story. You know, it's it's an emotional favorite of mine. Even if I don't think it's one of his all time greatest, it's It's almost like the big ideas and the the big concept that it has lifts it up. It elevate it a little bit more. And I think that's where the community lands to. Because if you look it up on Inducks,
it has a very high rating.
It's an eight point two as of right now, which is good for number sixteen
out of all, you know, forty two thousand thousand three hundred.
So people love this story. I think it probably gets inflated a little bit just because it is so memorable, but I I think it deserves be the conversation But is it... The I mean being the marble is what makes it itself. Right. Yeah. Exactly. It's just it's not one of the stories that has Al like, it doesn't have strong themes, like say only a poor man or the Golden helmet does.
Some other stories Like, there's...
Like, it's not... Doesn't get as tens or emotional which Only few really good births stores really do I think on Yeah.
It's it's. It feels almost more the the tone feels but adventurous will also a bit more like the ten pages a lot will also to dial is so funny and clever all the time. Right. It's one of these things that makes Barks a bit meet so configure of other stuff that's so imaginative and wacky and right love it.
Yeah. It it it is just a wildly
entertaining story. You guys before we wrap up, does anyone wanna go to bat for any, like, specific panel that we didn't give attention to
favorites? Yes. If I may,
there's on the first page, we see the
the worry room. Right? And it's funny because it looks like
some of these rooms
that you
find in
not houses wise where...
It's an isolation room and it's, you know, it's it has this protected this these rules or detected by some Yeah. Decided wall and you can imagine that when
screws really goes
insane
worrying, he will smash his head against the walls. And I love these kinds of details so much. So I like Yeah. I love it. I love that. Yeah. That that is a nice touch. Thank you about. How I few, Tim. Any any that you wanna point out? I'm thinking of somewhat. I think might have both three been pretty thorough, I think. Yeah. I think so. Yeah. I love the whole sequence like I said were the just in terms of storytelling where the nephews go down Al Tahoe and that's it's really black bowel and of course, the big refill of the Severino. Yeah. That's Often my favorite panels are just three stupid faces that can
Al
argue. Yeah. I love the one... I've also mentioned the ones were the they start enrolling for the first design that is a pretty silly looking on and analytics this is great. That's a good one to advocate for because it's not one of the big, like, show panels. But it is... I mean, the show panels really are spectacular. And just that whole first page that this is among Barks. Best
introduction pages. I think, panel for a panel. It does such a good job. Al the character. I totally agree. And by the way, there is on page two, I think you... You have this beautiful
little
Barks
and a bridge and
Scrooge and Donald walking there and you can... This is so realistic.
It's a place we really can go and it's so simple and I love this zooming out and Yeah. Showing
a bit of nature
in this harsh
city.
I love it.
Yeah. And that that panel you're right, that one is really lovely. Well, you guys thank you so much for joining me in this, like big
Round robin
rehash of this story. I had so much fun doing it. People
can can check you guys out you're being You're all being published over there in Netherlands. I am both I'm both
writing and a lot by the way at the moment. Especially the... How do you this club, the club of the
club. The ones the four thousand
Like
the basically the four animals, so yeah a bit big wolf and. Oh, okay. Nice. Yeah. Slow unquote evil characters from the the four.
They're owl fellows
Fine.
It's more an established thing now
think It was also a thing in Al Us economics with a few different characters, but it's really, like, a big established thing in the Dutch. Pos. Nice. Yeah. So I'm writing for... I love these the setting and with the big bad wolf, it's fellow
criminals.
And
wolf is is always a fun character. Yes. I think so. I I I'm not allowed to draw it myself, but
unfortunately,
because they want me to produce
Ducktales mainly.
So it's forbidden.
And, yeah, I'm drawing now of course Al time every night having fun. That's excellent.
I wish I wish they were still being published over here. I wish I could keep up with with the great comments being pushed out overseas. Yeah. The magazine is currently not running at all in the Us. Even right before it stopped, like the... Well, the the last few months, the last months so was in a year, if it was not very good. But before that they were putting out so many European economics and doing great translations of them. So hopefully, if there will be a license again and they get these editors again. I'm sure there will be more... Right.
Your?
People should definitely look you guys up and
I really appreciate you all joining me for this. Why don't we close it out?
By reading that last to line. Now do you mind reading it's just he's sure ain't been around has he partners? He's sure been around. Has he partners knows excellent.
Listeners can check out barge Barks on Facebook
and
Instagram. And join us next time as we get to cover
another pretty famous Scrooge adventure, the lost crown of Gong khan. And... Yeah, Thank you guys again.