Hello, and welcome to Barks Remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Mc Ducktales and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comic of all time. Join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological publishing order get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Welcome Come back to Barks from Remarks, I'm Mark Sever, a Grown man who loves Inducks con,
and
I'm gonna I'm gonna introduce my guests for today as we talk about a a fairly famous Scrooge adventure. I'm joined by Mi miguel H and
we're gonna be talking about the lost crown of
Khan,
you are a fan artist
from Norway. Do you wanna introduce yourself and maybe just mention a little bit about your
history with the economics? Yeah. Hi, Mark. It's great to be back again and on my own man who also grew up with Barks amazing chrome.
And a huge fan especially,
especially of local screw venture adventures. Yeah. My history with the fan art and
so is that I back in two thousand and twelve
participated in
make your own car for the rich down Magazine
and I got a little five page
story and published. And
I've written some pre face
texts for a book and been on this
in Way to talk about drawing and I'm think I made
six stories that has been published. So far? Yeah. Excellent. So so more than just a fan artist, you've you've gotten to be published. Very... That must be really exciting.
Very thrilling. I I really enjoy your art. You put out a new... Just just yesterday. You had a really cool
new image of screws that I really like
and and you mentioned
Disney channel. That's an appropriate thing to talk about. Right? Because
duct, I I assume that's where duck paired in in Norway.
Yeah. And also
Yeah. It used to error on
our main channel.
Mostly, I think before we go even there's general. Right. Yeah. Kinda the same over here in the Us where it would aaron and Inducks indication and then eventually on Disney channel.
But this is a pretty famous
stuck story as far as as, like, Ducktales itself goes.
I'm definitely planning to mention the the episode. So so let me ask you before we even get into the story, the the
distinct thing about this story is the presence of the
creature, the the obama snowman,
aka k, the Y. It's it's got a lot of lot of names from around the world, different culture
you know, big foot is kind of on another version of it. But I'm wondering
what what is your, like, first pop culture
experience with the obama snowman or yet or whatever you wanna call. That's because what feeling because I didn't... I've given you some thoughts. And I think my first experience with the the, the abdominal snowman, I think that was actually the first time I also
and encountered Uncle Scrooge
in the duck election.
Okay.
So so that actually was your first encounter with it. That's pretty cool think so. Yeah. Very neat. I think this probably would have been my second third. This this is like a a big pop culture trope. Right? A lot a lot of shows will maybe have an episode
a a nice winter
episodes sat in in the Hi himalayas, which is usually where the snowman takes place.
For me, there's a very famous stop motion cartoon in the Us by by the production company rank and Barks. The root off the red nose is Reindeer deer, Cartoon. Is that is that something that is known in Scan at all? Yeah. We have a lots of other with with the rudolph the the red nose rain there. I can think of men
cartoons
with I can't remember anyone with the bum snowman or.
So so in the states, this is probably like one of the three or four most famous Christmas cartoons. There's like this one very specific version of root off the Red nose rain reindeer. Like I said, that's stop motion. And it has a really
comic version of the
snowman that they call the bundle. It's it's a fun
characterization, and it's kind of... It kind of is gonna play in with the the comic
and very goofy depiction in in this story. But... Yeah. Yeah. This is like this is a story that the story of the
snowman the myth, I guess, is always kinda fascinated me as a kid, right? The idea of this, like, creature, this Al Barks feature
that hides up in the mountains.
Did you... Did you happen to do any research like I did into kind of the origins of the myth? Yeah. I I did some research and go ahead and get ready and here... Here's what I'll do. Why don't I introduce the comic, right? Because we're gonna talk about when this was published, which was kind of like a kind of a hot time
for for the
snow. But our our story today, again, the full title is the lost crown of Youngest khan. Has got a nice
exclamation point at the end of it just to make it extra exciting. This one came out
and it had a cover date of May of nineteen fifty six. So we're we're into the second half of the fifties at this point, you know, we're kind of getting farther away from World war two, which informed some of Barks earlier stories and we're kinda going into, like, an area of kind of cold war paranoia,
which is gonna be kind of the backdrop for some of his stories going forward. This one was published in the uncles screws number fourteen,
and it it hasn't had as many reprint at least in the United States as many
comparable uncle Scrooge events. It's it's only eight of them including the original one. And a it's a fairly short screw as well. It's only nineteen pages.
So, Nicole, we mentioned that this takes place in nineteen
fifty six.
This was published to nineteen fifty six what did you learn about the
Yeti Myth? Around that time? Yeah. As you said, Mark, the story is made then it's actually made in nineteen fifty five
right. Published in fifty six. And that's the eight of the safe conservative American family life and with the rest of the cold war and leaning in the back ground. Yeah. But the the people know to get some excitement as long as this was in control forms and only for a short time. So news
broadcast on television really got into this the time with reports of the for the bum snowman. Mh mh And I found out that the the british explorer eric shipment from many huge footprints in on the mainland
glacier of amongst everest nineteen fifty one, and the new support true themselves and this and
rev old legend of the Y. The huge
more than two meters tall, Al ply feature of
Mountains, they're encrypted similar to the American Source.
And one of the local names for the essay actually can be translated to folds,
full smelling slow man.
Neat. So yeah I didn't I didn't catch all of that. I did see of an expedition
a couple years after that, I think Or around that time where they reported finding what were supposedly the the hairs from from a Y pe or something Did you see
about the story published by Isaac Al off. No. I I found some stuff about
nowhere, actually in nineteen fifty five when while Barks is looking for a Plot for fourteenth Scrooge adventure. And the news report
provided in mid long. The stories was really catching on again with reports of a borders which I for
of new giant footprints in the tv tibetan mountains and bbc and television made ninety minutes program named the creature, which hammer films two years later,
remade into a moving named the bamboo snowman ma'am and the new coast or said worksheet shit with someone brave. A timeless territory to freeze you receipts.
That's great. I wonder if that... It's kinda neat how there's, like, it's this...
It's one of those ideas that seems to occur in parallel and different cultures, kinda like a dragon and, you know, there's so many cultures that have this, like, head space for a giant
mysterious
Al ply creature. And you can imagine this coming from, like siding in in like In North America, if you ever investigate any of the sas watch siding, it always ends up being a bear that has lost its hair for some reason.
So I imagine in the Is it's probably similar but maybe with the Y or or the like. As far as
one other pop culture thing is that isaac Al of of the famous sci f writer he had a short story, I think, published
everest. In the fifties in the early fifties. That helps
this
where apparently apparently when they... When an expedition discovers
y in the Himalayas, they actually turn out to be martian but they're in the Himalayas because, like, that's the kind of that's the kind of atmosphere they can tolerate I thought that was kinda cool. It. So that's that's kind of the the cultural background that I've got for this one Al I I found surprisingly little about, like, the actual
production of the story by Barks.
So do you know anything about the production? Well, not much
except that. Of course. He watched the news and he got fairly
simple straightforward Id for... Yeah. Straightforward treasure. Yeah. It's kinda like explorers go out. They find the pressure and the return and similar fashion
lost world. Yeah. It does
seem reminiscent of that. I I gonna talk about it when we get there, but I I find it interesting that this is one of those times It's unusual how screwed is gonna send a team out. Yeah. This is more of
getting the t Barks career Right. Not it. It's a recovery mission.
I I guess the other bit of historical background, you know, Severino everyone knows who Gin Khan is. Right? The famous
leader of the mongols
who ruled over much of eurasia many centuries ago. Now as far as the question, did he have an actual Crown. I I looked that up. No. He did... Doesn't seem to have. I I saw a cool image of of his wife's Crown, and, of course, it doesn't look anything like the one we're gonna see in this story. It's it's a very... It's a very European looking crap. But, yeah, It's it's neat that Barks created a whole treasure. For this. Because now if you like Google, if you just Google the words,
crown of gang this Khan it leads to Barks and Ducktales and nothing. Alright. So we always take a moment. I like to take a moment to pan to international listeners.
By mentioning some of the title translations from around the world, This one's just not that interesting. I'm... I I really find it intriguing.
When they go with kind of one countries and their the translators go with
unexpected titles. But for the most part, this one is just gonna end up being different variations of the lost crown of getting this khan or the the treasure of the ab ama
snow monster
or or whatever. So
since since I've got a Norwegian guest on Miguel, why don't you tell us the the Norwegian title. Yeah. The no norwegian entitled for the stories but very straight
translation is just jen cons top the q, which just means the last chrome of Gen khan. Right.
And then I will do... Let's see and...
I... I'm most comfortable with Spanish. So in Spain and Mexico,
this is a very straightforward
La corona compared to be they again this kind. That said, let's let's go ahead and launch into the story. Alright. So Mick, the the loss crown of Khan. Now we usually open
with Scrooge in his money Bin. In these adventure choice. And and this one is no different. But it is a little bit different that Scrooge is doing something
fairly pedestrian.
He is me an old clock that he's got... It's an old
pocket watch. Style clock. And he is... He's just listening to it
reassuring ticking. And thinking about how much he enjoys this very cheap watch. That helps him go to sleep.
Any he any drifts off to sleep in his pile of money. It's a very... It's a a very neat image.
And then Bark uses some narration boxes to transition us
away to the other side of the world and he says Can can you tell us about that that narration box? Yeah. Uncle unsecured wouldn't feel so snug if you knew that thousand of miles away the sandals feet of for very runners are petting or the lu
of the Inducks mountains bringing bad news. Yeah. And and so we get... We get this trope that we see a lot in in media
where it's one messenger
past along some information to another messenger in a pretty treacherous place where you can't really use the telephone or anything like that.
It's it's very intriguing, I think. What do you think about this this first sequence? Alright. I think it's really interesting. You it certainly brings this sense of mystery. What is this bad news and what is this danger that on the Scrooge
meet on this new adventure. So it it really brings the red to the story. I think from on from the very first page. Yeah. I agree. It's it's some good storytelling, right? Because it is both intriguing
and it also kinda gives us this neat little preview. Of the setting itself without having to like just use
exposition
dialogue to do it. Yeah. I really like first opening panel with Scrooge flying there in the pile of coins because it's it's an early establishing of the stores big you're running joe the sheep watch that costs Scrooge a dollar. Because this is gonna be
pretty important Right. Plan. I'm glad you pointed that out because
right away in that very first panel, we can actually
quote here, we read the clock ticking and that's gonna be kind of an ever present thing. And
it's it's a nice kind of poetic narrator box that introduces it. To a watch that ticks loudly
and a strange den of the roof of the world our two men that end danger the safety of uncle Scrooge in his newest adventure. It's it's a very intriguing open too. So on the next page when
when the messenger
service, like eventually
arrives to uncle Scrooge
via telegram,
we we just see him very
dismay and surprised saying great stumbling could apostrophe.
I hadn't expected this to happen. And and he allude to needing to
deal with whatever this matter is in person
and we see him like, he and worrying about how he can trick Donald and the boys. Into joining him because he knows that they wouldn't if asked
and and so while he's pays saying we do transition to Donald and the boys. You wanna tell us make what they're up to? Main meanwhile across tom And his Nephews are watching the news guest. The broadcaster is telling about once again, stories are copying
about the mysterious bum snowman asia. They sitting there in the living room and watching television and the new report telling about the footprints of one of the frightening to reach your creatures at the twenty three thousand some feet on the
So I like the name of that plateau.
It's it's a pun. Right? In in English, it's gas and.
But it definitely kinda has that south Asian South Central Asian field to it. This is a trope that is not... You know, the the whole, like, the story is gonna get explained and you introduce it via a news cast don't think it's the best trope. It it it seems very like happens stands, a little overly coincidental to me but that's fine I think it's actually a good thing because
Barks.
The the big thing Barks is gonna do, but the story is it's gonna
make fun of media of television and how day hyper up stories and kind of make Al legend that's it's not not necessarily true. So for the story and the story Barks want to tell. I think is important to get the
in on the beginning. Right you yeah with what I agree with your Barks. That's that's not the best way. But for this particular story, I think it works and it's necessary. You're you're right. You're you're definitely right because it's it's gonna book and with the gag,
the the gag and. So that's a very fair points. So we transition back to screws where he has decided on the next page. So the only... The only option for him is to trick the boys into... Into coming with him. He's gonna promise them, like, enjoy ride on his plane. And then once they get airborne, he admits to Shanghai.
But but then he's gonna give them the option if they really want when they arrive at their destination in Al,
when they arrive and Ka, they can decide to to go back. Mcgill, this is definitely not the first time that he's tricked them into it. It it feels like one of the more gentle times though that he
tricks his nephews into coming on Al adventure. Yeah. Huey, usually often try to rigorous way out of paying them thirty cents an hour and we're also saw in the men the that he then trick them to not even take care payments for
Yeah. This time, it is gently gives them the option of returning home, but then they will feel like they are chicken. So Right. And and after what promises to be, I I would assume, like, a twenty hour plane right? So while while they're in the air and then the net user are annoyed.
Screws explains just what the heck is going on. And he tells them about how he had a caravan
a month ago, that was in Outer mon
crossing the Inducks Push Mountains, and he says that the acts were loaded mostly with hides and wall but that one of them had a treasure of unbelievable richness.
And
this is the part we had alluded to on the next page he talks about how his agents. He had his agent
scouring Asia for years to find this treasure and and when they... When the caravan van camp out, in an ic pass, the treasure is gonna end up being stolen We already mentioned that it's a little bit weird
that you know, Scrooge has his quote agents
seeking out a treasure. That's not very... That's not kind of the classic trope that a lot of people who who enjoy these comics
and duck,
especially like the second duck series. That's not what they think of when they think Scrooge. Try. He he usually does it directly. Yeah. The new doctor has re reboot made it into that screwed she's even more in for that adventure and for the themselves.
Personally thing it's Scrooge is definitely Severino which is for Richard's sake because. Yeah. Yeah. That that that aspect of the second
really robbed to me a little bit the wrong way that, like, obsession
with Adventure
rather than treasure. I I I feel like they they almost wanted to make a show out of the original theme so there. I can definitely see that. I remember the tour that that the top there was basically just Scrooge one to two climb of mount Severino, I think it was and Right. The only only the reason was to prove that it could do it. There was no economical profit to gain from it. So Right.
Isn't
And and so we get a nice little reveal here. Right? Donald is is busting to find out what this fantastic treasure was that
quote that you rate it more valuable than hour time. And he reveals that it was the lost
crown of Gen hot.
It's a pretty cool panel of two of the she holding up that crown. It's really is. I it's really glowing in my
of in my. Yeah. I I would say that this is probably one of the coolest
treasures that the Ducktales have gone after.
And and probably, like maybe the need kind of original bark treasure. Because as we say, this is not like a historical or a mythological
artifact. But it just... It's just feels I icon. Definitely.
And and it's got a really cool look to it. Al as a duct fan, I feel like the look of the actual
treasure itself is really iconic as well. I also really like the pacing of how Bark has screws reveal what's happened, you know, that he goes on to explain that something has happened to the treasure
during the night in the Ic pass, the crown was somehow
stole. And and he basically wraps it up by saying he needs their help to to track it down. Yeah. I can we can also mention that.
Here do
Ask how did your agents happen to find it. Al to huge just transfer never mind that's a story for another time. Right now, I'm more interested in finding it again. And of course, Don Rosa would make an explanation for how the agents found the crown and back do some rights that could say. Yeah. Well, and will definitely get into that follow ups story as well. I... I'm definitely excited to talk about that one. And and then I guess I should also mention that Scrooge
description of the crown is pretty interesting.
What is the what is notable about the crown itself? Yeah. Yeah. It's crust with Al thousand jewels, one for every city that it conquered. So that's neat little flourish. Right? That that makes the crown, I think, feel even more
special, more impactful
Right? It it feels... Now it feels like Al even more bloody.
Fact. Yeah. We can we start to fastest
about all the people that's not the one time to do for every new. Right. Because,
you know, it it is it's definitely not legend
about how the khan went about conquering.
Cities.
So when they do arrive in Al,
you know, the the the Ducktales have not been convinced initially.
It sounds like too much of a task for them. But
as
as they see screws walking off, on his own.
They they they do kind of predictably
start to feel, you know, guilty about letting an old duck go off and the awful now alone.
What do you think Miguel about about what the Nephews say here? I I love this plan this impressive
I love this part of the story. And the boys say besides, we are not cities. Turbo brown is short ton. And then they're really
research and wait on the, we'd like a crocodile adventures sells and Scrooge things hey I knew that come along and like, I really like the fly smile and Scrooge choice in this panel because it really looks.
Yeah. It is fun seeing that. Live version of Scrooge who knows how to get what he wants and and make make the other characters think it was their idea. So I I don't know if it carries over in Norwegian, but the word sis That's something that was like it it hasn't really aged well. These days, but it was like, super common lingo back in the fifties and sixties
and later, it's it's a word for, like, an a feminine little boy. It would be coded as It would be coded as a little bit home homophobic.
Today, it wasn't like specifically thinking about
about that because, like, that wasn't even talked about that. But but it definitely had that kind of coding. But again, you you could find that in any number of comments from this time. So
I I like this term roof of the world for the Himalayas is. Right? We'll see that in the comics a few times and now we see the docs para out over the roof of the world, and we transition pretty quickly to the site where the crown
disappear. Where it's just one guard who's kinda stations to keep the clues intact.
And we see Scrooge
talk at him in in local language, which
I think Barks is using some basically chicken scratch to to represent,
but but at least we're spared from any kind of, like,
gibberish
like language.
I did some research on on Al language area. And I I think we're
want this to be
most likely the she power
cher bar or share language, which is the the basic language spoken in And the Indian status of
Severino
mainly by the She. It's definitely not real writing, but it it bears some similar similarities or
resemblance at least to the to the written language and... But, yeah, it's basically
chicken writing, but it's not just awful as a first thought it's possible. Right. Yeah. You're right. It definitely... It definitely looks in Al line. I can't remember the name of the language family. It's like Lost tibetan or something. But but but but it it is reasonable to say that the the depiction of the She of people and and throughout this story is generally pretty respectful. It's it's pretty fine. For the nine fifties. Yeah So that won't be an issue in this story. No. I would also like to say that it could also be asian.
I don't think so but we know that from Sol laurent then Scrooge.
Could speak to native language of the alliance that's... We learned
language when it was a york buyer and. So probably right the same. Yeah. It's it's kind of interesting, Tell how much Barks
returns to this, like, pretty small area of the world. Right? There's we've got we've got this story
and we've bought Trauma lot
and each other... Oh
unicorn. Try Al of the unicorn. Yeah. Right. Yeah. And so trail, the unicorn,
So... He's really... He's really interested in this region
This isn't a neat reveal. Right? Why don't you tell us about what the
the guide leads them to? Yeah. So the she go ahead is leading Scrooge if you up to a blanket since snow. The spirit says, they preserved the tea straps in the snow wonder that blankets. And then the She,
what's under there and dongle
experience yeah chats, but short what sort of beast made those prints and we have this three towed
clog
huge footprints and the kids and don't are looking scared, but huge more normal annoyed or something or kinda for I would say.
It's not a beast voice, but maybe you're not a man either, and then sku turns around looking
total
and say, it's like the message said the Wonder Mca Caravan drivers were afraid to go after that teeth. What do mean saying, don't. Excuse. Turns around again and say, don't are tracks on a bum snowman.
Don't then phone Severino. No heat answers.
Right. I like kelly actually falls over from fear. So this is a pretty cool moment. Right? It's a neat reveal and and screws is really tricked to them into something.
Pretty pretty frightening. Those and those footprints really do look very ominous and suspense. It works really does a good job of bringing up the suspense. Earlier. That's gonna be important. Right. And and so the docks take a little bit of time to kinda reconcile what kind of terrible
mission they've been rope into
and screws reminds them that they've committed to it. So they they kinda go and and proceed up the mountain, and they they eventually get to a spot where the
snowman traps have been disappeared have disappeared marked by a steak and they're they're looking around and thinking to themselves. How could it possibly
disappear? How can you go here from here
without leaving any more footprints. So that's an intriguing way to continue this. It's also something that Barks built from the real adventures documented in the news because the footprints wood often So the docks, you know, they proceed on and on, they they go up the mountain to try to look for more trash. And and they do find them and the tracks seem to be pretty fresh. And this is where this is where Scrooge is why is gonna come back and play. Right? Because as he manages them to be quiet so that we can sneak up on them, Barks reminds us of that pocket watch with the little on
tick to.
Hey. What's the On pi in Norwegian for a clock ticking set? It would be tick
thick.
So this same.
Yeah. Yeah. It's just.
We use Tiktok as well. And and so Donald,
Donald kinda highlights the problem. He says that it out loud. He says, if you expect to be quiet, you better do something about that watch. I can hear it ticking away back here.
This this is a great Scrooge moment. Right? Make I'll tell us, tell us about this this internal debate. Yeah. And Scrooge Gladstone at his workshop
without very worried
expression and I can't do anything about till runs down. Certainly throw away thing that cost the dollar says is a great Barks.
It is. It's very silly, but it's also like it's screws and not shell. Right? He can't bring himself to throw this away. Even if it's gonna be a big problem. We we have a saying in English
penny wise and pound foolish. That's kind of what screws is like a lot of the time. So eventually, they do lose the tracks and he doesn't really have to worry about about what to do about the watch right away. And and the Nephews comment that he couldn't have jumped to another crash this time, the the monster must have either flown... He had to fly or turn invisible. And
Like Barks makes this
logical and practical
reasoning. Not the dogs ask themselves, like, Did they fly away or poke could do? Well can you just manage those Barks, of course, later we'll have a practical reason for why the snowman man is able to do so. Right. Exact. Clean. And it's worth mentioning, you know that we've left the She behind. So we're we're just the five docks.
Going steadily up this this himalayan Mountain, you know, they've got their... They've got their like version of winter gear on, but but they feel really small and really helpless. And I think that heightened the tension pretty nice. Yeah. It could be interesting to have the She out as an actual character that follows on, but he wouldn't really be necessary and Barks, of course, wesley focus on the main characters and it makes it not dangerous interest. It's it's only them. They don't have. They don't have a local to save them guide them. Right. And and they're definitely out of their elements.
So so what happens as they
as they
start to go up the mountain and and we see
slash here, screws just watch ticking again. Well, that's Scrooge is trying to... Was starting to climb up the mountains side and don't come have this little funny Barks that. Some, someday will run out of mountain.
And then huge snow slides
bur
under snow and then they dig themselves out of it and one of the Nephews say, there's snow mandate that he's trying to stop us and it seems to know exactly where we are at all time. So we never see him. And then don't of course, say that's of course, in knows where we are. You can spot this whether that com from the watch, like I said.
It's it's a fun moment.
I like seeing screws looking Al cheap
here.
And and Mick, we got another great scene here. Another very Scrooge scene. What's what's his solution? How does he wanna fix this problem? Well, it doesn't we don't want to throw away. A very expensive workshop. He decides to camp there for the nights. To give the clock some time to run down. And I like Donald comment. You wanna tell Donald comment? What's the solution? With a million dollar kronos steak, he loses a whole nice to save a book
Al it's great. This again feels like a very Scrooge moment. And I really like the drawing the art of the Ducktales like, all cozy heat up in in their campsite, you know, with the, like, special sleeping bags this a little bit of nice attention to detail. That Barks goes through. And again, we got a great comic beat here
Tell me how the page wraps up. Well, the they're snuggle look in there bag well screwed say, oh oh, and one of the boys runs server over to and what's wrong of the pittsburgh and then we here tick
I forgot some wound that com from watch.
Right.
So he's done he's the thing that I think we probably find pretty
identifiable,
right? You're like thinking to yourself Oh, I'd better I'd better go ahead and make I don't do this one thing. And then we totally absent minded
do it on on auto pilot.
Right? This is super relatable.
But it's also
it's also very funny. I also think this is the point where the gloves
disappears. For the rest of the story? Yeah. He just kinda stops
drawing their gloves in. Right? We're we're not meant to think that it's taken by the the snowman or anything.
This is just bark subtly, maybe being tired of drawing with the docks with them or perhaps forgetting and deciding, you know, not to go back.
Because most readers are not gonna notice I I didn't really notice until you brought No it also makes it easier to draw the the fingers and because the Inducks are no just running around in their everyday clothing. Right. Right? And there will probably be some scenes where they need to,
you know, use their their digits more. So I like that we don't have to deal with another day or anything
because the the problem of the clock has essentially been taken away by the next page. Because it disappears
overnight. At first, they think that it stopped ticking but then when Scrooge goes to to look for it, he realizes that it's It's been stolen and we see more of those ominous and and I I will say they're pretty scary. Those those big footprints show that the monster was in there camp last night. And so the docs go to follow him because it should be much easier.
And and
but they're gonna have a quick breakfast first to build up their strength. And Scrooge notices
Hue is the Nephew named.
Has cottage it chill. Yeah. It's also... It worth it's worth noting that Box takes time to actually have the dog breakfast.
And don't say, just a minute we can't go battling ten foot
without our breakfast.
And how many woman Cartoon were comic group routers would actually take time to to just throw this neat little logical thing to do into the story. Right. I I like that that line of dialogue on a lot. I'm glad you noted that. And and when I think about why he did that, I think
he probably
wanted this snacks I think he probably liked the idea of building
suspense by having the Nephew being
seated and developing, you know, these fear chills
because
this is a tense moment, and we need the dots to be kind of still. So that they can all
here the sound of the watch.
Ticking. It's a neat... It's a neat little a moment. Right? It definitely is
the doctors are breakfast and Scrooge is pouring up some either coffee or tea and yes.
Such she here, you have you caught a shoe and he is
looking really scared sitting there and... No. I've just got the sons in my pill air. Your watch taking, and then we her have this tiny little writing
Yeah. It's a testament to Barks storytelling,
right? That he can make that little on pi
that you can't even hear that you have to read very very frightening and very suspense. And and so Scrooge
is is not scared very long. He
decides to run at the monster behind the wall of rocks that he's stuck that. Intending to las out ham with just just a rope just to la. But again, The monster plow some snow on them. We we
as we have this whole story, we still haven't gotten Al glimpse to him. And he vanish again without leaving a single
footprint. So again, we get one of these moments where they're pondering this mystery. How could this be paused well, how can you just disappear? And then one of the nephews figures that figures it out. You wanna tell us what he
discover miguel? Well, with the
magnifying glass, that's I guess, every good will bring within wherever.
I've got it, ma'am. I sold the mystery. He explains that the snowman man covers his tricks by dragging a white animal fur behind him. See. Faint drug Barks and white tears.
And know screws looking real surprised twice. I'll be gray bearded hoop old. Make, I really like I really like the solution to this mystery. I think this is a really satisfying
explanation. You know, sometimes when you get mysteries in these comments,
the the the solution feels a little bit convoluted. And this is neat. Yeah really. And we obviously we got the the next solution to the rest of the
of how we can climb so forth. Right.
Yeah. So we're we're at this next part where the Ducktales
discover a y hair row,
and they figure out that they must be at
Scrooge calls at
his home must be at the top of the Scotch
staircase case. Al interesting little turn of phrase.
And he did I gloss over the part where he talks the first time about mid with big feet? Is that something that they alluded to? Yeah. Here one is running up with the last so size. It's probably a with big feeds.
Alright. Right. So, you know, Donald
cautions him. He he tells him, hey, that's a risky way to go calling. Even on quote mid with big feet, which he, you know, he had supposed previously is how is how he escapes so fast.
This is a word that is just not politely used in English.
Anymore. It was in totally common use at the time, so I'm not gonna like... I'm not gonna cast
any shade of Barks for using this.
But that's the only time I will use it. You know, he even had that word in, like, the title of some of a later story. But but again, we just say little person now. Okay. You know, Scrooge. This plays out pretty quickly Scrooge
sees
a harry and
terrifying looking arm reach over the edge and shake him down to the bottom
of of this ledge. Do you wanna tell us about what what happens on the next page? Scrooge only here only falls not giving Al little
Yeah. Well, Scrooge just phoned down and
he looks surprisingly happy because his home is up there. Alright. I could see the front of a cave and don't looking worried staring up the mountains and I'd say, Well, we'll have to see you strategy to get into that place. And then we get this view of of the cave and I cliffs side right outside it and the tax
noticed that there is a oppressive recipes piece
bow from which we could log or ourselves his ledge. And this row will reach Come on. Right. And so they they managed to lower themselves from above, and they're able to kinda sneak up on him. And around the bend, they actually see them on but he's covered himself with his his fur blanket.
And and Miguel, that that image to me is really chilling. Right? Because it kind of... It's it's very still. It's very suspense.
We're still at the point of imagining
what the monster looks like underneath. So I I think it's very scary. It's really it's a really area panel because we see that it is large. Is tall.
You still don't know who. What his? And so while he's outside of his cave, they're able to sneak into it and you know, find out more about him. And as they enter, we see kind of a lot of junk. Right? There's some bones and what looks to be like A mammoth tu,
some hides and some various, like, tools and implements that he must have gotten over the years.
And and it's just a bunch of cheap tri in junk as screwed says on the next page.
He seems to be a big collector of hat because he has a number of local hats there.
And then Donald allude to a jewel cole bucket. That he's tossed in the corner, calling him a dim width. And
and then we get a panel of Scrooge, just totally, like, with a very goofy expression.
Telling him that's no coal bucket you've doubled in with. That's the lost crown of Gen Khan. That's it's pretty cool. It's a very satisfying
moment where they they find the treasure. It's really nice. Al like screws tongue is hanging out his mouth. Or.
Yeah. And and meanwhile, the Nephews have been waiting outside standing lookout.
And they're getting nervous
and they're commenting that, you know, at least we'll hear the watch ticking if the snowman comes back. And then in nearly the same moment, one of them comments that he thinks he does hear it now And and the reader does see again that triple tech tick tech on a p. And when happens? Well, this huge fur blanket we have already already seen being carried, but snowman is thrown over the Nephews, and we see these large hairy arms and digits
floors
towing up the the fur into a huge. Barks
with the Nephews inside, and Barks once again, use this visual
where visual way to show them that we can hardly hear Nephew. There's the sound is muffled by this tiny little board
hell. Hell. How screwed save yourself. Yeah. Yeah. It's a neat way of of indicating the mu.
So again, we're we're amp up the fear. We're amp up the dread
the nephews have been caught and we know that, you know, screws and donald are moments away from this kind of danger as well And so and so the bigger reveal. Yes.
Yes. The big reveal, I I can I can barely
contain my self Mick from from making a
sound here?
Donald, we we transitioned back to the cave where Donald says I hear muffled sounds outside. Come on. The kids may be in trouble
and sp, you know, is still focused on the crown and and and they start to rush out.
I
I... It's really.
I'm sure that this works. I don't know if this works for you. I... This this must work for some readers. But I I think it works because I know what Barks is up to and I will go more into that in detail later with It is goofy.
Is incredibly goofy. I... I'm excited to hear your thoughts and your inside about it. But but let me let me go ahead and describe him We We see Uncle Scrooge and Donald. They've got the snowman
looming over them, and they have a very Barks draws them in a Al a astonished pose, and the snowman
stands he looks to be about eight to ten feet tall, and he's just as goofy as all get out. I mean, even if not for the fact that he's just wearing this random
launch of goofy clothes,
that the shape of his head is...
It's almost diamond shape. He has these enormous ears,
nose ring, all these mismatched accessories
all over him, a goofy little tu of hair. It is
For me, it is this weird mix of of let down
and
I mean, it's comic. It's it's goofy
and the humorous
and it sub
the the fear and the dread that we've been
experiencing for most of the story, but I I gotta a same call. I'm I'm reminded. I really like my structure for this podcast. Right? Because I've never really gone through these sequential.
And it was just a couple of episodes ago that that I covered that I covered the golden fleece six. Yeah. Yeah and this story it makes me think about the golden placing many anyways because Barks got
the editors told him that the lord... The lower were suggestive of madness and we got Al lot of complaints. So in a way, I kinda wonder if he just so I'll make this monster so as little scary as possible because of that I think I think that your position there is right. I think that must be what happened. Right? Because it's it's the same sort of situation I think that the golden fleece does such a great sense of building up.
It builds up this great sense of dread so effectively
for the majority of the story for at least the first half of the story. And then when we actually get to because, it's for this cooking.
And it's it's very invent, and it's very funny, but I do feel like it deflate a lot of that build. And I don't think this one has quite Al scary a build. Although it is, there there's a great sense of, like, creeping dread in the first part of the story.
And then it's like he just lets the air out of the room with this big reveal of this just
impossible
goof fee. Goofy creature. I don't I don't like the creature design yet. No. It's definitely not the best box. So It makes me think a little about to sleep dragon and the golden,
which also looks kinda beautiful. But
it looks cooler do is
everyone is calling
the snowman and the store good because it's one one of two war warranty you.
It can say you or reboot? Yes. But I think
he captures Scrooge and is nephews. And when they are minutes later
behind bars and looking at this legend of the mountains. I think we get to the point of why Barks choose to make making into this anti anticlimactic
screws comments, I can tell you that I'm not pleased based of what I see. It Barks cunning snowman, the legendary
of the top piece and then we switched over in the next panel to this snowman sitting there with a mirror and local screws top ups on top of his head.
Al looking at himself, like Al like a little child. Right. And it's it's a funny little comment that Scrooge makes. Right? Yeah. It definitely is and where he says, he says my hat has never sat on a smaller brain. The docs are just totally
disgusted. So, Make Al, I'm curious what, what do you think? Barb is going for here. Is is this is it supposed to be like this sort of paper tiger
situation where, you know, this this feared opponents, This feared
just turns out to be nothing. Is it like the disappointment? What what do you think he's going for? What do you think he's trying to say by doing this. I think the Barks is trying to make fun of the media and it is likely Barks or your navy or the meter
twists things.
That is why it turns the to a joke. Since the maid the other time was doing their best to this cunning beasts of terror,
and the ending makes it pretty clear that
this is what Barks was aiming for. Because the meter
fabric
stories to to sell newspapers to make people watch solution. And I would say it's a relevant subject even today. Then they need definitely make room makes thing makeup stories.
Sure. I like that take. I'm not sure. I totally agree with it, but I that's a really valid take on it. I wonder if Barks just kinda liked the idea of, you know, def our expectations like that, or maybe like you were saying he he really was trying to kind of forest stall any of that editor push back you know, you can't make him too scary.
It's almost like he feels like he now in this era and this era of storytelling. He only he has like this quota of
frightening
scenes
that he's allowed to use, and he's almost used it up, and and it's you know, the dell promise to parents doesn't isn't gonna allow for it to be that scary at the end. I I mean, I think your take is definitely right in the he is definitely
mocking the media.
But but I feel like it's... It comes more to play at the end here. Yeah. It's definitely not to be ending. Which show way to come on, but I think you're right. I think it is more of a combination of the two. It's yeah can't make it too scary. And it's always taking good care to not make it. Two series
in the old castle secrets
still keeps it
safely
on the on the children's side of
not making it into fully fledged horror movie. Right.
Edges just line a little more there. Yeah. And this time, it really...
I I think I was getting tired of power
western
of
next hate
Yeah. I I think you're right. So I am gonna I'm gonna pick it up just a little bit here. We get we get kind of this scene that I would call an and tips
seen, you know, the Inducks are worrying, they're very fearful about what he's gonna do with them while
while the snow monster
is messing around with
the things that he's gotten from them. And and he quickly figures out that the watch is something new and special, and it becomes his favorite toy because he just loves the tick, you know, we see him holding it up to his Barks. We see him seeming to dance with it and he is so into it. It he actually covers himself with his big fur blanket. So that you can focus on the ticking, which gives the docs a chance to
physically
bust
through the wooden cage
doors that they had been in. And and escape with the
with the crown and and Scrooge is top half fortunately. And so we we do have this last moment though of tension before actually escaping because when the docs arrived, they noticed that their rope is gone
that the snowman has taken it and so when they go to use his role,
he encounters them and he gives one more goo with a with a big broad smile, though. It seems like maybe he's not He's not too intimidating initially. But then he is gonna look... He's he's probably gonna look about his scariest on the next page.
Right, Mi miguel, this is a this is a tense situation tell us about it. We have Scrooge on this nephew standing right there on the edge with this huge shadow of
looming towards them with out stretch fingers and it's the bare cage for us for keep as donald and some Scrooge Barks but below money, I will never see it again.
Sure she sure has his p priorities.
He always does.
Yeah. So they're they're Inducks mu over whether
whether or not to jump Doesn't seem like a bad idea. Right? People can survive. Like falling into these snow drift. But then Scrooge has this this
idea.
This kinda reminds me of the, like, trope of of the solar eclipse, right, impress
you know, the... Maybe a time traveler predicts a solar eclipse or something. Kinda of what I was reminded of. Because tell us about what Scrooge is gonna realize. Well, the clock... It's uncle unscrew pocket Barks that's Karl
cleverly introduced in the very first panel. Now it really comes into play. Mh. Because some,
it predicts that it's gonna stop any minute now. So we it points up
Al snowman who now has this angry
expression on face it's not playing around and anymore no he's angry. Right. And,
I put on the show power watch
and
click
Right.
Very conveniently.
Runs out,
you know, this must... This is one of those watches. And
I found this really believable.
Right? Because to me, it seems
sensible. Scrooge is so invested in in his little this seems like very character with Scrooge knowing down to the second
when his watch might run out. And we got this neat little scene of him negotiating
with the monster using sign language
making a deal to put the ladder down so that they can escape.
And we get one
one last panel from a distance.
Of the snowman dancing happily to the ticking and them saying, you know, we better be far away before that watch runs down again. And
and this is gonna bring us to the final scene of the story. Make Al why don't you tell us about how it closes Yeah. We are now back into the back home Inducks bergen and we see plane in Scrooge this nephew surviving and a group of people is awaiting them and saying here comes Scrooge token and his nephews home from the Inducks crush Mountains. The papers came they had from tax the adventure. Let me true. I'm a reporter. So heavy now really get Barks commentary the media there because Scrooge coming off to the plane saying I did the folks. I recovered the lost chrome of the great king
camp and it starts to show the pointing Al the duo and explaining it there's a root
and diamond for every sixty that com. And then they get this pricing twist to depend the journalists and the people say, who and the jewels have threw on the chromebook youngest camp. We want to hear about goo, the vulnerable snowman with screws is very she is
confused
confused expression breaking the fork wall looking at the riots.
Yeah. He kinda... He he does. He breaks the fourth while he gets one of those reaction shots, those like, can you believe this folks?
As you say, it it does seem to be kind of a commentary on the sensational
media I would say it's not one of Barks strongest.
Endings. No. It doesn't have isn't really
gag more of a surprise, more of a commentary on people doesn't want truth they want a good story and right. Yeah. Even though... I mean, let's face it. Like, the actual
the treasure is is both things too. And it's the truth and it's a great yarn, but I can definitely imagine myself. Being, you know, this is encrypted if someone found a real script, I would wanna hear about it. Too. It's interesting that the story that the Ducktales story seems to have also reached them ahead of time, right, to the point where they know that he's named goo.
It's it's all it's all very goofy. It's it's it's a very silly broad ending
to
to you know, what... What's a pretty fine
adequate bark story, I think. Mh Yeah. Definitely something of Barks, absolutely strongest ones. I I personally think it's
middle of this three. It's a it's a good story, but it's more of case or is definitely not the with the plastics from the early fifties.
Yeah. We are moving out of Barks
golden nature. I'll still think it if I'm going to be strict, I would say four four eight to fifty five is per definite
golden age. But I also liked the airs of fifty six and fifty seven. I think he made many good stories there like land of the big,
indian,
Yeah. The second british stuck and land the underneath to ground. But after nineteen fifty seven, I would say it definitely has scotland to the end Yeah. Yeah. I think you're right. As you say, he's he's still gonna show, like, frequent flashes of brilliance, there's gonna be some other classic still coming up. We just don't have that, like,
consistent
brilliance
Mentally, I kinda think about, like, late forty eight through fifty five is fifty four is kind of my mental marker. But again, it's it's like it's it's like a plotted distribution graph. Right? Like,
you're gonna have... They're all kinda clustered in there, and you're still gonna have frequent great stories. This one is... It it definitely shows
some moments that are really clever. It's got some neat pacing. It's got some neat elements.
But boy. That weird monster
really leaves a sour taste
for me. It's just it's so... It's so incredibly odd and I just don't... I just don't like the creature design. I think it's that combination right of like, yes. He's goofy. And and I also don't like the creature design if if it was just one of those,
I think I would've have I would have taken it a little bit better. That's I think Barks took a little light on the research for what what's this. Yeah. If this supposedly look like he he got to tall for heads up and described it to her, but
it doesn't really look eight like either. It's more like a a brain charlotte of Barks. Yeah. It's it's very... It's kinda Huey,
it's almost like Ne and thor or something. I don't know. It's it doesn't it doesn't really work for me. I do feel like the story is pretty memorable.
You know, I like the... I like the clock ticking element of it. It's...
I I guess this is around the same time that that was a plot point in
Peter pan
I mean, that goes back. I'm I'm thinking
in the
adaptation. Right. Never smile or crocodile the dial. I I love... I love the crocodile
that swallowed the latch jumping in the captain Hooks watch
in in Peter pan, of course, that's an element from the story from a long time before. But... But it's a fun trope. You know, I like... I like this story device of being able to hear it. And it creates such a nice sense of dread. I just... It dove does feel like Al let down to me. Yeah.
I like Barks doesn't is really a good consistent running gag that ends up solving the solution like Scrooge memory pills and back to the plan is clogged in in gold clogged pores setting, mister ray like thermostats. Yeah. In that sense it is it is tightly
constructed.
Maybe a little too tightly constructed. Right? Because, like, this is Al a nineteen pager, it's pretty brisk.
I feel like I feel like it could've have... It it might have benefited from a little bit more length, but there's not too much meat to this story. So maybe that would have been padding. Well Bo does Huey, get this magical number three. I think the porch brought up three times and the final time is big year, a big solution. Right. Yeah. So that's pretty cool. Let's see.
As far as some reflect So, you know, you and I, I think I think we're in an agreement that this is, like fine I would agree with you. This is kind of an average
Barks
Scrooge adventure. And and the community would would pretty much agree with us. Right? This one this one has on index the site that we check in on to see how the community is ranked things. It's got a a score of seven point six which is good for a rank as of right now, rank one hundred and ninety nine out of all... Yeah. We're at about forty two thousand some rankings.
So you know, top two hundred, that's solid.
If you look at just the Barks stories, it's about the middle of the road for the Barks adventure story. So that's it's an average
story as far as community. Thanks. This one has... You know, you had alluded to the Don Rosa file that is
one of the cases, I think, Miguel,
where the rows of follow is much
stronger and the original Barks story. That might be maybe that's a hot take.
I'm sure there are some Barks p
that would vehemently
disagree with me. But
I think return to X do is among Don roses
very bad
stories.
Very great with you their markets...
It's different than Barks and
probably more in is a more epic story that's what's working. And
I think it's Done Done rosa best
definitely his best earlier story. Yeah. And I don't know. I it... It's probably in my top, like, two to three. I also think of his manager team Ducktales is being pretty far up there.
But it's it's a very strong story and to be clear, it is much more of a follow to trauma Al law than it is to this story, the lost crown of getting this gone. But he did something really special, I think with those two stories where he he combined these elements
in these two Himalayas set stories. In a way that feels
really nasty control, has some really strong story telling. It does not feel at all. Like he just sm them together
just because they're both Hem himalayas out like it it feels like a very thoughtful
way to to create this follow up to two stories
you know, and he connects it to the to the classic c ridge poem about Za.
Really really a great achievement of his eye. Yeah. I think it was really clever to combine them and make trouble Al lot to be not do. And Right. Also because the crown of Youngest khan is is a key element that's locked it on together is it's necessary to... Because the docs will never go back to travel willingly after after that's chester that's happened. Right?
Right. Exactly. Yeah. I I think it's one of Don roses kind singular achievements after the whole like life and times.
Story. And and then I know that, you know, Bark is famous for his paintings things and lit the graphs. But I don't think he had one any any corresponding paintings. For this one as far as I know. No. It it would mostly be fans asking for
and pictures. So I suppose no fan. One to the picture for this tour. Yeah. I don't I don't think goo. But, you know, the the obvious scene would be the the monster walking in. Right? And I don't think anyone would be too likely to want Al lavish whale painting of that goof ball. Will be fun just imagine this oil painting with the.
Yeah. Yeah. I can imagine it. And and so here's the fun element that I'm I'm kind of excited to mention. Miguel, did you... You're you're quite a bit younger than Al. So like, we're we're in we're in different generations. But as a child in nineteen eighty nine, I loved me some Disney comics.
Which, you know, I'm proud that I I am proud that I discovered the comments
before I discovered Ducktales just by a few months. But it was not the other way around, but I did. I love duck.
And and I loved my Nintendo entertainment system.
So in nineteen eighty nine, we got a duck video game on the N nes made by Cap.
Did you ever happen to plant? No and they we're really play that much with video games as as a child. It's more and later
with friends so looking to with do games. But I didn't time it doesn't a trailer that was have more old school ringing. Nice. Well, so, I mean, it it would... It would have been a pretty dated system for you. But
a lot of those old Disney games, any video game wasn't really that connected, you know, when they're representing things in eight But anyway, one of the five levels of the Ducktales
nintendo game was the Himalayas and
the the boss of the the video game level was.
Snow monster. It was not this one.
Because it looked more like classically
for ferocious. But when when you defeat him, you do earn the treasure of the lost crown of getting this card.
So it's fun to have that direct Barks reference in in a classic video game. It's also got a fun eight bit sound soft probably
probably stick a little bit of it right.
Oh and and it was definitely the most annoying level
because
screwed with c skip on his thing but you couldn't sticking no because would just
So so Mick, we we alluded to this, right? We mentions
Ducktales
but
but this is one of a handful
of straightforward
Karl Barks
adaptations that the show did.
And and they made some interesting choices for it. What what would you say is kind of the big change that they made in this one?
Definitely, the biggest french I made was to make a vulnerable snowman into the woman
snow woman.
Right I think it was a creative and much good decision for the cartoon.
Sure. And and, you know, they use the webb character it kind of it kind of made for a a little relationship moment with her.
It's also notable that
This is one of those, like adventure club
episodes where Scrooge is actually
going on a competition
to
to find this treasure. You know? So that's that's how this one is pitched, and that's why he's doing this.
The villa of that too. It kinda reminds me about Barks face building just that this one is
dog face with star is
friend of your classic humid Yeah. Toilet.
Yeah. Totally agree with you. He definitely could have been mixed wine or whatever.
The pig face
name was that leak. I I went to. I thought it was a pretty good episode, you know? It was it was in early in the run. I think it was in the middle of their for season or so. And
I don't I certainly don't love the Ducktales
show the way that I did as a kid
But but it's it's definitely...
It's it's still a lot of fun. There's still Al lot of creativity.
And and I thought that up was pretty good. Especially compared to some that I've revisited a recently.
I'm thankful for the show that's because it did bring me into the Barks classics.
Yeah. I was four years old when I first watched doctor, and I quickly got the chronic Barks and I didn't really
continue watching doctor. I think we... We only had a few episodes going on the which television. But all of them were done. So there only a few of them. This one was the first I got to see. Yeah. So I I kinda feel like that that gave this... That makes this story Al little bit more extra
extra famous just for being Inducks.
Okay. And it's probably,
you know, when I think about it, probably how a lot of American fans got into Barks
because it came out in Gladstone.
Publication of duck number one, the comic book that they had that mixed, like the Barks stories with adaptations of some of the episodes.
So... Awesome. The that sudden. It had a quick little reference to the story with the helmet of henri discount. Just
throw away reference really in the usual. Yeah. I I couldn't remember that. I didn't I didn't find anything. So I'm glad glad you mentioned that. That's gonna
they didn't make it fairly similar to Barks the same. Right. Yeah. They tend to do that. They'll, like, make it look like it, and then they'll just Al.
Yeah. In terms of the story elements, they'll straight from Let's see. I have three
there's ones that would look like Absolutely.
Because in nineteen fifty seven, the year after the lost chrome got published,
the oil magnets
thomas be slick from Texas
organized the next expedition of find the get new week paper then published a picture from Barks comic to illustrate the story on the letter page.
Bo probably kicked this out from the page paper and kept it. And that's me. It's neat little data I'll I will send you picture Barks so. Yeah. That's
Didn't I didn't catch that. Thank you for catching that. And it's funny that some people actually... There has been surprised the much critical of the story actually. Because two guys from Chile
and named the ariel do North and Arm
Metal,
I'm I'm sorry I mispronounced this, but they have a very strong political again that
published in nineteen seventy one a book called
I'll download later how
English with the title how to redo down deck with the secondary title in
radiology in the disney comic. And they worked with the portal. They translated local printing and and no Who Barks himself was So there are, of course, right and the create of
calling site
colonization and robin all the cultures
for their treasures. But the sentence of this book is afterwards I have read I I haven't read myself for with anger. And no worries that more clear done in the criticism of the assumed insults in the Los cr khan. Where David red Guru
snowman Barks
interpretation of local mongolia
people at taught fool
behaves and talks like a child willingly offering the valuable crown for worthless Barks. And this is, of course, a little unfair criticism since I'm sure the box was... This wasn't his intention. I do not read you as a
representation of locals
these Barks of create of the media there or just
goofy snowman and the
monster and also Barks strongly this live such.
Well I think you have some clever Barks or thoughts on this because apparently, I said Al one point
on the snowman preparing the when asked why does snowman preferred the cheap watch of the Golden Chrome Barks said It is a highly developed sense of what is important that prevents us all from the becoming y shall must say have some wonderful truth. Yeah. That's interesting. I'm I'm Gladstone highlighted that. I've been I've been curious about that book and I
I remember encountering it years ago or at least a digital version of it, and I was curious about reading it. For for doing this podcast.
As you say, it's a little bit of a screen. I think the problem I think it's fair to criticize Barks.
For some of his, like, very
colonial
themes.
I think you're right. Too that that grew is meant not grew. Goo that goo is meant to be he's not meant to be Huey, here. You know, he's definitely meant to be, like, a quote creature. I think. Probably something in between something in between man and eighth. And and to be clear, Barks wasn't afraid to like kind of poke fun hat and used stereotypes
of indigenous people. Just when he did it, it was, like obvious.
You know?
And and Goo is not really. He's he's. I think he's just a goofy like Barks
creation. So, yeah, that's an interesting point. That's something that chew over. Alright. So let's
let's go ahead and mention favorite panels.
Mikhail, do you have any any favorite panels that you'd like to highlight for this one? Yeah.
I think there is actually many noise panels in this and the one I would like to highlight first is on the... Not on the last page for page eighteen. On the last panel, we have a Scrooge looking
looking very clever and saying, no, as a man of magical powers, I have this abdominal
boom hulk eating out of my hand. I think that's a it's a nice and then glad don't decided to use this is the the front cover for the
publication, the Barks library and color. Yeah. You're right. That's a cool pose with him trying doing some magical fingers. I think for my part, I really like the panel where they just get that glimpse of the snowman wearing his his fur ominous, and they can't actually see him. It's it's the last, like, creepy part of the story, you know? And and it is very striking to me. I like that a lot. As you say though, there's a lot of nice ones. There's a lot of good
reaction shots, you know, Scrooge looking sheep, donald being sarcastic. There's there's still a lot to like about this one. Even if it's not one of my favorites.
No. Barks
was still
still on top of his game, the character the design, I would say, the Ducktales still it's still small. They don't got long legs
and sure later gets.
Right.
Excellent.
Alright. And any other any other thoughts before we wrap it up? Yeah. Just have one one quick little thing and mh. It's interesting that Barks wasn't the only artist that got inspired by the whole
thing going on because the Belgian Cartridge interior would make his own story to that in nineteen fifty eight to fifty nine. The creative of team twenty zero along with cap heather to find them in search of ten lost friend, Shu
shen. So, yeah. It's cool that also boulder
pretty much from the same time decided to send their heroes on a quest for to best. Absolutely.
One of one of the other most famous comment.
Creations around that era.
Haven't read... Haven't read Tan myself I'm more of an asterisk fan. But.
But I know a lot of people. Hello. Lu been. Excellent. Well,
thank you very much for joining me Miguel. To go over this story. There's a lot of interesting stuff to talk about, I think.
And and people can always check your your fan art out if they'd like too. Right?
I'll share it on
on Facebook, but I believe you are
say it again?
Hog technique. Right. So it's it's your name, and then the word draws
in
Norwegian. Right? So it's m I k k e l h a g e n and then n an s, And then how you spell tech Ci again?
Tech Ninja.
Is t e g n e r. Yes. Excellent.
Alright. Getting better at that. Yeah. So H,
So yeah. Check checkout check out, mick miguel at you're on
Instagram Yeah. But I I cannot wonder if I should make an a different
page and Instagram just for.
Sure. Is that weird accept the since not not a bad idea. And then we we have our own socials where
we post on Facebook
and Instagram and Twitter Bark remarks and check us out next time, we will cover... Oh, this is gonna be a nice milestone
story. We get cover the second richest duck, very excited for that. Mi, you wanna close this out by by reading
the last
dialogue
death again. Yeah we have the last panel and the journalists saying oh, fo on the Chrome of Ka khan, we want to hear about gi. They're vulnerable snowman man, acts.
Thanks again, Miguel. Thanks for helping work.