We can have
Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer an artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comments of all time. Join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks. Welcome back to Barks remarks, I'm mark Sever, a grown man who loves duck comics, and I love to have guests on so that I can indulge myself and talk about great Carl Barks stories. I... We've got a real
day. I'm really excited about it. And I'm I'm also really excited about my returning guest
dan can you introduce yourself and just remind us your
remind how you feel about these comments?
Sure. Well, first of all, it's a pleasure to be back and thank you for having back again, especially for such an important story like this one. Mh. And, yeah, I am a professional
illustrator and designer, and I've been a very big
supporter of all the Disney comic book work
especially in the past twenty fifteen, fifteen years where we kind of ran dry in the early two thousands and the comics
sort of faded away when the Internet got to be very mainstream.
And similar along the way, all of the stories came back and all of them became revived got restored and
had regular comic book publishing. They had some new material
and graphics came along and established the Carl library in a very affordable format.
Yeah. That's
that is definitely worth... I I will echo that. Right? They don't they don't sponsor us or or. Thing. But but we're happy to suggest that people get the fan graphics collections. You know, it's it is hard to get a hold of Disney comics these days. They're not being printed in the states anymore. So the Carl Barks library collection, as well as those really cool Disney masters. Yeah. Collections that they put out. That's that's basically what we get now. Yeah. And actually, the nice thing is, you know, you know at the moment, status, there's gonna be two uncle Scrooge specials coming out hard cover editions
within the next couple of weeks in November of twenty twenty two. Those of you listing in the future. Mh it's gonna be we're gonna be receiving the uncle screwed. I think it's called the diamond j, the seventy fifth anniversary edition. That's gonna have a lot of
reprinted Barks classics.
And then there's gonna be a bit of an omni this edition call, Donald Inducks and Uncle screwed bear. I think it's called Barks Mountain Adventures. Is that the name of it Right? Yeah. I think it might be bear mountain stories.
That's I think that's right. Yeah. With that's another large hard back collection, and that's gonna have several different orders. If stories sit on bear Mountain, which goes back to the first appearance of Scrooge Inducks.
Which is a really nice idea. Right. Yeah. It is interesting. I didn't I didn't actually realize how many artists had had their own take on on the Barks Mountain setting. I think I've only read Barks Rosa and and the the Daniel Bro story. I know I that read. Yeah. So so by all means, people should definitely
definitely
support the Fan graphics
collections.
It's it's great work and it's it's one of our
one of the best ways to keep Carl Barks
relevant at another great ways this podcast I'd I'd like think. And
and and it's so nice to have the chance to, like, actually talk about stories that I've spent so many years thinking about Dan Today, as you said, we were covering a. We get to talk about the second richest dot And this story is notable, of course, for for... Who are we? Who's joining the chat Dan? So this is the first appearance
of the second Richard duck Barks Glen gold he officially
makes his debut
and in maybe the most aggressive fashion possible.
You've never seen any other character really kind of match Scrooge in this way in terms of style in terms of temperament
and in terms of Al,
Yes. Yes.
Al
himself, if this is his very first appearance, it's kinda weird to think that it's gonna be only one of three times that he
he appears in a Barks story. But the this is one of the last, I guess like big original characters that Barks was responsible for. You know, we're where we are now, we have not yet encountered magic could this spell.
Sure. But I guess I I'd say those are the big three. Right? Where we got... We we've had plenty of the beetle boys. Yep. Since the storm practically, they've been... They've been there. Ryan, yeah... Oh like, you say, only shows up three times,
you know, in a very memorable sense, you almost wonder if Barks didn't wanna place in the well and you go overboard with it. Because he did, you know, the funny thing about Flint card is A couple of years later, Barks had that very tall Texas cowboy
billionaire called long horn tall grass.
Remember him, there was a gag story with him, and then he showed up again in the twenty four karat moon when they were racing to the moon.
That story you'd almost think Heart would have been a really good, you know, foil to have built a rocket try and take care of that later. Sure. I was thinking of that earlier and then I realized that should knowing knowing how Barks crafted because twenty four car, I really luck the conclusion to that story. I know you'll get to it and future episode. So I won't blow the ending for anyone. But it is... But adding flint hard into the mix there, it kinda makes a little more personal I think it would take the edge off of the
moral
conclusion of that story. Yeah. I think that's right. I think his presence almost might have distract to... Yeah. Because again, then you would... It was just would've have been another
competition in terms of a race or measuring of wealth.
However, the funny thing is now a couple years previous to this, we had the
of how you stand during the Right
one of my favorites
stat us. Spend threats. Right? And that was kind of the
light template for what we're about to talk about here today. The difference being that during that match, Scrooge was never really worried. He didn't sweat it at all. Right kinda He he knew the mah only had so much. This is the first time that someone's really risen to his level and you see him like he's not really at ease with. The fact that, like, not only is this guy like kinda getting in his lane, this guy's kinda copied and his entire stick. Right. It's it's a really fun concept.
So so we got kinda two things in one here, Dan. Right? We got two,
I guess, classic, like, tropes or story archetypes. That that really resonate. We got the competition story. That... That's the thing that's the thing about Flint hart, but that's what he's notable for in these couple of stories, that Barks uses him in. It's it's the these money face off. These money competitions. That's kind of his whole real reason for exist. And then this is also a do game or story. A trip people are really interested by the idea of of the do or the person, you know, your exact matt somewhere. Yeah. The the broken mirror version of yourself or
get the protagonist in this case. The funny thing is, you know, I... I was looking this a yesterday. This pre dates Vis bizarre Superman, which I didn't realize. Oh, that's a good a good reference to point out. Yeah. Yeah. Because, like, they... You know, Dc did... And they the were reverse slash. They had a couple things of that nature. This three dates Bizarre by, like, two years, even the what was it Mirror mirror episode Star trek again know, the Evil version.
Think he evil go spa. This one... Yeah. This would definitely pre day that. Right? Y. Yeah. By this... By by a identity Barks.
Mh. And the funny thing is if you look at their appearance,
now, you know, Long has sorted of this
crooked, probably, you know, like a like, a you know, like, a weather
piece of wood as a cane screwed just that kind of, you know, gil age sort of
monopoly man sort of straight cane, which really contrast their personality alone. And Glen is at actually a little bit more of a smart dresser he has sort of an Es. He has, like, a nice black blazer. He does where the the tam
However, he is after by origin. And the interesting thing I found is that even his bill is sharper. His bill is very similar to glad stones at least by way of Barks. Mh. Where Scrooge is sort of that rounded donald and his glass the frames of his glasses are darker. It's that again, that contrasting thing where he's
he's... Like you say he's sort of that evil Do version where Scrooge screw just has the whisk but Glen has the full beard. Alright. So... I'm gonna go off on just a little bit of a ramp here. Yeah. Because, you know, you said that and and it's it's at and he's the evil do or he's like he's like the wario to to Mario or thing. Right? But but really, he here's something that I'd like us to pay attention to as we go through the story, I think you you see that come up a lot in in comments
writings and in books about, you know, Barks or on the Internet that people won't know that he is he is basically the evil version of Scrooge. And that is true, right, except it's only true
retrospectively. If you look at him across his three Barks appearances,
and what other creators went on Yes. To to do. Because, like, if you actually take a look at this story and isolation as though we're reading it when it first comes out, and it's the only story we have to go by Guam. He is really not coded
as evil
or as a bad guy in this one. He really truly is.
Scrooge just like mirror image in this one, and and there are moments where it'll be a little bit crafty
and and a little bit under handed, But
Bark is very pointed to to give Scrooge these, like hangs of ambition where he's a little bit more ruthless, than he would normally be So that I'd like to pay attention to that because I think I think at least the is this original
incarnation here. He's really not that bad of a guy, he's not noticeably
more evil,
more,
Scrooge screwed himself it. You're
really that's absolutely
apt perception because he's... They're really on equal footing. The only difference is that, you know, Gru has the home ground advantage because Alright. In Africa Scrooge jazz the benefit of his family helping him out. Yeah. So... That definitely does. That definitely is going to soften him. Right? He's got he's got his family around to help him out and maybe raining his is a little. I don't mean to be all like justice for Glam gold or anything. People are it's accurate to think of him as that sounds like a hash tag. Yeah
But but when you when you just look at this one in isolation, I think the reason that the reason that this story works
so well. And and I'm I'm gonna lay it out right here. I love this story. This is a tight great later Scrooge adventure. This one works
So well, I think the reason that it works up so incredibly well is that they are these mirror images. It it it is so fascinating to see Scrooge
meat
himself, basically,
and and see see some of the discomfort register.
On him, even if he doesn't quite understand what's happening. Absolutely I so... And this... Like you said, the evolution, like, let's we can talk about other incarnation after, but Yeah. The evolution of the three stories Barks did, you don't see Flint card become morally bankrupt until somewhere in the next story. Right. Then he turns by the third story. He's Al flat out. He's absolutely the scam draw. Yeah. He's vis he would and he was out to kill basically.
Right. But like, you said here, it's, you know, you you kinda see this at the... This is the spark that got the
going but, like you said, it he's not... Yeah. He doesn't want anything. It's
this is a matter of pride. And this is a matter of their, you know, their own personal title. Right. So an excellent pro log excellent pre dan, let's talk a little bit about the story itself and it's creation So we are into the later half of the fifties now. We're in the the covered date of this story is July of nineteen
fifty six. And we're in Uncle Scrooge, number fifteen.
And you and I were talking, and I noted that this one has quite a few reprint.
It makes sense, you know, it's an iconic villain, and I a fairly iconic character.
It's had fourteen fourteen printing and including the original in the United States. Okay. And it's a it's it's a fairly short adventure story. It's a twenty pager But
I I think it's really tight. I don't I don't think it suffers from being too short or anything like that. No. I would... You know, I'll tell you. I wouldn't have mind it another two pages of just more, you know, string bun yeah. Throughout the throughout the Savannah. But it's it's really... It's compact, and it also doesn't... It takes its time when it needs to within those twenty pages, which is nice. Right. And one thing I wanna just point out is
I wanna just remind the listeners that prior to the comics
career. Barks was a gag man at the Walt Disney Studio. He was a... What is really a story board artist now. And when you're devi things for the screen especially in the mid to late thirties, there's a lot of visual gigs. There's one in here in particular that only someone in animation would have devised, and it Barks so beautifully, I will I will point it out when we get to it. But Yeah I think I I have a feeling I know it's when you're talking about. But yeah But we'll put a pen in that I'll see. Let's
see. I was gonna sit... Hey, what do you think if we did the, like, old
family feud thing and asked a hundred people to list Carl Barks characters.
Right? Characters that Barks his most famous for. Where do you think Flint heart would be on that list? I mean right with it... It's got any uncle Scrooge. Mh. Is isn't number one. Mh Right. Probably g Gear list number two? I would think so. After that, you would pick off the wood trucks count. Yeah. That
gonna... Right. Right. You know? But I think Magic is right under them. I was thinking the beagle boys might might be the the first villain on...
I mean, they do It's hard. It's it is hard. Because I you know what if you gave people like a key of, you know, fifty characters and instead are alright here are fifty characters, which do you know Right. That, you know, It's hard. But, yeah, I I feel like he would... I mean, he's definitely in the top ten, but he may be number five. Yeah. I was thinking he'd be somewhere around, like, five, six seven. He... He has such an interesting space to me. I'm really fascinated by the fact that Barks just used in those three times. He feels he he oc has much more of, like he he has a way
space in the sort of Disney comics.
Sphere. Yeah. That lot of my a lot of people pardon the upon Al on to and a lot of people really used him. At Bike car really used him a lot as I recall. Mh. From the from the from the
Burgess, the reprint during the glad. I know there's a lot of There's a lot of and brother used them quite a bit too. There was a couple of really good ones to used to for. Yeah. You. Practically name a a Disney comics artist and there's a great chance that they use Long more times than Barks. Yeah. I... The only person like I'm trying to think I don't think Sc but used him very much. I think he was more with them Rock duck at all. Right. Yeah. The Italians loved love them some some John rocker docs. But, yeah, It was it was more... I think one of the scandinavian
countries that really, like, really lean into long.
But and... But again, they had a good... The the... The nice thing for them to have the only the three stories they could kinda take it into different directions they could kinda flush them out it which because you got you got different different iterations of him. He's he's kind of a different character. In each of the three stories. Yep Alright. You know, the only little bit of trivia that I think I'll mention right now is that that there is this weird brief little illusion
to the second rich stuck in the world in an earlier ten pager, like, totally unrelated to this one. There's it's in... It's in the story turkey with all the scheming,
which I've been thinking about putting out as Christmas
episodes. Oh, is that the
the
baloney. Yes. Yes. Who Donald poses as is is mentioned.
As being the second richest stuck in the world. And specifically Inducks, right, not the man, but I think we're we're to understand that when Scrooge says the I'm the reach stuck in the world. He is... He is counting himself as the richest quote human. That's always been my reading. I really I also really like the title for this one. You know, I I like that it's it's unclear
until you get to the end who it's actually referring to. Mh. And
Yeah. I think I think I'm ready to go into our little international segments.
Sure.
Because this... I... I'm excited for this dan. I love to to my international listeners. You know, this this podcast is as much for the Western Europeans, the scandinavians
and and whoever else around the world is listening to me ramble about ducks in English. I say I think they love it as much as we do collectively even more So... Yes. Yes. They they love their Inducks,
and and they keep these stories alive. So so what I like to do is I like to run through what some of the titles from around the world are. But but in this one I was thinking to myself Huey, Long has such a cookie key and fun name. Right flint heart Guam. That's part of the That's part of the genius of the character.
That it it evo hard harden flint part. And then Guam gold is like money grabbing. So he's up upright. He's a hard hard money grab. So... And also, you know what funny is it? A Barks used Guam, a lot. He used as sound defect. Somebody was passing by and grabbed something on the way Guam was always a part of the caption. I always enjoyed that. It's a great word. It's it's one of a handful
of a number of words that I have in My vocabulary and mentally think about solely because of the Barks. Yeah. No. He because you know what he does inform our a vocabulary and often are kind of conscious thoughts. And. Yes something I mentioned you earlier was there was a dick... There's an Al to Dick Tracy during the earlier
Chester Gold newspaper strips. His name was Vitamin Flint heart. He was kind of a middle aged desk being very air died. But he always took a up very contemporary now. He could took a lot of supplements
vitamins, and that was well before this, this is fifty six. I think he appeared in early relief the early forties. Barks was a pretty avid reader of newspaper comic strip especially the serial immunizations. I'm guessing that's where Flint heart came from Unless those dime novel from earlier in his youth
when he was a, you know, when he was a young younger guy. Yeah. It seems as likely to me as anything. I mean, he's he's had fifty some years of being an avid reader of National Geographic and serial economics. So of course, it would bleed in. Alright. So I am going to mention a couple of the titles from around the world. And then Daniel and I can kinda take our hand at some of the iterations of Blonde gold name. So let's see. I really enjoy the one from
Netherlands
where the story is called D
Von Huey,, which is the tango of greed
And stretch. Yeah. It is. I I guess, I it must refer to the the string getting it tangled up. A couple of these stories will just end up being basically Scrooge versus Guam gold. Mh.
So hold off on those. I liked Italy. Italy, we've got
in the monetary
tournament.
And then Norway is ph and colon.
Scrooge gets a competitor. Oh all highlights lights. Spain which was just called Los
Y.
The two the same. It must be some kind of like,
or expression or something. Yeah. It sounds like an independent film. Know right? Alright. So so the real the real bit that I'm excited about. Let's let's go over a couple of the character names.
What do you got dan? So in Germany, long gold name translates
to Matte money.
And that that is his name.
Not money stock. Yeah. That's awesome. I really like in a couple of the scan
countries they're they're pretty similar.
It is.
So it sounds still like flint Barks. But I gather that gold his gold and he Eva evo is is a name, but it's sounds kinda like hard hearted or something like that. If you know the line... Old hard. Yeah. Right. And then how about Italy? So Italy, his name is Cor,
Sum,
and we had looked Al up a few moments ago. And did we say it was basically old heart.
Right. It was like
Was gold hot Golden Hunger, Barks stone. We're guessing. It's like stone hearted money grab. Right. Wow. Yeah. Which is great. And France,
so screws is named p sue. Right? Mh. Am I pronouncing that right? I think Yep. That's I believe that's that's... Because I know Ducktales and france is likely bundy peace. Right. So they call him peaks to and and they went with a I name for Long. He's
grape you. So the story was called Pete sue called the Groups you. And he's called A
Grip zoo. And and I like that. Yeah. And I gather that
grape
I think it might... So sue, I think is like a word for coin. Right like old French. Right? So greek maybe be grab. Right. Yeah. I think I think so.
What else do that? This is your Facebook. Your your Facebook list just have to chime in and give us their if anyone from from any of those respective countries, should really give us like the, you know, the breakdown
Right and let us know if we're close completely off days. Right. Because, like, we can translate it, but but sometimes, you know, there's there's a little flavor of that translation that we just. Aren't gonna know. And I'm sure there's one. To this too. Just like On. I can't imagine that's translated anywhere else in the world. Yeah. If for for international listeners, if you don't know, the word Guam, It does mean to grab something, but it's basically
unused
in English. Right? It's it's it
a very, like, frantic
guess matching something snatch.
Exactly. Let's see. There was
Brazilian Portuguese
was a
Mac money. So they're kinda going with, like, a Scottish name there. I? And
did I mention
dead
in in Dutch, he's called Gov
good Gladstone.
And I just didn't have the chance to look that one I that... Yeah. And they're going with the
there.
So anyway, lot of fun. He's a mouthful.
He's a pain in the butt in any language.
So let's let's do it. Let's dive into this story itself. So dan, the second richest dot I I... This this story is so great. It's got a really great opening
It it's the rare Scrooge story where we start out outside of the money Bin. Screws is just out and enjoying the day. And he encounters his nephew Donald Duck on his way somewhere in a hurry, and he warm costs him asking
Donald where he's off to and Donald tells him that he's he's on his way downtown. He's gonna get a tall cool gooey ice cream soda. And this is this leads into...
I think this is the first time we really get this dynamic. I mean, it was kind of introduced in only a plural man. Right where Scrooge is like lobbying donald to his kind of lifestyle. But but this is this is kind of the icon difference. Between Donald and Screws. Right? Scrooge is gonna do this thing where he tries to convince Donald not to waste his money on, like, f volley.
And it's a very
philosophical
thing. Right? Because Scrooge is like he's trying to convince him you're gonna get so much more satisfaction if you save your money.
And Donald
he... He's clearly content with the idea of
spending his few coins on a few nice world pleasures.
We we get some really good dialogue and some great great poses some awesome pain jab from Scrooge as he badger and button the holes donald telling him
telling
dan every every bit of dialogue here on this opening page, every exchange between Scrooge and donald is so great. He yes. Him why. Why? So does cost money. Think it nephew.
Donald says I did and I still wanna soda. And and it goes on to say you should never put your stomach out of your personal boy. Invest that two bit and it'll will become fifty cents at compound interest. Donald
goes to say, I know I know and but dollars aren't eat like ice cream sodas.
This is classic call and response comedy team.
Level every it's, you know, one state
you automatically have a snappy answer for. Yeah. It's it's very fast. It's a great bit of dialogue. It's why I'm tempted to read this whole darn page, which is something that I almost never do. Now how many... I'm gonna do it. I'm gonna read this last panel here.
He says, I'm a ashamed of you, Donald. You're a wasteful and a spam lift to donald. I'll just create gives this great shrub I know, but it's the only way I can get sodas. I love it. That... I don't think there's been a single page that has ever kind of delineate
the the difference
between Scrooge and Donald.
As it really... It really works well. Because it just it down, it's it's entertaining, but you get the exact idea of which if never read any of these before. This breaks everyone down perfectly.
I also like the fact that, you know, we're we're in nineteen fifty six. Even only a portal man for it's this this really cemented because now we're in the air like alright. There more Tvs easy and homes, everyone has more leisure your time, everyone has a little more extra money.
And Scrooge just from that industrial era and from the, you know, from the error of need from the error of being scrappy and frugal. And Donald is just at this point in life where it's like no. There are simple pleasures and I'm there for them, I wanna watch Tv. I want to drink a nice
soda I wanna go to a ball game and I wanna lay in a hammock. Yeah. That is that beautiful contrast that that shows here in in... And digit, but it's just it's done in such an entertaining way. And like you said, the Cain jab I think there's...
Just Severino I think they're three out of five panels just regain, which is great. Right. So we we transitioned to the next page, and they're basically
almost casually, if not accidentally wondering towards the bin, and there's... Yet another call in response and this next panel
screwed pulls out his first time. It's not the first time we've seen it. Nor it'd be the last
there's a lot of Barks referencing his own stories.
Within this story, which did not happen terribly often. He yeah. Really references a lot of the stuff he's done in the past the dine being one of those devices.
As well as they're heading up towards the bin, which is on in this in the case of this story, It's on Kill hill still. It's not as steep as it often is but the port carlos is there as they enter the bin, and you can see,
Donald is just basically being yank into another economics lesson. Mh.
And Scrooge takes me to the bin and even though Donald seen it before. There's this lovely panoramic panel and Scrooge just
Spread arm says there you see. This has made me the richest stuck in the world, owner of three cubic acres of money, un accountable oil well gold mines or railroads,
factories,
and fish houses. And, of course, Donald Has to.
And I bet you've never enjoyed a soda in your life
because that younger generation is always gonna sas and sure enough screwed just get out On wasting my time with you. You have no appreciation for the finer things in life. And as he kinda scoot his nephew out, they passed by a giant ball of string. Yeah. The the signaling on this story, the the the fore foreshadowing on this page is really great. Right? Because it's it's done with a lot of care
more care than more care than Al have done and some of his stories. Right? Because again, it's very natural the way he points out that first time and Donald points out oh you sure do have it. It's tied to you with a string even.
So, you know, Barks is boxes is telling us right away, he's signaling that... He even has Scrooge mentioned. I saved string too in case you can imagine anyone being that thrifty So we get these, like, three references to the strings saving on this second page. It's great setup. I didn't see a lot dan about, you know, Barks thoughts on this story, but but I did see in or was it. That was in the infant graphics.
The commentary mentions that Bark had said, he had the string idea early on because he had remembers
years before saving tin foil and string used to be quite a thing. Doesn't say so directly there, but I'm I'm imagining that must be referring to the depression. Yeah... Well, you you gotta think the depression and also growing up in a very rural area. You know, these parents were
really pioneer people. So, you know, even if New York and Chicago were in a gil age that were they were in the Pacific Northwest, like they probably had a general store, and that was it. And they were probably.
Trading with farmers and local. So if they got something tied up with string, I'm sure they saved it. I imagine the Barks family would have been right conservative. And and that's what the quote goes on to say. You said, we always
string around the house. We didn't have Scotch tape so we use string for holding things together. Some people carried it to the point of seeing how big a ball string they could accumulate. Oh, and apparently, that was quoted in the
celeste arts. His life and Times book for me. Yeah. Okay. That's... Yeah. That's right that would have been in there if that makes good sense. So it... It's interesting to think about Barks kinda chewing over this idea, You know, of of taking it from there. And if you think of how, you know, how the country was at, you know, the first twenty, you know, the first twenty years of the twentieth century, there had to be a lot of people doing exactly that. That had to be fairly common. It was probably really relatable too just coming, you know, ten years after the end of World war two or eleven years after the end of of World war too, where there was a lot of that rash. Going on.
So onto the third page, this sequence is all about Scrooge
stew and his
His relationship with newspapers, we see this a lot where Scrooge is unwilling to buy a newspaper. He walks through town, fuming that he's the richest Inducks in the world and just knowing that makes up for all the tall cool busy sodas that I've missed while getting that way. And that's gonna be an important point. Right? That's gonna be a lot of the justification for what happens down the
into the story. And so he passes a newspaper boy, you know, classic something that's a great time capsule thing.
And he tells him to take it away, he never buys his newspapers since they cost ten cents. This is one of those many references to him getting his papers
in the parks.
And when he finds a recent one,
this a great line.
I love this Dan. He says, here's one that's only two days old. That's better than the one I found yesterday, which was full of news about the nineteen o six birth quick. And and here is where he learns the detail that sets the whole story into motion. The
headline, the the story and the paper reads Flint heart Guam, the fabulous
South African Line owner is now the richest Inducks in the world. And
knocked out. Yeah. Oh, man, Dan, what do you think about about these panels?
Where where he's just days and and and just dead to. The head. Yep. Yep. The head spinning in he's slow over. I, you know, his his hat is actually, like, dangling off his foot. He's absolutely... He's got the sweats. Like this is... You you rarely see him this
shook. Yeah. Something. And it gets this this is this is the first time that someone's actually like in its kitchen. Right. Right. Someone's just really gotten into his head because it's in the papers it must be true.
He goes on to read his discovery of a vein of Pure gold and his newest mine has pushed his fortune past with one multiple Al nine of squad Al Barks. So this this is another mark in my occasional series where we take note of Scrooge just like
where Barks will actually
describe his net worth with with totally changing figures. Boy, I'm reading a lot, but there's a lot of great dialogue here this is gonna be... This is Al line that's gonna get echo look. He thinks to himself in a days. That ups start that Johnny come completely. He can't do this to me. And as we, you know, as we close this stage, it's screws just... He's walking off of the ten yard stairs. He's he's not doing. Right? And we get to the next page. He is just kinda like he's he's sort of just rejected. He's sniff into a hank of in a way we've really never seen before.
Life won't be worth living now that I've lost the money championship and. If I have and he kinda runs with a little bit more courage back to the Bin because he hasn't checked up on his own fortune about a week, and you see his very exhausted clerk in a sea take tape Scrooge dashes,
Clerk Clerk, what is the latest daughter of my wealth berkeley replies. Fantastic sir, completely fantastic I have it right here. And again, you can only see us clerk from the chest up because the took tape is just that. It is just the c. Oh, the total value of all your minds mills, money vincent and so forth is one multiple jillian
nine of sq v.
Sp,
six hundred and twenty three dollars and sixty two cents which
turns the tables completely this is now on over the abs quid... Oh of boy.
Obstacle quick million mark. I'm not a second class millionaire yet, and that's a lovely victory pose. That's a real it's
fluid fluidity
but I love and this this kind this just sleep in the air. Oh, yeah. But with, you know, with that... That's very much Al Don test kind of opposed right there. He could he really stretches the du out, and I really love to see see them really brought to their extremes like that. Yeah. I I would really encourage people to take a look at each of Scrooge
expressions on this...
What are we on? Just the fourth page here? Yeah. But and and he has some page, we we he basically you ran a gamut of a emotion. Actually, this whole page, he's running every emotion possible. Oh, yeah. That going further ahead.
Because. And yeah. That you you read it. That is
you know, the previous one was Guam gold net worth. But I noticed in this one that it ends on
with sixty two cents. It's usually
sixteen cents. Yeah. Which I think sixty just a funny number. Right. Barks
obviously does to house. So no. This might be the only time he references it. I don't I don't know. It's certainly the first that the clerk mentions
the value of all your minds, mills, money bin.
He says money bin plural. And that's one of those things where, like,
fans and other artist have kinda speculated. Well, you know, that bin is is not... Probably couldn't account for as whole fortune That's been one of those things where people have
supposed in some stories that, you know, this is just his main bin with his nostalgic money. Right. Yeah. This is like his photo album. Right. The interesting little aside. Because I think there have been some people have used like, they downtown. They reserved bins and things like that. So... Yeah. And that's that's kind of an... Again, there's you know, there's never gonna be a definitive anything, but you can kinda... You know, I always take these things to face value. Damn I love the end of the page where he he says he's gonna match him mine oh, it's it's great rioting. Do you wanna read that panel? But well, yeah, he he basically, he points to him map on the wall and he decides to have a show down with Bernard Gone gold and your your caf I'll match in mind from mind mill for million and dime for dime until we know exactly which one of us is the richard Inducks and slammed is fist on the desk with the sack money and the coins go like, with the word exactly, that's what they that's where fifth meets the... Yeah. Yeah. Did per base of the desk It's a really great one. And then again, just going back to the running every possible gamut of emotions,
then you just see him kinda lean slumped back in his office chair, and he's just exhausted because he did indeed run every gamut of a emotion, and he asked the clerk to book passage for his nephews because they'll need them to carry him home if he loses.
Right. And the very idea
him Well great build that So we transition with all of the Inducks
heading to Africa.
We're gonna take a ship And
this sequence is very cool. This one has Scrooge
This this is where we see that it's a passage for the Ducktales hand the ball of string. And and Scrooge is talking about taking along the list of everything that he owns to to be able to match against Guam gold. And when an nephew queries why he's bringing the ball of string, he says, this is the only way he can keep saving things while he's on board. He goes to
to point out a piece of string that he can wind onto to his ball.
This is a great little Gladstone stick bit where the string just keeps whining and winding. It ends up being a very long piece of string. And one of the nephews rounds the quarter. To see where it's coming from. Any yelp run for for life on bridge. You're unwinding some other string Severino ball of string.
And to and we see... I mean, I'm gonna describe him with the energy that the story presents him. Right? We see an older duck with mu chops, pension nes, spectacle,
What would how did you describe that hat? I think that's a Tam. A ham. Yeah. You're right. Al Tam S. Is that what it's called? Mh.
A ham hat
He's an older duck He seems to be, you know, and combo lasting a little bit under a quilt and he looks up a gas to see this ball of string. So he's not named. This is obviously
flint heart guam gold, even even an
sophisticated
reader even a child reader probably...
I think there's a good chance that they're gonna pick up on that. Right? Yeah. But I think it's been telegraph pretty pretty easily. And has.
Right, the Ducktales do not know it, but but we're signal because we never encounter Inducks
that look like Scrooge. This the first time we've been presented with this.
It's great. It's it's inn, but it's this nice little
kind of almost wink wink nudge nudge. For foreshadowing, I think. But but you know, it's it's also entirely possible that the reader didn't see it coming. Too because Barks does put some odd ball characters out sometimes in in his stories. That just background.
That's true. That's through because even... Yeah, about even the... You know, even the news boy. On the previous stage, he was pretty well designed, you know, for something as as a one off, you know, inn thing. Right. It could be... It could be a throw way. Yep. But we get to the next page now the
The other passenger with the ball string is not having it, and he's basically kicking chasing Scrooge up and exhaust pipe on deck and it is... And the this... The moment these two go face to face, it is just... It isn't... It's our they're already clashing. They don't even realized they they're the ones who were coming after afterwards. It's the inverse of the the h shield. I I love... Loved you before I met you Right? They they hate each other before they manage each up.
So Donald just Barks that when lot of string local Scrooge won't save. Is one of the nephews supplies. It's some character, but that's our Scrooge And finally, it causes Huey, to kinda lean against one of the cabin and say, yep, that's our uncle Scrooge.
I wonder what S Al gold is like.
And some days later, the Ducktales learned in the valley of the Limp
they have a rented car and they're pulling up to a very familiar looking structure of a money pin almost identical. Just Scrooge.
And is it... Now is that a pound, the dollar sign is Al a pound, or is that a random do you think? Yeah. That's a pound sign.
Yeah. That's the pound. Right? Because
this was this was part of the British empire. Where where is the limp po? Do you know? So really, we're looking at
South
Africa. The River runs Southeast Africa. This is also not far from... Or not terribly far from Kimberly, which is the largest diamond in mining area in the world. Right. And that is...
I think that's one of the reasons Barks chose to make K African
was the connection with Diamonds If there wasn't a nefarious
context to it, I know even At this time, there was a lot... What they call blood diamonds or conflict diamonds that were smuggled out and the profits of which were used to funds civil wars. I'm guessing that might have inspired Barks to set it in Africa for that very reason beyond the diamonds and also just to get them out into the
Savannah. Yeah. I mentioned there's a lot of fortunes
that were made. I think I think Barks just has a little bit of a fast an issue two with South Africa, you know, he loves to reference the borrower war canon and. Yep. That's right. That's right. Yeah we're gonna that right here in the moment. Right. I I knew that it was South Africa. I didn't know exactly where. I just looked it up just so people know. It is in the northeastern
part of so out Africa. As you say in okay Yes. But but you're right. It's it's in the south. It's it's... Well I guess to be in the southeastern part of yeah.
Funds in it. And it's just on the border of boats botswana. Mh. And it's
it's... You know, and again, you You go back to nineteen fifty six. You had to think it was even more un contained at parts. Right. So if you if you... There's some sub too. Right? Like it Barks, this is never a thing in the story, but I guess it's unavoidable that like Flint heart is definitely coded as, like, quote.
Right. So so he's definitely part of the
minority
population. Mh. In South Africa
that is that that would go on later. That would go on to perpetuate a part. Not I'm not I'm not calling I'm not calling flint hearts.
Out in that respect. It's just that that is like, that is the energy. Right? That It would have been, like, a land owner he would've have... He would have been an... A big big time exploit
in this... Of of the workforce. And again, he he... He would have been more likely to have maybe participated in some illegal sales
smuggling or mining operations. Right. You know, we never get there, but you could see that that might be within his character. Mh. And and I think if we think if we open ourselves up to thinking about the other two stories, that's definitely a fair sub position. Right. But you see that again, the similarities are
cycling right down to the port palace. Now the funny thing you just mentioned, Donald says Well no doubt he's copied a lot of your ideas,
and the moment he knocks in the door the or war canon pops through. Now the funny thing here is Number one, we didn't see the Canon in this story at Scrooge office, but we've seen it several times before in previous stories. Right? And the really interesting thing here is what I'd said earlier, this is kind of Barks power in the self, which I really think is a remarkable turn here. Because for someone who didn't really, you know, go with hard continuity of his own work, this is enjoyable as it is. With a cold read. If you've read the earlier Barks work, this is twice as funny. Oh, yeah. It's it's totally additive. Right? And and you feel like Barks is is kinda taking... He's basking a little bit. He's taking a bit of a victory lap here in this really cool character mythology that he's built up. Absolutely. This guy maybe doesn't admire Scrooge, but he sure aware of who he is and what about. Or or so Scrooge thanks. And in my head, he really genuinely does know about him. And and this is all happened stands. That's that's my take on it. That's possible. Too. So on the next page, we transition it the the whole time Scrooge is sn
about, you know, what a cheap skate this guy is, and how he's copying him. And he announces him itself is having sent a cable saying that you'd arrived and who he is. And we get this fun little bit where
Gold Barks, Did you send the cable c o d and Scrooge of course,
did because he'd never paid for cables that he send, and long gold likewise would never pay it for cables that he gets. So he didn't know he was coming. What is that acronym there dan? That should be care of delivery. Care of delivery. Okay. Alright. And that's the essentially the
equivalent of a collect call, I'm guessing. That's right. Right. Okay. So we got this great illusion where he he lets Scrooge and he says, oh, I... I've read about Huey, Inducks and papers found in the park.
Scrooge says in So rotated Donald. This tight law doesn't even buy new newspapers. Can you... Can you beat that? I I love that
lack of awareness. That's it's very funny. It's that little hand to the side that kinda breaks mirroring.
And so once he gets in, we we are gonna get the reveal. We don't see long until he emerges from a money bathtub
another,
another
and Scrooge is shocked to see that your Barks long, the old crank I met coming over,
and Donald observe the two richest Inducks in the world and they're sword each other already. And and this here begins
one of the great sequences the Barks is ever done. It's the money argument sequence. Dan. I love it.
Each of the ty cones is gonna go on to show off and brag about and just list what they have Guam gold shows and I... It might as well be screwed just money been. It looks exactly identical and
he has a crane in there and kinda steam shovel and his, I think. I love Scrooge just response you cats this guy is a scandalous old money.
It's so great.
Go ahead run run through more of the money argument. And now there's you see and again, those teeth those teeth are buried once again, he says, I'm no tall or myself Columbia go, I have three cubic acres and money in my money ben and Glen little shade, can add much is that in pounds and shi
Scrooge screws pulls out of. Very comic long piece of paper with the figures. Mh. And said I can't stay off him, but I've got figures right here on this paper. And En discussed on a paper that's small and they just start comparing, you know, the bottom four feet of my money been full of diamonds.
I'm not impressed the bottom for feet of my bin is as star chef fires. Then it gets aggressive.
Yes.
Because at the they they just they start wiping up in the air renting then they actually...
Then it becomes physical, and it's very funny. It's... It... This is very pope. Damn the sequences
so funny to me. We we gotta treat this whole thing as one sequence here. Here's what we should do. We we need to we just need to acknowledge that the docks are gonna go through this argument. I was gonna say it slowly,
but it really doesn't. It immediately
escalate into an An outright
of fist fight... They're p each other as they compare figures. And and I think we just need to
talk about some of our favorite You know what we need to do, dan. Yeah. We need to read this
verbatim. Okay. With one of us is Scrooge and one of us is long. Sure. We want wanna get to that...
Tell me where you wanna start. Here's where we're gonna start. And and the reason is because we're we're gonna start with the the list. Mh. Where he he shows off the the figures on the paper. And that's because that's gonna be the very first instance where it turns out to be the same. And you know what? You're the guest I will let you be screws if you would like.
Alright. So
who's just, you know, Scrooge kinda pops up to... I'm gonna pop or myself gone old I have three cubic acres of money in my money then. And he Al and asks how much is that in pounds and shi?
I can't say off offhand, but I've got the figures right here on this paper. On a paper that small.
You seem to have about the same amount of cash Al I have. Quite a showing for the second which Inducks.
You'd better not call me that until you can prove it. Of course, you don't know that the bottom four feet of my money bin is full of diamonds.
I'm not last the bottom four feet of my bin
star sapphire.
I've also got ten tons of.
I've got twelve tons too. Long tons short. I've got one thousand and two oil wells. I've got one thousand and two two went two digging. I also own farms. I've got six hundred acres of bump. Never mind the acres. How many pumpkins?
And and eventually,
eventually
donald and the other docks have... They have to jump in and and rest strain them from hu each other.
And and they decide this as
and they decide this as Scrooge
stump on guam. Like he's stopping on him. Saying I'll match you Very for berry any kind of blue goose hu grand straw, black rest, logan or Juniper. And eventually,
the the other Inducks resort to tying them up picking a soft sack of money and just letting them hash it out all night
overnight. And eventually,
Donald approaches them in the morning and asks them what is the score now
and Scrooge tells him it's even all even
except for one thing, we can't decide who has saved the biggest ball of strength. And what a perfect
to this face off? Because not only did we go from the most valuable
possible assets now we're down to the most ridiculous
min of their own frugal Al. It's it's wonderful. This is such a great high concept. Right? The idea of these guys being so evenly matched that this is what they have to do. It's totally ridiculous. Right? Because we know the way money works that these guys are literally they're they're at the whim of the stock market is changing the value of their fortune.
Alright. One of their pumpkin fields is certainly just like taken, you know, a hoard of locust but but deep down, there's this like there's this
universal idea that these guys are basically evenly matched. And it's just it's just the truth because it is. Yeah. And it's again, it's it's this isn't this isn't about how much it's the point of pride as to who owns the title. You know, it's almost like room wrestling in a way. Actually, that whole f that whole argument that's very reminiscent pro looking in away. That's it's it's a very violent. It's it's Al hilariously.
Violent match.
And when do you think about that it's, like, between a couple of eighty something or whatever.
Old man.
It's it's wonderful.
Alright. So tell us
tell us about the beginning of the sequence And so Donald does absolutely be welder heat just for Remarks. You mean to say those goofy Barks as string are worth h over of course, they were do get and out all night. Miss spring seems to be the last piece of the puzzle. So naturally Scrooge has his string ball brought over from the hotel, and you could see the two of them the measuring cape trying to kinda just get a general gauge. They look equal. They seem to be the same circumference
So Scrooge determines the... We'll have to take these Barks to the open country and un them and they rolled the balls out from the entrance
of Long gold been out through the heart of Africa. And they're, we have this crazy challenge
about to take place and you can see parts is playing. Barks plays a lot with shadows in this ins silhouette in particular in the story.
But there's a really... The the fourth... Sorry, The the fifth pack... The fourth panel has them kinda just overlooking the horizon with the balls of string. It's it's kinda cinematic. And it's a really nice setup up to what we're about to... And you can see the the twisted Ban trees, the branches
and the trunk in the foreground. There's a lot of nice... There's lot nice little just suggestions that we're not in Ducktales here that we are kind of been wild country.
And enrolling them across the African valve Scrooge says yes the only fairway to enroll them in a straight line. Donald just march you've gone wacky uncle Scrooge that be right through the heart of Africa and screws Relentless says you bet, there'll be no arguments about cutting corners. Is that okay with you Glen and Guam gold is... Now you see this shifting kind of, you know, ref glen gold come to the service and he agrees. And he said I was about to suggest that same course myself. And now you see that dd kind of
you know, that you could see those wheels turning at the end of this stage.
Right. And and he definitely looks devious there. But like in fairness to him, again, he's he's really letting
letting Scrooge take some bait here. There's there's nothing at this point unethical about what he's doing. I would say you know, it they they both theoretically have the same chance here, but he he just knows the area. I love this c when stand, the the the story transitions from the that one great sequence of matching portions to to this other one And and this is great. This is such a unusual
bonkers
weird
concepts, but it's so imaginative
and that as you say that Vista looking through, you know, what promises to be the heart of Africa.
I would say this is gotta be in the contention for for one is screwed for one of Barks best africa for stories For one thing it has much less baggage than most of them do. But it just feels very imaginative. And it really feels like the the part of Africa that we're in. It... And, you know, the the first two pages of being out out in front of the heart of Africa
the... There's no real outside of the mountains. There's no real indication that there's not... You know, there's no animals, but you you see the wide open. You see that it's kind of un unchanged Yeah. We definitely get the idea this is gonna be hard. So the next page, you know, this this is really devoted to the start of the race. Others there's a nice moment where Donald despair that it wasn't bad enough that there was one millionaire in the world as Wacky as uncle Scrooge, their has to be two. And the
look at that one responded nephew went bed. Yeah. The really like oh, this again Right.
And and that really kinda hammers home, the whole
idea. And and so the two string rollers set off with with Donald Fetching about how silly this comp competition is. And the docs point out that the two ends, you might you might spend days enrolling it and still come out even. They could they say that the the Inducks could match to a brilliant of an inch.
And here's where we see Scrooge being graph you know, he says he wanted to get into rough country for things that could happen
where things could happen to Al
precious string.
And he points out there are are five of the docks to protect his string, but Flynn heart is alone, of course, we transition a Flynn heart who's have it... Having his own crafty ideas ideas about
you know, he knows the lay of the land. And so he very effectively kinda hints Al the rest of the story. He he schemes way till we get to the ant country and Thorn Ramble, Africa will take care of Al Scrooge
string.
I like that the two docs already have these
nickname for each heather. Yeah. There it's there... It's this kind of less angry effect, if you will. The interesting thing about this page, like, from the first panel to the last, they've probably gone about fifteen feet. They've only taken high and full of steps but we've really gotten into everybody's head and look at the blast two panels look at the parallel between their poses, and they're kinda there with the way their minds are working. It's really like These guys really are cut from the same cloth. Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. Now we kinda move a little bit further into the day and the fact of matter is that, you know, the having five of the Inducks versus one glen gold is beneficial because they can all take turn rolling the ball. And everyone else can kinda go at a better pace. Scrooge just just kinda he's just dancing along. He has a great little pose in that first page. Yeah. But they are...
Everyone's getting worn out already. Finally, they get camp and glen being the only one rolling his ball string is absolutely
wiped out. So he's kinda, you know, just collapsed on top of his ball. Scrooge in a possibly
generous gesture offers him a cup of coffee and Glen gold is very gracious.
In accepting it and offers screws a tip to protect his string from Removing animals. He points over to the cone of Clay. He just put your ball up on that. And it'll be safe from fan or clock. Again, they're very very very coral Barks right there. Nice and enterprise.
And Scrooge is Genuinely,
you know appreciative. Thank you, Flu, and he and Donald h the ball up on the cone of clay. You use a little suspicion you know, I never dreamed you would do anybody a favor either uncle Scrooge and uncle Scrooge kinda slightly looks at his nephew it says, I have disappointed you that coffee I gave was loaded with sleeping pattern. We can already see that the logs are being sold off panel. Coupon gold is collapsed again on top ball string because Scrooge was suspicious that maybe he might sneak back and rewind his
string wall the other Ducktales slept. So he kind of uses it as preventative measure. And one of the Nephew says well, if you were figuring doing some of for your own rewind wall hard
you better get busy
because the ball that Scrooge Donald h up onto to that Kona Clay was a giant handheld hill. And the ants are absolutely knowing away. What would you say? That's about half of the diameter of the ball? Oh, yeah. Yeah. Correct. That's that's about right. It's it's it's being devoured. It's it's pretty active. You know. This is... This is very much in Indiana Jones style.
Yeah. Kind of a trick. And Donald Scrooge are kinda like trying to brush the ants off with their jackets Which nice about that last panel is the... There ins silhouette against the shadow... I guess I think it would be the shadow in the Al, and the net user are fully drawn in the foreground But they kinda have to... They have to kinda laughing remark that old came up best in the first exchange of favors. I I like how Barks is kinda outlining it. You know, it's almost breaking the fourth wall. Right we're gonna get... We're gonna Al three segments here where
the environment
as flint said, Africa is gonna whittle him down to size It feels very, like, real. You know, it feels very visceral.
This is a great sequence.
The only notable thing I'd say we've got we got screws drug flint hard. It's not a great look, but No. No. It's even sleeping powder. You have to wonder how how well circulated this story will be in future years.
I went... And that was Al that was a pretty common cartoon convention, but Yeah. By
too. I'm sure. Right. So that... That's our first after sequence. Our our neck one is gonna be the thorn bra sequence as fl is kind of mold over in his head and, you know,
We transition immediately to the next morning where Glam gold has had a great night sleep courtesy of the sleeping powder and
Scrooge is fuming about being out smart the previous night. And and long jive, you know, you should give up because it's plane that I have the most string But the whole premise of this, the fantastic premise to this story is that you don't know how much string there is until it's been rolled out. Okay
And so all of the Inducks get ready to to take off when heart leaves first she rolling is
string. As as they kind all over that will be ready for any tricks.
One of the nephews used comments that their Ce picture is m see, kind of an interesting spelling of syrup there. I don't usually see that Al
really a Uk or a Canadian Yeah. Looks like to me. But but none of them made all the Syrup and and they note that there are a lot of ants coming from all directions.
Because of course, Guam gold has poured the entire picture of Syrup on his ball of strain and tanya. This is a great line. Yep, Dan. Donald says he ants walk to you again. That's the line out we remember from this story. I I love it. And
and Scrooge, you know, he has to, like, use a stick to push the ball somewhere safe where he can try and deal with this catastrophe.
And Guam gold very helpful points to a river over in one direction.
And this ends that being a great bit of reverse. Psychology. Right? Because Scrooge is this is a very kid friendly demonstration of that concept. Scrooge is not gonna listen. He's not gonna trust him But as he pushes the ball over what he thinks is a bank, it ends up being a pre,
full of thorn bra.
And glenn... You know, Glen gold gl that he he did try to tell him of course, predictably, he knew that he would not listen.
And we we transition but this ball is getting whittled down pretty fast. Isn't it dan. Yeah. You might be right. It it might have been nice to see, like, two to four more pages
of ball.
Yeah. Nothing not gonna call it ball shrinking at
but
No erosion. That's good word. Oh, yes. String,
radius
shrinking, anything anything to avoid being on record saying ball shrinking. But, yeah. Just give just little, you know, on both sides, it would have been kinda fun. But Yeah. I mean like minor it's a minor
picked. It does it does transition quickly, but it's naturally
Scrooge has sent his poor grand nephews to recover it and they obviously look worse for the wear and they say that they un all the string they could reach, but there is basically a normal sized ball of stream The could your two hands left. And Guam gold is gl mildly saying that Africa has whittled you down your proper size and your double sure the second richest Inducks.
And screws is really fuming at the end he's kinda. Now he's, you know, he's basically holding that it's not even the size of volleyball this point. Yeah.
Alright. But they they have to go back, you know, set up camp again. And in the midst of the night, one of the nephews here's
strange noise. You said, what is that roar off to the north? It's not thunder, we'd see lightning. Screwed Barks up and says it says medicine saying it's coming closer.
And I'm gold. Does gold realize it... Like oh, no. No. No. Oh, I'm sorry. En said I'm scared. I wish I had a safe place to slash my ball string. Because his ball string is still, you know, it's it's it's practically the size it was when they took off the bandwidth with. Scrooge on the other hand can fit his Al of string right into his top hat, the nephews reply that it's becoming a chewing sound like a buzzing be of a billion wings. And it turns out to be a gigantic
a absolute
Frantic form of the locust.
And if you go to that last panel, plum gold has his jacket off now and he's beating them off of his ball of string. A very
electric
lively panel with these.
It's maybe one of the most. It this this is a very marble comics es panel. Right here. It's very action packed. Right? You know? And in the meantime, he's just frantically trying to save this string both. Screw other and just has a simple fly water. And he's clothing that. I can't help you fl. I got my hands keeping them for meeting my hat and it's funny because the previous panel with glen beating is
beating his string bowl. It looks so... It looks just... It it looks like an absolute nightmare. And screw just sitting and you're very calmly with Al fly sw like
and there It's nothing. But Barks really like again, like, a lot of the Barks backgrounds have been fairly simple until we got to the thorn ramble.
And until we got to the locust, Africa has been pretty spa. Yeah. It's true.
And it's it's about to get a lot busier.
Right. That the the low sequence, it's it's almost not over. Right? Because it seems like everything is passed and and long gold is is disappearing that they ate at least fifteen hundred miles of his string it's pretty comic because it still dwarf.
Screws. But, you know, I guess this gives Scrooge a little bit of hope. And Scrooge points out he's still got a lot of
coming to you. And now the do see this really ominous
chain of fires
to the south and west.
This is a really interesting part Dan. Right? Because
Gets this look of error on his face as he recognizes what going on. This version of Guam gold is not going to he's not gonna choose to leave the doc for dead, he yelp that it's grass fires, the natives, uses native are burning the valve to stop the locust Sm tells them to run for their lives. Yep. And and the Ducktales are confused because there's no grass to burn nearby, but he explains.
Just just very truthfully and, honestly, that the danger isn't fires, it's animals, There's gonna be a stampede
past in the next few minutes. So everyone should climb the strongest tree that they can. And and sure enough, we get
one of the... Definitely one of the stand out panels, right of the story.
I was obsessed with, like, african animals at this age dan. Yeah. And I just... I loved this panel depicting all of these
Savannah. Mostly Savannah type animals stamped heating past the docks in in beautiful
silhouette. In the tree.
Screws gets off a funny line, which kind of soften the danger here a bit by saying, I'll be a dog on sitting duck. Those guys would step on you. And it is a real... It... You know, it... This is a real who's who of African animals. And home again, you know, Severino
area
anatomical, you know they're still cartoon, but they're very anatomical well represented. We have even at Hip running, which is kinda funny way. Right.
Beeping cells.
But, yes, so they are rushing by. And like you said, Glen kinda like explained to them like, you know, in a way of, like, almost for reciprocal compassion, you know, they're all trade but Scrooge at this point sees there's kind of a vulnerability with Al gold kind of nestled on that out or limb. So he just tries to swing himself around jiggle branch so that the string ball would drop, but do we kind of rep man's says don't you there that's cheating. Scrooge just still bit more,
you know, he he's he kinda... He's he's resisting temptation. He says doug got it. This is for title. Yeah.
Before you get to that this very animated sequence coming up here, Dan, this. This is the this is a really notable little mini seat right because this is one of the most
scanned.
That Scrooge is gonna act in this story. Maybe not in any story, but Mh. But this is a low point for Scrooge where he starts to cheat and he's
restrained by his family. And and that this this panel is part of why I feel sympathetic for Al because this is like nothing worse.
L heart didn't do anything worse than what screwed starts to do here. Right Yeah. Again, they're really uneven. They're on and even ke in terms of their own moral you know, their own moral standing. You have to say that. And that's the funny thing. It's just that you you... You know, the the whole thing was drives sharpen than the sharpie tough than tough each smarter than spa any major your money square. This isn't square dealing here. Right. If you look at it. And that's... This is a little un en
the guy we are the the Ducktales know. But but it does feel even if even if Barks isn't explicitly thinking this, it it feels like
the Ducktales
his his nephews are, like, outsourced his conscious.
His conference a little bit. Right. And he he does pull back, but... But it was there. So this is the sequence I was talking about earlier where I think Barks the animation story board artist Gag man really comes into play as the rhino.
Rams into the tree out of the panic, the string bowl that Glen gold was holding
falls goes around the neck of... I... What I think would be a crane and the ball in falls directly onto the horn of the rhino,
the bird keeps flying, pulling the string and the boss of string unwind, and to you have to see it to understand it, but this is something that would have been in any animated short, this would have been such a terrific gag, and I would tell you any other artist would probably just had the ball fall and the rhino and the rhino and what it kept running. This is five times funnier. Oh, yeah. If not twenty times linear. It's is great. You're right, and it feels very animated. And sometimes I'll criticize some of the sequences that I see where Barks you know, is is clearly trying to do a cartoon style gag because they don't always work in in the medium of of paper and panels. But this one works phenomenally. He stages it like beautifully. It's gorge... And the other nice thing is going back to what you're saying is this is such a fun little bit of ira irony and comedy that counters the kind of the the darker motive Scrooge screws just three panels yeah. Yeah. Definitely
deflate that a little bit. There's a nice balance to this page. And and flint heart, to sparingly
this says that happens is pretty great him hanging down from that tree.
And and so Scrooge on the next page where we're approaching the end here, Scrooge thinks that he's maybe gonna get the upper hand, but it turns out that a bird flying past has clipped on a small little bird has gotten its foot tangled in his string, which was sticking out of his hat a little bit and has
likewise wound away a lot of it. Scrooge is only able to recover. What looks like about a golf ball worth of string. So Barks is really... He's he's only got a couple pages here to work with. He's really accelerating the to its end. And We transition to hours later where Glam gold recovers his ball And and they both have been made into
string pop.
We get this awesome panel where they hold out there string balls and the palms of their hands,
glaring at them side by side, donald commenting that you guys are even once again Africa little you both down the size. And Barks
is gonna wrap up this last part with a narrator box that says the great show of wealth and string is finally decided on a strip no longer than a picnic table and they've stake them out in the ground from their starting point the Nephews are watching on and they're commenting that they can't come out even on this test. Because after all that's happened to that string, it would be in possible.
And this is such a wonderful panel where you fit everybody into the frame and you see these two
unbelievably wealthy men like children with marble, rolling their tiny ball string down to the last voice. But. But they're cautiously watching. They're not watching their own they're watching each other. Almost like just waiting for the the moment of
waiting for the moment of discussion or cheating on the other guy's part. And and your marble comment is right on because this is just so childish of them. It is. It's it... This one's from ridiculous to absolutely
absurd, but it's such a... It's... There's so much balance to this panel I absolutely adore it. Oh, yeah. And take us home, dan. Yeah. Well, guess what, they do come out even. Donald this donald on one and he he has a ruler, and he says you guys must have been going to be equals and all things and en is just lost it finally since I can't stand it this isn't right. I can't be. It can't be now. I am no longer the richest stuck in the world Scrooge just stands up he says you never were yet Jon come lately because telegraph what we that was telegraph early on in the story that you pointed out I'm still as always, the one and only, they're just stuck in the world I have proof right here in my pocket. The string tied to his number one dime adds more than enough length to his own string to make in the champ. And Pro has the classic comic book. X over the eyes and just has to do the do do the faint. Right. We get a nice pratt. Mh. And, of course, this is Barks so we have to tie it nicely to the
initial opening scene and screws just explain to donald. You see what choice saving can bring to a person the power what satisfaction what sterling victories and for that, again call response. Donald just says maybe so and Scrooge, but I'll still take a tall cool soda.
And as they're on the foreground, nephews are helping a rather
rejected guam gold back on his feet, heading towards the money Bin.
Dan, this this last page is it's like perfect. It is. Either so much to love about it from from the predictable fact that, yes, they the string measured exactly the same down to we assume a sq of an inch. And then the pacing
where Barks really draws out Scrooge is revealed. You can see him taking
satisfaction in it. And and he did such a good job of, like,
signal and introducing that Scrooge. But he he still did it in a subtle enough way that you're not like, I don't know about you, but I distinctly remember the first time I read it. I was not waiting for that moment. I was not
anticipating it. It came as a delightful
surprise. To me. So to me, he struck the exact right balance of... Oh, yeah. I totally remember that. And again, it's not something that was introduced for this story that had been present previously
because did the callbacks in this story really. Like, this is one of those things where everything just converge so nicely.
Really
especially the past, let's say the pest fourteen issues.
Right. Right. You know, where where a lot of these books didn't go in that direction where continuity was not really Things were not touched upon from a previous book. Right. Right. And and as you say it's it's book
so nicely with with the continuation of Scrooge and donald
conversation, and that last panel is so lovely
with that mix of silhouette. You you called it the the panels where he does the silhouette and the full drawing.
They they... They're lovely. They really seem to evo the long shadows in the air developed. It's really notable too how warm the Nephews how kind of the nephews are being with Al gold. You know, they really seem like they've had the six experience together. They they're they're kinda nicely inclined. It's it's... It would feel out of character later. Yeah. It would. But, you know, here too, it's like they... You know, Okay. Not only did they have to go through the initial conflict, but, you know, they were camping out There had to be conversation. They had to have my connection with him. They at least have this big experience together. It's it's easy to imagine the relationship
between sp and Glen gold going a different way after this. And then being like, rivals,
but not as
opposition as they will be. But if but, you know, barb, that's not where Barks wants to go. No. And I I do seem to remember at one point reading that
something that I couldn't find this time about Barks use of Guam just said, he just didn't feel the need to use them anymore, but because he just didn't have anywhere else to go with him. But I really think that's a shame. When you think about all the times he just used generic pig faced villain, you know, mix wine or or whoever.
Long is much more interesting. Huey, yes. And that's you're right. And I... Again, I I feel like he just he... I think he kind of respected this character to bring him back enough but maybe he didn't want to make him that regular...
You know, just that that regular guide because that might have, like, taken the... That might have taken the vi out of them. It it is kind of it is kinda odd that he didn't lean on him as much as Magic would will come in about two years from the point of this story. I think was four years. Right I know he used her, like, six times seven times, but yeah. Like something around there. Yeah. But I guess when you have a sources that isn't necessarily all powerful or competent. There's more story potential there than
right. She's the only real, like, magic element
that that he's gonna use that much of even if she's not really magic, but she's definitely... She's definitely a fascinating name character. So I understand what you wanted
He also probably...
Well, there's a lot to say about Man. Yeah. No. There is Al lot fun. Yeah. That's all that you're gonna have you gonna have a lot of people coming for that. I'm sure. U. But, you know, funny thing is with the next story we see long, this the money trap. Right? That's the title of it. It's like Yeah. The the confrontation when they meet here is funny. When you get to the money champ, that confrontation is twice as fast and twice as funny and twice as violent. Yeah. It's so neat to see him, like,
really have Scrooge get get physical. Yeah. It's hilarious when you stop and think about what elderly territory is supposed to be. So so, Dan, I loved going through this one. Does this was this has been a blast to summarize I have not I think that I've made pretty clear how I feel about this story. I think it works
spectacularly
well. And and I just... I love this one. If this one flows so beautifully and just everything... You know, like certain films are that way where Severino same transitions
so perfectly. There's not a jump every... It's it seamless you don't even realize you're going from one sequence to one to another this one is one of those stories that just... It just... It it's like silk. It absolutely...
It absolutely just brings you right along to the next scene with that any bumps or jumps or anything. Right. So, Dan, we talk... We'll we always check in for how the community feels about a given story. I know you and I big fans of this one, obvious this is like a second tier story for me. It's it's right
outside the all time plastics.
As far as voters on Inducks,
the the big Disney comics
website where people can can chime in and and rank stories This one has a very strong sport. It's got an eight point one out of ten which is good right now for number twenty four out of all, like, forty two thousand or whatever
Disney comics. So, you know, the the the community, it's it's not too surprising. Right? This is Sc first appearance so that that in and of itself is gonna cause people to vote this one very highly.
But I think that this story really holds up much like Gladstone first to appearance, you know, people loved that, but it also happened to be a great great story. It it's the same deal here. I guess this the same thing for the B boy's kara Boys is another all time class So the these characters got introduced in some truly great stories. Yeah. That was not accidental.
I I would have to say. There's just... There's there's certain ways to ring bring a new character to bring a new concepts into the fold. And oftentimes,
that's the thing that the the way you launch them really like the memorable or makes them not. Because some things just never returned. Right. So we also like to talk about kind of appearances
in other media.
Boy. That that's a huge can worms. Right? Flint heart mom gold is is gonna go on. He's never gonna be like the biggest Disney character ever. But he's a recognizable
iconic character who's certainly used outside of the Barks stories we had mentioned before many other Disney comics creators have you used him. He's he's appeared.
Even outside the Disney comics he's definitely appeared in both of the runs of Ducktales.
Yep. Al little different in that... I think the a Barks side aspect, especially in the eighties, I think that's what kind of might of
spur them to make him
scottish.
That's more point. I know more especially in nineteen eighty seven, you know, that's that really made a more of a black mirror version of Scrooge.
Right. Right. Yeah. So it's weird. I always thought it's weird that he's
relocated to Duck and he's a scottish duck Inducks, but you're absolutely right. That makes sense. Couldn't have probably gotten away with having him because I I think it would have been insensitive. You know? Especially not that. Because if things Barks so volatile at that time. Right. And then he's just... He is such a deeply ridiculous character in the newest run of Ducktales I will admit to
finding him pretty entertaining and and amusing from time to time. But but on the whole, that version of the care tray. As I'm amusing as he can be, it just kinda rubs me the wrong way. I... Well, look again, coming from this is your origin point, it's such a far stretch. But within the absurd of the twenty seventeen show, it's funny that this guy is such a desperate wanna be. Right. There there is some comedy to that. That, like, again, I kinda see past all of it. There there really is. The the episode that where he gets amnesia is probably
in in... Among my favorite from that show. That gets dark.
Yes. That one sounds dark. And they give him... Boy they get... I think they give him a name. And, oh, they call him Duke below. Yeah. That's right. And that way callback to the store? That was a weird,
weird Al little callback. But he and and they they did have him originally from Africa from South Africa. Right. As as a as a kid, which was kind of kind of round breaking too. Right. It's... Again, like, there... There's a lot of layers to that. But, yeah. Like, his his overall goal was, like, No. No. No. I... If you don't you chance, I'm gonna try and be just like this guy. But I'm gonna be more Scottish than him. Right you're mori rich him. And and
that that was also, I guess, partially taken from the Don Rosa
story, right? From the life and times. Yes.
Because Rosa did do... He he it ends up being one of those, like, that the trip were you and counter your villain in your past and you don't even know it, but Scrooge doesn't encounter Gold without even realizing it in the After set.
Chapter of life and times. Right. And that was originally gonna be in the son of the southern, the first of story. Yeah.
Space for it, which is kind of interesting too. But but, you know, Rosa was... Rosa was the one that really took Glen gold back to the Barks level and then he he again, he made long to threat. Where did not. Right. And, and he used him pretty, pretty quickly in his own span of stories.
As as the bad guy and a few of those early run ones, including this very first
Fine. Which I love that one. Boy, you know, we've we've we've mentioned a lot of great panels. Are there any that you would like to kind of really go to bat four that we didn't that we didn't, like, spend too much. Give too much attention to as for a favorite panel? Tell you the one I really I mean, the, you know, the locust...
The locust detects silhouette, the... Even the thorn Bra is a really beautiful one, but I think those are the obvious ones. What I was looking at before, when I just reset to the first page here, that opening panel is so nice where you just have poses of donald Scrooge screws. They're kind of in encountering each other. But Look it, look at Zuckerberg Look at the look at the mountains, look at the factories on the river. It's very...
It's evo of Seattle in a way. Yeah. And I really like that depiction because they're... There's a couple of one or two other stories you an earlier one where the ducks are on top of the building and they're looking over Inducks bergen, you could see the Tu bug river Yeah. And some magic
glass. Yeah. And it's... And you you really get a sense of what the city is like. And I always... I always like Inducks Duck to either Seattle or Portland. I always put it in the Pacific Northwest in my mind. For some reason because I always see that like kind of city scape with the surrounding
suburbs and then the kind of industrial section, all kind of incorporating one, you know, one one one of this though. Yeah. That is love. And I and I definitely think of those like factories as representing, you know, the ones that Scrooge is gonna talk about in a few panels. What about you? What panels did did you really, you know, respond to or? Which ones really caught you by surprised by this reading? So I wanna reiterate again, but that that second page,
know that fourth page where he's
disappearing and he goes to talk to his clerk and how every expression is better in the last but specifically, I wanna call out the panel where his clerk is reading out the figures,
and he's like biting his finger
in in anticipation. I I find that one whole hilarious.
But there there are just so many wonder ones every every panel during their money fights, I remember as a kid always loving the one where he just utterly yells
long tons
short
just that just cracks me up that that little guy. So really, really a great story Dan. I didn't I think we did a great job of covering this one. But, listen Thank you as always. I really enjoyed it. And this is this was a pleasure to come back to again, this is one of those I haven't read, you know, quite a few years. So this was... It's nice to see this thing fresh eyes. Yeah. Absolutely. I and treat to have you back on dan. I really appreciate it. That's awesome.
So I I would definitely encourage people to reach out. If they wanna share their thoughts. We're we're
present on the socials, Facebook and Instagram. And please check in on our next adventure length episode where we get to talk about back long ago.
Dan dean mind reading the last panel to close the
episode out Yeah. Absolutely.
And
this sounds pretty good right about now.
May so uncle screwed but I'll still take Al tall, cool soda. Awesome. Thanks so much, Dan. Thanks a lot. I'll talk to you soon.
The life is mike an.
And and screw just
fail.
Accounting top my god.