We can have
Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer an artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comments of all time. Join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks. Welcome back to Barks remarks. I'm Mark Sever a grown man who's still loves Inducks comics. I love talking about these great adventure stories, and I really enjoy meeting people and getting to actually
actually chat about Disney comics. Which I... Which I never got to do growing up and reading them in isolation. And today, I have a brand new guest host with me, and he's got his own Youtube series. Where he talks about comic books
and duck and other pop culture, So I'm gonna introduce him by his Youtube handle. I am delighted to be joined by Bucket Think tank. How about a bucket? Did I... Did I introduce your Youtube channel okay? How would how do you describe it? I would probably describe it as another grown man who also I really had no one to talk to about this. And
just likes to talk about likes to share what's going on here, and he's very particular about what he does, which means it's kind of bad to some extent.
But... Yeah. Yeah. I I talk about primarily, don't who when it's... It's fund... Disney is always fine Did... Disney world series who what talked about disney it princess,
the Ducktales lower video, which I did response to twenty seventeen,
Ducktales,
which I... My greatest crime of that was... Well, two things. When I did the life was Scrooge series of I didn't use a lot of roses actual Art by mistake that was not intentional. U. And then I did the the Ducktales Lower on Scrooge. I post it not knowing. It was down Rosa birthday, and it was... I posted it to the donald rosa not like, what do you think of this? I didn't realize it was his birthday. And downloads is not a fan of duck.
So I'll I really stepped in it that time. But for the most part, you got it. Right? I'm just a guy who when he likes something he wants share with people... Doesn't like something he wants to share with people. And, you know, wants to really show off to some extent, show off. To some extent they has an idea or two. Absolutely.
It it it's it's great. I love... I love being a grown man on the Internet who, you know, has this way of connecting with people
in my very, like, very particular very specific nerdy interests and just getting to talk to other people about it and share my thoughts and and finding, hey, there are actually people who are who are interested in listening to those thoughts. It's it's a lot of fun. And I think bucket, what's gonna be really fun. Oh, just just again, you know, we'll we'll do a plug at the end, but definitely check him out on you You can get there pretty easily right by by plugging in your handle bucket tank. Right? Yes. Yes. It's it's a very out there name which has its own very not interesting it the stories to it. Used to wear a bucket hat a lot. Yeah. And there was a car game that I used to play called Car Vanguard hated of the game actually. It was a very horribly on unbalanced game for me, but one I think the lock was the Oracle thing tank. Group four. I like okay let's just sort of put those together the bucket hat. And the phrase tank, which always sounds really contentious and really smart. Let's do that and I stuck. I really like the name. I I think it's nice and sticky. So I think it's... I think it's a good choice. But but I'm gonna be going by bucket with with your approval for the That's for the recording. And
bucket, today we get to talk about a pretty interesting and and pretty weird, frankly Carl Barks uncle Scrooge and Donald duct venture,
recovering back too long ago.
This this a really cookie story. I've gotta to say right off the bat. Like, I I think I think this is a perfectly fine story. This is a pretty enjoyable one. It's not like one of my favorites, but but I think it's gonna make for a really good podcast conversation just because of some of the background of it and and how deeply weird this one is. Yeah. Yeah. It is
It's a story that I don't think you would look to for, like a a recommendation. Because when you wanna recommend something to someone, you wanna get one that just grabs this is one of those where after you've read a couple, you're like, okay, this is a this is a fun story. This this is one that you automatically go to. Of like, more like a comfort story, but it's one of those it gets the job done. Like, you know what? This is fine. This is fine. This is funny in some ways.
This is engineering, it has...
There's nothing about it it stands out, but it's never bad. Yeah. I I think you nailed it there. I think that's a great way to to describe it because you're right. You wouldn't you wouldn't wanna read this necessarily as one of your first spark stories. I don't think it's likely to grab you maybe someone out there, you know, every story I found is someone's favorite out there, you know. And some... For someone this was probably their inter introduction but you're right. I don't think you would tell someone. Oh, you've gotta get into Carl Barks This is just the story for it. First off, you know, it's It's pretty weird. It's a little bit deep into it. That is kinda how I read it too. You know? I I read I started reading Barks in the late eighties,
blade eighties with the Gladstone printing.
And I didn't see this one until Disney comic Scott around to it, and I think nineteen ninety three or so. They reprint. It was a really cool rosa cover.
And and I I liked the story pretty well. I remember, I I re reread it relatively frequently. It was not one of my like ones that I re reread all the time, but but even even the first time I read it, I remember thinking boy. This is pretty strange this tail of past lives
regression.
Yeah. I remember when I used to go to the com store my grandmother to try to find it because she was the one that would take me to all these different common Barks bookstores to find like
Scrooge squeeze adventures economics because that's the ones that I would that I would find. Right. I remember something when I saw, like, the Paul bun machine and
how the Wi mills. I would often see Barks long ago, I would just see what looked like Scrooge and Donald, like, you know, holding so again. I'm my, this looks really cool. I'm like, I kinda... I kinda wanna see this. And it turns out that's not really... This more that's sort just the cover, which is always the great moment. The cover should just be the hook
You should never go the covers exactly what the story is. No. That's that's Severino fuck. Yeah. I agree. It's nice one the cover just really like does a good job of hinting at the story.
It's it's kind of one of my pet peeve
is when the cover are, like really reviews.
Something. At the same time, I don't like the... If if we think about the original printing of this, which I'm gonna go ahead and just mentioned, let... Let's start talking about the original printing. It it was published Inducks uncle Scrooge sixteen,
and it had one of those Carl Barks gag covers that he got to do for most of the the stories.
I like it when, you know, back to the deck. It gives you a really good idea of some of the meat of the story, same thing when home only a poor man.
But without really spoiling it,
So so the publication was in cover date of October nineteen fifty six.
This one has been reprinted kind of an average number of times. In in the states it's had eleven printing, including the original
Bucket, this is a relatively
short
adventure story. It's twenty one pages.
And and I think it it doesn't necessarily feel like a rush story or anything to me. But but it's definitely... Not as long as it's, like thirty two pages.
Yeah. He had a very clear idea of the story Huey, wanted to tell. There's not a lot of twists and turn still. It's mostly straight line with maybe one hurdle. It's two different characters and this in this instance where it Scrooge down on opposite ends reaching to the same goal. So that's really where most of the padding happens. And Mark's one of them arrived there at the same time.
Right. So that was really the the one unquote hurdle there. And as you you just hinted, you know, the dynamic of this story is that it's a Scrooge versus
Donald story. This is this is one of those
occasional. They're not like rare, but they they certainly don't happen all the time. Stories where the Ducktales not c cooperating they're actually competing against each other. Barks likes to do this every once in a while. It kind of kinda har back to the old Disney cartoons that use to work on.
You know what? You know what? Thought just crossed my mind bucket. As I hold up my my reprint of the Disney comic that Rose did the cover for This might be one of the very rare bits of cover art that technically doesn't feature
any of the Disney main characters
because we're we're looking at the... On this cover from uncle screws number two seventy nine, we're looking at the
request to the long ago. Characters that they're gonna travel pack in time. To inhabit Donald as what Boston pin tail and
Scrooge as medium Inducks.
Yes.
I remember seeing
these two before and that they would like the big. This was one comic as kid. I was like, I had to find this comment just because it went was squash buck pirates. I signed me up for navy Inducks I don't... I'd seen him in Don Rosa life and times of Inducks
run And I had... And then he's on the doc Family tree along with Pi. Is may
Malcolm maybe Inducks. And he's his story is hilarious in the context that is provided here. And it's even better when you go to Roses
Scrooge series and it's part five. It's it's it's hilarious. The back and forth there. Right, because because Don Rose is really gonna run with the cara Pearson.
As he does, he he just... He picks out some of the details that Barks used
and he uses them for his, you know,
story in in an interesting way. So here's that I in a to bucket.
Before we actually launch into the story,
I we gotta take a moment to talk about the the weird hook. Of this one. Right? Which is it's something called past lives regression.
In in this story, Scrooge and Donald sep are both gonna visit hit,
who
put their patients into
I'm I'm gonna use scare quotes around patients.
Put there patience into a deep trans
through diagnosis and they talk to them about their experiences
in their past lives as separate people. Right? So we're talking like same soul, different body.
And and the hope for this is that, you know, this is gonna be a fad and duck where a lot of people are gonna end up discovering riches that they're past selves
have, you know, would have known about. But bucket, do you know anything about kind of the real history behind this? Honestly, I I don't, but it did sound interesting. I knew it felt like this was a thing that did happen. And if you look at other cartoons,
for of the time,
like came on the nineties Hi was everywhere.
Fred Flint stone got one point, elmer overflow was ties to think that he was a rabbit at one point and then... Right. Only recently got him hepatitis that he was out referred. Hip was always been a really fun idea It's always been fun. I think this just felt so natural and idea. Yeah. You're you're right.
Is is a very common trope in cartoons and comics ever since, like I I guess Floyd kinda popularized it
but but this, like, very specific branch of it, the repressed memories. I think that's a little less common, although definitely, there are instances of this and pop culture. But... And and rein,
right, that's like an an age old idea that appears in a lot of world religions that's in that's in hi.
That's in I I looked it up and and even old ancient and Greek philosophers, like socrates keys and play top played talked about it. So, you know, there's There's nothing new about that. But what what did happen in the twentieth century is that hit
Al a way to, like, support
to Delve into people's, like memories
became more popularized.
And and this is crazy. I looked to this up that keep and people have done like whole podcasts about this specific case. But there there is a very specific incident in the fifties
that almost certainly
informed Barks,
you know, creation of this story.
And it
It's the story of a woman.
And her past life, the woman's name her real name was
Virginia
ti or tai. I'm not sure how to pronounce that. But it's it's the story of bride Murphy. And this was first told in a series of articles by William J Baker and published in the Denver post in nineteen fifty four. Right? So we're looking at just
just a couple years prior in early fifty six,
there was a book released
called the search for B Murphy And and basically,
what it happened was in nineteen fifty two, this amateur hit test named Mori Bernstein
put this housewife
Virginia Tai
from Colorado inn a That sparked off this
revelation
that she had about her past life as a nineteenth
century
as a nineteenth Century Irish woman and
and it it became this, like,
sensational
thing that was, you know, very widespread
in and popular media.
There was a lot of interest in it. People would have these, like, come as you were parties
dressing as you as you were in one of your past lives,
The book was really popular. There was a movie option for it. I think they did make it the woman, she was always skeptical about it and she kinda wanted to stay anonymous.
She had a pseudo him for a while. But eventually, like, you know, as these things do, it it basically totally fell apart when people, like, looked up the details,
you know, because, like, she... She had all these specific details. Some of them hand out and she spoke with an Irish accent even though she wasn't really.
And basically, they figured out
sorry. I'm getting keyed up because this is really interesting.
They they figured out that it it was a case of something
called
Instead of amnesia, it's the case of crypto n.
Where you like are able to recover real memories from your childhood
that you have basically
forgotten So apparently, even though she was like raised by Norwegian, American Parents,
she had these, like, Al Ant uncle
who were from Ireland.
And there was, like, a neighbor when she was three that was named bride Murphy.
And and, you know, so she must have been hearing Irish the cyrus accent and and it all... It all just kinda fell apart in that way. But it it didn't fall apart quick enough for this to really take off and and just to become a very popular thing that people that really
people. So, you know, like the most of the country Bark read the paper. He almost certainly
encountered this and other similar stories that were really in v. During during that spam. It it is a fun idea the more you think about. And in regards to her, like, it shows exactly with the power of consciousness
and the mind and what these things, what you can really dig up and how it can affect who you on how you've developed. And in terms of wanting to find out that, hey, maybe the life you're living now is just part two. Of this way moisture life this is a cool down period. And right like, you know, you made have that a pirate
or, you know, March with Washington,
you know, it's always a really fun idea. It's it's really tempting to explore that aspect. It's also just fun. I could see like it... Again but Al like, hey, at this point, you were... Actually, you were actually just a sheep dealer. You're still sheep. I'm sorry. That you piqued... This is actually your best life. I'm sorry.
I know. Because because everyone was like Maria
Antoinette or or Ne Td or something and they're supposed past lives instead of, like like you say a swine her
or a a surf in in Sa Russia.
Someone definitely at this point, things. They have Al loss duchess anastasia.
Like, it's it's me, I promise it's me.
Right. Yeah. I I think you nailed why why this is so popular or why this is such an inviting and tempting idea. And I don't think the Barks
necessarily bought into it, but I think he definitely saw the potential
of of this making a good story and because he had to write so many of these. But as you say, Hip, it's not the first time. He's going back to that well. Because
he's used he is... Even at this point, there's been a number of stories that feature hit,
probably most famously adventure down under. That one gets started off by a really funny
experienced donald has with with the hit.
And then there's another memorable one in the the Christmas story, you can't guess. As well as several ten pager, probably one of his most famous ten pages is the hip pit gun or the the Bin you're.
Story.
That's a great one to check out. Mh.
Alright. So Al lot lot a good background for this one bucket. We're gonna launch into the story soon. But before we do, I do like to check in with,
you know, some of the titles from around the world and to the international listeners.
Who can listen to us, try to wrap our wrap our tons around different, the stories, titles and different languages.
So yeah. It's it's a good time. So here's the thing. A lot of these stories,
they have a a title that doesn't translate nicely. And then some of the stories they just basically translate it word for word. This this is for the most part one of those that's not too interesting. But I did give you one title that that to me sounds Al little more interesting than the other. So I'm in a rattle off a few of them, and then I'll let you do that Italian one. But... Okay. So
Denmark in Danish, this one is just translated as back to the past.
Teal bag, teal ford
in finish.
I don't I don't usually do the finish because that's the hardest one for me. I'm gonna try it. Mat
Mend
Yu
is a trip to the past.
And then in German, now let's go with French.
In French, it's either tres,
temporal treasure
or v donald don't voyage and time or just time travel. So not There those are all fine. Pretty straightforward
They they did make an interesting choice for the Italian though. What's that one? They did they did... So when telling you, it's Severino,
Al Ducktales,
which translates to uncle Scrooge and the Queen's treasure, which really echo echoes nothing. About what's gonna happen almost feels was like, it could be any other story. Yeah. Which is which is fine. Sounds really exciting.
Either way. Yeah. I thought it was an odd choice. I don't think any of them quite have the connotation that you get in English. Right? With back to long ago because just long ago sounds
more for voting than the past.
Alright. So we're gonna go ahead and and plow into this story. Alright. Buckets. So back to long ago opens up, We get one of our very common opening for the Scrooge adventure where
he is in. He's in his bin or at least Huey, in a room Adjacent. It's signaled to us
how Rich he is because he's sitting on a giant money bag and it's full of money. There's a great site ga that his his candle is resting on ledger labeled bills, bills, two, more bills,
also more yet. I like that. And and what he's doing is he's pouring through his his accounts his ledger and he discovers that there is a tenant in one of his office buildings that hasn't paid his rent for three months.
So because Scrooge is very hands on person, he's gonna go right over
and throw him out.
And he's it's it's it's an engaging opening. He's striving forth
glaring at the note and figuring out the calculating that he owes me ninety dollars
pondering suppose all of my tenants stopped paying their rent in two thousand years had be broke. And as he gets up to the tenant office, he he notes that the guy's name is Me J spell castor. H p d h,
says you should add a D to those initials
for dead beads.
That really cracks me up. And the page closes with him just in mid sentence.
Okay. Hp d h d b shell out or get out.
And and the he launch into his tail of woe and what a hard time he's had. What do you think bucket? I I like this opening. I think it's pretty strong. I do. I first of all, opening up in the money that has always been one of my favorite things. The all money that. I remember here Barks talking about you know, he would always show how Scrooge screws was, but you know, he put money in one room or like money on the jazz. You do it more and more and more. So like you know, there's a lot of money.
The the... One thing I don't like about that opening scene is just the bag he's sitting on. It looks like a little too big is kinda distracting, but I still love the energy here. It was... Was one of my favorite parts of the sunken city, you know, he's going over his ledger and it looks so serious. And then hear this, like, what the amount is, like you... Know. And I love that he is like, you know what? I will deal with this myself. Like, Right comes to people owing him money despite the fact that he wants a world empire. This is something he has to begin with himself. And you can see that in the invader Fort Inducks
when they talk about how Scrooge bought fort duck,
Kill mu Hill, and the Junior wichita to still hold up there huge like running out dead is one of my favorite things.
So this is kind of it too, but also the absurdity of the fact that, you know, this guy who's him ninety dollars. And picked the most extreme with you know, if all of my tenants stop paying in two thousand years I'd be broke. Which is just hell hilarious is the how rich you have to be. Exactly.
That.
And you mentioned Secret of. This does
evo that opening where he's gonna approach donald for Al even more try amount.
And that story you mentioned, of course is one of the chapters in Roses
adaptation.
These stories. Alright. So I I like the back and forth between him and the hit. Scrooge just has no sympathy
for his b. The guy is is a explaining to him that he that he's a hit test, and the business has been overcrowded
lately. Al like Scrooge remark, you'll find plenty of elbow room in the par.
And and I think this kind of mirrors, you know, how
how I was saying
was a big fat at this point.
He's talking about just all these people have opened up shop Scrooge references it being a rocket. But he says, no. It's not a rack mister Up. We believe we can actually
levi persons back in mind to lives they lived hundreds of years ago You know, so right away, Barks is is
specifying what kind of cookie hit he's talking about. And and the hit makes him this offer that he it will give him some of his services
instead of paying the money. He owes. And screwed, you know, initially,
he has no interest in it, but the
starts to persuade him bucket, do you wanna tell us how he goes about successfully
persuading him? He does what a lot of good sales when do.
Automatically if he pulling out people who benefit from it. He points out to
to mister a new rich. Mister New, like know hey look this guy, he was Peg when them. She just last month, but back in history, he found he was one of bizarre soldiers, and he spot a location of a case of
gold like look it.
Insane, but hear me go. Al He returned to the present he flew through and honor the hood, which is part that former formalized centuries ago, and like, wait a minute it. Well that's kinda cool. And, you know, plush cake you know, whom he levi back to france of sixteenth, let you know? You know, it it's it's a great little g possibly. But we're showing actual receipts here. She found that in her and her life there, she had been made to madam du Bower, and I such she hidden a great... The great beauty jewels
when the mom swept into Loot Her share tell. So, you know, there's some really good stuff here. To really get you like, you know, this isn't just kind of ridiculous. People are making... Make making a good profit off of this off of just sitting down and remembering. Right? Yeah Exactly right away, Barks is telling us that no. This is not a rocket. This guy, while he might be ridiculous,
This is all real. And and this this was kinda one of the things that left a weird taste and my mouth about this story because because I'm such a skeptic and It it always... It always weird me out to see Scrooge buying into some of these, like, kinda cookie beliefs. But but it's fine. And, you know, in the Inducks Universe, this is clearly something that has been discovered
to be real.
And and so Scrooge Barks to mall over the possibilities.
We got a great signaling,
you know, a money eyes
panel from him
What does he ponder bucket?
Perhaps long ago was keep of King Solomon long lost minds, you know? Or maybe I was guard of of the treasurer owners the past that came crisis.
Yeah Right I could be so... I could have so much more money. I could have so much more.
Maybe, maybe, I was a like secretary for the treasure the ninth temp. Like he hasn't said it. But, yeah, the scale can never be too big for food. It's never just a simple thing.
On a bit of a tangent if you look to say the Ducktales movie. When food has three wishes, he goes like four wishes in his head. The world's biggest diamond, the world's biggest time in mind. No. All the diamond minds. Know the entire mining Inducks industry. That's right. He thinks big. And I think that is a great rate that he has as a businessman,
if anything else.
Yeah. That's right. I forgotten about that line, but that just transported me back to rewatch that up over and over as.
It's interesting to note of course that both of those just little quick illusions can solomon lines that the treasure of king cr.
So, of course, it won't be too too long before Barks is gonna make a story out of King Solomon, long lost minds.
He does never get around crisis though. I think I think Rosa will do one of those and probably any other number any number of other Ducktales creators.
So Scrooge, you know, he sees the possibility. He's gonna take the the me, the the hit up on this offer. And as he sits down, he learns that for ninety dollars, he's gonna get nine minutes in new quote rusty pass. Which, of course, works out to be ten dollars a minute. The quote union scale for this type of hit
I like that. It's it's funny. It's it's a good bit. I'm not gonna run that through the inflation converter because I know that it's roughly ten times plus just a little bit. So we're talking about basically a hundred bucks a minute. I I can just imagine a bunch of hit to the other day like, what is? What is our set scale?
The of this, Like, you know, because on the off chance, they don't get anything, and they're not happy. We need like, a set amount.
Alright? Because it may not work. They may not lock they're actually swan hurt or, you know, you know,
something to make sure that we get out of this. Alright?
Right. And and Barks, that's a good... It's a cute gag, the the idea of having a union scale for something ridiculous
you know, the help talk about the, like, b boys, having a a bang robert's union stuff like that eventually. Frequently. Alright. So the next sequence,
The next sequence is about putting screws into his.
And and bucket, there's no suspense about this working. You know, he he puts him under and it works
immediately
And immediately, he is catapult
back into the past
very conveniently
in a robot heading to shore with a chest... What what clearly is a treasure chest? And
he is accompanied
by one other
individual. And bucket, do you wanna tell us about about these two people and and their interaction and what they what they get up to. So here,
they're just, you know, on the boat on the road robot,
Maybe Ducktales, you know, at the at the start of it, so to speak, and we have Boston Pen,
Rowan, almost like this great universal division labor between these two characters.
And
he's said... Pinto asking
what was in it? It was not said what's in it and made with justice, any full can guess which from the Spanish treasure
that they dumped off trinidad Al. Okay. Okay. And the world seal is on the log. I suppose it's special
loop for Queen Ba Queen Elizabeth. Mh.
You know, And
may Inducks property like wag civil tongue, Pint tail, her majesty cactus never take loot they take war prizes, which is a fun way to say, you know, we didn't, like, steal it. It was... You know, we there was a thing for hampton. And you know, it's it's our trophy. Like, you know, fair square. And pit temple out the chest is so valuable they bed on this island whilst they weighed Westwood along the Spanish main, and the captain thinks it'll be safer here during their dangerous voyage. It's all very
straightforward
It's almost as if... As as Scrooge is...
If like, it's... We're really sort of taken out sort of see the story happening. It's it's being told to us what's going as opposed to possibly us being,
I wanna say this could have actually just been a caption a dialogue box by the narrator. But because we've gone back in town, we have to be almost a third person. Who just woke up as Scrooge,
theoretically just woke up and made Inducks body. Yeah. Doesn't it doesn't it really feel Doesn't it have the feel of a movie flash? Yeah. It it's very effective I think... So here's an interesting thing that I'm noticing in in my reprint at least. And I think you're you're consulting what looks like one of the reproduction of the original story. Maybe you can tell me if that's the case. But it kind of sep tone the coloring. They've... The the color is has has very effectively
kinda muddy to the colors for this
flat... I guess, flash isn't the right term. But, you know, this this jump back too long ago,
the docs are just a little bit rare than Scrooge is.
No they look the same really? Okay. So the original caller didn't make that choice. I I like the choice for the reprint. Hey, I got a say bucket. That that bothers pen tail He looks ever so slightly familiar to me. Clearly, he's pete from you...
Goofy his next door neighbor. But, you know,
But,
yeah. Yeah. He does. He looks like someone,
someone who has a very temper
someone who... Like, even his clothes look oddly.
Like the
of the black and the red and the blue hat. It's. I I don't know. I don't I'm sure will come up later. I have sure. Maybe not. Just
so we're we're goof. But, like, the point is There this is glaring
obviously
signaled as being donald. Right? This is this is Donald in a past life. When he wakes up Scrooge is not going to immediately realize that like the reader does. But there there is just Barks does not allow any... It's not very subtle here. It really isn't.
And it it doesn't take away anything to it. It's... Again, this story is not very complicated, and you don't really have to make a big mystery of this. But it sorta of makes sense that Scrooge wouldn't notice this because it's not really what matters. What happens here is he's taken the... He's gone back to someone who already knows who this is in that current tense. Right. Yeah. Yeah. And he's he's
sen focused on this fantastic treasure.
So so we do proceed to them doing the classic trope of burying this treasure chest and marking the coordinates on them on a map. There's nothing too interesting about this part. I mean, it's it's neat. It's it's it's very...
It's very well detailed and and the art is really nice. It's just Al pretty straightforward thing where they the the conversation is interesting, you know, they make a pledge that in the event that,
you know, they're the only
survivors of maybe some catastrophe and end of being the only people that know about the location of this treasure.
They're talking about what they would go on to do
medium doc sense is very honorable
Huey, vows to deliver it on to her majesty in person and and Bo Pint patel is a little bit more reluctant about that
But they end up the queen, they make that val and they head off for the rest of the Spanish main, and then very abruptly
Scrooge just nine minutes seem to have ended and he is catapult
back
back to the present. The back back to our nineteen fifty six present.
From back to long ago to back to nine minutes later.
This has been I guess, the the h test is asking, you know, did have a nice journey and and Scrooge is just he is off to the races. He's not even gonna stop to tell the hi
about what he's seen. He's just had this great opportunity, of course, he's gonna go treasure Hunting and recover that chest. Of gold. He braces to Tu berg planning to head to a hardware
store to not to buy a shovel bucket. But to check on the price to see if you can get a good bargain
on a shuffle. And
we see a very familiar silhouette of a shadow.
Around the corner, do you wanna tell us about who he encounters in their conversation? He runs into the legendary
Donald Duck.
Okay.
And what's really cool about when they when they crash and which other is? They both Pretty much to almost laps into their pass into sw labs past life. Know, we the loads and ladies saved.
And they put like donald, my bird brain nephew,
and Don goes on the Scrooge, and what's really cool is in this quick moment here. Sm goes on new example sail I one met I wonder how to look with an fashion. And donna was like, you know what? You got a strange feel about you too Scrooge sc. I wanna if be looking with Al flu hat and wearing a cut. I would also point out that, you know,
maid mc Ducktales was wearing actual shoes,
which is always weird to me for die so. Yeah. You know, Donald like, yeah. That that's just life. And donald has no time. Like, you know what? I gotta go. We got a laundry drain make and Scrooge cease the shovel.
And yeah. This
this is a pretty great exchange.
It's a little bit again Barks really isn't as subtle as I think I would like him to be. It's a very per
meeting. We we know exactly they're supposed to both
Donald is supposed to let it slip that he's basically had the same experience that Scrooge has. I do love the panel where they collide and their bills fold down and pressed into each other. It's a riot. That... That's a great one.
But
but on the, it's a pretty serviceable
sequence. It's funny because this sets the real story up. And in a lot of ways, it feels like we could've gone a slightly different route with this. Like one of them could have gone to the other about them what they've seen. But the the difference... I wanna think about Screwed and Donald is is that at times they're bigger kids than the nephews. Mh. And they're all for themselves. This is a very weird Scrooge versus downs
in my mind, because usually a versus Donald story is donald or sp each like they're smarter than the other. And the other one has to prove them wrong. But this one is just sort of
we could easily fix this by just talking to each other.
But no. We don't have that... That's not what this comic is about.
So they go off. That's an excellent point. Right? This is definitely one of those situations where the lack of communication... I mean, it drives the story forward, but it can be a little a little bit frustrating.
And I have that same thought. Right? In another Scrooge story this could very easily be okay. I'm gonna first time gonna go to the hardware store and find a bargain on shovel, and next, I'm gonna go get donald and the kids because I'll need their help. To figure out blah blah blah. But... But that's not what's what Barks wants to do here he wants to have this this opposition story.
And so we set up the opposition by having Scrooge talk
with the nephews
and and they don't really know what's going on. But they know just enough to flu Scrooge jin saying that Donald been acting mis mysterious ever since he came out of a hit distance office down the street just now.
And I like I like Scrooge
exclamation. Oh my plume hack. And he has already bought a shovel.
And and so Scrooge just thinking out loud. Donald on is the reborn, Boston Benton tail. He knows where the treasure is by having been levi into the past same as I was.
So Scrooge sets off to a tropical
airline ticket office planning to beat him to the islands and the nephews
we're we're gonna transition now because it's not solely a screwed story. Mh. We're gonna transition to Donald and the kids. And and the net are gonna slow donald
down a little bit by very reasonably
demanding an explanation of why he wants them to get their sea tags.
Packed for example.
It's fun. It it it is... The whole thing is it's really funny yeah. The fact that
Oh my p had, and he's already bought a shovel.
Right.
Right the bill breaker. Like he's already got the shovel. He's basically dug the treasure out now.
So like, I can't waste any anytime. I gotta go and he we do emilio sort of like we have no idea what is going on. Let's like, look. Look on down. We love you.
We respect you something that is... But... What's what's going on? What is going on? You talked it to a man, levi you and now we gotta get sea tags
and we're ten years old. Why do we have details?
And they're reasonably
they're reasonably skeptical because he's just been
too. I like I like that little touch.
So, you know, we we transitioned through a narrator box where Barb talks about the explanation,
and and the Nephews is her like, Are willing to blow your whole fortune on a trip to this island without knowing for sure the whole business wasn't a dream.
And and they make him prove prove it, basically by resting some details out of him
and they're able... They're gonna be able to confirm the the records
the name of the ship through the library records.
I like the name of the ship. It it's called the Falcon Rover and he remembers the dates,
which was December six fifteen sixty four. So, hey, we're, you know, that's really handy. I I just realized we're gonna be
I'm gonna be releasing this right around
pretty close at least to the anniversary.
Same month the least.
And then they're able to figure out that the islands, the island is about a days sale Northwest of Trinidad,
and an island called Lonely Island. And so the nephews leave to go do their research while Donald Paste worrying about new millions and treasurer state and the kids being practical. And the nephews
are pretty excited when they're able to confirm those details at the library
including a passage called the last days of the Falcon Rover. Yeah. This is...
This is just a really fun sequence
altogether then once again, there are stories when he were doing little all the voices of reasons, they're the adults in the room and this is pretty intrigued
So like now, no. None of this makes any sense.
So give us some fax here. Which is really how you would address anyone who says like, hey, I was this in the past life. Well then you should know this. So, you know, that.
And so they get the data, and they go. You know what? Let's research this. Which really screws would have done any other time. Right But once the what's the idea of gold is in his head, he tends to just jet off without thinking, we see Donald do it. Like I said earlier, like, most days Scrooge it down to other big other kids in the and he we're dealing Louie sort of forced to grow up a bit more. Again, why do they have sea tags
and really in school
They have a vast amount of knowledge and desire for research.
That would not be expected if anyone there age. But this sort of like in line would say Johnny Quest.
They're
surprisingly brought kids. And once they get the fax, like, you know what, this actually might be fun. Let's go look a dialed. Yeah And and it's good wish fulfillment of course for the for the young readers.
I I
you're noting that it's it's a very sensible thing, right, for them to confirm this, you're absolutely right, and it's exactly what the guy, the hit twist who
did that story of variety
authority of sobriety Murphy. He did not do this basic research.
That would have confirmed, you know, that the real woman's
story was not true. So... Yeah. And you mentioned too that Scrooge Donald are they are. They're very impulsive. This whole story feels very impulsive to me.
So they they're on board and and after...
Oh, they they also tell him the the most promising
detail that they're gonna tell on the next page is that the the Falcon rover was reported with all hands being lost
just a few days after or leaving that island. So Donald takes a moment to more and, you know, poor pen tail.
And they they get packed including shovel, and they head off to the airport,
and bucket, who should be
one place ahead of them in line.
Person ahead of them with his own shovel because that's seems to be a big point in this entire story. Right.
It's uncle Scrooge.
Right there, I love that the shovel almost feels like its own character here. U. Dual breaker. It's the plot mover. Could they not just buy shove when Huey, get.
Exactly. No shovel and Trinidad. That you gotta pay the pay the luggage. You gotta go to the trouble of taking one on the airline.
The idea one thing I wanna address is like sort of sad look on Doll face when he found out that Pen tilt died, he's basically realizing, oh, yeah. I died at one point.
Like but, yeah. Otherwise, you wouldn't be here Al. Right. That's how past lives work.
Yeah. It's a very mel calling little moments that that you know, Barks doesn't have time to dwell on. But it it does definitely makes you think...
Yeah. This is a weird and and kind of
more idea. So
So with Scrooge
ahead of him in line, he feels... He doesn't feel like he has to keep it secret. He introduces himself as Donald old b man,
Mick dot
The docks have a nice little p for, the the the Nephews, say Kill H for swabs, this would have to happen.
And Scrooge.
He's he's pretty cut throat here. What what does he do? Fuck. He does something that carries on through most Inducks stories. He decides to buy all the seats left on the through that plane.
Room for his shovel.
Right and this is something where Barks is really flexible. He will use screws
stream thrifty
for gigs when he wants to having him unwilling to, like, spring for a a modern map. For a dollar instead of a dime and say the great steamboat raise because that's funny, and it's in character.
And then in this one, he'll likewise, he'll uses a stream wealth and have him be a little bit spend for for another good guy.
There there's no real logic to it, but it but is very funny. It's a fun and almost Friday thing about screws to think of how much you could accomplish just by throwing down a stack. And I think people sort of forget that you the characters like, say the penguin. Or
from batman who can throw his wealth around to get horrible things done. Those things they heard Scrooge, they sometimes a occur along gold. But for Scrooge is like no, no. He will throw that money around, usually to teach someone lesson, and usually, it's not or if it's stressed out, say in Ducktales and the storage around the economy because his money's is on the top floor of of Al hotel. He just sound like, no, I'll just buy the whole building. And just call it quits. Like, he can just do that. And for anyone else that be like, you'd have to, like, I can't just buy it. Now Scrooge has that kind of money. No right? He can walk in somewhere and just buy whatever he's looking at.
For.
And Scrooge story tell, they have this great leeway because of what Barks is done. And how he goes both ways with. So we we're gonna transition pretty quickly here to Lonely Island.
Screws has got a kind of a little boats
He's got at least a days head start on Donald. And, you know, he
transitioned to the boat
moment. He... He's kind of... He's kind of mu over what he's done to get ready checking his preparations.
And he thinks to himself, I took off in a Mon dr Hurry, who? I don't think I've ever encountered that word before.
I took off in a Mon stray hurry, but I'm sure I didn't forget us. Thing, you know, which is gonna be a nice little hints that he has forgotten something. Mon str. Yeah. I don't see that. And
I don't see that. In the dictionary or anything. So it looks like that that was Barks cleaning
his own adjective there. And and so, you know, you might think that the net fuse wouldn't have bothered since they're gonna be so far behind in the race.
But they have... They've spent Donald money for their passage. They're very for lauren about it. And they're even more down hard when they learn that a fear tropical storm is making it necessary for them to land
in the South American Main.
And and it's gonna keep them out of the game for a while. Right? Back up? Mh. It's... It's one of those moments where when you lose this heat this
this lead because by default,
on that plain. Means he's already there. He's he's already a day ahead. Right. And it's very hard to make up a day. Alright. Because we say ourselves like, if whether we have a project do anything, when we lose the day.
You're never gonna get that day back. You'd have to do double the work, but this is us trying to get somewhere And then, of course, the weather happens and it just makes it so much worse.
So they have a perfect Gottfredson to feel so bad about this.
Right. And and if not for this weather
situation,
because that storm is gonna end up effect things Scrooge really badly. And and the Nephews user kind of board waiting in their hotel until they venture out again. And they decide to take a look at the storm. It does look like a pretty pretty significant one. And
it's a really neat little
small splash panel that he does of the storm itself. It's one of the... There's not a lot of really flash here show panels in this one. But this one's pretty cool that the Caribbean kids in full roar as Donald sets.
And and the Caribbean in full roar is pretty dangerous.
It's just an interesting scene to see like, hey. Looks crazy out there. Just
Caribbean storms are are no joke, especially on the screen. It's really just sort of setting you up, hey, this is going to happen. The thing Scrooge forgot to check was the weather, which is a
the rule for people going on the sea or the ocean, you know, you check the weather. Because right it's more than a day you could lose it there. And you're right. I'm glad you pointed that out. I forgot to mention that Scrooge has that that
recollection.
He's says blast my pinnacle, I did forget to check something.
There there's a lot of pretty straightforward
storytelling
in this one. It's fine. It's very serviceable.
So what do the du end up seeing throughout this storm search?
They see a rather familiar boat, just sort of, you know, losing it out there in the Caribbean sea going back and forth being pretty much tossed around like a bean bag in the Caribbean salt storm. And Donald just wants to go up there,
Hue and Dub That's their Donald holds your horse which I do appreciate
that the the nephews have totally invested in this pirate story that they've just changed their accurate and everything else.
This like hide behind the rock. And because this boat it turns out is uncle Sp boat. That has crashed on the rocks. Right. That's right. As you say, it's it's a nice little touch that Bark makes all of the characters
throughout
use a little bit of this old maritime
slang And and and he doesn't it. It doesn't get, like, higher some I don't think. It's also interesting that, you know, it's donald here who really wants to be kind of the good deed do and the nephews were like, hold up. Let's do. See who this is. But you're right, they discover that it's uncle screws forced to go to shore again with that shovel. That's the only thing that he's saved.
So the docs are very cheered because everyone's on even putting now. We do get another really cool full width splash panel of of the storm and all of its glory. It's like wrecking every ship on the island.
Very neat. I like that one a lot.
But but Scrooge does notice one nice gift that's been
secured high and drive of the waves. You wanna tell us about that interaction?
He sees it. Okay. Cool. Skip. Got this. I just gotta get this skip good. He goes to visit the... To see the gentleman who owns the house
who presume it owns to skip. He's like, hey, I'd like to mention you about after the storm, and you turn around and the storm was happened to the ski.
And with the gentleman acts,
it was you asked the dumbest questions.
Just goes off. It's it's a great bit of pacing. Right? It asked him for it in one panel. A tree
destroys it in another. And and the guy is like
it's still a deal.
I I found it very funny. It's a it's a good little gag in the midst of it. So we transition to the end of the storm.
And the Ducktales making plans to be the first to get to Lonely island.
But
as they inquire about renting a boat,
It's cute. Some of the villagers are kinda cheering. The storm is over a eva had a Sunshine
and a little bit of pigeon English
span Span. I guess. Mh. It's worth noting that, you know, this is not one of those stories where the people on the island are treated with... That they're treated very respect. There's not not a ton of stereo.
Going on here. At least relative to some of the other stories that would have similar settings.
And so they talked to someone who points out that the only craft left to afloat in these waters is one called the little pageant raider
which is a small copy of an English man war that's used in, like, their pageant.
So this is a nice touch. Right? Because the Ducktales that the ship would be... Or basically, it would be a replica
of the falcon Rover, but but in small scale,
So they want a rush to be the first ones to rent it, but but as with the airport, they recognize the voice of a certain someone
who is just one step ahead. To wanna read the line there that that Scrooge uses bucket. That welcome my eyes. This is the clone crap I've seen since I barge gold down the Yukon, but I'll have to rent it and it turns out it's uncle Scrooge in case the Yukon bit didn't give me the give you the clue. But it's always nice to hear cro screwed. It's it's one of my favorite things. That out all the different iterations. If he's not cro, I don't want him.
Yeah. I really like that line. I find that very funny. So again, the Ducktales
spare, but they do get this
opportunity because Scrooge is is gonna have a really hard time finding a crew to to run what is basically like a show boat. And so, what what is the Ducktales sprite idea bucket?
They have taken the bride and pretty ingenious idea really of, you know, putting on a disguise and, you know, pretending to be his crew, like can't. He needs a crew, he won't clearly won't help us let's pretend to be actual hard and say who know what's going on and, you know, these group. It's charming it's hilarious, the costumes are adorable and it's hell hilarious Scrooge screw just identifies them as a one I'd sailor in three digits.
Right. And, of course, you know, that's a term that is definitely out of fashion these days.
It was very commonly used in in that era, so I won't pick on Barks for using it, but but it should... It should be noted that we would call them little people today.
But they're pretty funny like classic marks disguise. Right? Mh. Yeah. Yeah. The nephews look deceptive enough that you would that I could see how sk wouldn't think. They were his grand Nephews, but Donald clearly. Clearly all he is done. Is cover one eye. Right.
I looks more like buzz in Pint frankly now. I think the trick is that
down doesn't have a shovel. I think that's the clue.
The shovel would be giving him away.
Right.
Excellent. So again, this is pretty straightforward
in in a longer Barks story, he probably would've have stretched this last voyage out a little bit. They might have encountered something else.
But we're just we're heading towards our islands and and, you know, the Nephews are kind of
celebrating their clever idea in in secret
saying we couldn't beat uncle Scrooge to the treasure. So we'll just get there at the same time. And, eventually, they
they land
Scrooge sp Lonely island with a spy Gladstone
Donald comments.
Do you wanna tell us Donald line
swallow my sc. It looks just like you did in fifteen sixty four.
Yeah.
And and so screwed commands that they stay aboard as he'll go a sure alone in the demi of the little boat. And Donald now revealed himself shockingly.
Saying you wouldn't be leaving your old buddy behind. Would you maybe mac Ducktales
I love that... I love Scrooge just outraged
surprise here. Right?
Donald you horn swapping flow back to a pint tilt pirate. You tricks me.
That's a great line. You know, so Scrooge is just gonna he's gonna have to make the best of it. They're gonna try and and do the honorable thing.
It's it's kind of hilarious
because this could have all been exactly the same story. How do they just agreed to go together?
You are. That's really.
There's not much ant
in the back and forth Granted, that will be clearly
and undone in the next sequence,
but it was still just
just a fun bits that I think hadn't been played up a bit more. It would have felt a bit more deserving of the shock, but Scrooge down had been like vague sw has been missing donald like every other chance. She sort of have a back and forth with them. There's no real pb dialogue outside of the shock that donald here on the Scrooge just here and mcdonald's here. With his shuttle uncle group is here with a shovel, and now, we're gonna see these shovel pay off.
Right. Right. He know what just occurred to me actually, when you mentioned this could have been the same story with someone else I feel like there's a lost
opportunity to have had a specific villain in this story. I think I would have liked to have seen Chi Mcs
from the horse ra story. As as the antagonist. I'm I'm imagining if he were if he Scrooge is off opposition.
You know, instead of Donald and Donald was was part of the same deal that could been really interesting because of course, they faced off in this same Caribbean part of the world and and And you know, the the idea of the horse
being this, like, weird, but at the time precious cargo
in that story, kinda plays well with how this one. So so just an idle thought, but but I also really like Chi to as a villa I thought he would have been needs to stick around. Yeah. That idea is that is actually better than mind. My thought was just to go sort of basic
not sure if you've been introduced you yet at this point, but we could've have brought our Al on this. Another moment for them to have a back and forth. Because that would have worked even more you could have had it be that, you know, Donald needs work. Alright? You Al Donald tends to. And he is hired. By global, doesn't even know it's going like, hey, this guy, the switch guy needs me to go help find a treasure. And by the time he finds out it's blowing, it's too late he's already there. And the nephews user there... It it would all still sort of work. Right. Yeah. It's it's funny. You say that because this is almost
with the second rich duck. I haven't released it yet, but I... It's I just recorded it a couple of nights ago. It'll be the episode right before this one. So Oh so, yeah. If you if he had in the mood to reuse Guam, I could definitely see it working out. Yeah. And if he had done that, I'm sure I'm sure we have seen a lot more appearances.
Alright. So, anyway, tell us tell us about their arrival on the beach. So as soon as they get there and...
Despite the fact they're two grown adults who've realize they both kinda have a stake in this. It's like you know what? Let's just fight with these shovel.
Alright. Al salute Boston Pint says Scrooge to the treasure, long lived the treasure,
and Huey, just wash his two grown men, fighting with shovel. And this is Let let's be clear a shovel is not the safest thing. To know people.
And but luckily, these three ten year olds just tackle their grown adults. And grown.
And like, aren't you shave yourself? Al of that notable about how you made long ago, he wanted to find it over the treasure like a pair of common pirates.
To up I personally made no valves.
Right. Right.
It's hilarious
you're right. That fights really funny. I like how it starts out with them, like, basically pretending to be noble or making an effort to it, Right, salute each other, and then it just dev.
I also like how it it totally parallels,
the val that they had previously made to Queen Ba, But, of course, this one is much less noble they're just
the treasure itself. So, yeah. The Nephews point out that, you know, there's nothing worth fighting over
until we confirm that this isn't some sort of double dream But why don't you take us home and and tell us about the actual
excavation here. So after nice rapid digging fast, just really great Severino.
Seconds later as the nail reports out they find the chest, it's a relatively light chest and
don't have like, you know, whatever say, it's ours You know, Queen Basketball won't miss the money. You know? Okay. Sure.
They found that it's empty,
but it isn't empty. There's some dried potatoes inside. Along with Al letter, and the it explains everything written by caps talk, it is my friend belief that these strange one vegetables will be greatly surprised by her imperial majesty
and dewey we points out. Yeah.
Potatoes were unknown left time and Louie, which I think this is a very really question Well, what do you boys going to do with your rare old treasure
And for the first time they're generally on the same page as whole story, and they decide to beat the brakes off
off the Treasure chest And so we're gonna do way worse to a couple of.
It it's a it's a solid ending. It's a nice little
Barks likes these
imminent
threat of violence endings.
It it's pretty funny, and this is a fun trope. Right? The the the the treasure is something that would have been valuable at the time,
but no longer holds any value whatsoever
today. That that's a trope that I've always
enjoyed, and it works really well in this context.
All in all, I think this is a really solid ending.
To... You know, I I mentioned that the that the story doesn't
necessarily feel rushed but as we've gone through it, I I'm kinda reconsider... I I do think this feels a little bit rushed and it coulda used maybe three or four more pages to breathe. Yeah.
I think the problem is that the the conflict is so
weak and and shallow in a lot of ways
because there's no reason why Scrooge wouldn't wanna work with donald the story outside of the fact he wants the treasure for himself. It really feels like bugs wanna create social a disconnect between the sort of noble
men that Malcolm and Boston Pent tell were that they're doing this service of the queen of the captain of the service they provided here, these two just want the treasure. Yeah. I think you're right. There's there's a lot of... He tries to get a lot of mileage out of these
contrast.
And it largely works
but, you know, maybe not as well as it could have. I also tend to like the the stories where Barks does a really great job of book ending.
Know and we don't really get that book here,
there there's no returning to Ducktales sequence
We don't see like, the the hit
To me, it would have been funny or if we saw the hit is, like escaping out his Barks door with
Scrooge and Donald both holding up their shovel men
trying to knock their way into to his office or something like that. I don't know I'm I'm just spit football.
But the story it does feel a little bit of abrupt. I I do...
I I enjoy this one. I I think I don't think I expected to enjoy this one as much as I did before I revisited it. You know? Because I remember this. And I always remember thinking this is a pretty weird story. It'll be interesting to talk about this one for the podcast that the hit
stuff always left a a bit of a bad taste in my mouth bucket because it's one of these examples of of a few Barks stories where Barks has screws really invested in something kinda cookie key, and I don't like that. I don't like seeing Scrooge
acting cookie. I think about this one and, like, Al later sixties story where Scrooge is like obsessed with his his,
star chart. Trying remember. It's like a... It's it's one where he's looking for a cave full of emerald. The title escapes me right now. But... But I always...
That's just not my bag as far as the story goes where he's into this kind of like new a
off. But but if you do,
if you just accept the premise of this one, I think this is a pretty fun
entertaining story. Yeah. It it it keeps the job done.
I I I agree with you. I like when Foods is sort of put more into the
your grandfather that knows everything.
He's the season traveler. I think only a paul of man really showcase that really well. Right. And got this wealth of experiences right on or...
In King solomon minds. I think he shows off his intelligence is a bit more here. This sort of shows Scrooge just still sort of prone to fad
in some ways that... But you have to really sell the profit idea here. That it's worth way more the idea that a Scrooge gives up
on ninety dollars. Is a chance he'll know, come out with so much more. And that would get we saw the same thing in the golden fleece. Like, you know, even when even though screwed is a bit, you know, ridiculously trusting of of of this mysterious person, the always was was like, this, I'm not quite sure. I don't... No. I don't... Then he gets these Ac the golden fleece is put in front of them. And you sort of...
The rash side, it sort of goes goes to sleep a bit or it's like push aside. Right. Yeah. And and it helps in this one he's he is skeptical of it until he's actually
ties.
But, you know, he's open enough to it to to buy in. It's it's just not the kind of premise that's for me. But
but I This is a fun one on the whole.
I would I would put this. I would kinda slot this in as like an average
Barks story is kind of the way I think of it it's your your typical just fine Barks story, which, of course, you know, in in terms compared to, like, a lot of other comments creators, that still places it in its own sort of range of greatness. Right? Mh. It's a it's a solid story that I think it's only real downside is it's completed. It's competing against other really good stories. Right. But it's still... It's still... Again, still solid, it's still funny.
Reread this here, I've never realized how much I love the character of the shovel. Alright. This is this is top tier or character here. Alright. Like, I I think Bard should have really got a whole series about this organization of shovel.
March universe. Alright? Because stop going on here. The shop is the michelle will start this store in its own way and then they end the story and this how shovel there the treasure a shovel
could be used to protect the treasure that has shovel destroyed is the treasure. Yeah.
Like poetry which arrives.
Right. Yeah. It is it is a very funny bit. I do. I do like the over use of the treasure for of of the shovel for comic effect. It's it's really good. Let's see. I I think we covered that pretty well. Are you ready to get into kind of the the community consensus for this story? Yes. Let let let's see what the what the people have to say. Right. So so it sounds like you and I are in pretty close agreement. Right? That this is neither of our favorite stories, but there's nothing like really objection about it and and it's it's a fine time. It's it's a good. It's a good enough story.
If we check in on Inducks,
you know, which is the great resource that has all kinds of information about Disney comics and that users can can rate the comments on. So it gives us pretty pretty good idea of what community thinks. This one gets a seven point seven out of ten bucket And and that's a that's pretty solid.
It's good for a numeric score of... It's it's a ranked score of one hundred and twenty six. As of right now out of all the Disney comments. So, you know, it's not coming in in the top hundred
or anything, but it's definitely, like in the higher here of Barks Adventures. I I don't remember. I made a... I made a very nerdy list at some point and I did like
I did. What do you call those things with the video games where they they rank characters
by tier... A tiers list? They did a tiers list at one point. And I believe this one was just in that average range.
Probably probably well into the upper half though. Of stories as most of these really Scrooge adventures.
Are. But, yeah, people like this one well enough. And
it has had a little bit of an after life in other Disney.
Right? You had mentioned...
You'd already alluded to the fact that Don Rosa uses some of these details to to flash out his life and times
you mentioned chapter five. Right? That's that's where we're gonna get the most That's a very strange chapter. In that series. I'm I'm guessing it's probably the most divisive chapter. For a lot of people.
Maybe. Maybe... I know I loved it. I love it as kid. But then again, I read that entire story out of order.
Sure sure. I started with part twelve
And that would be
didn't even know. It was part twelve. I'd like this looks cool. I no idea what's food is so sad.
Right. But last page was really good. And I remember reading
Part five and large of Castle mc Inducks, and
Seeing going to Inducks kevin and seeing all these other Inducks really sort of showed you a bit more that I thought was really capable of this story at this time. Guess This was this is the only comments I was reading at time. I didn't have any access to really anything I saw it and went with it. And hearing that that seem like quietly circle Quack Inducks Al has call, Al malcolm duck out when he says that Screws invested all his money and the cattle energy before it went bust, he has no business sense. And so quack points out, and who went down with the falcon roll with fifteen sixty four on a treasure hunt ford potatoes.
Like, it may been special to England at the time, but there's no financial feature
potatoes.
Yeah. So that that chapter... I mean, I I I love... I love that. Series.
But, like, there are parts of it where I look back on that one. I'm like that, that's pretty weird. Right? That, you know, in a way that is a little bit to comforting to me. But... But then if I think about this story, I Barks had his moments where he went went with these kinda cookie premises too. So So in light of that, it's definitely not that weird at all. Let's see. You know, I but I I think I've pretty much gotten to share all of my thoughts other than doing, like, a
checking in on our favorite panels. Do you have any other any other thoughts that you'd really wanted to mention regarding this story?
So
my my version, which I think is is the original version. I do like
when Scrooge is
clothes or that one set color. This times where it's green, and I really like the green. This sort of burgundy.
And like a really good color for which was another thing going into the comics was very awkward for me to get... Because I was used to the red and blue from the Ducktales car. Right. I think my favorite scene would have to be sort of at the end when donald and screws, you know, pledged to the treasure and of course, the flash
of malcolm and... Or maybe dot this one and
pen Al making you the pledge to the queen. And of course, the the scene of the beginning,
just sort of seeing Scrooge in his money office, which I think it is the actual Bin because you can see the little window. And.
Yeah. Yeah. I think it's one of his overflow rooms.
Yeah. Those are that's a good choice. I I like that contrast between those two salute a lot.
As as far as, like favorite panels, I'm thinking about it and and in this read through, it really stood out to me the
the the smashing into each other while holding the shovel. That... That's just such a great slaps stick panel. I also really like the very first panel where he travels back to the past, and you see them growing their their gift to the shore the first time that they appear as their past lives themselves
There's just some really beautiful details, a nice illustration of that we see the I guess, it's our only real shot of the Falcon rover. In fact. In the whole thing. So there's a good view of the falcon Rover or a couple of
another example of Barks bird for grounding where he draws couple of a bunch of assistants Barks around and... Yes. It's just really lovely. Lovely panel. And then I did really like that sequence where the
The the dry doctor vote gets crushed immediately. Scrooge is bargain before it Any mean, any other favorite panels that came to mind for you?
Anytime you would doing Louie are allowed to look so cynical about what is it going on.
There's nothing there's nothing like amazingly drawn about it. It's it's just a steady standard moment. But
anytime those three are sort of forced to be the voice of reason,
I just sort of enjoy because you almost forget from moment that they're nine to ten year olds. Right. And it's a fun thing. You'll see in sort like the Simpsons with Lisa, and it's always fun because then you go to so where they are just allowed to be kids. And right. It's still hilarious and it's still fun. Then all of a sudden their their geniuses. And it's fun and
I've been debating on my next Ducktales lo video. And I'm not ready for donald. There's is way too much of donald.
But I was thinking you're dude here were doing Louie because they... While they free interchangeable
in the in the comics. There's always a special role they play. Maybe not individuals but as is collective fun unit.
Of of characters that they like donald, they can sort of adjust to any story, but rather they adjust to whatever role the store needs and to be in. Yeah. They they're very reflective of whatever the store needs them to be. And I love them for that. Yeah. That's that's I think that's right. They're definitely a unit.
And and definitely in this one, it's pretty rare that they're even named
individually. You know, you were pointing out their cynical kinda sequence. I I just was going through this part. Check out this panel
where they're pouring over the log book and they kinda dive in to get a closer look and the two nephews on the outside.
Sandwich, the middle connect.
Memorable. That that panel, I really like too. That's really cool. Yeah. It is is it is a fun one. It it really is. And I think one thing I've always liked about the nephews in regards to this, is there's always been the question as to the inevitable moment when Scrooge will go unquote pass or travel through time, going out match fitness bell.
The jury is still out.
Who would take over and he's always sort of implied that it will not be done. As much as he secretly likes donald. Donald not the one. He does love the potential the hard work ethic,
the open minded of the nephews.
And here, they're not so much Al short off open minded, but in this and the goal the least, they show off there the maturity, but they're hesitate to always go for the shiny anything thing going on here, and I do like that. They've got a lot more risk strength than the adult dots and in some of these stories for sure.
It sort of goes with the idea that a full and his money is parted
The boys mentioned like, Donald going to risk his entire quote unquote fortune Scrooge has not only lost ninety dollars, but however much she paid,
for all the of the plane as well as to rent out. The replica the fan Rover of Falcon Rover, Huey, lost all of that. For a treasure chest of trill up potatoes.
Yeah.
Yeah. It's a fun. It's a fun out. Come. It's not it's not maybe the most memorable ending.
I mean I mean, I guess it is fairly memorable actually. Probably the most memorable part of this story. Is...
I mean, certainly, it's the the actual
traveling back to the past. The the past lives regression. But Al close second would be that ending itself, which which has a nice little kit. Yeah. The story is more selling the the gimmick of hi. This isn't the story that really elevate
screwed donald to the characters that we tend to think of them as. This sort goes was like, no. That there was a time when they were just Scrooge donald. And in the same way that you would look at what we expect from characters like batman now was not expected of him at the time this was all written now. He was just looking for a good the end. And this is a good time to be had. Yeah. Yeah. I think I this an adventure that's well worth joining the du on
if if mostly to laugh Al them. Alright. I I did just... Try to mention duck.
Right? I'll just I'm not aware of any
of any time that duck tried to adopt this in either of the series iterations. But I don't have that great memory of the
second one. Because I only gave it one watch through. Do you know of any reference to this story?
So if I'm not mistaken in the
curse of Castle
was... I forget the name of the episode. It's it's early and season one. When they go to visit castle like document, I do believe you'll see Malcolm medium Inducks
as one of the ghost and cows Inducks, but that's pretty much it. Now
original or the reboot address this particular story because it's really not that exciting story. It's It's pretty generic in terms of the premise. If you take off hi. There's a treasure we go look for it. That's kind of it.
Nothing nothing really more than Al fleeting reference.
Excellent life. I think we did an admirable
job of covering this one.
So let's see. I guess we should... I guess we should give each other a nice shovel salute and and wrap the story up.
I I really appreciate you joining me for this one bucket bucket think tank of course is your channel on Youtube, right? Where people can find your duck, videos, Ducktales, lower videos, as well as other things. And anything else you wanted to mention or promote?
So
the Ducktales lower video, I have no set date for that because I'm still not even a hundred percent sure I wanted you were doing Louie.
Because what I do for those is I would go for each iteration of them as possible. Now for the common version, it's more... They don't really stand out as individuals.
But you go to say it's different cartoons and generations. One thing I'm somewhat proud of is what I saw the first episode of twenty seventeen, when I know exactly which episodes the original Ducktales they use for the Al. I do want to see if I could think of another another video where I would compare different stories or ideas. From, say the twenty seventeen series to other versions, especially if I could find the actual
that it was based off. Thankfully
fantastic graphics graphics terrible what it's called.
Is been a great help. Oh, I know. It's it's it's nice to have. It's it's nice to have someone.
Still releasing dot com in some form in the states. Is these right?
Well well, yeah. People... I I don't people can check out your your lora videos. And
I again, I really appreciate you joining me. It's been a lot of fun. We'll have to have you back for another of these. People can check us out are we're on the socials, sparks remarks is on Facebook
and
and Instagram. I share a lot of fun stuff on Facebook is especially
including a more expanded, like, favorite panels things. So
definitely encourage you to check out Instagram kind of an after thought, but do some fun stuff on there too. Our next
episode
should be a.
It's it's a huge favorite of mine. I'm big fan of a cold bargain. So I'm very excited to cover that one. Bucket, I like to... These days I like to close out the episode by having the guest read the last panel. So
even if it's a repeat, close this out. Right. Alright. I'm just gonna go to that page. Alright. But not half as much as we're going to do to a couple of.
Excellent.
Alright. Thanks again. I really appreciate it, Tar. Thanks for having. Yeah, it's been a pleasure.