We can have
Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer an artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comments of all time. Join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks. Welcome back to Barks remarks. I'm Mark Sever a Grown man who loves comics, and I'm joined by a couple of other grown men
we're gonna talk today about
what I consider to be a great classic Barks story.
We'll be talking about the seasonally appropriate cold bargain, at least pretty cold where I am. And
I am joined by a returning guest who is a comet book fan, but a Carl Barks newbie,
and that's Ryan. Say hello, Ryan. Hello, everyone. And then as as a new guest, I'm joined by Va
Who is
joining us by way of from Poland, but by way of Finland. Right? You are a finish fan bay? Yes.
Room. Excellent.
So so, Ryan, I was wondering have you ever gotten over extended in an off.
Probably not the extent that he did. I... I've never spent a trillion dollars on anything. I do
collect auto graphs, and sometimes
If you're keeping an eye out for the good pieces, sometimes you see a good piece that you know you're not gonna see again.
And I remember there was one in one
collector group. I was in... Someone was selling his pieces that had already been dedicated, meaning it said two so sell, But they said to Ryan, and and so there was a a hands drawn picture by matt Grain of Lisa Simpson saying hi, Ryan and then signed by Matt Gran and david, and then another one
Edna mo from the incredibles drawn by Brad Bird and signed right bad Bradford that also said Hi Ryan No cape. And both of those were so choice.
Pretty. And they were both of those guys are pretty expensive on their own, like, what would be probably a few hundred
depending on the circumstances, but
they were little cheaper because who would want one that's already dedicated to someone else, you know, that has someone else's name on them. So Sure So it was a very good deal for me, but also
a little more than I would usually spend, but they were so excellent.
Are hard to pass up. Right? Awesome. And how about you waco, this is your first time joining me on the podcast.
When people join me for the first time, I like to learn a a little bit about them as as Carl Barks fans and and you know, your own perspectives. So, you know, tell us about how long you've been reading Barks.
Well, I've been reading Barks as long as I can remember because
Al a lot of finished to learn of my generation and also for generation,
reasons I
grew up reading
down magazine or first having it read to me and then learning could rate course from it. Pretty much as far I again, I can remember, I was also aware of car Barks as as this guy who who with the best double
clinics. When I was growing up in the mid eighty was a
period for the fish downtime
magazine
they they had this
editorial
column sort of similar to the one that that that was the American
issues Al at at the time and they was often feature
articles there
about car Barks
Car was
after time I I think the only are still they mentioned by name. I mean all the the already in the in the the comic book we're still
not credited even even Barks.
But
it was sort of an open secret that that this
we could come we're probably by white Barks and and and his name last was mentioned there. And and and they they also
answered
letters from the from the Burritos. Yeah. He's always been like the the good Ducktales artist.
Yeah. It's it's so fun hearing to me. It's so fun hearing about European readers who had this experience that I I wish I'd had, you know, being read to karl Barks to me. I was just... I was lucky to find it. They revive the the series back when Ducktales was was launched. But, yeah, it's great. A lot of a lot of Scandinavian
and european readers have similar
experiences to you. Do you... Do you have any favorites stories that are, like, really
significant to you maker.
Well,
since we are getting here the Christmas or or in the christmas season and I I I would like to mention one of my
stories
a little to stan
that must be my favorites of the birth Christmas stories and and it's it's also one of the earliest that I can remember from my childhood because it it was first published in finished on like magazine in the day, this when I when it was tried. So I I and remember it coming out in this
installations.
Just before Christmas I nineteen eighty five or or nine eighty six. So there's not that's one of the
recent and still one of my every stories Oh, yeah. A big fan of letters to Santa. That's that's a great Barks Christmas story. So eighty five eighty six. I think you started reading just the brown the same time I did. It was probably lady...
Probably early eighty seven for me. I'm gonna guess. Donald Duck and Magazine is Ak An. Is that how you say it? Oh, yes. Yep. Okay. I've I've I've never actually heard it settle out, so I was kinda curious. Awesome. Thank you so much for joining us. Faith go Alright. So gentlemen, I'm really excited to talk about this. This is a long time favorite of mine. I I came across like, a a list on one of my old computers that I had made of some of my favorite Carl Barks stories a couple of decades ago. And I did mention this on, like, my top ten list. I don't know that I'd put it quite up that high these days, but I I have...
There's like, Al place in my heart for this story. I think there's a lot about it that works really well.
Kind of the the unspoken premise of this series that I guess I'm staying out loud is that all of these stories are worth talking about But I think this one is is more worth talking about than than a lot of them. Because we've got like this really neat cold war in intrigued
in in a cold bargain. I mean, you know, right in the title, it's kind of a evo of of the thing of the cold war and the United States is like nuclear stand with the Soviet Union. And Bark is gonna... You know, the the comics came out of the second world War Barks was he started doing them when the Us was in the midst of it. And so a lot of the stories were informed by that. Ryan, you were you with me in some of the... Those earlier stories I I imagine even if it's not over, you can probably see a lot of the undertone
Right? How can you escape it? I'm thinking especially of, like, when we did tear of the river, and you know, what the c sharpen bent that one felt very informed. By World War two. And this is the other great geo
political conflict that's gonna kind of... That's gonna kind of under occurred what Barks is doing and he doesn't often go as, like
obvious into it as he does in this story. But but for that reason, it's really
historically interesting to me.
Ryan, were you kinda thinking about about that history as you read this one?
A little bit. Yeah. I thought It actually seemed a lot more focused on those kinds of things than the other ones were. The other one seemed more
kind of more like
national geographic,
explore the world, kind of these are interesting cultures and exploring the bottom of the sea and finding the lost night and Right. All these other things
that could happen in in any time any kind of adventure story, it could been an edgar categorized burrows apple you know. Yeah. A lot of the ones that I had you joined for were were kinda more of those early, like, almost travel log stories that Barks did.
I guess you could kinda call them post colonial in a lot of ways. But... Yeah. What what about you waco? You know, someone who grew up kind of on the edge of the eastern block. I imagine that that to you the the cold war
elements really stand out in this one. Well, yes. I mean, especially when I was re reread it now, I I was
taking off the cold war aspect.
I would say,
even even more than when I originally
already. I I I don't have any very
strong recollection of actually first reading this this this story, but I remember they will when I got the
publication waived was first published in
in in in finland
because it very unusual in that it
appear in the actual downtime magazine
instead it was published in this
paper Barks series that
I'm sure all the
Al notes are are very familiar with. And probably some Al and German
well because
they the same series was published in
conditions.
This series of paper Barks about
two hundred pages each
that usually, feature said this
very weird italian
doctor and and
our stories
there
they can be pretty surreal and rendering
end. And
that's fair. Yeah. Yeah. And
get a little odd. Right right. And then they yes.
To have
value
more bit than
done done right weird. And so so this this the series generally
bit of like a bargain basement quality
only the... Every second page or base was colors. So so that the
like a white pages. I'll do with the experiments. But but suddenly in the fiftieth
installment of this series, which came out in nineteen eighty. But but but in this fifty is
suddenly published,
not only this this story I called Bargain, but two other Barks stories well the secret of the is and
the city of golden groups.
And and none of those service have had had come out in in in finish
before... So so so this this really certain event. And and usually, this story I called Barks is is is one that finish Barks fans remember. From that the paper remember that this was the book very could finally published. Because of course,
when the
when it was originally published in the United States in ninety fifty seven, the this this was a very very difficult time for
finland and and the ob Union,
especially the late and Oracle early when this could
come out in.
So so
it wasn't published in in
and in fact it wasn't published in any of the and that
that published don't coming Al the time. So not in denmark. Sweden or norway way. And I...
But I imagine
Sorry to... Sorry to interrupt like, like as you're saying here it would have been especially
sensitive probably to publish it in finland that that time. Right? Yes. Yes,
especially since in in in those years, that and the unit did have this crisis where the so but
withdraw their ambassadors from Finland and
there all these
negotiations And if even even
cartoons were,
I mean, I mean, political
were sometimes been involved in in all this because there was
one
political cartoon particular
who room for the biggest finish daily paper and he often had to care yourself
any nikita
shop with also
in this in Barks. Sorry or Al least. That's that's what some people say And he got to the point in ninety fifty nine that actually the finished
at the time. We're okay. And had to apologize for this
carlton that were have published in this.
They use newspaper.
Some representative And it's
important for Contact transactions because
the magazine was part of this same publishing house that that also published is
this daily newspaper and and that was also the finished publisher of reader tires, I guess. Oh so so they would have been... They would have been paying attention by then. Yes. I I think I very very that that you might have actually had had the situation where the president has to Al for. Yeah. Is it fair to say,
do you think
do you think it's fair to say that this story had it been published could Barks the geopolitical crisis? Oh yes. Absolutely
or these being.
Or at least some friction.
Yeah. Yeah. Right. It would it would have probably sparked an international apology. That's that's really fascinating to me. And and to be clear, you know, I think this is a great story in its own regard. I'm not just interested in talking about it. As as a cold were terrible
or or whatever. But I think this is a really fun... No. I saw someone
somewhere say that it's almost unfair to call this Al adventure story because it's like, it's it's a pretty slaps stick wrong. It's it's very funny.
It definitely has, like, the tone and the trapping
or the setting of an adventure story, but it's it's it's very far too in a way that I really like Yes. Yes. I I I agree with that, and that's also the reason why it's one of my favorites
of this
late fifties
Scrooge stories. I'm I'm not such great fan of the more adventure type
stories. The the ones that take
places on exotic places and and whether hunting pictures or ryan.
Yeah.
Yeah something that I'm observing as I do the series is that, like, the real Barks fans, you know, they they kinda think more highly of a lot of the ten pages Oh For my part, you know, the podcast, it's just more interesting to talk about the adventure price. But I do loved talking about that, you know, we've got the ten page podcast for that. I have a new question. Yeah. I love I love new questions. What part of what I've got you on here for, you know So
the first episode, probably the first few episodes, I was on, The comic was called Donald Inducks Adventures. And this comic is called Uncle Scrooge, and I was wondering if this is like a sql series or if there are multiple series running parallel, that is a good quest.
So
the these have been reprinted so many times. Right? That the scans that I would have sent you, they'd have been from titles that only existed later on, you know, the Donald Duck Adventures and uncle Scrooge adventures series. Most of the ones you were originally on for would have been published in a series called four color or one shot where it
every
issue, it might have been like bugs bunny one issue and then little lulu,
And eventually, Western Publishing,
if they had, like a breakout issue,
they might spin that off into its own title.
You know? So that that happens for both uncle Scrooge,
and and Donald duck, the the on the strength of the Carl Barks stories. Western
spun them off into
uncle Scrooge you know, only a poor man was was basically his trial. That was a big deal that he got his own character
spun off into its own.
Lined.
And he was the Uncle Scrooge comments line. It was a bim monthly comic, I believe, for the most part. And they only published it for the first. Many years of its existence when there was new Barks content.
But but it's safe to say that Barks career is kinda split into the Donald focused stuff. And then the Scrooge focus stuff. Right? So so I'll kinda transition here into the the comic itself. Right? Because we're up to uncle Scrooge number seventeen
at this point. It's only been around for a a few years
as a title.
As Said this one was... It had a cover date at least to early nineteen fifty seven.
And this one's been reprinted nine times.
So, Ryan, you know,
the first printing would have been is the uncle Scrooge title. But then it it'll... It'll it might be published in whatever.
You know, kind of lineup up, they think that they're running at the time,
basically in in Disney Comics hay for a while. There was enough material to support Al uncle Scrooge and an uncle Scrooge Adventures
And and that that nice golden age when when V and I started reading. Yeah. So let's see. This one is page length wise, this one is kind of a... It's a longer story. It's almost twenty seven pages.
We've already talked a little bit about some of the kind of culture and the history behind and this one, which is I think very interesting. But They, you mentioned Scrooge
shove, is russian one of your languages?
Yes.
Russian, actually, my first foreign language
nice in in the is school. So how should we all be pronouncing his name? K shift? Gru
well, I I think the
standard
English
or or the other way of writing it is full ship
However, in Russian, be pronounced first job oh crucial.
Okay. With the.
Yeah. So Ryan, did you did you catch
that... Oh, I'm I'm spacing on the word for a carrier that that kara couture, did you recognize him as a whoo shove character?
The B
ambassador? No. But, definitely not. I could probably...
I could probably recognize the stall analog, but I I actually don't know what cruise job looks like.
Yeah. So I think I think he kinda famously
has that sort of ball dome and that slightly a regular
shape to his head I think most people who who know what what the but that the Premier. Right? They were premier back then? Yeah. From
so up
the chairman would probably have recognized him as being a.
However, I did... I'm so glad that I looked Al my glad
reprint because there's a quote from barb at the end. You know, it ends with that weird, like, cutoff off page where it's three fourth of a page. And Gladstone chose to put a small
exchange that Barks made. I think it was in one of his letters.
Called the trillion dollar ball.
And and in it, he said he poses this question that fans have asked him was the B
ambassador,
anybody in particular?
No He was a composite of power hungry arms spiders from many nations with no. I should probably have given him the face of one of my sn pig villains that appeared a lot in later years. But I wanted to make him look
international. So that's what he officially says, but I'm I'm gonna call Bs.
I'm gonna say that he is clearly
intended to my eye to be a a cruise shove. Kara could show. What what do you think there?
Yes. Mean I I also read that statement from Barks and it's it's a it's a bit
but puzzling. I I I like to know what
exactly what's the behind I. I
Gladstone
right to Barks and and asking through
write something and
they did birth maybe right, just kind of a tom cheek notes to go because he basically this allows any cold war connections for the already also says that it it's...
Such suggest that is complete coincidence that the elements that after called.
Just that... Yeah. Do you wanna read us? The the other part I left out that here, you know what? Let me... I'll just mention the ask jim, and then I'll have you read that that quote in just a moment. Because this is the other element to the the story that I find really cool. It it's one of the many many pieces of pop culture
where the creator has to, like, make up an invented element. And and I love that. And in this case, it's called... It's called Ba. And I think that it's one of the best names of these, like fake elements.
You guys we we can all probably think of a few, you know, other movies and shows that have used pretend elements
do do either of you guys have
have a a favorite that comes to mind? You know, like, I think people would probably commonly think of, like, una titanium. Is that is that what Avatar called it? Yeah.
Possibly. I've never seen movies. So... Yeah. It's it's a it's a pretty on the nose one. Marvel
themselves have a couple of different ones, right? Like Adam
and by, is the,
the one from pond Al
and the black hand.
Yeah.
My one of my favorite series dis world has oc iron that there's just so many of these, and they're always a lot of fun. And So, you wanna tell us the the quote that Barks has in that about
Jim. I just remembered. Yes. I'm looking. No. Now. I'm looking Al a a a list of fictional elements. One of which is Bombastic on the on the Wikipedia.
But I was just reminded of element zero from Mass effect. Nice from back in the day,
Mass effect has really, really Ducktales,
like
history and everything I kind of explain everything in the game if you're willing to learn it all. And they... In this
fictional future, they've discovered element zero, which if you run a current through it, it makes something have no mass,
which then... And under under the laws of relativity, now you can fire that thing past the speed of light because it's not breaking any rules. And
so they kind of came up with this can t the reason why we're allowed to travel the galaxy in this game. And the charts like Yeah cool. It's neat when they'll actually try justification and and some of these elements are just, like really valuable,
where some of them do something very specific like in the case of this story. They go Why don't tell us what what Barks says about Mom.
Yes. So so here's the quote Barks.
Back in the nineteen fifties,
the financial news and most scientific publications
we're servicing with tongue twisting names of new elements that signed were recently shifting from rare or sputtering on the walls of cycle phones. I don't find boom yet in the table of elements but I won't be app surprised if it suddenly appears. Scientists will surely run up letters at some point. And have to use b
sooner or later. So so there is a sort of suggesting that if it was, you know, just a going is study having to have this
b o n
sure the name of the. But... Yeah, it's
it's it's it's contact that. And it make let me suspect maybe maybe
part, you know, purpose
maybe this the statement as over the top as as possible.
Huey, can
and it's gonna be taken
face feedback about.
That's... That's how say.
It it's
definitely wondering if they... If last
order to steady statement
from Barks with the with the exact purpose that that if they had is kind of
from from Inducks to probably
because some possible
Al.
Exactly. I said we could... Because this was the first time that these I've been in the... Yeah.
United that as well. It it it did appear in the heart color Barks library
to use papers about every day they that never were been in the comic book for me. And and even so they they have to make some slight
the operations three to... Right. Because this one's been a little bit
controversial. Right? Do you wanna? Do you wanna tell us faye a little bit about the
the art?
And the and other changes that they made for this? Yeah. So so apparently, in the
glad reprint, they chased the official features of the
k off character rocket. So that he he he appear. So they typically Russian, they
removed the high cheap ones and and also made
lives less less prominent. I I I think those only to change that I I I I think he
came out with rather
with with the new version. And then they also
changed the dialogue a bit so that one of the repeat advice in these stories that that is always saying to
Scrooge
reach big of Inducks and in the glass on, they change the word did to dog. So so they they they did sort of an
change in the other direction than what and but what the bugs would have wanted to do. And it's it's also interesting that Barks that it it it would've been better if he had actually connected to
the
leader as as a as a as a... I I I would imagine that be even even more commercial. But the
right because, like pig is a classic criticism
of of American capitalism.
Right? So... Yes. Yeah. So he probably wasn't thinking about that when he... When he kinda tossed that off. I imagine. Yeah. Right. And I didn't tell you about this, but this one's been fairly mildly altered, I would say as far as some of the Barks stories goes, I'm not accustomed to there being like, censorship
over, you know, technically
European features.
But, of course, you know, there's a there's a history of kara characterizing your your wartime components even if cold were never turned high. Yep. So for the listeners, his head is
extremely pointy. It's kind of an egg shape head and then he has a big big shoulders he has got a big body inside his suit that you can see there. I was I was trying to think of who it reminds me If I realized it's say
It would be the Barks bald bowl from Mike Tyson punch out. Look Al look at him again, Mark and tell me if that's not both from Mike tyson bunch of. I need the lift out ball bold because now I don't remember him Okay. All but. Yeah. You're right. Al the same the same shape. Yeah. That's funny.
And I've another
probably in this statement from Barks that that he identifies this guy has
ambassador. But in in the help, he never no recorded. It's it's the never made clear
what... What is he Huey, he
referred to by any other title was well, but he was... You know, I think he was probably
he was probably mixing him up with the the later story swamp of no return. Because he gonna use... He's gonna use the element
you fictional country of B To, which is an obvious stand for the Soviet Union, a couple more times. He doesn't always do this. But he does have a b
ambassador in the swamp of no return. Yes. And of course you know, R help is is a clear Port tow of... I saw everyone saying brute and Utopia, but I I think it's gotta actually be brutal. And Utopia are are probably
the true words. Right? Yeah. It's it's a great fictional country name. And and yeah. Bombastic,
obvious, it's the word bombastic for fantastic or over the top, but but we're also evo the bomb of the of the Adam Bomb. So lots lots to talk about, so you guys
so gentlemen before we...
Before we launch into story itself. I do like to take a moment to panda
to our international listeners by talking about some of the translations
of the different titles from around the world.
So, you know, Ryan, why don't you and I each tackle one and then Va, I think they're two of them that you had wanted to mention. Alright. Ryan let's let's hear from the Italian.
The italians called this one Z papa,
Scrooge, the sub zero treasure. So you know, Va, you didn't mention wanting to do the finish one. To me, it's kinda funny if I do the finish one and you can, like, react to mine.
So, you know, I've I've gotta a finish
guests today. So why don't I go ahead. I'll I'll try... I... I've mentioned this before. Finish. I find one of the most
intimidating
languages to try to do these for. So you you let me know how poorly I do. It is called Q.
A cold trade in most of the finish
translations.
Yes. That's a very very good very good
pronunciation. Alright. Wow. What would it sound like if you said it.
I I think there's also Al
also title,
which a bit longer
which is, you know, just the sending but with the hugo Scrooge. Right. In in in france of uncle Scrooge
called by or called Bargain. Nice. Excellent. So they, which which two interested you? Right. So
well in keeping with the cold team of this story, I I I thought that a couple of
languages. Yeah So in in Russian this store is called Ia Pac.
Which is a pretty straightforward
translation
some like Icy bargain or
I buy and
and then in Polish,
polish is kind of be interesting. It's cool fruit lot And
I I think here the translator
may been gone for a kind of a pun because,
well, the primary meaning of this
study would be
ball among the ice But yeah, you can also also understand it as the wall among the ice cream because the the same words polish.
Loading means size I in in in the plural or ice cream. I'm I'm I'm not quite sure if if if it's meant to be a pan but but at least has that.
Right. Well it works. I I like it when they kinda get get something they go a little bit of an extra mile in in translation. A good translator will do that. You yourself are in translation. Right? Yes. Yeah. Although, you don't you don't do, like, fun comic book translation and you do the more technical stuff.
Yeah. I I I haven't done any
session. It's it's mainly taking look up for also some sub for
something I've done in the past and then
okay.
Excellent. Thank you guys. Let's go ahead and talk about this this excellent story. So this story opens up with kind of a classic trope. Right? The character
unexpectedly
happening
on an auction.
We we saw this Ryan in tear of the river, it opens with Donald Wandering
into an auction. And that much older Barks story
but this is a Scrooge story. And right away, we see that this auction is a big deal because as he gets in he sees that it's attended by bankers and ty cones from all over the world,
and they all look very serious
And and the auction Huey,, you know, he brings in the consignment
with with kind of a lot of Sarah. Right? We can see... Ryan, do you wanna tell us about the consignment itself and how it's brought in? Well,
there's
some armed guards with rifles
bringing in a block of ice
with a strange orange ball inside. Yeah It's suspended the ice clear so you can see the the orange bowl is suspended inside. Right. And and and the neat trick here is that Scrooge has no idea what it is.
Nor does the reader, but everyone else there clearly does and is excited about it. So it's a really good way to build suspense. And scratch is just pla commenting that it looks like She as the auction year,
you know, starts to explain
that the ball is a compressed wall of the rarest element known to man. And Barb does actually make make a point of calling out the color is reddish. He doesn't usually... You know, he's never responsible, Ryan for the coloring.
So it's it's important that he mentions it here so that the colors
will actually keep consistent
on this one. Yeah.
Makeup?
Yes. I I
I I hadn't know before that for reddish. I mean, that also be a cold war coke. Yeah.
Red. But
platform from exactly that it's kind of comic that they they this
global advised that that's already melting there on the on the
cable. We right. Raven
see the streets streams of water pouring off the sides. Yeah. Yeah. I think it's... It it wasn't like had read the whole story and read it again that I caught the full shadowing of. It looks like She. Yeah.
Exactly.
Gonna end up being a good little book ended element. I guess it's worth noting too that it comes from the minds of the belgian
congo,
which has kind of a a bloody and mysterious
history, I guess. So the the auction
itself starts, and and I think the auction seen is great because all these ty cones are super impatient to just get on with it It's clear that there's like this desperate clam to bid on whatever
this thing is.
And and so Scrooge, basically while he's wondering about this, he gets tram by all these other desperate ty who start bidding
immediately in fantastic numbers.
And there's this great panel where he's asking this random like other victim of the the stampede from under their feet just what is that stuff? And he gets you guys the explanation that is the world's known supply of bomb ba.
But the guy He doesn't know. Tell us Ryan, what what's the only thing that this anonymous sky knows about it. It has to be kept frozen or it will evaporate
on its own. Right. So so we're setting that up this important detail while the auction is going on, And and we're really only meant to focus on two of the auction...
The the participants. Right?
They're they're clearly the only serious ones. They, do you wanna tell us about those two
participants?
Yes. Well, one of them is the
And ambassador or or... A representative. I. Yes. Yes. And the other one is the
director of
general kudos,
which I I presume this Al is a on on
general motors. Right? Right. Yeah. Yeah. So the these two men are immediately like, they're they're both desperate. They're sc Al each other.
We can tell they're the only serious
bidder pretty quickly because they bid it up to
two hundred million
and then three Al bill excuse me. Two hundred billion and three hundred billion
respectively.
We get this great panel
of Scrooge
pondering. Ryan do you wanna to read his bit of dialogue on the bottom of page too. Says fan my feathers. If the stuff is that good, perhaps I should buy it.
I I love it.
And he leaves up and he says general scooters can't put my scooter factory out of business, and that known for B top too. And he immediately jumps the bidding up to one trillion
dollars. But you guys think of his
his reckless bid there? It did seem a little loud of Character.
The the one later on where he where he raises the man by one sink seems more character.
Right. Just a few paddle away. But... Yeah. But it it's you would think you would go, oh, it's three hundred billion and one cent. Seems seems the difficult screw Ducktales
Yeah. Sc usually has the patience to do that, but but the purpose, the point it's important for Barks. Right? That Scrooge is gonna really over extend himself so that he feels really desperate for the rest of this story, because that's a big element of the story his desperation that his regret. And Ryan, you mentioned the kitchen sink bit. That this is one of the famous
elements of this story, the funny gag
I love it. Screws bid knocks the general scooters guy out, but the Utopian
representative
says that he's not through.
My country B top,
bids one trillion dollars and all of the kitchen syncs of its happy people.
And and when Scrooge inquire how many that is, the representative
tells him five.
And so of course, he does the predictable and... And yet still to me hilarious thing. Of bidding one trillion dollars and six kitchen, sinks. I love this seems so much you guys.
It is it is fantastic. Yeah. And yeah. At we should keep in mind that this is back in the fifties when a trillion dollars was a lot of money.
Yeah. Yeah We didn't have anyone who could realistically claim to be racing as they are right now to become the world's first trillion. Right. Right. Well the other with the kind of sums that bar usually
has a,
you know, pro claim. It's it's kind of surprising that he... Yeah To get almost closer
bankrupt after
this wondering.
You you would think that that that's
money for for transcription.
This story ends up causing... It's it's a common question for Barks fans of, like, it's one of those ridiculous back of the napkin things of trying to think about how much money does Scrooge
actually have, and it's a fool game. Right? Because number one, that's not the point of any of these stories. Number two, Barks has, like, ten to twenty stories where he'll name a different amount every time.
But but it's still kind of something that people like to about. But this one really makes it difficult because you can see how much it diminishes this fortune by. I like to imagine that's just his, like, kind of his
nostalgic money. It doesn't count for his treasures and
etcetera. But anyway, Scrooge
he escalate the bid and he does win it.
I I love the auction here. Do you mind reading that dialogue Ryan? Sold to the little Ducktales the many sinks and the big bank rule.
And of course get
introduction if you don't have enough sinks.
Just
the old knowledge. And
I would be remiss if I didn't mention the old saying. Right? This is, like, This is the... Everything, but the kitchen sink. So the the the B has bid the entire value of his country and its kitchen sink. That's a a famous idiom in English.
Yes.
I don't I don't know if he if it's because of of that idiom, but
this one that I been remember being translated
a bit differently in the in the finish edition. Yeah. Curious.
They're the
Ducktales,
he will
bit one three dollars and all the color television sets of these happy people and
out that
we have
five.
Nice. That seems like a good substitution if you don't have that that specific that very particular idiom Yeah. Yeah.
Alright. So when Scrooge wins it, of course, now he's gotta figure out what you actually do with that. The general scooters guy hope that it power his factories for all eternity, but he is
dismay to find out that nobody
knows it's just this very rare element
that everyone supposed
must have a lot of power in its adams
But Scrooge, you know, he... He's a set he says he's been took. And the next
the next page is basically about screws buyer's
remorse.
We see him... We see him lock it away in in his very nineteen fifties ice box and we see him watching
This Con v of armor trucks hauling out Tell us about the specifics ryan of the Con envoy.
Well, we just see a a con of armored
trucks, you can see the rivets in the sides. They're all named Blink Money express and for days, truckload of of money are moving out of his money been
ten truck loads Severino day for ten weeks. So again, we could kind of calculate it if we were that kind of obsessive nerd.
But but I mean, the point of we are. Right?
I'm not quite that caliber.
But I know that people have done done the math before But but the point of this is to make Scrooge watch. Right, and and despair. Mh I suspect too that these trucks are kind of like blinking it's gone. Is is what it's supposed to evo there. Yeah. We see him looking at the seventy foot mark on his money gauge, which is usually at the ninety nine foot mark. And and you know, you really feel for the
the me
trillion error there.
I didn't know Huey, usually at the ninety nine foot mark. Yeah. I I didn't know what the what the what the comparison scale was there. I do see the crane in the background where he that he uses just scoop
scoop money out.
But, yeah, that would apply. You should have probably a little over two twilio left in there if it's all
fairly
much
Exactly.
Exactly. This is why this, like throws such a monkey wrench into people's efforts to to into nerds efforts to calculate it. So at this point in the story, Barks is gonna bring in Donald and the nephews
to get another percent of. And they just... They wanna see the bomb ba. It's it's clearly become a famous
thing in the papers.
And when Scrooge
screws opens the fridge, they see an ominous
trail
of
the puddle pooling of water
showing that it's melted.
There there is still a crust of ice
around it, but but the ice block is nearly melted Scrooge just horror.
Because apparently, the motor has stopped
they do you wanna tell us about why the motor is stopped? Yes. So in the next panel
sc, I I remember now, I got in a hassle with the electric company about my bill and they've turned the power off. This is one of those classic bark bits where he
he's gonna show Scrooge just like penny pinching
causing him. These these kinds of problems. It's very funny. To make And this next sequence is one of the most slaps that Barks has done in an in a while file, I think this sequence is great. Your mileage may vary, but but basically, the whole the whole span is devoted to the docks taking that
rapidly melting
ball of bombastic
to a special freezer plant And you guys, I'm not gonna go through every chronic beat of this sequence, but do either of you have a favorite moment from this, like slaps part I could tell... I could tell where it was going as soon as they dropped it down the stairs and it bounces off the stairs and then rolls up a a wooden plank, who knows why the wooden plank is in there.
But it rolls up the wooden plank up to a a, like, a drum of hot tar that's being fired up right now to to work on the street to make asphalt.
And I was like, okay. It's time to Ducktales in. We're gonna. We're gonna see how how crazy we can take this and
he he came up with some pretty good pretty good good. Probably the one that should be mentioned is that when it goes into the hot springs, you know, Scrooge
it down,
down, like, into a ge
spout,
and and as Donald warned him you'll be drenched. He says who cares about a little dr.
I caught it, and that's gonna be a repeated element later in the story.
It's it's wonderful. It's slaps stick, so I won't you know, we can't talk too much about it because it's very visual. But ultimately the Inducks,
they do make it with a very thin crust device to the freezer plant.
Aren't aren't guys boiling hot. I mean, wouldn't he surely have been killed?
Spinning
right in the middle of... Okay. I think they can vary in in house scouting. They are or aren't
Okay. But but... Yeah. I'm... I would just be glad it's not my trillion dollars.
Yeah. That's true.
One thing we'll never have to worry about until this podcast really takes off.
That's alright. Mh. That's right.
This
episode sponsored by the Leaky Kona ice cream company.
So next Barks
pulls it out, kinda kinda literally. Right? He pulls back as the duct kind of pond or what else could go wrong
for this
ball of ice
and and they realized that, you know,
what if lightning
struck and Ducktales
had a a black had a power outage.
Sp is just escalating the word and the dread for screws at this point. And I think any of us could problem solve, you know, bad up generators,
blah blah blah.
It it's easy enough to be like, alright. You know, for a million bucks a year, I can be certain
that I can keep this safe. But but for the point of the comment, it makes sense
what the boys
proposed as the solution. They, you wanna tell us about the proposed solution here? Yes. So of course, the nephews so their
junior Inducks
checks guide book, and they read that the first subscription says, what am I going to do three dollar wall of Boom
could note anywhere. And then Huey, or where this says oh, no. It couldn't. According to the junior Wood guide book there is a place where it would stay frozen forever the great ice mountains
around the south pole and the after dot Scrooge
boys. We're going to the south pole.
He's he's pretty hasty there. Even that his
is is a nice character beat. Right? Because
Donald is like, Huey,, hold your horses. You don't just buy a ticket. You know, this is obviously an expedition. But I really like the panel.
At the bottom of this page gentlemen, where where Scrooge says,
don't blame me if I don't think of those Angles boys, I've been a in a state of shock ever since I saw my trillion dollars, go over the hill. That's a really nice character moment. Right? Because
it invest this sense of, like, the spare and disappointment Inducks screws and it's gonna go a long way towards explaining some of the, like,
un
bad decisions that he's making throughout this story. So the next sequence really is all about the preparations for the journey
There's nothing too interesting about it except we do get to watch Scrooge
despair
as his scientists
grind out like a little... I don't know like, a thumbnail. What's a good comparison
for that
that amount, like a Him worth
yeah. Of the bombastic to do, like, to do further testing
Ryan, did you notice the random little background gag at the top right?
One of Barks random background art.
Is it his curtains that have dollar sons on them? They're green buttons?
I wasn't even noticing that, but that's in fun one too. I just noticing the picture that's just z fast buck. Yeah. With the a coin that has legs and it's clearly running very quickly,
Right. Just one of those little
surreal
background elements.
But, yeah, the scientists are gonna be running experiments while they're on the x expedition. And and so we see them launch
from a a vessel that's pretty well out for. It's an ice it's an x navy ice break or a some nice detail.
But Scrooge towels tells the docks in a great bit of fore foreshadowing.
He says, Ryan, do you wanna read what he says the bottom on the page there? It's not the ship nor the crew that worries me now Donald. It's that B utopian guy. He said he'd see me again, and I'm beginning to wonder when. Yeah. If not as reader had completely forgotten about him, and I don't think we'll be seeing him anymore.
And and whether you did or didn't, it's a it's a good little reminder. And and you know, it's thing to me as we continue on the journey, as we embark on the journey, the tone is, like, boredom. Right? We're gonna we're gonna transition now to the Nephews
point of view. This is obviously a long journey
It is the first time that Barks has set an adventure
or any story as far as I know in
any hard, so this is exciting.
But but the nephews are so bored that they're not even interested did in the whales that are, like fro
all around the ice breaker. And you know, they're despair that they don't have
any game aboard
to play with.
And and so they make a decision
to play a frank. I really like the element of the story. It's very whim, but it feels it feels
very
natural. The way Barks is introduced to. Vehicle, do you wanna tell us about the prank that they're gonna play? Yes. So they're going to gonna make Al another
ball
that resembles the
well...
Well, they say that they they can freeze Al block of colored eyes and have the wall from it that that they have some flavoring
to it to to give color. They they start with
strawberry flavoring then put some orange extract to tow it down and
some
to to give
etcetera
and so on. And and and then then finally, they come up with it with this school that that that that's
exactly the same shape for. Right. I I like this because it really feels like the kind of thing that, like,
I would have done as a kid where I like to just randomly them like kinda mix flavors and stuff together. But Having think its neat,
and we haven't seen too much of the nephews in the story so far. So, you know, once they have this matching block of ice, they talk about how they're gonna
use it to print Gun Scrooge.
What do you think, Ryan? Also, I I I was just thinking as they're as they're talking their way through of how to make it look right. This is another kind of instructions to the color.
Yeah.
Almost like color going
Nope. That's to red. I need to put a little orange in there to tone it down.
Yeah. This is one of the very few stories where every coloring of it should technically
Al least this element of the story. Every coloring should look pretty much the same. You know, I recently got to release land beneath the grounds.
Which is like a real landmark Scrooge story, one of his most famous ones and the creatures in that are like these rock ball creatures, the cherries and the Fermi.
And
it just
varies widely
whether the call made them, like, super colorful,
made them look like actual rocks.
So it's it's interesting to see what where he's like
okay. Color really matters here. So we're gonna we're gonna actually
name it, even even even bolts the... That's too red.
Well burn some orange
extract. I guess, technically, the album that I'm looking at right now yes. It's orange, kind of Al orange just brown, to be honest. So... So, anyway, they're debating what they're gonna do with the ice or they're just gonna play catch with it, roll it back and forth
when all of a sudden, their thoughts are interrupted
by a quote, large black something.
Surfacing
off of their star. And so here, this is where Barks is gonna bring back that Utopian
threat
because we've got
Ryan, you wanna tell us about what we've got. At first, it looks almost exactly like the the sperm whales that have been, like, leap out of the water and incredibly dramatic ways.
Right. Around the ship for the this whole journey.
But then it then it has a tower and a gun on the top, and it's
clear that it's a a submarine
Al attack submarine.
Right.
And screws recognizes the the flag as his old friend.
Yeah. The black course the, of course as we see on the bottom just has a knife. It's just a
a big un knife.
Right Right, yeah. I was wondering what you guys think about, You know, it's not a hammer and simple.
Yeah. Although although I think I think that in in one of the later
resolved stories. Barks does have this
flag that it kind of look like the
Am and Sequel. Yeah. But but I I I did Huey, here give be that. Too much because
already has.
Has so many much of these called wardrobe workshops here. Right. It's some pretty clear It's some pretty clear signaling they are a threat.
And, of course, and nephews are very excited. Yes.
Because they are bored out of their right.
Yeah. Tell us about Ryan what they do in their excitement. They... Instead of playing with the ice ball as part of their print, they just put it in the freezer with the real one right next to it and the two of them appear identical to my ass
which I think is an important part of the plot here. And then they run out onto the deck saying. Oh, boy oh boy boy.
Right.
And and so we do indeed see the b top now dressed up and kind of some like military ga. Coming out of the submarine
and say, I I love his line here. He says my country, B top,
bids you greetings,
rich, pay dot or, you know, dog of Inducks depending on what you're looking at. I'm gotta say dog of the Ducktales doesn't work too badly.
As far as changes, they both sound like pe,
dog of a doc
is, you know, little at least. So... Right. So that works okay. And and, you know, there's no there's no time wasted. Va didn't... Did it strike you then in other stories
Sk would have made some efforts to hide the ball. Right?
Yeah. Probably, probably. I mean, yeah you're right there.
There's no no
generally in this in the store. It's it's very fast moving and and... Yeah. That's it That's kind of one of the things I I like about yeah. I agree. And I think the the reason Barks is able to do this to kinda gloss over Scrooge just efforts at, like, safeguard regarding it is is because he's so broken
from that, you know, earlier experience.
Right. And the timing is so important in this next sequence here. Right Barks does such a nice job of of Scrooge
The the
the representative gives... Does Al literal shake down. Right? He grabs him and by by his coat. And tells him what
Wants B top takes.
You're giving me that bombastic.
And so Scrooge
Barks to the freezer, and he's just crying and despair
as he's gonna grab the ball
and And you know, it's only him approaching the freezer. One of the nephews
wants to offer. He makes used to get it, but the B hope pulls him back. And by the time
he approaches
the the freezer with the airs sa ball. He's so blinded by tears that he doesn't notice that there are two of them. But do you guys think of that perspective shot, you know, where the reader sees him?
I think it's pretty cool. Yeah. It's...
Especially if, you know, if you're really really wee
like he
things might appear double anyway. Like, he he probably doesn't even seem suspicious. Right. Yeah. I... I really like how this is staged.
And the whole time, the reader is like, really tense and wondering, you know, are we gonna get... Are we gonna give him the real ball or not is he gonna notice.
And I like the... I like the quick thinking nephews. I like that Hue has already like done all the math, and he's like, no. No. I can I can fix this problem? I know exactly what to do for this. Yeah. And and it's Al that's a good point too because Barks trust says readers enough not to give us a panel where they're like confirming with each other though hey, if you if we can convince him, then maybe he can take the wrong one. We just... We just know. Yeah. We're also clever little boy they know. We're all clever little boys together with you we do Louis.
Yes. That's right.
So the the next part It's it's very predictable. Right? We know it's gonna happen. The nephews are gonna reveal that there's still a ball, but Barks,
He un roles it. He lays it out in a in a very neat way.
The nephews
show him once the route left look So the nephews
are they're kind of like caution him. They're telling him basically, we we did this joke we don't know if this is real bomb ba or not.
And there's this really tense moment where they are staring at it and they decide that the only way to figure it out is by giving it a look and seeing if it tastes like any of those flavoring agents that they use and unfortunately,
the first nephew gives it a lick and says, oh, I taste strawberry.
And then the next nephew tries it again and says,
I taste orange and
Vanilla,
and and then they just spare that it it would be the ice ball and they in frustration they get ready to throw throw it into the ocean. And and then at that moment, Donald decides that he needs to have a taste of something sweet after the days bad luck, and he
detects a taste of peppermint.
And and as the nephews are puzzled because they didn't put in any peppermint,
Scrooge gets ready to chuck it into the ocean.
And just before he does,
he sees that tell
little dent where the scientist
Scrooge out all that testing material.
And real... And they realized they've got this... The ball of ba still safe and and with them on board.
I I love that sequence you guys. I think it's... I think it's great. I think it's a wonderful payoff.
Any thoughts they go? Yeah. Yeah. I mean, it's it's it's great great
sequence really.
Click hang moment
because the panel wear Scrooge notice the
notice that
the very
of and end of page, and we're not sure if you if you actually
we'll throw it. But,
Of course, it doesn't want he.
Realizes that it's
sebastian. And I almost threw it overboard And
Yeah. It's here. That's this out. It's very well time with, like, the architecture of the Com page. Any comments, ryan? It it also does seem a little unscrew. Yeah. I think I think it depends on him being just just at the end of his rope and he's been completely emotionally burned out by this whole experience and... Because I think I think your usual screwed your clever Scrooge would have he would gotten tested. And then maybe even if it is just she, maybe still try and sell it as bombastic and
recoup some of that money, you know?
Right. Pretty convincing looking.
I guess, it's worth noting too that we've got a little bit of cartoon logic here where they can, like, kinda taste
different
distinct flavors.
But but, you know, that's fine. I I also really like where the sequence continues on the next page as they all kinda take turns
licking at again and and they they alternate
from the different...
Ryan, do you wanna tell us the different flavors they alternate through rapid fire.
We get Banana peach, cherry, winter green, gu chocolate, tamarind,
lime, butters scotch.
And like there's
enough to recognize Tamarind. Yeah. Yeah. Maybe they... Maybe that's one of their favorite favorite treats. Right. And this this
this waste full licking
is enough to revive Scrooge
because as he says, you letters slip up a million dollars worth of mom ba them. Every time you lick a flavor
and he sn
And and just at that moment, Vac, you wanna tell us what happens?
Yeah. So we we have the sound of it bump and and see that something has bumped into the boat
group christ. What now and we see the... Well as chrome Barks and it's it's a way the has come.
Come up under the sheet. And they they got the one best.
Something. That way. Yeah. Why don't you tell us about the the the sequence this quick little whale sequence. Yeah. Yeah. It's it's is it's one of the most
exciting sequences in this story. So
so, of course, Scrooge
immediately
jumps our board on the whale and it's chasing this telephone
and it goes down way from this old the that wells on on their back, but I don't know what's Oh, english. It's it's a blow hole. Global. Right. Right. This is...
Went in there and the nephews or or maybe donald is
crying get back and goes screw get back, he'll be drenched. But what happens is that the whale
blows the the the wall... The
back with
ro and and then
Scrooge replace this line. Barks Al about a little french. I called it. It's it's a very goofy few little slaps stick bit, but but it works for the repetition.
And I love that panel of him
expanding the length of the whale in pursuit of the Mom.
When Disney, when Disney finally gets around to making the live action
movies of all of these comics, this is gonna be the the key action set piece of this this feature. Yeah. That'll will be a real show.
So let's see. We're pretty or pretty far into the story at this point you guys, and we have just arrived
to an antarctica.
The last continent that the du have not have yet to to explorer of yet to be on in the Barks stories. And being an antarctica,
there's not too much interesting
about the the continent
from a a comment book artist perspective. So
so he... He's gonna really do what he can with this part of the story art wise, you know? But but I think most of the the interest of the rest of the story is gonna lie in
in who he meets there. We're gonna encounter and antarctica most famous inhabitants, the penguins.
I do like the panel of seeing the ice breaker at work, you know,
tearing through the the ice shelf there making their way in because they do still reference wanting to be hidden from the Utopian.
And the next part of the story, you know, it's pretty straightforward.
Basically, they they need to walk inland towards those mountains.
They need to... Where they're gonna bury the bomb ba and carefully documented it and
and that's it. Then it doesn't... It's not gonna go as planned
because as they land, they have... They have a fun little and encounter
with the penguin.
Does one of you is one of you particularly?
Yeah. Tell us the encounter. We we get them... The artist, you'll notice
introduces them as we see the the bigger shot, the wide shot of the ice breaker cracking through the ice, you see the tiny penguins
watching from a cliff. As comes in. And then
as as our hike have all their
expedition gear and they're walking through the the ice and snow,
they come across kind of a line of penguins
and the screws start speculating how he could make money from penguins.
Then go to
that the Bombastic must have rolled out of his Map act, and then he spots it being sat upon by
by one of one of the penguins
And then and then for the rest of the issue, we are almost certainly mis gender this penguin because the male penguins are almost always the ones
sitting on the eggs, especially an egg that they just encounter. So... But we call... We call... We call him a her the rest of the issue, which I thought was interesting. Yeah. That's a good point. I didn't I didn't catch that. I didn't think of that. You're right. It's the it's the female penguin generally that lays the eggs, then goes off to find food as the meal. Stays with the check. And I... And the egg is usually like, on their feet. It's it's it's a... It's only awesome. Is anyone... They do show like his stomach
feathers kind of going over the top of it like a real penguin would do though. So it's it's it's not exactly right, but it's in the right direction. Yeah. And I think the the penguins are all drawn
very, like I'd say they're very realistic slash Huey,. You know, these these are not like cartoon pain they definitely
evo Real Penguins like he was using one of his national geographic references or something. Yeah. And I I love the element of the the penguin in the story. I think it's very cute
We see as as Scrooge recover the egg and says get off of that, you moon idle setting him. That's no egg as as he recovers the bomb bathroom.
We we see them walk off and she's got a thought balloon that is just, like, a little hard heartbreaking as she imagine. A little check emerging from from what he or she supposed
is an... Is a Penguin.
Any comments makeup?
Yeah. Well, I I
like ping in in in general. So so so this is definitely one of my sequences in this in this story. Yeah. I I think it's still delightful I like penguins as well. And Barb has a narrator box tell us the cold miles pass swiftly.
And the docs are stuck in a blizzard,
which, I guess, would be would be quite a surprise. Right? Because, like
Famously is a whole desert
So I wonder if it's a wind storm rather than a blizzard, but but that's just a little pedantic thing point out.
That it's very rare that it actually
snows there. But but rather
accumulated
snow over millions of years. So the docs can't see each other the point of the sequence, and they kinda go down the line, making sure that everyone is still there. And when we get to the end of the line, Scrooge says, well, if I am behind all of you, who is this behind me. I'm sure enough. It is Va. Do you wanna read his... His bit of dialogue there? It's... That that the god happy ping win.
Talk
with the
We're getting out of the again.
She's very determined to get that egg.
And and I really like this very funny panel of him
doing
as they laugh about how you've made a friend for life. She's gonna follow you to the south pole to get that quote egg
And we get a great silhouette panel where he's saying I've never been so embarrassed in all of my life.
Let's see Ryan, do you wanna tell us about the next sequence when they arrive at a likely spot to bury yet?
So they they find a spot on this slopes of the ice mountains
of Antarctica.
And I I I assume it was chosen for being in the middle of nowhere.
And
for never getting warm enough to melt anything. So they start kind of just digging a a hole in the ice.
In the snow and
slowly lower it in while the penguin looks on
with some distress.
Scrooge
screw notes that he can't put a marker there to show where it's been hidden because then it wouldn't be hidden anymore. He just has to write down the precise latitude,
which he does in a notebook,
and everybody's pushing Donald is pushing the the penguin back trying to explain to the penguin in English
that this is not an egg.
It's it's just a a weird ball of some new elements. You know.
For some reason, the penguin doesn't seem to understand.
And the penguin one is for Lauren. And sits on the spot now that has been re varied, and they're concerned that the payment will try to dig it back up so they
put a leash on it and and start hauling it back as part of the the con v back to society.
Right. Yeah. Exactly.
I like seeing screws
siding the the coordinates using an actual substance, always a nice touch.
I really you gotta really feel for that penguin in the sea months. Right? Yeah. Yeah. Even in the last frame, he's he's walking off
looking at his notebook. So pleased do himself and pulling the leash with the penguin. And the penguin is still looking back with an obviously very worried look on its face. Right. And she's supposed to very Al egg. And that's supposed to be an egg in the snow not a good thing to do.
Yeah. Yeah. The penguin knows what's up.
And and even into the next sequence,
even into the next sequence, you know, she's there su
as the Bra utopian
representative
returns for the last time he's He's taken what I assume must be a pretty risky
journey and helicopter down to the south pole, and he gets set out very angry saying my country B top bids you no greetings
rich pick a dot
because
Happy people are angry at you for fooling them with a ball of flavored ice. I do like these repeated references to the happy people of B who only has five kitchen sinks. But that really tells us we don't need to, like, state the obvious about what Barks how is describing
the Soviet union's
analog here.
So
You know, he runs at them,
but he is tripped up by the penguin. And and finally, he resorts to a little trick with his helicopter So, you know, the the B has his pilot basically
hover above them and and blow them back using the helicopters,
you know, force
and is finally
able to grab that. He finds Scrooge notebook.
He immediately figures out that it must be important. He spots the notation
about the coordinates.
Latitude Omni down, longitudinal Dd, you know, it's Barks will sometimes use real coordinates in these stories, but doesn't really matter for this one. And as the Bra is about to tell the pilot
where they're gonna go, they get a message
from their short waive radio from Scrooge Du scientists.
Trying to contact him. Do you want Va to tell us about the message that they get from home?
Right. So the big
saying org clock
station x k two dot trying to contact Scrooge dot somewhere at South Pole. It's it's measured from Uncle Cruisers scientist is and
donald
here to give it... Give them a single to read. And then they tell that they have probably used program boom one best you. They found only it was per.
And...
Yeah. And and I guess it's a really obvious
what what this was is, but Scrooge says that
he he he just wants to turn off who cares because he he doesn't have this
anyway, but the
comes
comes Barks eye
this
years experiments. So then they tend designs say that
makes ice cream. One item of investing properties are barrel barrel water makes a barrel of ice screen and every barrel is a different flavor.
Pistachio, p,
pineapple, Cherry, Covid. And course the
won't of this.
But what use is that of.
In, the happy people do not meet ice cream.
We should by not more on, I think. Yeah. Yeah.
This is one detail but Barks got wrong about the union because at least when not been in in Russia in times they it it lot ice Scrooge even in the winter. Have this products
sending it to the people in the space. So Wow. Ice like, ice cream traps even during the winter. Oh, yes. Yes. That's cool
baby. Yeah. Right. That's interesting.
So you guys... This is a definitely like a comic book moment you know, this is a very Disney moment
because for one, it's a very whim
outcome, you know, bomb ba,
is not gonna be an analog for any kind of atomic bomb. It's it's all about ice cream It's obviously very silly.
It's it's a it's a leap but I do find it very funny and very satisfying.
What do you think Ryan? And he thoughts about the ultimate use for Ba?
Yeah.
I like it. I like... I like that there's a twist. I like that it's not actually a an endless power supply or or some other kind of thing that for them to fight over. I like the Big oven is is just ice cream just
a trillion Al of ice.
Right.
Right. Right. And every adam.
Right? So I guess like I guess technically, if you like really, you could probably figure out a way to generate
electricity if you're getting a a whole barrel of some thing from something the size of an adam.
But... But anyway, we're we're not meant to think too much about it. We're we're just supposed to know that
that that there is an outcome and it's something that they'll that the young kids reading this are gonna really relate to, and they're gonna find it really delight. Fault. But because the Utopian,
you know, is definitely not interested in the joy that ice cream can bring, he takes the
unforgivable step of burning the note so that no one can have it. How mad
were you guys at the B and and is the answer so mad.
I was super super bad. Yeah. It seemed it seemed so petty. Just so spite. It it benefits him nothing. It's not even, like, he spent any money on the thing. He just chased it, you know? And and well, he you know, resent it like he's been... He's been fleece somehow.
Right. Yeah. I was I was pretty much
as well, but I was also mad at Scrooge because
before in the story, I get always said
when it was reading reading his notes, even if you need it his on mind let it do so and so let me do so much such. So he he didn't say it the numbers himself and maybe that way he he could've have actually memorized them. He's instead setting them know I'm just on side. Yeah. This is another example. Of him being very careless,
probably not quite in his in his, you know, at his best.
Hopefully, Barks has done a good job of just find that. Because, yeah, we can all say that load, he should have had all the Inducks chanting the numbers together so that they memorized it etcetera, etcetera. If I had one hundred dollars buried somewhere, I would memorize its location so well.
Right.
So I like... I like that in this
almost closing sequence. You know, he gets to
in his misery
with peggy
as he calls the penguin at this point,
and then they check to see if there's any follow up information from Doctor.
And they learned that our episodes sponsor the leaky Kona ice cream company would like to provide
Al of Bombastic
offering...
Now you know, business one zero one, I'm thinking says
cost plus ten percent.
Right?
Probably
a good good ballpark. But for little kids reading it, we're just gonna double it. They're offering two trillion dollars for the ball.
So sc could even have turned
boy. Not just a profit Quite a profit. Yeah. And and the doctor you know, they're gonna give it the old try. They're gonna see if they can remember or he can't remember, but they're gonna see if they can find it And at this point, you know, they turn the penguin loose to let her a head back to the coast, having no doubt forgotten all about the quote egg by now. But predictably,
you know, this is an arctic. It's it's all ice. There's a few mountains, but there... There's nothing
to reference,
and there's no way that they're gonna find it.
And and then this story wraps up it the resolution is excellent,
I think. Because,
of course, we've all read stories about animals doing incredible things that are, like, physically impossible for humans that they have some kind of an innate sense.
Indeed
One of the Inducks
buys something on the horizon and through the,
they see that it is that devoted
adorable penguin, and she is t
to a spot that she seems to know where she's going. I'm sure enough. She she leads them to
the ball of ba thinking it's an egg.
Brian, what does Scrooge say?
So
when she finds the Barks ass sits on it. This old girl can sit on the best Bump him for a while. She can even melt off a few billion dollars worth she's earned this.
It's it's pretty un,
but it's also it does feel very earned for peggy there. Yeah. And then it wraps up with a a fun little book ending vic code. Do you wanna tell us the how the story wraps up? Yes. So so they were back in an auction
with the testing that...
So now whenever on Scrooge goes goes to the auction, people think he's a little clear. And then then there are people
whispering Scrooge. That's the people's Scrooge
indeed. I've heard of him. They say he always makes one brother's Scrooge purchase. Yes. A ping with. But he buys one every time a new shipment comes come from the from Barks. Does even anyone know what he does with the egg Yes. He ships it back to the and thirty to be given to a certain big ping.
Certain thing. Can see that. And then and then we see
manning is very there bid a dollar high dollar for.
Right. It's very cute. I like it. I think it's a nice... It's a pretty abrupt ending, but but I think it's a nice way to book and it with the auction and and wrap it up to to show that that gratitude. That very un
gratitude
that he shows for the penguin. And that is that is a cold bargain gentleman. I I really enjoyed talking about this one. Let's let's go ahead and share, you know, our our overall thoughts about the story. Ryan, do you wanna go first? Sure. I like it a lot. I like... You know, we go somewhere new. Again, we're
kind of facing off against
a real
villain which we don't always get in these stories. And
and then the penguins are very cute. The penguin one is the hear of the story, and like, everybody kind of gets a happy ending except for the happy people of B help.
Right.
Yeah. As someone who... I haven't had you do a ton of the Scrooge adventures. I know you got to do the secret of Lan, which is a very famous one. What did you think of this is just like a it has a Barks screwed story as someone who's... Who hasn't read a ton of these over many decades. Yeah. I mean, it seemed it's seemed very Scrooge to me. You know, some circumstances come up, and he sees opportunity to make a lot of money and
things get pretty crazy, and then he's walking on a whale. And and...
Yeah. There's some... There's some adventure. There's a little bit of payroll. There's a little bit of quick thinking. Right now a little bit of luck Yeah.
Yes.
Excellent.
How what about You waco? What what are your... What's... Where are you on this? Well, yes, sir I mean, as Mentioned, it it is it is one of my favorites of the late
which stories. I I of, like the cold war
team that's.
I
like the fact that it's it's so task moving as as as I mentioned And also since I generally tend to like the ten pages more than the long,
I I I like factor that the beginning of the stories
sort of like a...
Or almost a
dent or of the adding for online just when they're funding the both capacity still Barks in in in Barks. And and then then since I'm
bit animal lover, I I always like these
stories with
with with some other animals and
especially this stories where
Sk has this
phone that's for for animal yeah for the team win and I I think there's there's not not story where. Yeah. Yeah Al also set up somewhere in a snowy way the location where where he has
gets we gets friendly with with some some dog I
which started. Oh, yeah.
North north of the Yukon with Yeah.
With old Barks, the the ba. Hey. Yeah. That's that's a fun one. That's probably Scrooge at his softest.
Interesting seen this kind soft version of sp. You know, you mentioned that this one kinda opens like a ten page I think you're right, and and it kind of feels like a good complement to that secret of Atlanta to story I did with you, Ryan, how that one opens
as a ten pager and then it kind of expands into an adventure. Although, this one never really loses that kind of semi.
Tone. It is nice. I think it's nice that the B does feel like like a threat. Right? Because the story is otherwise, so light hard. That's true. I point you missed the point where where
the representative from Bert when he's taking control of the situation into Antarctica, and Donald is trying to get the notebook.
The Says, must I do Bro hope and folk dance on your thick head to teach you that I boss here? Right. Yeah. That's a good thing to point out because he... He's a heavy. Right? And he... He pulls a gun on them, Does he? I don't remember the gun. Why do I... Why am I visualizing him with a gun?
Maybe I'm mis remembering. I know that they've got the guns shit pointed hot. Yeah. The submarine does have its tour. Yeah.
Right. Well, just twice there's nice. Yes.
Yeah. He... He's he is a genuine threat.
I think this is a great story. I think it... I think it lands really well. I think it holds up really. Well, definitely a bit of a cold war artifact. But but in in the best way. For the same reasons you said they you know, it's a neat... Look. It's it's nice that it it kinda soften and Scrooge, but he's never like, overly
soft. Right? He's still definitely
ru Inducks in this one.
And the penguin is just adorable. It's it's a lot of fun all around. I I remember reading this one a lot. As a kid over and over. So you guys I mentioned that, you know, I really like this story. This is a a favorite of mine. It's maybe not like a all time favorite, but it's it's pretty close. It's it's pretty high up there for me. And we like to check in on the Ducktales community
as seen through the website Inducks, which is a great resource for all Disney comics
and has a nice ranking
system where people will will assign
a value to it. So it's it's it's a good if imp precise way to get a feel for the community So this one does rank very highly. This has an eight point zero out of ten. As of today, you know, these do change a bit over the time, but they generally stay pretty consistent. And that's good for number thirty five out of all like roughly forty two thousand
Disney comics that are ranked on the site. And it... So if you pull out just the Barks ones, I don't know exactly where it lands, but that's probably roughly the top twenty five or so story. So so this is a very well remembered very well regarded story. Al as far as how this as far as follow ups or other Disney comics or other media,
you know,
I don't think there's ever been a lot of big sql from big name artist.
A number of other Disney
comments, Barks writers have used, like, root top as a setting or like, a fictional country. I know that Don Rose and one of his stories briefly, like, I think he'll use the representative as, like, a just a background character.
Occasionally but he never did any of his sequels or follow ups. To this. Ryan, do you remember back in the eighties, duck
had a big five episode arc where they went back in time, and they encountered the cave... The cave Ducktales.
Baba Duck, he... He's a... He's a recurring character and the Ducktales series that a lot of bark stands. And and I guess a lot of Ducktales fans
don't like... He's a pretty annoying character, but the kids tend to delight him. So they they used him Anyway, the time machine that Ji Gear loose
built
that takes them back to the past
in this episode, which is called
this five episode arc, which is called time is money. That time machine was powered by Bombastic. Naturally. Yes.
So
second use. We found the second use for mom.
This the ice cream thing and also time travel. Roughly,
I would say in this. Yeah So so dale never really tackle the story, but they use they just use Ba as this throw away element, I think it rolls off the tongue nicely.
So other than that, again, other artists have used B Help, and I think the b being representative has appeared occasionally
Alright. So you guys were about ready to wrap up I'm I'm really glad to have covered this one, but before we go, are there any handles that, like, really stood out to you that we didn't already get to highlight.
My favorite was
at the auction after
Scrooge and another guy who is not a duck, he has a appoint beak have been pushed over and and now they're just like under the feet of the other of the other auction attendees,
and they're just chatting with each. And so I just like the shot of the two of them just just down on the ground, and then you see all the legs and shoes behind them as they're talking with each other about what's going on in this same and It's just... I mean, it's just exposition. You have to you have to deduct the position here at the beginning, and he just found a really interesting way of framing that in individual medium. Yeah. I think that's a great one to highlight. Mostly because that entire auction
just panel by panel.
Is is very funny,
very well drawn. I especially like the one where the B is just
staring dagger at the general scooters guy, Scrooge is just
considering them still still on the floor from that tram
So so, yeah, I would encourage readers to really take a look at that whole auction sequence because it is is white. What about you waco?
Yeah. I mean, this story doesn't really have any of these
flash panels that that
Barks was famous for there's one oversized panel
on the
various page, but it just the shows
score to go and going into the the auction. So it's from like a
spectacular panel anything. So I I I think I I will have to name this very last
panel
with the scotia test and the team my that's my favorite
it it's just so funny and hard the way
smiling and and
so happy. You're so happy so it is. And it's adorable. It's a great one. Awesome. Well, you guys thank you so much.
For joining me to to go over this really interesting story. I I really do appreciate it. People can check out Barks remarks on the various social sites. We're on Facebook and Instagram and join us next time when we will be covering
a really fascinating
story land of the p.
Brian read us the last bit of dialogue to close this out. Says a dollar I been a dollar for the penguin egg. Awesome. Thank you guys again. Thank you.