We can have
Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer an artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comments of all time. Join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks. Welcome back to Barks remarks. I'm Mark Sever of Grown man who enjoys stuff comments,
and I'm I'm here with a couple of returning guests
Who I go...
We go way back, and I'm excited to have both of them on together.
I am joined by Ryan Bailey and Susan Bailey
How are you guys doing happy New Year? Happy day year. It's good to see you. I'm doing good. We're here. We're excited. For doc. Excellent.
Awesome. Thank you guys. So much for joining me. I really appreciate you guys making time for
both of you letting your kids no doubt like, your walls or probably just covered with markers right now. I'll send you a bill.
We're gonna be talking about a Carl Barks classic today. We're be talking about land of the p Inducks.
And you guys are both definitely
Barks newbie right, Ryan, I've had you on for quite a few of these episodes
and...
You're you're a big comic book fan. In general. Yeah. I probably gotten you to read the in the double digits of these at this point or or something close to it. And any thoughts on Barks and and the Ducktales story so far.
Yeah. I mean, it's... I think it's largely what I expected, kind of some
adventure
and exploring the world. I mean, I'm I'm kinda curious, you know, you like,
I would
I would probably rant about these all through high school while you were generally reading comics like x men. I guess, kinda of my question would be did is your expectation of what these comments would be like, kind of match your first impressions?
No. I remember. I remember... And I can't remember any specific examples. But I remember, like, the duck cartoon show going pretty big for kids shows at the time and having some kind of major swatch buck adventures or, like, Indiana Jones, kind of adventures or whatever and payroll and and and that sort of thing. I feel like the tone of the comics is pretty consistent with you know, a lot of the, you know, Disney shorts and and other things that I remember from from when I was a kid right on. And and sue, I had you on,
I think around this time last year, you did a a pretty notable donald Inducks story called land of the tote poles. So Think it's gonna be interesting to kinda compare, you know, Barks stream and a native Americans in that one versus this one. Do you have any kind of initial thoughts
how they compared to each other.
I feel like that this one is... He was using... He was using the Inducks as as the like, antagonists
In the other and the other one, and I don't feel like they're an antagonist diagnostic forced in this in this comic. I feel like they're... I don't know. Maybe c protagonists because they're they're not... They're not men. They're not, like, gonna roast him over the fire or whatever they we're gonna do in the last one I can't remember.
And and he made them... He made them little even though there are no big news in North America. And I and I I have to assume that that was on purpose.
So that they wouldn't be men? I don't know. Yeah. That's a really good point. That's something that people will will kinda of remark on about Barks big, you know, adventures where the Inducks will kind of stumble into a lost
civilization
is is that in a lot of their stories, you know, the Inducks are smaller than a lot of the characters
and and that's some of the men. So So Barks when he wants them to
sometimes he'll kind of turn the tables and they'll have the little creatures that the Ducktales
discover, be much smaller than them. So that they are a kind of the menace. And, you know, we see that in in this one, we saw it in the mystery of the swamp, the the earlier sort of telling of this story
very famously and, like, laminate brown. Terri and the fermi.
There there a number of stories where he's gonna do this. And so you're you're not like a common book fan in general. Right? No. I don't read a lot of comments. I read a lot of stories, but not a lot of come. I want that Ryan Sc Al me and that you suck at me.
Right. Awesome. But but you're a big reader otherwise. Are you by chance familiar with with Long fellow and the Hi alaska, the Famous I lot the story. No.
That's okay. There's... I I would say it's not very relevant today, but it is kind of a it's a semi classic of American literature or or or poetry. That that's pretty important to this one. So
I could tell they were referencing something, and I'm like, I don't know that one. So... Yeah. I
two different times in the story. I noticed Yeah. And and we'll we'll definitely talk about Hi
because that was really important. It's it's one of those things I'm really fascinated by stuff from Aries different era of American pop culture that was really big and then kind of just fell off the face of the art. Right? And like, Hi
was just huge in though like, a big part of the early twentieth century
kind of in the way that, like, just wild west shows and less, you know, we're really popular from, like, say, the twenties through the sixties and then and then just basically utterly
disappear.
And and I don't... Alright. So a a disclaimer is is pretty important, right, for this one. So I'm I'm gonna lay out my cards a little bit. I I have a deep emotional attachment to this story. I really like this one. I I think it's a very good good very well whole Barks story, but it's definitely a big time capsule. Right? There there a lot of attitudes and
a lot of terminology towards native Americans that we definitely wouldn't use today. They're they were very run of the mail at the at the time in nineteen fifty seven when Barks wrote this, you know, they were very expected. The some of the terminology...
You know, they're they're gonna use the he's gonna use... He's gonna have the docs use the the r word that that is used
to describe Indians a few times
you know, and and and we won't be using that. It's the one that the Washington
baseball team football team but the Washington
football team goes for.
That the Washington
football team used to be called. They also... I mean, they use the term pig me when is kind of like a marginal word as far as, like, whether it's a pe,
And and I think the general style guide says that, like, if you're using it to refer to, like, the actual people in Central and Southern Africa, then it's acceptable, but, like, if you're using it to demonstrate people,
there's a lot of people who aren't comfortable with that. So I I mean, I'm gonna use that term because it's in the title. The land of the ping, but I'm not gonna use it a whole lot.
Savage is another of those words that is like, big majority of nowadays and we'll kinda use that sparingly, I think. So just just know that if we if we say anything like that, we're using it descriptive in reference to the story. But you guys can basically get your own comfort level. Right? So the the story that we're talking about today, end of the P Inducks
is one that was first published
in April nineteen fifty seven, at least that was a cover date. And we're up to Scrooge number eighteen.
This one has been
reprinted to a decent number of times that ten in the United States And it's a relatively
long Barks story for for this era. It's it's twenty seven pages.
It's not up to, like, the thirty two pages that some of these earlier ones were. But it's on the longer side. It's it's quite dense.
I will say, I did not count the pages, but hearing you, say it was twenty seven is kind of surprising to me. I actually thought it was probably thirty thirty five pages.
So this one felt kind of long to you. Did it did feel long and like didn't drag to you? A little bit. I think I think the pacing was a little slow, but that's not that's that's something I expect from from this era? I I know modern stories and modern comics can't get away with leisure pacing
anymore. And so I think it just feels slow because we're used to a faster pace market. Yeah. That's interesting. So I mentioned...
I mentioned the song of High.
That one, that one is really important to to understanding this story. Henry W long fellow as a poets
in... And and in eighteen fifty five. He put out this like, epic poem, the tail of High loss thought, the song of Hi, which was a very sympathetic tale of Native Americans, and it kind of matched up all of these
native legends that he he learned about, you know, directly from native. So you said. And and the weird thing about it, the notable thing is that he wrote it in Tropes archaic pent.
Do you guys...
That is the stun.
Okay it it is. It was very much a stunned, and and he did it because it was supposed to kind of mimic Indian Native of American chanting or song. Right, the kind of stereotype
of the chance. And, apparently, he was a big admire of the Ka,
the the very famous finish
epic poem that is, like the fit the national Story of Finland.
And you of you guys heard about the Ka?
No. I have not heard of this. Well, you you are not good things because everything
knows the Ka.
I don't even know what you would compare it to
to for for another country. It is like, the finish. I and I'm mentioning it because down the rug, Don Rose is gonna do a big light story where he to the entire country of Finland, which famously
likes
the dot com more per capita than just about anyone else. So is about, like, the the founding of the country? Is it, like a the origin myth? I mean, it's... It it goes back.
Very far. But I I think I... It's been a while since I read anything either about the poem or or Roses tail of C.
I'm I'm I'm showing my ignorance
of anything beyond really the title and the fact that they used that that type meter. But but apparently, that was a more common, like, that's more appropriate and finish because it matches the language.
And he was like widely der divided. Right? This poem was mocked. When it came out. They're all these scathing reviews And then today, we're like, well, this is, like really...
It's very little.
It's it's very, like noble savage trope
today. So... But it had this, like, sweet spot this golden age. And and in the late thirties, Disney released this Cartoon
called
Little ohio Watson. Does that ring a bell for either of you? Oh, that does ring a bell. Yeah. Yeah. Well let let me just I'm gonna show you...
I'll I'll share just really quickly Al image because
if if you grew up in the eighties, this was kind of still Ryan
something that you would have expected
to know. It would have been run. I don't know if that looks familiar. Oh, yeah.
Yeah. So this animated short was really, really big. It became big in, like, Disney comments because they adapted the Disney common. So so these comments were running for a while before Barks, you know, at least a decade before barb put out this story. So that the high lock the stories really did inspire this and and it was really big and pop culture, and weirdly the Europeans loved the high. Stories as well into the, like, two thousands.
I think it's the problem with the Indian, like, stories,
and pop culture
Either they're very, like, wild west, cowboys and,
very directly racist tropes.
Or they treat Inducks as, like characters.
Right? Not as real people. Yeah. I I know I know... I mean, I knew growing up in the Us that that
European had a fascination with the natives
because they don't really have native. They are the natives in Europe. You know what I mean? Yeah. And so having having an ancient culture that that you happen upon, you know, in fairly recent history and and and everything is,
you know, kind of exciting to them. Right. Right. And and we're not a immune to that. Right? Because, like, we have tons of that this this like, Noble Indian trope. Which is what Barks is really gonna lean into.
In this one. It's it's a different kind of...
It it's a different sort of problematic treatment. Like, on it face. Yeah. It looks like he's being much kinder to to the natives.
You know. This story compared to, like, land the tote bulls But, like, are they even real people in this that they're they're really not? No. He's totally
like, in
them. They're just they're... And part of that is because they're little. You know what I mean? It's easier. It's easier to...
They're they're not real people. They're they're fun little characters. And when we were kids, like, the biggest movies were last of the Mo
and dances with wolves. And right now,
avatar the way of water is making a million dollars.
Guys
they're not native Americans. They're aliens Barks. It has nothing to do with native Americans.
I did see it. I took... I took my my daughter. I took me Al a see it over winter break. And and we had a good time, you know? Because it's some in press spec and three d.
But as you say, Avatar is all about this, like, native peoples
connected to the Lands stroke and And like, if you don't read what modern natives have to say about this on its face, it might seem okay. This is very noble to is a very positive stereotype, but let's sue, you said the word in infant. That's the word that was on the tip of my brain. It doesn't go into kind of the complex city of either ancient Indian life or modern Indian life.
It's very
simplistic. Yes. Native were like probably more in touch with the land and in their environment, but, like, we don't really recognize how how they were managing it actively it. It really does a disservice to just turn them into these characters.
So so that's some of the caveats, and that's some of the things that, like, make it... That that makes it hard for me to revisit this story in the same way that I enjoyed it as an I year. Right?
But but I do think that there is a lot to really like about this story
and it and it really has to do with Barks
characterization of Scrooge
and some of his moral complexity in this one that's really fascinated. Barb got really at at some point, I mean, I'm gonna say it was in about nineteen fifty seven. At some point, he turned very up ecological minded in a way that is surprising.
To me, you know, for a man, he he was fifty six years old at this point. He was living in San Justin,
California,
where he had kind of, like, gone out to to have his own pocket with the... With clean air that didn't, you know, bother his didn't bother his asthma.
But I think he kind of felt...
Ryan, you can probably relate to this Al as someone who grew up in California with me. He felt civilization encroaching
the pollution was, like, the environmental movement was really getting going in the late fifties. And it's really interesting. This is the first story where he really leans into this kind of message of conservation. Yeah.
A lot of what you just said is depicted in the very first frame.
Yeah. Yeah, he's he's shouting in a real estate man. And then in the background, you can see just just smokes stacks.
Buff
who knows what into the air
across the whole horizon. And and the real estate man has... Even has an Al next to him that says
Shaq and San jack, nine thousand
c. I don't know. Maybe that's the currency in Duck...
It's funny that San sent gets gets called out in the first frame.
Yeah. Yeah. He he gets a kick out of putting occasional references to his hometown.
In here. And and... Yeah, like, it's... And this is before the clean... The, you know, the all the laws that came about in the late sixties
for for a period of time, like, American pollution was really bad too. So it's something we're always dealing with, but but it's actually gotten a lot better Yeah. I think Clean air act is nineteen seventy two. I wanna say... Yeah. Yeah. You're right. Later part of them. Barks back there in the early seventies. That's right. So, you know, yeah, fifty sixties, it would have been that it's peak, you know, where you can
light your local river on fire, light your tap water on fire. Right. Yeah. The C Guy, I guess wouldn't have been too far away from where from where this took place.
And and again, I mentioned that he
ecological mine that's something that's really interested in me. Interested me about Barks because, like he's he's very economically
conservative comes out in a lot of these stories.
But he's a bit of a hippie
and is later
in his later...
That's probably a simplification But, like, his last several stories are gonna be these junior chat stories that are that are Scrooge
against pollution and have the
how Scrooge cast Al kind of a villain. So it's just gonna be really interesting to see kind of the contrast between Scrooge,
as the person who like brought about all this environmental
degradation
to Ducktales
than than wanting to scape it. And and I find this to be a very interesting morally complex story,
especially with the great running gag. Of of him just never being able to get it off his mine. He can't turn off the the exploitation lens. He just he's like, Oh, I could make money off of this and enough of this something.
Right.
And and for me, that bit is is is Riot. I love it. I I as I was researching some people kind of were like,
this running gag gets played a little bit into the ground. So I'm curious is to let you guys think of it, but I but I'm I'm there for it the whole way through. I liked it. I I didn't think it got old because it's so in character, like Right. I I don't know. If he had tried to do that with another character, but it's it's screwed. He has a money pig. He's got a whole doll where he dies Inducks money. Of course, he can't turn it off. Right. Right. Yeah. No. I think I think it's a great... I think it's a great character b. One of Barks good quotes about this one was Well, first off, so he noted that the Ducktales docks themselves were always pee in comparison with the villains. In order of them to become a menace. They had to come up against somebody's smaller. And then his kind of, like, reason behind this story, he said clean air, clean water, clean environment. We think of those things as part of our birth birthright. They once were a long ago before we overrun them with our brand of civilization now would be a air so polluted that we have to grind it before it will filter through our gas masks water saw drinkable that is safer to die of thirst.
Environment so liter that we cannot see the ground and ground so positive with chemical spills that eat through the soul of our shoes and quiet who knows what that is anymore. So we dream that somewhere in the boom knobs, we can find a place that is still Al clean as nature intended but if we find such a place, would be safe to move in. Uncle Scrooge tries and this tail of the oxygen belt and finds that his kind and our kind are mighty darned unavailable I I mean, that that in and of itself is pretty poetic. So I think that was from some of his correspondence
with Jeffrey Blu and the age it's a it's a great selection of this story. So you guys let's...
Before we get into the story
itself, let's
take a moment to hand to my international
listeners.
I like to check in on how these stories get titled around the world. Sometimes it's really interesting because, like, story titles don't work in other languages.
And then sometimes they just kinda straight up translate salmon. And that's mostly the case here. You will see that most of the stories
it's just land of the Hidden Inducks or land of the North Indian But but here and there, it's it's a little bit different. So
sue do you wanna kick us off? Sure. Okay. In Brazil, both Inducks non.
The run Inducks.
Yeah. So slight variation on the theme. What did you... Which one did you wanna cover, Ryan? I'll do it good.
Big In the land of the Pink Inducks.
Yep. Very nice And that leaves me with the the tricky one, which is Danish.
So in Denmark, this was a
Inducks.
It's var in the Indiana land. In the land of the dwarf Inducks.
That's
that was the mouthful. Alright. So let's see.
I think I'm ready to dive into this one And then I guess I'll know This is one definitely one of the earlier Scrooge
adventures. That I ever read. I think I had this at eighty nine. It was probably among the first twenty or thirty of these stories. And and Ryan, you had alluded to the opening of this one.
I I usually say that a story has a strong opening because he's usually very good about opening his stories with a a great representation of the characters. But I think this one is especially strong because it it just... There is so much messaging
loaded into this first panel of him approaching really w Scrooge is w at Sidewalk
sam, the real estate man
And and he is complaining about wanting to leave Inducks
with its smog and noise
that he wants a home far out in the wild. And as you say, Ryan, we see all these smokes stacks in the background and and sign up Sam himself is one of these like characters that Barks will pull out occasionally where he's just this bit character who only appears
for a page
and and change. But to me is very memorable. He's this, like
very well designed Shady real estate guy who's sitting in an unusually low share
with up with a. He's got this weird just position where he's like dress very fancy, but he's, like, operating off Al, like,
storefront
in in the way that a real estate agent definitely would not jumping on a cigar. To me, he looks like W c fields.
And you guys have any thoughts about sidewalk Sam himself? I think
I think, you know, he's just... He's just in a Al a low chair on the sidewalk in front of his shop there. And he just has like notices, paper notices,
mailed up or pinned or something to the outside of the building, and Scrooge just walks up and and buys this huge property from him on the sidewalk
in Ducktales, and I think I think it kind of is meant to... I think it helps accent
one of the themes of the story of just kind of how preposterous it is that two rich white dudes in some distant lands can can pull out a map and, like, draw a square and be like you own this now, and I need it now.
They've they've never been there. They... You know, they have connection to the land. They have no answer ancestry through there. They don't speak the language of the people who live there. They just draw line and they go This is this is this is who owns it now. We have decided the ownership of this, and it's like, who are you?
It reminds me, it reminds me of, like, you know, the Shady guy on the streets in New York selling
boot like Dvds. Watches. Yeah. Yes. It's like This is not mine, but I'm selling it to you. Sort of deal. Yeah. That's that's what get from sidewalks.
Maybe in the guy who sells the Brooklyn bridge to you.
And, yeah, that's that's especially true, Ryan. This is a great supporting of the the theme itself of the story this this
on its face of it, like, this is kind of the this is the dis of some of the problems of monitoring capitalism. Right? This ownership of land this this distraction of everything
of value. And and, boy, I love that second panel where Sam is kind of leaning over.
And and his his cigar,
the smokes stack in the background, it almost looks like it's coming out from his cigar. It's an neat little touch and he, Just physician. And he he casually
sells Scrooge a plot of of a thousand lakes that he said are in the region north of Lakes superior.
So so we're just just north, I guess, if of
Minnesota into Southern Canada
in a part that is was pretty wild and and still is pretty wild. Famously called land end of a thousand late There's a there's a funny little bit where Scrooge says he'll Sam is referenced to how many acres and Scrooge says he'll take a thousand, but he means a thousand lakes.
And so
on on the next page, as screws draws out the deal with Sam, he gets a a rei reassurance from him. So do you wanna tell us about the the assurance that he gets from him. Oh, yeah. No. He's he's trying to make sure there's no people. There's nobody there, not even the Inducks and sidewalk sam is very confident. That's right. You'll have the whole place to yourself, which, you know, we we know from the title that's not the case. So that's gonna be a phone's price frame him later. Right. Right. And and and it's ridiculous. Right? He
sidewalk sam can say whatever Huey, wants. And so
we get this neat little sequence of Scrooge kind of pondering how excited he is to leave the smoke and smog of duck.
But there's a real contradiction there. He's he says I'm through with it. Even though I am the guy that started all of those smelly
industry.
And and boy, that's a stark thing to say, right? To want to
to want to develop all of this stuff and then when it's too much, Scrooge is not considering, like, cleaning it up.
Or dis dismantling it. He he just wants to leave it. Yeah. He's he's still making money from it. Certainly.
Right. You wanna impact that. And so he's coming to you. We we see him grab donald than the nephews.
Who are... They're an interesting role in this, because they're largely
comp and what he's doing here. Right? He's gonna take them along to look for a a good location to bring him, and I think he allude to moving his money in there. They they they board a neat looking sea plain and he talks about how he brought plenty of equipment for having fun, hunting and fishing. And and sue what is Scrooge is definition of hunting and efficient. I hello. I love that you something he's something gold, silver, nickel copper, what else? Would you want?
Right. Right. So it's just it's just mining equipment. It's a great character beat. It's a great guy, and he is gonna go back to that well quite a bit. And and so we transition pretty quickly to this land of a thousand lakes. I really like the landscape
that's that
straws in this story guys. I think it's really beautiful. The the wilderness and the animals are all drawn in a really neat way.
The docs land in in a hooks shape or new near a Home shape hook shaped Lake
that kind of is the guy for where his plot of land is And basically
throughout the next pages
as they're exploring the property, we're gonna have this kind of like running theme
running gag going on that we've mentioned a little bit, but Ryan, do you wanna tell us what's basically gonna be happening during this stan. Oh, as he's looking at the natural beauty, he is
imagining all of the
resources that he can extract out of it. He can
turn the timber and paper. He he sees a moose and he wants to sell some move mistakes back in the in the duck oh in the New York Barks. Right right. So like everything
here. Everything that he sees is just g for his industry. And and he cannot help himself. Did you wants the model the? Model the air. Yeah. Yes. He even references
bottle the air and selling it
back Inducks.
It it is pretty.
It's it's a little bit over the top. It's pretty funny. Yeah. So... And and then we get the Inducks kind of, like, talking about how, you know, it's fortunate that there's nobody that lives there. So they're they're gonna leave all of that stuff. They're playing, their camp. The whole time they're gonna be leaving it unattended And they see this bra moose
at some point. And
their...
The reader is gonna get this kind of ominous
view of the moose that the Inducks don't get. So do you wanna tell us about that moose? Yeah. No. I really really loved this like visual
for foreshadowing and kind of like, they're just talking about how there's nobody around, but on the other backside side of the moose, the move is built up on a platform with a little ladder up to it. It looks like a little spy hole and
I like... I I liked it. That it was funny. Right.
Exactly. It's our... It's our. First hints that there are in fact humans here.
But but they must be fairly small and and it Al echoes an early gag and mystery of the swamp, Ryan that very weird story with the measles
where we got a similar view of an alligator that has little nasal fee good fee. Oh, yes.
Running running beneath it. So this was his... I think this was the first time that he did this type of story remake Most people would say that this one is much much stronger that he kinda refined this story and that it's better than the mystery of the small. I myself love mystery of the swamp because it's just so weird,
but I I can't help but agree that this this is just generally a better story
overall. So, the the whole way Scrooge
cannot
shut up about the the kind of resource extraction that he would love to do. And and we see the nephews.
He be doing
kind of spa. I I hope on the Scrooge will leave this country clean and free for the animals and birds. He alone can decide that, you know, because he has that deed from Sidewalk sam.
And and we get to their campsite site, and this is a direct
redo of where how they camp when they were in the gl in mystery of the swamp
They don't secure anything Scrooge
is seeing like platinum
and so forth. And and when they wake up in the morning, Ryan, do you wanna tell us what they find.
All their stuff has been rec up. Everything's all, you know, their supplies and stove and everything have been thrown into the the hooks shaped like, around them. And as they're looking around to try and figure out Al some tracks or something, maybe an animal did this,
Scrooge is just checking out the minerals in the ground to to see if there's any valuable minerals.
Right. Right. You even as
even as he's supposed to be kind of investigating for what's been going on. He can't help himself.
It's interesting to think, right? Like, did was Scrooge always like this? Did his, like, hunt for wealth kind of like, per preferred him into this. Don Rose is gonna do some stories later on and especially in his life and times of Scrooge.
Like, young Scrooge stories where he kind of references
that that change in Scrooge and show screws tiny for the days when you could look at something.
As a beautiful natural feature instead of like, resource extraction. You guys, I love the the very well timed Joke. That they have with the moose
where where they're puzzling over onto the next page here, they're puzzling over you know, who could have taken this? What could have happened because raiders would come by canoe and Canoe don't make tracks
And and then we cut immediately to their canoe floating away, and an nephew who says ours does, I I really like that. I I think that's very funny.
And and when they go to check it, thinking that they've figured out the mystery, they realized, oh, it's just... It's just a dogg on wandering moose But, of course, the reader knows that most likely, it is the... It is the hidden little characters that are stealing it away and disguise.
And and the docs get their first
direct
intuition of of who is men them. Sued do you wanna tell us when they approach a a little visual sign. Yeah. They've got a little tree there, and it's got
an arrow tied to the tree and the error was pointing to a branch that is just holding an egg and I think I think the the nephews do they... Do they pull up their, like, little wood both?
Oh, this means.
Go back where you came from. Right. It's it's a pretty obvious. It's it's a bla siren of a sign. Right? I don't know that anyone would really need to interpret that way.
But it then it feels very clever to me. And I like...
I guess it's worth noting too that a lot of the stuff that is like, native in this or Indian and this really is Inducks.
Right? He's gonna use... He's gonna kinda
all these Indian tropes the way that every
everyone did throughout the entirety of the nineteen fifties. And so, yeah, It's a sign that says go back where you came from and and sp is outraged, and he's gonna let out with a no savages can do this to me on my land. I'll start charging them rent.
So so screws is is pretty
throughout most of this story.
He... I mean, he's used the villain of this story
very arguably.
Yeah. Definitely. Yeah.
No question. And and we get this this funny little gag
where Donald, you know, he he's like, hey, this egg might be years old. I'm gonna inspect it to make sure it's fresh. And then the very predictable thing happens,
tiny little arrow fires through the egg in a perfect bit of comment tied, timing,
sp it on him, and he says it was today's egg thank goodness.
It's it's cute. It's predictable but I liked it. Yeah. I thought it was cool. I thought it was a Clever Donald to think of, you know, is this something someone left twenty years ago, or or is this a message for us?
Right. And and so the next a couple of pages are devoted to this sequence that is going to...
It's gonna gradually hint at the size of the Inducks. Right?
And and it's going to be, like, it's gonna kind of show us that they are men,
but that their defense right as screws approaches them, he gets a volume of arrows
filling his top hat, which is pretty funny. We we get a moment where the this feels
extremely awkward in two thousand twenty three, you know, as he walks back to the canoe, yelling Al then he he says I'll be back later and he calls him that our word renegade
that's an illegal defiance of a landlord. Again, a lot a lot of listeners
are are probably listening in Europe where the more haven't, like turned as quickly but Like, we've we've been grappling with the use of that word for the last couple of decades. The last decades
in the United States,
and
it is just... It is now seen as a
Al ethnic
slur and is not used anymore, but it would have been in very common use in nineteen fifty seven. And and the whole point of this sequence besides showing them as defensive as again, hint to how small they are because we see their tiny little arrows.
We see eventually, we see.
Again, it is Indian, so we've got we're required to have the little single feather. All in the where feathers Barks, all of them...
Yeah.
Exactly.
And and we see them unusually close together. The debts suppose that they must be running through the tall grass but but then they... As Donald fires off the shot to to flush them out. They see them moving unusually fast. This is a bit that doesn't work as well as it would if it were animated. You know? Yeah.
And and then we get the reveal. Right, and it is supposed to be a little bit of a reveal where they they'd say, oh, don't tell me. H me Inducks. Right? I've read if had some kind of new species or whatever, like, the
Or, you know,
the measles or whoever, he likes to kind of create these new races or whatever and, like you know, These are these just kind of a native American Hobbits or something that is good.
Yeah. I think that's a good way of describing them. That's that's what they their Native American
habits effect. I think I think it's interesting that they're
essentially humans, they're essentially pink squishy humans like us. Right. That have some kind of a doc or some kind of vague
dog looking
person
or whatever, like, all of the occupancy of of Ducktales Right. Yeah. That's true. And and some of his earlier comics, he would
use more human characters. And then later on, he would only make sort of these other weird races be humans. So, do you wanna describe the Kiwi guys
for us and if you have any thoughts about them? Sure. Yeah. They're all very small, obviously.
They're all wearing feathers as we've noted all In have more better.
They've got, like, little tiny spears and
instead of horses, they have rapid.
Think it's
delightful.
But, yeah. They're just... They're just very small. They have a large noses.
Very. Yeah. Very large noses, noses is
forty percent of their face I would say. But, yeah, that's
leather of kind. Yeah. Yeah. They have... They'll have fringe
leather or clothing and mo.
And in the background, I can see
some tote poles like Pacific Northwest tribes would make.
Right. Yeah. Do when I learned a a good bit about tote poles from doing land of the tote poles. And and as you say, that is that is a Pacific Northwest thing. Not we we definitely have some mis mismatch here. Looks like are those wig ones, I guess? Oh, yeah. Or or or would that be a mini long house? I'm not sure, but sound. But at at least it's not a great plains tip p. Yeah. Yeah. Those those tote poles came a long way to Like superior that probably.
Yeah. And and again, he's gonna cast to the native the the little kiwi guys as they're called as very
sympathetic. We're supposed to identify with them. They're very determined They're very brave. We see them in this in this panic So I have a question. I I wanted to know your thoughts.
They they shoot a million arrows
over these two pages at the docks.
But they do not actually shoot the Ducktales with an arrow. Do you think that's on purpose? Do you think they're just trying to, like, warn off the Ducktales? Or do you think it's just plot armor and our heroes never get hurt. Do you think do you think these are, you know, precision warning shots or
clumsy shots?
For business. You know, I I think that's a great question. I think I I think... I think it's a little bit of both. I mean, I think we've definitely got plotted armor here. Throughout. But but yeah, I think the kiwi guys are so noble
Right? They don't actually want to hurt them. They given them ample worn and, you know, they're given them this sign and tried to convince them to leave.
So I I think these are precision,
get the heck out of here. Volumes.
I I I tend to agree with you there because the only
all the Ducktales wearing hats, but the only dog who has arrows in his hat is the bad guy. Right Like the Nephews and donald, they don't have arrows that their had. They're not the ones shouting
seventies.
It's like have in their. They're not being shot at. It's just screwed. Yeah. They're they're very responsive to the, like, true actual
threat.
What
it is something.
And and that panel with all of the Pb guys screen, that's a really cool panel. I I really like that. This is where we first encounter the kiwi guys cadence, their speech. This is something that Barks really this is unusual. Right? Because again, he did write there all of their dialogue was written
in this...
What did I say called
it is written in t
hand.
Does anyone know how to read T pen?
Heaven's know.
So I of course, well before researching this story.
Knew how to read
And of.
Obviously.
Clearly, I I did not practice this last night or any Basically, you are putting the stress on the first syllable. Right? In in in English,
we we have I I Al.
Stress where we would... We would stress
the the second syllable. So... And then you're you're doing it like every other. So so his... The the says that the chief is telling them go kiwi does from your village, flee, the mighty war, like strangers.
But it would be go kiwi guys from Your village.
Fleas mighty wore war likes. Stranger, something like that. I'm sure I'm not doing it very well, but it's that's it's got... It's definitely got this rhythm
The way you see it, it does make you wanna read it this way. So even if it... It's kind of imminent ridiculous that that Long fellow is doing this goofy
stereotype
thing.
It is still really notable, and I think really interesting.
And and definitely very poetic. In the way that Barks was was going for and Long fell was originally going for. Let's see. I have a quote about him and and doing this. He said, I came up with having the pin talk in the language of Long fellows song of Hi
about the eighth grade I had to read and recite in school. Thought it was a very tires way of telling the story back then, but the meter lands itself very well to the conversations of the ping when they talk about what they're going to do. It gives the story a special flavor. The dialogue took longer to write than normal if it practically had to be timed with with a metro or no, I've come up with the gist of what they wanna to say, then try to figure out a way to express it in long fellows meter. So I think that's really interesting I think that's a very cool and successful part of the story. I imagine
trying to write and
also helps
the
not sound as...
What again. What's the what's the word that I'm looking for? The land of the total pulls they found very... They use stupid. They just have
right. Right. It they use very pigeon
English and we got a lot.
And and sometimes they will like, they definitely use the kind of in infant
pronouns in this, They're gonna say Right. We instead of I,
But you're right. It does give them... It it it it makes them seem more special, definitely
But but, again, more like a carrot or more like a hobbit
than and a real human. And so, you know, as screwed approach is them fleeing because he wants to kind of like have a landlord
conversation with them.
A stray arrow from a rear guard slips down his
his rightful
destroying it. It's a very cool couple of panels. And and the Inducks have to flee temporarily and they're pondering what they're gonna do.
And screws says I could go back to that land and get my money back because of that guarantee
of nobody living here.
But he says I'm kind of taken with the possibilities.
Ryan, do you wanna read his line
that's on on the sixth panel of this page in the Ka canoe besides
Besides if I could tame those little savages, they make the best dogg on pipeline cleaners than ever.
Yeah.
It's seen a a a dome of match gas that he knew he could tap. And you gotta... You gotta pipe that to the
refineries
Right. Right. And and we're not highlighting every Scrooge moments of
noting, but you guys feel free to cut in as I skip over them because they're... They're interesting and it and it gives us a flavor.
How often they are. He does have also as he's saying this, you can see his face. He's still... He still has, like, sit on him from his exploding shotgun,
but he has this, like, villainous a smile
that's kind of men
and,
his nephews are ain't really shouting and him down.
Yeah...
This is definitely a story. You know, I I did the great
second richest dot is first experience meeting Flint heart, Glen, just a few episodes ago. And and the neat thing about that is you can see
long is like, is do or in this And the only thing that it Scrooge screws from descending into, like, kind of villain
is that his nephews are around keep him in chat. So I I think they're kind of an underrated part of his character. But but if that's a pretty awful thing to say, Right? Tame them to exploit him as pipeline planners And then this this so, this is gonna be a pretty weird part of the story. I wonder if this gave you pause, the Ducktales plan,
which is to capture.
You know, on even one of the, like, very sympathetic nephews says, we want we could capture one of little guys to get their message across to them to to them, you know, give them, like, say that they come peacefully.
I just
that part was weird to me. I was like, these guys have been the voice of res, and now they want to kid up somebody to tell them don't be afraid of us, that just seems like some seriously mixed messaging you guys right. And then they do can connect them they don't try to talk to them. And all they just run And I'm like, what? Where was your plan of of making this guy your in best?
Right. I heard that. I imagine they were they were gonna get to it, but they certainly aren't in a hurry. Ryan t, do you remember this story beat from mystery of a swamp at all? And he's been a year the kid map?
Yeah. They can have to.
Do you remember he he... They they build this make shift cage for how many swell up. Oh, yeah.
Very weirdly. It's it's a it's one of the odd
moments in all of our stories.
They didn't tell his
at that point. Yes.
I I... That's the only explanation is that he really felt like okay. Once he realized because he he had a comment here
where he he claims that he didn't realize at first that he was kind of retailing this story. He said, I realized that I I... I realized that the plot line was similar, all oh, I began coming up with the idea of me the out in the brush and brass. I suddenly realized that I was duplicating a plot line I had used years ago, the the and mystery of the swamp. This that gave me pause for a while, But I realized that only the plot was similar all other elements were breaking new route. Besides the fit were more believable,
and interesting than the diesel. So so I went ahead with the story and let the guides fall they might
and I mean, in a way that's right because the measles were so out there. But I I don't think that he's entirely right there because I think he he ended up following this story be maybe a little bit too closely, and it just... It doesn't fit. Yeah. But there's also in in the next frame, Scrooge says that's the ticket. Tell them I'll be easy on the rent, and I'll let them have one whole lake fish on out of the thousand lakes that he has bought. And and then if you say, they'll love you uncle groups.
Right. It's it's it's very sarcastic from the nephews, but I feel like they could be protesting a little bit harder. I feel like they're very passive throughout this whole story. Because Scrooge is really this, like, smog cloud of impending doom.
I mean. He he is absolutely
going to destroy the Kiwi guys way of life. Yeah. And and so we get this neat moment here where we cut to the Kiwi guys and we see what they're up to, and they are
celebrating that they have routed
the pale docs as they as they call them. So these characters are definitely coded as white men, right? Despite being docks. The these are... We know that they are white people. And they are literally white.
Yes.
I I really like their cute. We we kiwi we guys with our... With our arrows
still the thunder
in its boo.
No idea what Google is supposed to be, but I love it. So
So they they... That the the chief cha them not to celebrate too early because the dots may come back to and uncheck the kiwi guys. Gosh, I love their dialogue And the Ducktales approach them to the sound of distant
Tom Toms. Again, it's all very indian ish later that that evening.
And we see a moment where they porta. This is that's definitely a a word that I learned from these Comments. They ported their canoe over from one, lake, to another.
To kind of enact their plan.
And they see them chanting
what their plan is. But would anyone like to
can ham up there
they're yeah their monologue.
I'm on it. We must trick the pale deck warriors, we must bring them to our council. There to test their good intentions
and to ask what they are planning,
Al that was great, Ryan. Wonderful.
Thank you. I I hope by the way that now that I really highlighted this for modern listeners that you go back and try and, like,
maybe even read it aloud. It's it's kind of fun. It's neat to know that there is, like, a very specific rhythm that is supposed to have. Oh... It is interesting that they view the the Ducktales as warriors.
U. Like they had one weapon which is gone now, and it's just like an old man, a middle aged man, and some children.
And that's the that's the army that's come to page, you know. Yeah. Right. Right. The the kiwi guys are giving the docs a lot of credit throughout this story. It's kind of that like
it's that little trope about. Can they prove their worth and then we'll allow them to
to be in their kind of superior position.
And we get... We get a an awkward scalp reference to... Again, it's all Indian,
Donald
sneaks up and says are your scalp on tight
another of those very winds moments.
And and day,
the kiwi guys reveal what the big, like, deed that the have to do. Sue, do you wanna do you wanna tell us about the the a d that they have to do. Oh, they've got a... They've got a fish for the king sturgeon, which is they're like... He's there... He's their big bad in the lake. And so that's... It if the docs can can catch this fish, this giant King sturgeon, then then that proves that they're were. Right.
Exactly.
And then we get the little sequence the awkward sequence where they they g onto to the little scout that has
wise gone to look for the dots suspecting them speaking about, But but not wisely
chose unlikely not to bring a companion along with him. Well, I I sure love his thought balloon as he... I mean, it's it's very like, it's it's very common condescending because he uses the word the pronoun and me instead of eye. But
sue, would you... Would you like take a crack at reading his internal thoughts as he says me here not by. Me you're not but whispering pine trees. Hear the lapping of the waters. Here the cricket making squeaky and the woo hoo of the outlet.
So
they're extremely poetic. They're very dim.
And everything they do and say is very cute even when they're being threatening It's all super kinda condescending. But it... To me, it sure is
it's very entertaining. Also, I I feel like a lot of I mean, you know,
what am I... What am I trying to think of? Like, if if you look at, like, any kind of physical conflict like this, for... That's aimed at this age group, Like, you know, how how does Ga mail talk maybe with the Sm or or whoever the care Barks fight?
You know what I mean?
It's always going to be
kind of cute. Because you don't want to give little tiny kids nightmares.
Right. Right. He was know this.
Exactly. He he was writing this under sort of the Disney code. Western Publishing, you know, had very stringent guidelines about what you could do. So this is a way of making it interesting. And and so, you know, the next sequence months deals with the the capture and the aftermath of the capture.
This is this is pretty neat. They they get back to their sea plain and they find that it's been sunk.
I really like that panel. It shows all this wildlife life kind of squat on the half some c plain.
And and they're very... That now they're very distraught because as Donald says those little Tom
oh geez. We'll we'll be here in a few minutes like buzzing hornets.
That's a completely original slur as far as I know.
Yeah. I know. It's it's definitely a slur, but we can we can say it doesn't have a long legacy.
I I mean, it's it's a it's a it is not a nice thing to say. Right? This is just how that gets catherine throughout. And again, we I think it's interesting
the... Like, again, this is this is whole. I'm like, where are they going with this plan? They're gonna get on their sea plain. Where are they taking this guy
I.
This doesn't seem like they're plan at all.
Right. Right. This is like this is, like taking poc
fax to to England, I guess. To like. But what they're gonna do, show him the great smokes stacks of duck to try to, like, turn him around. I I know. It's it's a little.
We won't do this to your land.
Right. So so they basically have to flee on cattle.
And we get this this this sequence is both very neat, but it's also very, like, trophy. Right? We we see the that the little kiwi got
talking to the animals as he passes them. I really like the little conversation with the fish using little like bubble,
little conversation with the the little baby wildcat cats. I just like how
they're like
dismiss of him like, oh, look at him pretending to talk to the. The little the little war makes
believe he's talking to animals. He's sure a hard.
And I just love. I just love that, like, they're completely just dismissive and then that's actually what was happening.
Right.
Right. And it's weird for the the the Nephews to be dismissive that way because they're usually, like, more open minded than that.
But the little... The little kiwi we got that convince is a wildcat cat to
free him and then take his place as they're porting
the canoe between lakes.
And and then we get this neat little sequence where the wildcat cat attacks them causing them to
go overboard and syncing their canoe,
which has them really Inducks pickle because they hear
we got a pretty unfortunate, like,
of, I think, the sound of war whoop as as Donald has just
Again, coined another slur, the little... Oh there was Al nephews a little war.
What is the what is the voice scouts to analog the voice belong to? Which. Yeah. When when I was... When I was a with chuck, I actually got the canoe merit badge,
and you you can't make a canoe do that. It doesn't... It doesn't sink like that like the titanic. If you can fill it entirely with water so that that is just like a a bathtub of water to the top. And it will just hover a couple feet below the water.
So the water level in the will match the water level outside the ka canoe, but it'll still be there. You can actually keep pedal it.
If you're strong enough, it takes a lot of work because now you're pedal your own weight and then five hundred pounds of water.
But you can do. That's a great fact. That's why that's why why I've got guests on. That's awesome.
I guess, I guess we need to presume that the the wildcat cat
maybe
tore it up to this clause or that Barks just didn't know.
Actually, actually kinda... He does have some quote somewhere I read where he... He was never a boy scout,
but that he was very... Like, he had admired them and then, you know, the wood shots were kinda way of regretting that you didn't get to be one.
So this this is another of those echoes from mystery of the swamp where the dots are gonna hide and some tall reads and they're gonna use them to conceal themselves,
breathe through the the, like, weeds
It's neat. It's it's a fun little little thing that is ultimately gonna be
unsuccessful.
And and I feel like they should know that it's gonna be unsuccessful. Soon what you want... This is the part. This is the part where I'm like, this whole scene from the reads to the flying out of the water when the fish is, like, poke him in the box. I feel like this is what slowed down the pacing. Because we don't get anything new here. Like we already know they can talk to the animals. You're in a lake with fish. Like you already saw him talking to the fish. It should not be a surprise that you are not going to be able to hide here. And it kind of... It kind of just goes. And and I feel like it's a really long build up for the for the gag when they get helped in the bus. That was very funny. But I feel like I feel like you could have done with like one or two panels to set that up. Instead they've got, like, a page and a half here. And I think that's what slowed down the pacing for me. I was like, there's nothing
new here. This is just a very long build up to the visual gag. Sure. Yeah. I think that's reasonable. It it is... It could have been largely
taken out. I mean, it's it's a fun little bit. We see these ga.
I think their guard. They're actually wetting They're like noses on some underwater rocks to, like, quote sharpen them. But you're right. It's it's a weird plot hole because the Ducktales literally see them. Talking to fish.
So it feels like that's the moment to be like, okay. The jig is up, we we need to come clean to, like, maybe buy some honeywell goodwill but, you know, it's a poke in the butt gag, and it is comic for kids. So Yeah. No. I enjoyed the poke in the buck. Don't get me wrong. I'm saying the build was too long. Right.
Right. And the docs definitely do have it coming. I will say. Oh, for sure. Oh, boy. I I like I can't read every little bit of the Kiwi guys
dialogue, but I sure do like the... This one where where the chief says me have heard from Ga Pipe fish heard from Needle knows, the Pic rail. Wait, they say, and soon the pale ups will jump
will jump three high from the Ducktales.
And and sure enough they do
and and they have a
confrontation here. And and basically the point of the
confrontation, Well what do you think Ryan? What's the whole point of this confrontation?
Basically, they're arguing about ownership because the the chief is saying,
you know, we've caught them. We're gonna bring them to our counsel and ask them why they're probably through our waters. Scrooge says your water's your sq on my land and the chief is saying
by what token can be approved that you own these lakes and forests Scrooge screws has this paper from San the Real estate, ma'am.
Yeah. I can take you to his office. It was sidewalk sandy estate.
That that is a wonderful panel. Right? Because Scrooge has this, like, triumph
look on his face as though he has made,
you know, check made. I I can tell you and and the Nephew is like, in in the back looks very s in because he knows that it's in in the face. He kinda knows the deal. Right? And and they're surrounded biology these peaceful with one creatures because we've got this noble connected to the land trope going on here. But he knows what a ridiculous thing it is to tell these native Americans about land ownership
according to a piece of. Yeah. Let me explain to you what the county recorder is. You see there's the
Right. And there's even that there's even... I noticed in this panel, there's
kiwi got that has Al like a chip
just sitting on it on his head as part of the council.
Right. One go the proceedings. I didn't catch that on the first read. Right. And and you could be kind and read it as oh, the Pb guys are just so connected to nature they commune with the for us or you could be like, oh, the Pb guys might as well be animals of the forest.
Either way, it's it's definitely trophy and in,
but it but it's it's an it's a very cool scene
admittedly.
And and Scrooge, you know, he really is below.
He's saying I intense to save this land and myself from being sm by factories and so forth.
I love his little connecting look. On the next page. Where it kinda puts his hands
together, and he has this kind dreamy
hu
look on his faith on his face.
And
the Nephews are all smiling at all the animals around and chi him, but that very in a very subdued way. Because it's the kiwi guys that have to counter him. And and a couple of the regular kiwi guys, they they speak simultaneous
saying that their words are slim,
and they they resolve that the duct need to prove their worth by having their greatest warrior
attach the great king
sturgeon And
and that... That's gonna take us to the sturgeon
sequence.
So what do you what did you guys think about this version sequence ones?
I like... I like how one of the f nephews
is saying that the sturgeon is the the villain of the the pc because. So and I'm like
Nice try hon.
Right. Maybe yesterday. He was... He was there.
I I really like the sequence. It... Maybe it drags on a little bit. But I don't know. It it plays out pretty cool. It plays out in a pretty neat manner. We've got Donald kind of sitting around moaning because, of course, he's got kinda have. He's not the old man. He's not a he's not a literal child. So he's kinda capture the
the king surgeon
and and we see this nice little bit of for shadowing Ryan Tell us about the fore foreshadowing about the search sturgeon
size.
Well, they...
The tribe sends some couple canoe out to lower the kiwi got into the Cove, and then we just get a tail that kind of crosses through the the middle of the the canoe.
And and there is a painting, a famous painting called Mo dip by Rockwell
kent
that this, like, panel is supposed to be echoing.
Right. Now. It's pretty cool. Here. I'll I'll show it to you guys. Really quickly. Maybe be tech
kent.
Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah. Yeah. So I thought that was... That was a neat little illusion that I would never have known about if I didn't, like actively
research this story.
Alright. So
very reluctant and donald gets pushed out to do this.
And he's gonna use a pumpkin as bait because of the size of that king surgeon
and he's gonna try to do this from sure with a grapple hook that they conveniently have and
it's also worth noting
Scrooge just still kind of in Al play mode.
As soon as the canoe are destroyed, Scrooge tells donald,
go land that oversized min.
Yeah. Exactly.
This is not a big deal. Just go catch the little fish.
Right.
Right. And I And this sturgeon is like enormous. Have you guys ever seen a sturgeon in real life? No. No. They're terrifying on fishing trip ones, I saw one like surface
right next to where I was I was very unsuccessfully fishing. And I just blocked that. It must have been five or six feet. And it looked pre.
And and you know what, if you think about the Ducktales scale, the very biggest of surgeons, that this is only a little bit of an exaggeration kind a. Because they don't get this big in general, but they they can get pretty darn big. And this is a really neat fight... It's visually, I think, pretty exciting for a comment book. I we can't really do a justice
in the comment books, So I'm not really gonna try to. But you know, donald braces himself against the tree and it gets ripped out
and and the surgeon is pulling him around as he's as he's clinging to the tree, even jumping through the tree stock, like the tree trunk like a stock of Al. And and the whole time, this is Sc is not showing a ton of concern.
Is he? You guys wanna tell me about what Scrooge is up to? He's finding he's finding Rare earth minerals roles. He's got some lithium and some making it up and some...
What I don't don't remember what he calls them all, but Huey, it like Donald Donald is, like screaming for his life and screws is just, like in the sand
trying trying to exploit the land some more Yeah. It's not it's not a very... It doesn't paint a very good picture of screws here.
Boy rare
are pretty
hot commodity these days. Right? Like the these are these are in the news quite a bit. These are gonna be
a lot of our future words are gonna be fought over rare Earth minerals
and they make up c accept some pretty funny names as you say there's a couple of real ones in there, and then he's just kind of... This this apparently is incredibly
rich land and we've got this funny gag here where this very much Scrooge his character. He is so good at identifying this stuff that he's able to, like, pile it around, like a a little kid playing with play,
maybe.
And and the Nephews user panicking is Donald is swimming for his life, and they they yell at him
and he's just... He's... He might as well be trans by these minerals. And so it is up to the junior shocks.
To save them. And
junior would check Bailey, do you want to tell us about
about how they do it?
So they
decide they they should be able to do something with all those repair earth.
So they check their manual on on rare earth.
And
so they look for recipes under magic of...
That that's a weird little moment. Right? It's very scientific
I I noticed that the word balloon is a little bit bigger. I wonder if Barks was like maybe he just... He didn't get around to imagine it might have even been It might have been a placeholder holder word or something that he never kinda got around. We never fixed... That makes a lot more sense than... Yeah. Look under your man. Right. He's like okay.
Some something something would check magic. I'll think of something and And there private here.
Right. Right. Circuit trying here. Yeah.
So Tell us what they end up with.
So they they make the most powerful pill ever rolled.
Oxide of str bo. Do guys know what referencing
Str bo?
Str bo is he from Ben,
Yeah. In in in Disney's version of Pin,
it's not in the original Italian one, but they name him strong.
Which is also like a meat and cheese filled, Italian American pastry. Those are the only two things that I knew it from. And Again, res researching. I I learned that there is a pretty famous Italian volcano that is named str.
So Oh, wow. That makes sense. Yeah. And then we continue. Then they
throw it into
the fish open mouth as it's about to swallow donald. It is already swallowed
the tree that Donald used as Al. And the Donald was surfing for a while out in the... Out in the lake. And now Donald, it's Donald final moments.
And he's getting swallowed and the fish sw them both together. Right.
Yeah. He even says as he
as he Barks into the into the fish mouth. I'm bush to move over, Jonah. Here I come Yeah. I I really like this. It's very car ish right? The the giant monster
forwarded by eating a a spicy,
but
but that is funny. It worked for me. I love... I love seeing that they sturgeon and out of water. That's interesting to note that they didn't kill it. We see a little
sn z's
above the fish as donald in.
Another and another little moment
sue Scrooge can't help, but exploits
but think
taste oil.
Twice as a pint.
Right. And the kiwi guys are loading. They're celebrating the duct for having a van pushed the surgeon and. I guess he won't last very long out of the water like that, a sleep or not. Does it have disease in in the version of the story that you guys reading? Okay. Yeah. No. I'm trying can't through to see to see... Like, I I just assumed they were gonna eat him, but But no. We don't get any... Never appears again. He never appears again. No. Yeah.
That's it for the great king's surgeon and
probably been alive for a couple of centuries.
Alright. And and so now we've got our last big sequence of the story.
And another
very
indian
moment as the kiwi guys prepare
to Gonna say this with a big sigh. They they get ready to smoke them Indian style.
Right? They're they're using that Indian pigeon.
So that this is like, this is one of the things that all white people knew about Inducks and in this sierra is that they're... They always smoked piece five some And native Americans did use piece pipes, but it varied by culture varied by tribe.
This is naturally gonna be very Ducktales. But... But it was done in great ceremony, and
I I have no doubt that there's a lot of elements of this that he gets wrong here, but I'm not in the no enough.
So so yeah, they're gonna have a piece type ceremony as the kiwi guys sit down to listen to quotes
there... His
Scrooge many plans and wishes, and they will listen to his big ambition And
is one of you wanna tell me what Scrooge hopes are is very contradictory for hopes here. He says my hopes are to keep these Legs clean an air pure on the forest screen, which, you know, it's a little hard to swallow.
I won't add factories or sm at least I think I can keep myself from doing that at for a while, I hope.
So so every bit of signaling here, you guys is is that Scrooge is not gonna be able to... I mean, he is outright telling us. See he might as well be, like, elbow the reader. Like I'm Scrooge Mick dot. I'm I'm definitely going to exploit this land. And so... And so I think what the kiwi guys have done here is justified
because the the other thing that's hard swallow is is the peace pipe. Right?
He immediately choke because because one of the kiwi guys has poisoned him.
Uncle Scrooge kind of plop over looking very sick and the dumps say that they needed to rush him to the nearest doctor. And,
Ryan, do you wanna... Do you wanna tell about the the chief Huey, guys moment of confusion there? He didn't think that pale Inducks uncle visa week fit pipes smoke ruin him, and the other guy says, min now me sprinkle tobacco hinge of oxide of str bo,
Me points at the little the little pile that
that the boys made from all the rare elements. Right. And and he breaks the fourth wall a little bit. He wink clearly at the reader. I think that that
little kiwi guy is coded as being a which doctor. Right? Because he's got little
Yeah.
Or I guess his code is being a medicine, man. But but to me, that's kind of almost which doctor coding. So again, It's it's very Indian ish.
And then our our very final little cap sequence.
I guess this is a little bit of abrupt. Right? In in the mystery of the swamp, the denise get rid of
donald than the boys by giving them
some food that's been spiked with what they call for jet juice.
Gives the docs completing amnesia.
And and in a way, screws just chooses here to forget about it.
Soon you wanna tell us about him him waking up days later? Yeah. He he wakes up and his what's that wonderful smell and he sticks his nose out into the smog and just like, breathe it in and says this is like honey
compared to the that pipe
you know, and like, well what about the land? Like, what are you gonna do with it? And you he's decided he doesn't want it anymore if it means he has to smoke those piece pipes. With the Indian. So you'll just give it back to the land back to them. Right. So he's basically renown his claim. He might as well be forgetting the Pb guys and that gets to live in peace. With... I guess no king surgeon around to
them. So that that's it. That's land of the Pin
You guys.
What are your thoughts about this story overall? Ryan?
Like sue, I was also bracing myself or something
much more offensive.
And
I thought, you know, the environmental message was pretty good. Like, it was It was nice that the guy who wanted to exploit the land for its resources was not the hero of the story.
and that the people who lived there got to keep living there and and, you know, keep their way of life. And I thought the highlight was probably
donald versus the fish. I thought that was kind of an epic action set piece that would be cool to see Al animation or something.
Yeah. Yeah. I agree.
Yeah. Well said, I think that it it is a surprisingly
progressive
message, at least from Al ecological
standpoint for nineteen fifty seven from someone who is clearly an ardent capitalist like Carl Barks having having created the character of Uncle Group. He he definitely contains multi. Right? Because he is a big proponent of capitalism apart from, like, inventing Scrooge mick doc a lot of his correspondence does, like, make that explicit.
But but he's also very, very ecological minded. What about used to? What did you think of this? I think I think the...
Maybe maybe Barks six flooring that
that kind of push and pull between the exploit capitalism and the
ecological
you know, the the clear benefits you get from preserving the land and having to breathe and stuff. I think there was a really interesting probably
exploration for him because he he goes back and forth and back and forth on it. And and Scrooge never learns anything. He never learned the lesson. He's still like he he just... He just got poisoned and went home. You know what I mean? Like, I feel like that might have been Barks kind of like giving up on a on a way to reconcile those two things. I don't know. Maybe I'm wrong.
No. I I I don't think you should second guess yourself. There. I think that's a really... Like Scrooge is he's he's old and and he... We we see that he's not gonna change his ways. Right? We can tell from all that rare not side of sp william and and every other panel being him taken only by the resources. So, like, it's true. I think Scrooge is, like, too long gone in this story. He's he's pretty much corrupted
as far as this goes, and it's really up to the P guys to to take their own agents see I I like it a lot. I think it's... I... This story doesn't hold up in a lot of ways, obviously.
But but it's it's not means spirited about it. Right? It's more of a time capsule
and anything else.
It is... It isn't it is a really
neat
exploration as you say sue of these this like,
pushing and paul this, like, capitalism
versus land preservation And and he's just written too much Scrooge mick dot. To really come down on the side of ecology, even if we are meant to, like, relate to the Huey, guys behind them very noble. They they just have to do it over here. At the end of the story, we... We're going back to dump. Right? We're buying our comment books.
We're enjoying the fruits of those rare earth minerals throughout the rest of the fifties
and the sixties,
and and that's there's just nothing to be done for it.
So, like, the story has its problems, but this this is well, like, this is very well regarded by Barks stands. This is certainly
among the more famous stories. And and I think there's too much great about it to kind of discount So
we we've talked kind of extensively about, you know, what what is dated and archaic about it. It generally does not hold up very well.
This is not something where he did one of... I'm not aware of him doing any of his famous oil paintings or lift the grass for this one.
I think they're put in some cool. Subject matters from this, like the the sturgeon fight, you know, is was pretty neat. And again, you know, this this would been too problematic to adapt think into a duck
story It definitely
has... The the kiwi guys have been used again by other creators, you know,
Almost never did sequel to his stories even if he did, like, kind of revisit them. So Don Rosa did a direct sequel to this one called war of the When
are more of the win to go
where Scrooge ends up saving the Huey, guys. From
a much more villainous
developer in that one. Mh
I haven't read that one in a good decade. I'm looking forward to revisiting it in my
upcoming don rosa focused
podcast, but that'll be quite some time from now Can I tell you guys that I spinning off to Rosa remarks in a couple of months? No. That's a huge reveal.
Yes. Yes. It's It is a pretty big deal. I'm gonna start doing these bim monthly. Doing these by monthly and doing rosa or Barks.
Bim as well. So, yeah, they they did word of the.
There was another duct creator that did kind of a weird pre story that has the Pb guys
and a character from a Golden Helmet from hundreds of years
before. Alright. And then if we check on the community,
and how they feel about it on Inducks, the site that fans used to find out information about and and vote on the stories
This one does very well. It's clearly very well regarded by the community. It gets a seven point nine out of ten, which is good for rank fifty seven out of all forty two thousand some Disney comic stories. So definitely well regard. Let's see.
Before we wrap things up. Do you guys have any final thoughts or are there any, like, panels that you really that really stood out to you that you'd like to highlight as one of your favorites?
I was gonna point out. I like the one where the the tree that Mcdonald's has wrapped his cord around
finally rips out of the little
that he's on, and and he just... Is in the air mid air
getting pulled out into the lake by the by the fish. It's a good action shot. He's kind of standing on the tree and and bracing against it with the rope. It's... He looks like an action hero. Yeah. No. I I I like this one too. I think all the physical
I think that it holds up really well. I really also like the shot of the pumpkin on the Grappling hook. That's just sailing through the air as is his bait... This fish that's so big. He's bay.
Pumpkin.
Yeah.
You guys highlighted some panels from the
the surge and fight and and it is as you mentioned ryan. It's a great action piece. It's very well, John. It's very strong. I like the one where the surgeon is crunching the tree. He looks terrifying that. And then there's a lot of great panels here. There's some obvious ones like the big splash panel, the pb guys fleeing.
The the one of the, like Airs moves, the false moose is is very ominous and terrifying.
But like every little side of Scrooge kind of catching
himself, right, as he realizes that he's back to... He's he's back on his he's back on his stuff. He he can't help himself. And he he guilt
realizing that is great. I think this one has an unusual number. Of really great panels and it's got a lot of strong art. So so you guys...
This was a really cool story to talk about. Again, it's very deep.
There's a lot of layers to it for a kid's comic, I think.
And I appreciate it. It's also one that, you know, really needs a little bit of processing.
Thank you so much for joining me to process this one. As always listeners can reach out share comments and
follow along, you know, I've got some fun blog type thoughts about these stories that I post on Facebook and some on
Instagram, we're Al Barks remarks on the socials and join us again next week as we cover a pretty exciting Donald Duck adventure called for Forbidden Valley. Can you send us homes sue by reading the final panel of the story, please. Oh, okay. I don't want it. If holding, it hidden piece means I've got to smoke with those kiwi guys. I'll gladly, get it back to the indians. Awesome. Thank you guys so much. Yeah. No problem.