We can have
Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Mc Ducktales writer Al artist of the greatest donald and Scrooge comments of all time. Join us as we explore his longer adventure stories in their chronological
publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical context and how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks. Just a quick technical note. I had a few audio issues with this one. I had a Mike cord that unbeknownst to me was popping in and out a little bit, and so sometimes my nice microphone was my audio source, and sometimes, my lap top, not so ice microphone was my audio source. I I went and adjusted. I could, I think it came out pretty fine. Unfortunately, it's mostly the mic, but But here and there, just bear with it as the audio
does its thing and know that it should go back for the most part. And enjoy the app episode?
Welcome back to Barks remarks. I'm Mark Sever, a Grown man who enjoys com and I'm joined by a couple of other grown men. To talk about a later Donald Inducks adventure, I'm really excited gentlemen because this is one of the
where I get to pair a long time fan with newbie and my newbie today is my brother, Dan Sever. Dan, thank you so much for coming back. Yeah. Absolutely.
So I had you on some time ago for a big top Bed, which
it has some wonderful
mid century art. But other than that, it's kind of a weird one to start out when reading Barks.
So I'm I'm glad to bring you back to one that has more of a traditional narrative. Yeah. I I did enjoy Big talk Battle it was a fun one. It is a fun one. But it's it's kind of a strange almost after thought of a story. But I'm glad you did enjoy it. If I already to be honest, I would say I actually kinda like bit Big Bed. Better. It's... I found a little more action packed, but this one was good too. Excellent. Well, I'm curious to hear what you have to hear about it
and my long time
returning Ducktales
is Warren Harmon.
And warren you and I were just talking about
about how many of these episodes I've gotten to have you on. You're definitely one of my frequent flyers. But... That's great. I've had a a lot of fun and being a long time Barks fan and and Donald duct collector and Disney fan. I mean, I'd say, this is a natural fit for me, and I just enjoyed the conversations and the the research and the the education that you're giving, everybody in the duct community, I mean, with from your Facebook site to the podcast everything it's been it's a lot of fun. So thank you, and it's happy to do it. So it's been great ride. And
and, you know, for Dan too, this this story as Mark said, this this is more familiar territory for Barks. The the worldwide adventure with the nephews,
it it may lack Scrooge Inducks, but... Yeah. That's okay. Right. Yeah. This is kind of a classic iteration.
You you watch Ducktales when you were a kid dan does this kind of feel like it's in the same vein as that? I...
I don't know if you even remember watching.
We were a lot younger.
We had tennessee
Yeah. I absolutely remember watching it.
A lot of the
episodes. I I have trouble calling, but
this one did seem to follow a
kind that classic format of
one thing leading to the next.
I would say. Yeah, it's definitely less slaps stick mayhem ham than the when I previously had you on for. So again, to be official, we are here today to talk about Forbidden Valley, which is a fairly
late Donald Inducks adventure. We don't have a lot of them left to do. So I'm gonna mention a little bit of the Barks around about this story, and then we'll get the narrative for it. But this one was published in the year nineteen fifty seven with a July cover date. It was in donald dot number fifty four. Warren in the thing that struck me about this one when I checked it on index is that has an unusually small number of reprint. I noticed that two mark
you know, if I think the next was almost what ten years later or maybe maybe I'm even mistaken in there, but very small number.
It it it came out at a time nineteen fifty seven. I'm proud to say that's the year I was born. So
that it was created in December of nineteen fifty six, and then finally published in July, I believe a fifty seven. And like you said, and
Yeah. I I think this is one of Barks is returned to form And, again, I'm gonna say it's familiar territory,
I'm kinda of glad he did it and we'll we'll talk a little bit about what works and what doesn't work in my opinion too. Yeah. Yeah. There's definitely a lot to cover.
You're you're right Warren. There was a a big thirty year gap on thirty thirty year. Yeah.
Yeah. Between donald dot number fifty four and the first
reprint and glad stones run. Yeah Yep. I have that one. Yeah. Nineteen eighty six. It's got a pretty cool done yet this cover. So it's rate cover. Yeah, it looks like those were the only two new stand collections. The rest of them were like Carl Barks library and
collection publications. This this a weirdly...
This one just Barks exposure for whatever reason. So So, Dan, I'm curious this one falls into a classic story archetype, the the lost world archetype. Is that something that you are familiar with? Is that something you you enjoy that you're gonna kick out? Yeah. Yeah. It was it was definitely...
It it it wasn't
expected from the beginning that that it would end up that way. So it was it was enjoyable to see without giving any way, how they would... How they ended up Al this lost world and and right. The details of the lost world. Like we said earlier, Dan, you said that there's one one one scene
strangely leads to another seat, and then it leads to another scene and what begins as this sort of quest
to read a neighborhood of a pest
becomes this incredible, but we'll find out journey to the Forbidden Valley. Yeah. Conan doyle lost world cup still life again. So yes. Warren. I'm glad you referenced that classic.
Do you you wanna tell us that our Arthur Conan doyle. Right? Well arthur Conan and Doyle, everybody knows from Sherlock Holmes fame, but also a a the literary genius it his time and came up with a fan full about
beautiful story
of discovery a lost world where ancient
rep reptile existed in modern world. And...
Yeah. It's a it's a great story.
On several movie adaptations have been made. And
we'll get to this, but you know, when we look at nineteen fifty seven when this was created, fifty six fifty seven, and he was probably thinking about it in fifty six.
You're not looking at a lot of movies we're starting to play around with these themes.
There was signs fiction was coming of age the bob with Steve Mc mcqueen was was there. But these adventures to far off lands
were also there now lost Horizon was about two twenty years earlier,
but this is this is in that vein of the great
movies of the of the fifties and maybe even the bible that that were
dry.
Right. And and if you're reading this story decades later, I think that's the important take. That that's the thing to know about it. That's what you're getting is this take on the Her Arthur conan Doyle story? He he is the first guy rather the the first, you know, person who famously wrote about this this archetype, a group of outsiders
journey to a
lost Al where time has stood still for for whatever reason or another. And and and consequently, we're gonna have a story that features dinosaurs.
This is pretty unique warren. This is the only Barks story. Is is that right? This is the only... We had Al
trail of the unicorn that's not quite the same. But we were they stumbled on this incorrectly. But this is the only one that oh with dinosaurs.
Yeah. And so, Dan, the thing about this is this came about obviously a lot long before you and I were kids watching jurassic park for the fiftieth time
This is the like earlier
iteration of pop culture dinosaurs, you know, before Al
had advanced a little bit before Steven Spielberg
kinda of popularized the more accurate or early Al least somewhat more accurate modern take on them. Yeah So what what did you think of the depiction of Dinosaurs in this one dan. I thought they were really cool, actually. I I love the one
that was
giving them a ride. That one was...
I did two.
List the giant
really cool. I I really like that. Yeah. Almost wishing
that it became sort of like a sub character within the story or something,
you know, like a little bit of personality or or Also found myself wanting to see more of that particular dinosaur. Yeah. It's a bummer that it meets a pretty quick
end there.
Yeah, I think that's really important. To keep in mind that this is that archetype of the lost world. And Warren, the other kinda notable bit of Barks trivia about this one is that... I I didn't realize this until I was checking into it, but
we have a pretty significant first appearance here. Right? You do. We do nineteen fifty seven
from the research I've done and and looking back at some of the other
stories of Angus mix Wine
makes his debut in this story. Love the name. E isn't Angus Mc wine in the story is the the pic character is Barks has created as appeared in many stories. Yeah. The pig faced villain, but probably one of our favorite was dialed the milk man and of course, we did that one together and boy, he's a main character Is he dan. Right.
Yeah. Yeah. He's just perfectly emblem of a greedy
do whatever it takes
to to to get ahead. Yeah. That's about him He's always really cut throat nasty ambitious.
It's kind of weird to me how Huey, used him. Right warren. Be because,
he's kind of an anonymous villain. He changes the name frequently. All the time. We're calling him wine here because that's the name that he has the most. Mh.
But like, Barb was totally
inconsistent he would use like, in this one, his first name is connected to the, like the whole guy with pickles clearly. But.
Yeah. He... He's he's not... He's never the same character.
He's just drawn the same. He's his bark like generic papers face to vi. And he's just so nasty.
And when Barks didn't wanna use, like, flint Guam gold or, you know, the the story didn't call for magic. So we didn't wanna magic to spell the other ones to be almost. He just had his go to
generic nasty.
You know, we talked about this being the debut, and I and I and I just want ask you, mark, didn't the great steamboat race with Horseshoe hog come before this though, or am I am I mistaken? Well, I did. But I mean I don't.
Yeah. Worst july is like
very friends
That's he was he was more of the southern gentleman. Yeah. Yeah Yeah.
I'm looking in my mine's memory here looking at what what I I thought I saw Right but I... But I do know the mix line appears later and one of my favorite all time favorite Inducks stories in nineteen sixty six. So call the micro doctor outer space that's my favorite depiction of it. Nice. Yeah. That's a fun one.
I'm gonna I'm gonna run through some of his different names. What sure. I wanted to verify this on index that he was the first appearance.
That this was the first appearance you you can use Inducks to sort by the first appearance. And so this does tell me that here he is as p j Brian,
but he's also been Poor Man.
He's been he's been des sw.
He's been foul Scrooge in crown me.
Scouts nick. John the khan his his micro.
Appearance.
Yes to make the library. He's had a ton of them. I I guess that arguably
in old
California, did have, like, a a flashback
version of this character
I don't know if he's... I don't know if he's similar enough. He's obviously,
like an earlier, you know, Al flash version. So yeah. Inducks doesn't count. So so I'm gonna call it. This is his first official appearance. Office official. That's right. Yeah. And I think Barks played around with the an pig figure too. I mean, he really wanted to see what he could do with another animal. And like you said be the foil
and billing, but I think what he has going for him angus is Mc wine is he's probably one of the minus feelings I've ever met in my life. Sometimes he's said the bigger boys work with him very rarely, but I think But this solo act and what he's doing here, we'll get into the story and maybe comment on some of his
his way would you call it? I don't... I'm
is is vicious tactics to get the
office very under hand you you love to hate. That's right. Alright.
And the other notable thing that I've gotta mention before we get into this is that this is one of the situations where Barks
kind of remake... This is one of his pseudo remakes. He used this story structure once before and his older story called in Barks Africa,
which
you you can probably guess by the title Dan is a pretty
problematic story. We know we've bought I I want you to feel... I'm very curious when we get to that part to get your impression of of how how those you know, depictions have not aged. Have not aged well. Sure. I don't know. Did you find it jarring like, did you just kinda think of, this is part for the course with, you know, a comment look this.
Yeah. I I saw as a product of its time and just
maybe a little bit of just ignorance
in attitudes that people can tend to have
until they
become less ignorant about the world and more more educated about the world. Right. And and you know, we talked pretty about this, how these are just kind of like the the tropes that were just widespread and employment world. It doesn't use it. It's just it's something that we we understand it we don't excuse it.
Barks was born in nineteen o one was he born at nineteen hundred and nineteen o one. I always forget more. But he it Huey, to ninety nine. Yeah. He died in in in August of two thousand. So he was
one to two yeah. Correct. Yeah. So like warren, I think this must have been kind of a period for him that was a little bit. I think he must have had a little bit of of a struggle with creativity me around this time. You've got my three stories. They're pretty close to each other where he does this, he goes back to the well.
I pretty recently recorded an episode for land of the Picnic Inducks.
Which is, like, very close to this one and that that's like a a soft remake of because early storing mystery of the swan. And then, you know, he's got
city of golden and roofs, which is like. Is it coming up very soon, which is again, kind of remake of the land of the tone pole. So he does a lot of this story recycling,
which, you know, I think he makes them different
emails.
But it's it's definitely something you noticed.
I would agree. I I my comment earlier when They mentioned. I he went back to familiar territory it's the same thing you saying, and And, you know, the reader might say, and, like Dan said earlier,
yeah, It was a good story maybe not a great story. But I will we'll we'll we can move through it, but I really think he he struggled a little bit with finding some really out there new ideas. And so I think introducing the loss world element was one way to do that. And certainly, Mc Brian, the character
brought a new dimension to it too. But for me it was
it it was certainly past what you would call the golden era of of Barks. Right. Now. We're still gonna got some classic
not.
Gentlemen, I wanted to I wanna dive into the store itself, but before we do on a pan to our International
international.
Dan, I am just pasting into the chats the with two of the German titles. Would you mind
presenting the German titles after I have lauren
do? Let's see. Warren and why don't I give you the Brazilian title just because it's
geographically the closest to the story setting. There we go. Yeah. We're in the Amazon. Right? So it's appropriate. Yeah. Yeah.
We... We're at the eastern part of South America, and I was at Dan doesn't know this Marked does, but I returned from the Amazon Rainforest and
October, I was up in Ecuador and beautiful and some of the jungle depictions are very familiar. So
absolutely
Al. I'm sorry. Yeah.
Start So here's the Brazilian title. Ave ventura
No,
Roy
Ave ventura, No Valley Pro, sort of venture in the the for the prohibited Valley. A pretty...
For the most part, they were pretty great translations.
What right...
Mind give the german? No. Not at all. I Hope the native German speakers
are too put off by it. But
and crystal, which is the cucumber crisis. So that one cracks me up. Right? It's the the cucumber prices are really the pickle crisis. Right? Because I think we can must be pickle. Mh. Right thirteen.
Which is a great title. It doesn't tell you anything that the story except the the goofy part.
And then I I gave myself french title, which is Mcdonald's
Plural,
and it's mcdonald's war for pickles.
Again, a pretty off one. So so I gotta a kick got it. I gotta kick out of looking account that. Alright, Gentlemen. Are you guys ready to file into the forbidden valley here. We are. All set.
Alright. So
this one has an interesting
start. It's... To be honest, it's kind of a stretch to you guys because it's got donald reading an issue of the doctorate times for the deck Google, I guess.
He's not looking where he's going, and he is wandering through, like, a pretty rural area, where he doesn't seem to have any reason to be just like, I'm mostly reading a news newspaper, to be honest,
and he is reading about how the government is spending another billion dollars to knock out the fruit fly
It's just reading all these Ducktales of, like, the Us government finding
insects in fast infestation, which is definitely something
that, you know, is truthful. Right? This this is something that's constantly happening
Any answer up, he's wandering through either, like, field of prompts or garden and he ends up tripping over one of his nephews,
and he gives off the the head How didn't you let where I'm don? And he asks is matthew what he's up to, he explains that he's looking in the bind for author nose
which are a dreadful
south American
cucumber board that is destroying the Ducktales pickle
prompt. So I usually say you guys that we've got them... I usually call the openings pretty strong. Know that this is the strongest opening he's ever had. It's kinda of per performed to me the it is very funny. Dan your mind reading the little
the little narrator box before the very beginning by far the fiercest battle ever wage is man's battle with Bugs.
And and got this little ferocious looking bug hissing and snorkeling. But I don't know. I... It's it's a fine opening. It's very funny donald trips, but I do feel like this one might be a little force. It seems force, but we have to somehow get to the pickles and get to the cucumbers, I guess it's one way. The other thing is that I feel like Barks has used the bug
theme in other stories too, and he's got one coming up just a year later in gigantic gan and you've got others that he's done, but I... Yeah. I think it's it's it's it's to me, it's a fun way to introduce it. I love. I love that line you said about him wanted to look where Going. I think that's fantastic. I mean, I just backed up when I read that. But... Yeah. It's... Yeah. We have to get there and this is how we get there. And he also
to see Donald
embroiled in reading about the Us government just seems a little far fetched to me, but
Right.
Right. It's a classic dry you in character listening to a reading about the news... Yeah. It was news to me that the the fruit fly was bad enough to warrant
getting rid of. I thought it was good. I thought because he caught... I don't know which were the triplets it is. Him also surprised that for a moment, I thought they were telling Donald like, hey, why don't you look out where you're going? But it turned out to be Donald saying about you look at where I'm going. So Right. I thought that was pretty good. Yeah. It's it's a very funny simple. So we we got the stories from the Matthews pretty quickly what they're up to. They have been commissioned by some local sciences to
catch some of these pickle haters,
and they're gonna get five cents for each one of them, which is, you know, probably fifty five or sixty cents in modern denominator
so not not too bad. And, you know, Donald is is very supportive of this. He decides that he wants to help there there aren't too many of them around because they're just in the early stages of the investigation.
And they allude to how experience
mysterious oh the the pickle orders. I love the name by the way of those
you guys. How they got there and They eventually
do and counter one that's getting ready to drill a acute pump. Dan you Mind telling us about, like, what kind of the bugs, like the what's the bugs specific track. How does that intent?
They basically
drill into it, like, as if it were or
like a modern drill kinda spiking through the crop. And, yeah, this one particular,
when he
when the bug drills into it, he pulls out, like, what looks to be almost like a cork that was keeping in what
some gas from escaping or so. Maybe maybe the the odor from the pickle. It just completely deflate. It's it's very hard to modern. But I I found it very funny.
And I also really like the feature design and Al little, like...
Threatening
in the
the
insects
face. What did you guys think of the Barks itself? I love the bug. I I I and I'd love. I'd love the way it works. So I'd love the look on its face is determined.
It's got the cork Scrooge nose, which it like, Dan said it it... Looks like it's pulling out of court, but the the funny part of it, just not pickle juice. It's it's air or something because it inflate like a balloon and that's that ga logic. I mean, I I like the bug. Yeah. I like it too. I I I think it's kinda cute.
There is. It's it's very threatening working, but it's very funny. So so you guys, they are they've been looking in the vicinity of this old crap building it's called the Nick O'brien can't canon. Yeah. It must be the Mc mcbride Can comp. And there was there's an illusion at some point to have this is where they were first spot and they do start to find more and we get this little taste of some men
Warren, do you wanna tell us about what the mysterious figure the old building does? Right. As the Inducks are are collecting more and more bugs they get closer to the building,
a mysterious arm reaches out or hand reaches out with this cane
and and cracks the box open releasing all of the bugs
back into the patch. Right. And and the man, the unseen seen man acts like it was
mistake, like it was the accident.
Right? Mh And and will you see him looking on
as the docs go try and recover there insects.
And we get this view of him.
We we got a little set up for... We're we're gonna learn that this is Pj o'brien.
I don't know that we get his... Yeah. And he he mentions. It is I. Pj came Provide. Does he
Yeah.
Yep And we got we had reveal from his thought bloom balloon that he is the one who released these
terrible.
And and his plan, his home... His character Barks is motivation hearing you guys it's very silly.
Dan, do you do you wanna tell us what his plan is, he reveals oh, yeah. He
has a...
His Camry, he would pickle
omega, but frankly, I I don't know if I've heard of before. I I don't know that I've Severino worn myself. Yeah. And it... It's it's really
he he really... It it's almost like
mister Barks trying to block out the sun. You know, he wants to
leash an army of bugs to just destroy all of the local pickles
so that he can...
There will be no alternative, but for people to eat his root vegas. Right yeah. That's
clear. That's the whole... That's the whole reason. He's unleashed this
play.
Supply there too does... You know he's got how many how many Barks? Twenty three three million four fifty years.
Huey, lose to having hands them back in nineteen
twenty seven and you can't give them a away.
So you know, the stakes in this one are are are both very high because it's like deadly
a deadly
infestation but also we wheels well. So so eventually, the kids do recover a lot of those bugs and they're on their way to give them to the scientist to sent them to this task.
And and again, out of nowhere,
that man it it was he used his pain, which is gonna be kind of his signature.
Right? He wax the box of bugs out with his chain and
you know, it's very clear that it's on purpose to the that's this point. So Donald pursue them.
The Nephews kinda figuring out he's probably the smuggle
himself
and that they need to go to the sciences and tell them, you know, what happened. But
They do have a little painful Scrooge of luck who warren you wanna tell us about it. Yeah. Yeah. It turns out that the
they wanna go back into the lab until the scientists what happened. And then bug... Actually,
the loan bug takes a stab at donald speak and they take that as an opportunity to box it up and, you know, bring it back to the scientists.
Right. So they've have this... They they've been success even it's just the single. And we we transitioned to the laboratory
for bunch of serious
there is a scientist who is
like, communicating it. He's he's spraying a pest side, and they're
indicating that their worse concern... Your worst Barks are met no known bug sprays will phase him They've got these great nineteen fifties masks on. You know? From that and it... It's in the Department of pathology. I I love the wall. Yeah.
The wall the
fantastic.
Does does anyone know what the actual term is for the study Inducks?
Off of the top your head and.
Yep. Ent technology, that's the one.
I love the little panel where the bug is just staring at the nephew. And it's just like raging Al him it's great. There's
little that's funnier than a a very tiny creature roaring and snorkeling and a much bigger one. And so. But we see mc with me... They see Mc Mcbride actually appearing in the room from outside. He's got the over of there. Yeah. Right. Yeah. He's actually part of the whole operation and kind of kind of an inside job because he happens to be there they got a radio graham that arrived from mcdonald's on the upper
Amazon, which brings hope beyond
basically
that what stand do you wanna tell us about the hope that they've gotten...
Yeah. It's what's it called a... The jungle razor wasp
is the predator they need
to introduce to take care of the infestation of the
hit.
This reminds me dan of that classic up so from the the Simpsons where they go to Australia,
and and
the continent gets overrun
with that animal that Barks brings, they have to, like, figure out a a sequence of progressively bigger animals to address it. The what was it that the came towed? Was it And it's... That's what I thought about and just each one they they introduced just
creates more havoc than the than the last one, and then they have to try and... Yeah. Right. This is back in the fifties when when people thought that they could engineer the environment rather than just be.
But, anyway, they figure out that they need to like, mountain next expedition with this
Brian guys working on the inside. And so he offers to go at his own expense, but of course, this would have been a delaying tactic. And and the scientist to say no, It's gotta be someone anonymous so this bug sm won't catch on. So that's gonna set up the dynamic for the rest of the story where we've got Donald the kid, having the opportunity to catch these wasp.
For for a thousand dollars rather than a nickel apiece for the pickle heaters. And of course, Mc O'brien is gonna be along for the ride to sabotage
Yeah. He's not... He's not too happy that they went to unknown rights. So you guys I really like the
transition to the Amazon. Pretty abrupt. You don't get like a traveling montage or anything like that? But as we transition, we get this just hilarious
panel
definitely one of the stand out panels of this story that is is meant to convey what a dangerous region is it. Dan.
Dan, you mind describing that panel for us? Yeah. Just shows,
you know, just a picture of a River on the Amazon, and it's it's so
ferocious that the the animals seem to be eating each other crocodile is buying another crocodile house tail, and then three
bo constrict are tied around themselves almost
biting each other as if it were one of those
mythological creatures that that is, you know, like, time with it's twin brother and Right. And... Yeah, that's that's that's their way of getting across just how how wild the Amazon is. That it's so wild Dc creatures even even go after each other when I have nothing else to to get. It's so great.
I love it. I I I... When I when I started somebody I saw it, Dan mentioned, the alligator elevator. That's the first thing you see, and then you see the bo constrict eating each other or by Ducktales.
And then if you look close, you see the monkeys kind of having that monkey fight upside out, which is my favorite
thing. And then you take a look and you see the bird peck that alligator on the head while the insect is stinging. It looks like a rodent and door rat on the other. And then you see the little sword fight between the little
sting.
Right middle of the panel. Just so much going on here and, you know,
it it's just wonderful. One of my favorite panels and the little whole story. Yeah. It's it's great. It's one of those panels where you look at it the the longer you look at at the better gets. So you guys the next sequence is basically all about the duct forwarding the river
heading towards the place where those wasp are said to be there's some cool names like
only this and so forth. They got the word. It's it's it's a direct rip off of the scene in in Barks app where there's native that's like communicating via bomb goes and he's learning from a group of people, called the
Inducks
who live near who live near the past and have been Al saying that they know where to find a lot.
And and so Barks
gives the docs that piece of information.
But then has their died run off
because the
Indian
sleep danger. And then
the that's and heading towards that destination
which is all an excuse
for the un seen pj j mcbride to engage in some Sabotage
on the way. So instead, I'm detailing every little bit of that sabotage.
Maybe I'll ask each of you to mention just one of the little parts that the little sabotage moments that you like Sure.
You know, I think the the fact that pj But Brian is has access to the jungle way before they do his one thing. But again, you see the caine here, which I like it. You know, you know that that he's making his it is
stealing the the beats, if you will,
and
that's the last time that they want that to happen, of course, the Inducks, and that that's funny, I think. Mh. Right. And every everywhere look. At some point, you know, he's he's, like, filled their food with castor oil.
He has plants some mine in the river river wrecking bone
He's really s
who he lives memos in there in their canteen. Oh, yeah. And he even took the time to make rag dials out of their blanket. He actually took a scissors and made.
To me, that was just great.
Right. Adding a little bit of insult to injury.
Yeah. And and so the... But probably
the
most vicious thing Huey, does is is one of the cooler sequences
which is that he you you wanna tell us about this this sequence stand. Yeah. He he he awakens some sleeping crocodile
that are
around their boat and first he he he dropped a maybe a a a coconut
on Donald head,
which serves the dual purpose of hurting him and making a loud noise.
Right. To wake up the crocodile
and and that just goes ahead and all he does is just take a a rifle or a shotgun
and just fires it off like crazy just just and start the crocodile
to to to stampede them.
Reminding their boat. He's more vicious here than I've ever seen to and any bill practically because he's actually in my opinion, was like he was trying to kill them. That's. That's how I'm reading it. Yeah. This really is like Barks nasty Go to and, you know, when you wants someone to be genuinely un redeem. This is what he does. And and I haven't even mentioned
his, like really nasty lab that he's he does several times. Barks gives him this really, like very nasal like... Yeah. Yeah. I don't know how you say. I guess did you mind if I give it a shot? Yeah.
I think it's more like yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. I think you're right. I think it's the classic nasal
I think you nailed it. And and it's all in in service of selling is twenty three million terrible
ports Vegas.
So, you know, once he does this crocodile I stampede, which is really cool. This is a great. And I do love that Mh.
He is stolen the docks beads he has,
you know, the only means of barter with the the sticker...
Is that their name? The sticker Onions? Right. This the sticker ride beyond the.
The the sticker tribe. Yeah. So
bryant is looking good. He's he's pretty set. He's solid. But the debts are are just generally in trouble. They have to scatter or avoid some crocodile.
And so be dragging and weary they climb out of the river onto this very suspicious looking dry rock to get their win so they can decide what they're gonna do. And you guys this where the story takes a little bit of a turn. Right? Because as as you mentioned, Dan, this is a very cool feature that is like nothing we've ever seen before in in this story or any other Barks? You wanna describe it for us dan? Yeah. The boys first refer to it as a lizard. It looks an awful lot like a
tri.
It's purple.
It's it's it's...
You know, got a little bit of a combination of a Tri Top with the
s,
large ears that are almost like, like, the shape of an elephant. And I do kinda look like I'll see years I was kinda reminded of those, like,
it pro tops, the one that's kinda like tri, but with almost a f around? Mh but it it's I think it's definitely
supposed to be recognizable as a dinosaur,
and it doesn't really look like any scientifically typically no
right? Mh.
But it's a really
it's very arm kind of
pile.
And and the you know, they they awaken very startled obviously.
And they find that they can't really move because the future looks of issues, but they're
possession on its Barks so that he can't get them. And so they decide to just write it out because he's headed of the way that they wanna go. This is very much reminiscent of what happened in the in Barks Africa
where they were on their way to, like, a valley and they ended up on the Barks of them. Dan, you mentioned that it's this was an elephant in a previous story that Barks has remade basically.
So you guys were approaching the sequence where we counter the sticker Inducks. This is definitely a little off putting. Right? Because we're gonna one of these very pate
depictions of of of a Amazon and arrive. Lauren, do you wanna tell us what Brian gets up to? Well, first of all, he he holds up a picture of the wasp and he, and they're certainly familiar with it
It is kinda of funny when they say You betcha.
That's Al that's a Minnesota term, I guess, I would say. Right? And
So he he... And then they referred to it as the the fellow.
But they know that they are the natural enemy of the pickle haters, and so they're aware of that. So Mc o'brien has found or he thinks he has found the right, you know, native
population to go after for him. But when he offers some beads, he goes no deal. I'm not gonna take care. They're not gonna take the beats because
the wasp spends the winter in, and then we're introduced to the Forbidden Valley there. And the beautiful view, of beautiful artwork there and they don't go there
for all the beads in Brazil. That that's kinda funny. But, yeah. No. Mc brian's
at least for now, he's he's kind of, you know, you know, he has to make a tough to decision here. He's in a bit of a pickle. He's in bit above. And that was another thing too. Pj, they Pickle juice. Pickle Juice mc mcbride. I mean, that's also came up with. So I... Yeah. That's that's exactly what I was thinking. Right? Okay pulls
pickles are bronze and you yeah
be pickle
Dan what did you think of this very
depiction of the quote sticker Inducks. Well, I don't know if it was earlier, but I found interesting that
they have one native group
go searching for another native group and native group a is almost like four and eight group b.
First natives are, like, more, I guess, assimilated into the general population And... Right. Yeah. They're guy. Yeah. Most Mo. Yeah. What that we. Oh, the they're they're they're fearful of
tribe. They're completely wild to the tribe. They... Right. So it's a good storytelling technique because it increases the fear, it rashes it ratchet up the dr. It doesn't really hold up well in terms of how we understand the these groups to be, but... But it is a classic storytelling technique. So our dreadful villain brine, nor off away from the village. And then kinda has the epiphany that Huey, doesn't actually need to catch the wasp. All he needs to do is prevent the Inducks or anyone else from getting to them. So basically, does that by commissioning the locals using beads. Very condescending,
everything about them is very pate,
You know, they talk in a very childish manner.
I appreciate warren that you didn't like read their dialogue
like Them jumbo.
And like, why are they speaking english obviously?
Right right. So anyway, you can miss them to attack the Inducks on with arrows.
And he thinks he has he thinks he's got it made.
And then Al the that step close to Forbidden Al, they they came themselves that they need to
actually call the
for a help seems like a little bit of a weird plot, you guys, that all of a sudden are not really fearful
of this.
Oh, especially when their their former guide had worn them about that them. And so I I find it Al little bit hard to swallow. But you know, it's... It's it's a team to make them aware that they're there. Right. So, of course, the only thing that saves them from this trap. Is the
and and O'brien are rightfully fully terrified what they call. A dragon lizard from forbidden theft So right they just all kept and run. Guys, this is a pretty cool sequence I sure wouldn't blame anyone for being
afraid of this genuinely
training feature. Well I Also just say I I did Al little research on the term Dragon and Lizard, and there is that
one real existing animal where it has that sort of bill
by thermometer?
You have the monitor kind of or the Yeah. And so it's... It it... But they... There it's a reptile known as Dragon
Are not found in South America. They're in Australia and Asia they. But that's okay. I mean, I take it is just like that. That's just the sort of the Indian lingo. Right? That kind of like a bug you know, native of speak. Most. Yeah. Yeah. You're. I never thought of it that way, but that that makes sense now that they would have just put those words together. Yeah. Yeah. That's fine
Okay.
But a great animal. I'd like Dan said earlier just the design and the
introducing elements of of other pre
reptile, I think, is is really fascinated Right. How do you think dan? But those
both and arrows that that
Mc O'brien tells them to use against it. To clearly I have no effect on it. Oh, I thought it was funny when Nick Mcbride. After that fails, he
says... But by Vinegar,
I'll see that you never delivered them.
I thought the by vinegar was a pretty funny, pretty funny phrase.
It is. It's it's very them manic consistent. He's a a pickle man through and through or at least a pickle be man. Now we might mention that the creatures is basically like Al already made fork, which keeps them safe from the bows arrows. But again,
Mcbride is is real dillon. He
they may have gotten through into the valley that they gone through. That is a classic lost value. Guys we got. So we've got one way and one way out, we've got this really tight little ecosystem, and he threatens them human metal
you pests. And I can't seem to stop you from getting to the wasp. But my vinegar see that you never deliver them. As the line you mentioned and
step on there he's he's gonna stop. He wants to kill him. No idea. We get that nasal villain laugh again. And so they enter the valley. Dan Tell us about their first view of. Well, it's a lot bigger than it looked from the outside.
Got some just dinosaurs.
Bro
and
some
tea wrecked and little s sources.
They're they're all just
They look fairly peaceful. Not the... I mean, they're they're they're spa a little bit, but it's nothing like with the the bo constrict and the alligator in that one previous panel. That's true. It's it's less violent than the quote regular animal. So you guys the the thing that makes that always
makes me sad about this trope which which I love. I I am a dinosaur movie guy. I love lost Al. I love the whole idea of them. Filled with Flo and fauna lost to time. But but the sad thing is that they just... They fall apart under scrutiny.
If you know anything about biology
and environment and ecosystems,
There's just no way that,
you know, a small Al
or,
like, a lost island like Skull island in in the King Kong universe could support the kind of mega fan that I just I just love to see in this kind of story So it ultimately just makes me a little bit sad that this thing is is is
There's just no getting around the fact that it's total nonsense. Yeah. But as far as forbidden Al go this sum... The the do counters
and encounter with the dinosaur is pretty awesome that this scene. I'll I'll tell you guys. I I remember this story with a lot of fun. This. And I was I was really looking forward to revisiting it. And and when I went back to this scene, I was I was a little bit let down. I'm I I I had to kinda take a back and think to myself, you know, since reading this, originally, I've watched
jurassic Park movies and this and that. Oh.
So we're this this really is still pretty spectacular just despite what I said. Ted tell us about the encounter with the T rack. But well, the whole sequence leading up to up to the close ups shots, so is... Is probably some of the three or four best arch pages that Carl Barks.
Created for this story. I think he had a blast drawing these. So moving into the Forbidden
Valley into that wonderful
which, you know, it's funny you said that because I had a memory of this panel being a lot bigger,
and it it isn't, but it's it's still wonderful.
But then as they they move through,
the Inducks want to do everything to dis mount, they're armor,
the bearing animal, they're taxi, if you will, to get off. And then, of course, we see the
the der
beautifully drawn very traditional
going after them. So it's just a wonderful sequence.
Savage
and escape and
just the Ducktales surviving. You know, it's it's almost amazing that they did survive. Yeah.
Dan, what do you think of this Dinosaur... The the rack sequence?? Yeah. I I liked it.
It's just it's very clear what he's doing because every kid who knows about dinosaurs knows about the rex. It's kinda like the first major dinosaur you learn about. And it just sticks with us all the way through adult. So the t rex is just always symbolizes just like danger and and ferocity, and it's gonna kill you. How are you suggesting that he's hand to his kid readers here?
I am. Yeah. Yeah. I the the t rex always the bad boy, the Dinosaur pack, you know, the... Yeah. Leather jacket
Hood Yeah. Mh. Mh. Yeah. Like like Al all honesty for a story where the payoff is a valley full of dinosaurs. We don't really spend all that much time with them. To be honest. You gotta hit this with the t reps right away. And it's it's it's a pretty cool attack and as you say warren it's it's pretty
narrow escape. They hide in a in a hollow tree that seems very sturdy. And
unfortunately, for the die, and and conveniently for the story because Barks seems to want to wrap it up. You you may have had a count here the the three
is full of some loss, which do turn out to be the razor wasp. And Al
as the t rex bash into treating it flushed out and they attack the t rex and
donald comments, those wasp there's so tough they make even dinosaurs
scout
and and I'll say it's not the most anatomical correct looking drawing or the T reps. The bottom right one there with the the t mask kind sleep in.
But again, Al
has come long way since nineteen fifty seven. And he's from my wasp as well. So
it was definitely in line with, like,
one million bc.
Yeah.
I guess that would have been a little later wouldn't it. I'm trying to think of the old re house
dinosaur room. Yeah that was about sixty nine or seventy
that was in that area. Yeah. Al of the Gu, was that that around this time? I don't know. That's a good question.
So, anyway, we've got an neat little sequence where Donald
tell us about the resolution work. Well, you know, the the the wasp
seem to be gathering in a bunch here So his strategy was to take the
the box that they've been carrying in his hat. He had it under his hat. And to...
I'd love the paddle where they look at him in anger almost, but he's got this look at his face as the these stared them down. He's staring down the bugs the Wasp rather. And then he leaves out, and catches all of them in... But what he thinks is all of them in that box closes it quickly. And then, of course, we get another loan bug that that gets him.
We get we get a a literal comic sting. Tom sting nicely put. Yes. Yeah. That little sequence, I I could really imagine Barks doing in his time as an animated, you know, story board artist. It felt like one of his cartoon doing story Barks in the early days yes.
And then, Dan, you wanna tell us about the sequence where the nephews figure out the thing with the sound and how they use it for their escape from Forbidden Valley? They they they take
they fashion
tools where they use the the wasp that make a wasp like sound.
But they... They're bow
that sound like giant Boss in order to scare off the dinosaurs,
you know, they're they're... They're terrified of these little insects.
Right. They're very very afraid of them Have you... You were you guys familiar with bull?
No. I wasn't. I did a little research and they are they are this, I guess, handmade made
tool or... What would you call it, Barks? I had... It's a it it it simulate the loud roaring buzz of a deep deeper, and I've I've heard them, but I can probably call it an ancient rich music.
Just off the top of my head, not not consulting with wikipedia or anything that. Yeah. Like, almost a spiritual
sound that would either call the spirits or or Yeah. Apparently it was using a lot of ancient. That that's pretty neat. That was definitely the the thing I learned from this story. Pretty creative solution. Yeah. I was big they would reference the junior Wood chuck guide, book but they didn't. But I figured that's sure they got from anyway, maybe. Who knows?
Yeah. Seems like a missed opportunity you. So basically, as you might fact what they're doing with these bull aurora is circling behind all the animals of the valley and and gradually trying to lead them towards the past. So they start to flush the dinosaurs
out toward the entrance exit of the valley.
And and Barks does this do neat perspective switch here where he takes this out to Mc Mcbride who's just waiting out at the past.
Just wicked mu over his next step when the dust come out. Now we get an ominous
rum.
And we've get the big stand out panel of this story. Probably the one that most people are are gonna remember if they think back
on this story, it it is the Dinosaur
stampede.
Where
as Mcbride says, this is the most and, you know, you you can't go wrong
with a dinosaur stampede.
As as far as an action set piece goes, it's it's hard to disappoint your reader with something like this. As one of my favorite panels again, we're getting back to his love of drawing these dinosaurs and where we saw them in that Do Valley.
Now we're seeing them in this great splash panel where they're they're just running and and stamped and and and we get to see the scale. I don't know if it's accurate of Mc Bryant to them, but
it's just very dramatic. And you keep hearing the buzz of the you know in the background. I think it's just absolutely fabulous drawn. Yeah. What do you think Dan? Yeah. Yeah. I mean, they're absolutely panicked I I enjoy seeing
the s.
It's one of my favorite dinosaurs.
Always has been. And
But, yeah, the the the dinosaurs have just... It's funny because real life dinosaurs so to speak.
Wouldn't look as
Al. Like, the the the the faces on these dinosaurs look worried and troubled
and showing like pressing. Right? Yeah. Yeah... They're not just
running in on auto pilot. I mean, they're looking back at the bugs they they clearly are intelligent enough to
follow them. They see... Follow the bugs with their eyes, they look just just downright scared and human like what what what people would look like if they were afraid. Right. A little less, like, animal than you might sometimes drop. You guys are...
You guys I remember when I read this one, I compared it favorably
in in my kid head. So the similar scene from
Where it's this massive elephant stampede
instead. And it is just the t, right? That dinosaurs
and a dinosaur stampede is inherently cooler
than an elephant stampede. So, like, for me, mentally, it just it just stood out that naturally the dinosaur
must have been much cooler much better than the elephant arc. But
now now that I look at it in the context of doing this
doing this podcast and just with the knowing a little bit more about line work and comic Barks.
It it's pretty undeniable that the elephant stampede peed
is
vastly
superior our in terms of at least to the drawing the the artistic skill. Then the Dinosaur one
it's definitely worth taking a moment here to show you if if it doesn't take too long. I'll have to look it up later too. I would love to compare the the stories. First I'll go back after the... This episode recording and and review Barks stafford again, as as I said earlier out here. This is handy. I'm gonna just share this with you guys right now. I found
someone is set up a little side by side.
Of course, it's the guy It's it's Geo x from the dot comic review,
which a great blog about Disney comics, mostly a lot of barb and other stuff. So his dot com reviewed. He's got a little side by side comparing the two panels. Bear with me jen, and I will send this over in through the chat. Oh, wow. Oh, yeah. Making it a little bigger.
So so look at that.
My I'm gonna say again, the the
the artwork and from in africa is just to me now it looks dramatically superior. But what what do you think we're on? I'll I'll take a stab at it first. I fault... I've I've seen this comparison for the first time
and I totally agree that the Elephant stampede has so much more drama so much more action
and I love the depth of field of the of the horizon it goes all the way back and you've got... You've got this data on it just both are are dramatic, but... You can't compare the two though the stampede is
superior. Dan I know you haven't encountered the other story before, but what's your impression of it? No. I agree with you guys, and it's It's much more scary than the dinosaurs dinosaurs almost look feeble.
Yeah. In comparison to the elephants.
Yeah. They kinda look a little bit tooth plus little harmless. The the elephants are really are much more much more imposing which more intimidating. So yeah, Don't give me wrong. It's still a very cool sequence but Barks was clearly going back to the well for this one. But I will say both in both cases,
the animals the reptile and the elephants,
the dinosaurs, they have absolutely no regard for the figure in front. They are stating they they really don't care what happens and Al, of course, in in Forbidden Valley, that's the last scene we see in Forbidden Valley is that big splash panel. Before we see a little bit of a time jump. Right. Yeah. Let's let's go for it. Let's go ahead and wrap this up because we transition to the Ducktales having successfully gotten the wasp and they allude to Mc Mcbride being trapped in the hospital
back in Q Vista. But clearly against Ducktales orders, he has at the end smashed his way out of his hospital room to follow them and and use that cane one last time
to knock the wasp out of that box.
And just generally be a jerk. And warren you wanna wrap it up for us, talk about Brian's celebratory dinner Absolutely.
Bandages and all, but Brian is now in the restaurant
with a fancy waiter, and and he's he's ready to order a good meal. He wants the finest meal that they have at the restaurant.
That the the image is so funny anyway just with him all bandage up. But he's he's he's claiming victory. That's the key.
And
they have these great appetizers he wants something z.
He puts it in his mouth says it's absolutely horrible. Just this great on his face
turns out that it's a pickle route Vegas in Your. And core of cover
his he's disgusting
And he he he realizes that this is what he wanted, but I... He didn't realize that they were
a botched batch. I love that line
Yeah. So he...
Again, again his bandages
runs away from the table. And there he is. He's after those those wasp. Donald can't stand it anymore. But he says, no. No. I'm I'm
I'm not doing any more damage, guys. I'm here to help you catch the wasp. So that's the closing panel is he's joining them now to you could care less about his twenty three million jars of right. Because it's the very
or it's not much of Al. Like it's gonna be a market
market flop clearly.
So so, you know, that's that's
kinda reminiscent of the end of in Barks africa where there's like, a little bit of a
between the Ducktales and the huge jerk that's been
in competition with them again over an insect in in in Barks africa was a a very rare butterfly,
But. Yeah. Definitely Al lot peril between these two stories
deliberate. So so that's it. That's the end... It's it's a bit of a silly It's not the strongest ending to my eye. What did you think of the conclusion there dan? It was really
abrupt.
And I remember in the other one, I read,
they Big Taught Bed.
Mh.
The villain, you know, we get... We get more of a
that comes over to the right side. We get a... We get a a little bit more, like, a few panels of that story. This is literally just two panels. You have to... Like, one has to be able to infer that he's catching the wasp
in order.
It just says I'm I'm gonna help you catch the wall. It doesn't
infer in any way that the reason he wants to catch the wasp is So they can after Al have them
get the
the heaters.
This one just be very abrupt.
I agree with you. It did strike me as very abrupt It says satisfying in a way because, you know, it's as silly as the whole overall setup is. So it's proportionate to that. But it's ultimately kind of a small scale story for one that involves like a a hidden Al full of dinosaurs. That's a good way to describe it, Mark. I would say the same thing. I when I finished this, remembering some of these wonderful... The artwork and the panels. And, again, I hadn't really red Barks Africa, but it just seemed like a a mediocre story. It was just it it was okay. I would I wouldn't call it great. Yeah. And clearly, it's time to give our overall thoughts and reflections as you have been warren. I agree. I was I was just a little bit disappointed in this one. I'm I think it's a find story.
I Think it's a perfectly serviceable Barks story, but maybe it's just some of the that down from
my memories of this one as a kid. I still enjoyed it, but I I was definitely
surprised because I expected it to compare favorably
to to
Barks Africa, which honestly is like some really unfortunately vicious stereotypes and and is probably wanna bark most
means spirited
Adventure stories. And is just one that I I generally felt a bit uncomfortable
returning to but like like the sticker certainly not handled the best in this, but they're not... They're definitely less offensive character and the overt
can
locals
in that one. That one, I think has aged
particularly
poorly for Barks stories. But... But, again, I I I was surprised to find that I I do think now that it compares favorably to this one. Just at least in terms of the overall art and story. But I I do still enjoy this one it's always a treat to c dinosaurs like, you know, you know, especially Al earlier depiction of dinosaurs
before jurassic Barks change the whole game, it's just necessarily gonna look like a little bit of a time capsule. Since that just totally altered how we think of them. What about you, dan? Yeah. I mean, it was enjoyable.
The other couple of ones that you've had me read,
I liked a little bit better
I never thought about what you said where he was just convinced that his his Rh vegas would be a flop. I just kinda got the idea almost like I'd... Life's not worth
living without, like, a good pickle. You know, like, Right. Here's I make money if there's no pickles around eat. I think your take is probably right think that's supposed to be the comic beat, sort of a silly. Oh, no. They're so gross. What if I done? I was just gonna say if there's one redeeming quality to the story and that's the introduction of Angus Mc wine starring Al pj j Nick O'brien.
And this over the top Villain. I mean, who's ridiculously funny. You use the word solely. That's exactly how I describe the ending. I described the beginning. Some of the sequences as Silly. So there's this comedy, then you bring in this
incredible
adventure and this lost world references. So it's really lot going on here.
Maybe a little dis, but but I... But I do... I think Mc O'brien is the redeeming quality to the story for me. Yeah. Like that, how you referred to him as now. Her that that is kind of the way to think of him. Right? He's almost like a featured player
who's mixed wine as so and so. Definitely a notable character creation and lot
creators are gonna go on to use him. So you guys we've kinda covered our perspective on this stan, you've you're a newbie. So, you know, you're
necessarily gonna have kind of a different perspective on the. I do always try to be conscious of the fact that every story is someone's favorite. So... So, like, there there's certainly a lot to like about this when I don't wanna sound too down on it. And as a kid, I remember really enjoying the Hey, I think worry your about right. You know, this is pretty much an average
fine Barks story And if we check Inducks, we're fans and users can rate these story, as well as get lots of very useful information for their hypothetical podcast
We'll find that this story has a seven point six out of ten, which is good as of now for number two hundred and twelve out of all forty two thousand some
stories that are rated. And of course, the Barks stories get. They're they're usually positioned well near the top. And if you break out all of the Barks adventure stories and look at it compared to those, it falls pretty much in the middle of all of those. Okay.
As you might expect. Was gonna ask you that, I'm glad you you mentioned that because I know you've done your research to kinda break them apart from that whole index
my very very ne success Oh, I I think it's wonderful, but I think that's where it would fall in the middle because they have some high points, I wanna say it has any low points But the fact that he did kinda repeat the story from Africa One element that makes you think that I'm gonna try it different and I'm gonna try some new
newer phenomena, like dinosaurs to to get the kids in this time. So, yeah, I think there's a telling here. It's okay, but it's... I mean, I I would actually say that it has a few low points. I mean, there's no some There's some parts that feel a little bit per fun a little brief. Yeah.
Some stuff favorites it's seems like it happens because it's just supposed to happen.
It always bothers me when characters don't bog and just express amazement at seeing dinosaurs.
Right. Like sure the Inducks were impressed, but I feel like I need a little bit more conversation. From the junior wood Barks about how we're we're the first Inducks to see real dinosaurs
etcetera. I missed that too, by the way. I I had a note here on my my my notepad that said, were they not overwhelmed at the right person living humans to ever lay their eyes in score. I guess we're being
pate
now because, of course, the the sticker
Would have been the first to see them. But but the first outsiders. Right? I Al I can think of is it's just overall, he felt a little bit rushed. You know, he needed the crutch.
Of doing a remake for whatever reason around this time.
I could used a few more pages of the valley itself, you know? That's the big draw this for. I'd say like the art in the river traveling sequence, the
was was pretty cool. It was nice, but I don't think I needed so much of sequence compared to, like, spending more time in the Al itself. So
I think we're we're just about ready to wrap up. Couple couple more things.
I I I'll note that this this has never been adapted to duck
other than the fact that Ducktales is definitely had sort of dinosaur lost valleys. Of course, as we mentioned, other creators have used mixed wines
many many times
Don Rosa did do a a pretty notable
direct sequel to this one. You kinda tied it together
with an element from a spice detail, but was mostly a sequel to this one. I believe was a pretty late story of his. And and Rosa
really
kinda leaned into the dinosaur
stuff, which I think was a good decision. Boy I reread that in advance this one. I found that one a little bit tonal weird. To be honest it's not one of my favorites of his, but it did do some really cool like, king kong referencing and stuff. He he clearly had a lot of fun with the dinosaur aspect of it and some references.
Does that anyone have a favorite panels that
that they didn't get common on that you'd like to highlight. There are two panels that we didn't really comment on that I I do like and the one is mix wine
staring at twenty three million quarts of pickled Root to vegas because I I just... I just love the visual there. It's like the wine seller that he should have, but he's Gottfredson bag is in there. The other one that I really did like, and you talked about the boys not and the that's just not being odd by the dinosaurs, but they
when they discover them when they go through the Al, and then you see the two nephews, I love the two nephews are just kind of opposite one. This is colossal being in Lost world with Dinosaurs. There's the wonder. And then I just love the other one. I'm just too scared to enjoy. And I love the look on his face. So that's It's a little panel, but it it says a lot. Warren I'm glad you mentioned that Can panel. I think it's a good on to highlight even in this story of a lost world filled with a Dinosaur. There's a couple of really nice storytelling touches in it. You know, first, it's got, like, cob webs, spiders indicating how long it's been kind of moth. And the isles are listed
twenty two a. Twenty four a know, if if the aisle have both numbers and letters, that's giving us an idea, Just we up fast,
warehouse
full sold,
disgusting really the yeah. So
neat story to me by heart. I'm gonna go with one of the really obvious panels even though we did talk about it. But that that panel with the wildlife
fighting itself is just hilarious. And I love it. How about you, dan? Did any panels catch your eye? Let's see.
The one where
they're standing on a branch
and
the rex first grabs that branch
to eat them. It was it was a little scary. It it almost looks like he's going to chop bit by bit at that brand.
Until
the the the Ducktales on the end of the of, and
they just fall into his mouth and he me choose them to pieces.
I agree. I'm really glad you chose that one because that that is like a really good one. Maybe one of the scariest panels that Barks is done in in some time.
Excellent. Well, gentlemen, I think we've covered this really effectively, so I I really appreciate having having both of you join me. I hope listeners will come back as next time we get to cover the fantastic river race And, you know, check this out on the socials, Facebook and Instagram under Bark remarks. Keep an eye out
because in a couple of months,
sister podcast Rosa remarks
will be starting up covering in a similar manner many of the Don Rosa stories.
And we've mostly
as long as I don't forget to do it, been closing out to the episode by reading the dialogue from the very last panel. So Dan, if you don't mind going there, and I'll let you have last word. It's not the best closing line this issue, but but but this is my stick and I'm sticking with it. I'm not here to do any more damage Inducks. I'm here to help you catch the wasp.
Excellent. Thank you for that, and thank you to Warren and Dan both for joining me. Thanks for having me. I'll look forward to the next time. Thank you, and Dan great to meet you. Thank you again, Mark.