We have
Hello, and welcome to Barks Remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comics of all time. This episode is a ten page podcast, all about one of his short stories. Get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Welcome come back to Barks remarks, I'm Mark Sever a Grown man who still loves duck comic books, and I am joined this week by two other ground men
gonna
mention them and have them introduced themselves. I have got both Patrick block and Warren Harmon
returning, Patrick, why don't you introduce
yourself and tell us please about your most Donald Inducks
Job. Well, I'm Patrick Block,
disney the artist for the past thirty years, primarily da. And my most donald like job probably was assistant manager of the shoe store. First got out of college, and
Carl has so many jobs himself. And he was here, he could say that to the chicken farmer, if they looked on the rail right most sorts of tedious manual jobs, just like thing that she says
Had the deal with people and give Al kind of gag situations at this that naturally right themselves so that's. So I can figure and see where that helped
regular and jones. For sure
I could definitely picture a a donald duck story where he does that. How about you were? Yeah. Warren Herman. I'm a I'm Al long time Barks collector,
reader of Comics collector lit those and lit graphs and
all around Inducks fan, I've got quite a collection
that I started over fifty years ago. So, you know, when I'm Al little depressed, I just pick up a ten pager and all always is right in the world. Right?
Nothing else? Oh, absolutely.
And I have such a blast reading these stories. And when it comes to jobs, all out of out of high school in college. I did everything that Donald might have done. I was a parking lot attendant. I was a dishwasher. I know there some dishwasher jobs. I did a lot of gardening and landscaping.
So I can imagine donald doing those jobs, but probably my career and Al a manager kinda leads me to those
aspirational duck... Donald Ducktales of big a manager And those are some of my favorite stories because he wants to be in charge that those are the fun ones. And so I did that for many, many years and now happily retired and enjoying my collection. Mh. Excellent. Yeah. We we'll get to talk about a man
one today. As from my part, you know, I was I I I managed a blockbuster
video for a hot minute. So definitely not a duct type job
since that industry didn't exist. During that era, but
again we delusions of managerial
Grandeur. And then I I had an ill advised summer where I was just security
guard for
at my college.
Pretty.
So I I can definitely imagine Donald getting up to some good hygiene in that kind of role. And of course, gentlemen, the reason that we are talking about jobs is... Because this is one of our ten page podcast episodes where we're gonna do a package deal, we're gonna talk about some very
specific
stories. Lasted ten pager where Donald had us certain job of one kind or another. And by extension, we're gonna talk about Donald jobs throughout the com.
Because, you know, this is this has been a great storytelling telling device that that Barks and other creators have used. Right patrick. Yeah. I think that's so much of across ten pages based on Severino everyday like the stuff that everyone does. That's why there's so many jobs to because the naturally
longer with go through all of that jobs and all different people have had
not jobs to people hate, you know, we mcdonald's had those at one point or another. He always aspire to something better. It's a better lot life, but his personality gets in line Although is really hard. And these jobs really allow the reader to become relatable to the stories into the... You know, to... You know, whether they're said in the home or said in a museum or us store or
airplane. People relate to those those areas. And and the all of a sudden it becomes a little bit familiar and it's just a great story only vehicle. Yeah. That was Al about... I I think that word relatable is key. Right? These these are very relatable.
Everyone feels that pressure to earn a living and a paycheck. I'm sure a lot of kids and and young adults reading this had some of the same motivator that Donald did and anything
that is as long running as Barks, you know, for for how many hundreds of stories he did. It kinda reminds me of, like, the Simpsons. Is this like, incredibly long running show or or the Flint stones back in the day, You know, the you're almost forced,
I think as a creator to turn to that kind of storytelling
device and And after a while, it it almost gets a little bit ridiculous. Right? Because you can point to how many careers can we point to donald having or Barks Severino a good example of
how this how long car was in top the find story November forty seven. And the hotel story is for November fifty seven ten years later to in those ten years in, both stores are absolutely masterpieces.
Top notch stories. But for ten years, he he has this like tremendous tremendous amount of work that's beyond just to my other
storytelling.
It's.
Yeah. That's a great point, and that's very fitting that we've got that ten year span. Issues by accident it should. I should
articulate the specific ones that we get to talk about today. Right? So you mentioned the fire story that's gonna be like our featured
story because I think we widely
agree here in this podcast that it's it's an absolute
gem. Mh Yeah.
I think I think most of us... I think all of us think it's it's among the tops of his ten pages. I love it. Agreed. You're perfect. Yeah. It's icon. You know, I think... There's a reason that it was one of the covers for the carl Barks
the the library,
you know, And it it just... It stands out. It's it's a common masterpiece.
We're also gonna be talking about
the Stag moore Springs
hotel story, which I think might have originally been called the hotel manager. Yeah. Didn't have a name
don't think it's voice calls concerned what site my are That makes it very identifiable. And and this is just that's a good one to talk about for a few reasons because it's a very kinda conventional donald tries to master.
A story. I... It has it has a couple of other Barks Severino elements in there because we've got like a disguised dunk Scrooge and nephews along for the help. So it's like a good
essential Barks. Story.
I think it's fabulous like drugs so is lot going on, that can be drawing and the panel. Which one of them most interesting of the ten page job stores just because it's such a variety and things for long that hotel. And the fact that centered on that hotel I was enjoyed stores, where use the same location. And you see the location from different angles like the old castle secret. And see the castle We're not hotel, be really concentrated on Al one location all takes place that. It makes a very cool. That's true. Yeah gives the... Even though it's a short story yet, yeah gets to be really lived in. And then for our third story, you've got a little bit of a wild card. This is kind of a personal favorite. We're gonna we're gonna cover Donald the milk command where the mill command story, which took a long time to actually get published because it was a originally rejected.
And and it's a pretty odd role and, you, and a odd story in a few ways that we'll get to talk about. This is like, the mid seven days when that first appear? Yeah. In Europe, and finally a occurred in the in the European comic, and I'll tell you, Barks, you know, I I I a tough time finding out Al my collection. I finally found it in the G Al
yeah.
Place
in this special issue of walt Disney comments stories. Okay. It's expired fifty. I think that was its first American
publication
outside of that. Okay. So here's what we're not talking about. Right. There there are dozens
of jobs stories, great ones. We'll definitely do, like, a round table at the end where we can talk about some of the other ones. The ones that we're talking about are kind of a range of like, careers,
volunteer.
I mean, technically, Fire Mcdonald. He's a volunteer fire. So it it... Maybe it doesn't fit perfectly, but it's the excuse for this episode because kinda job yeah. The job
And then there there is a a specific class of job stories that I'm pointed not talking on. Because our next episode is gonna be a similar one all about the brutal mastery
stories that Barks did. And this is that's the special class of job stories where Donald just absolutely
masters
a a career, usually a really weird one. And then things go
wrong at the end.
And I love those specific ones. I already I already had an episode for the master for Rain maker, which is the all time greatest of those stories, but we'll we'll get to talk next week. Next episode about the master. Rain... I mean, sorry. The master rec, the mass remove and the master glass and a couple of others that kinda
sorta of fit in. So we can we can mention them if we if anyone wants to in the course of this episode, but they do get their own due in in that. So gentlemen, we should get right into this. Right? Because we have a lot say, let me give a little bit of the kind of lead up to Fire donald, which is gonna be our...
Again, our featured story. I'm gonna give some of the background
information
So Fire Donald mcdonald is our earliest story as mentioned.
You you noted that it was published in the cover date it was November of nineteen forty seven. This was published in Walt Disney Comments and stories number eighty six was its first print in the states in the Us. It only has six printing. That's that's actually kind of odd to me. Hasn't been printed as many times as I would expected. And it's very highly regarded Inducks. It gets a seven point five which is good for two hundred and eighty four out of all forty two thousand
and that's a great. So gentlemen, we're gonna... We're gonna go ahead and alternate
if you guys are down for it. So Fire Donald opens up with a page that has so many of these jobs stories will is gonna establish
what Donald is doing this issue. He is in the process of responding to
the the chief of the fire department and accepting a role as a new member of the volunteer
fire department.
Donald is shred his stuff a great pose and the nephews
are
very excited for him and either to join up
themselves. But Donald,
ko blocks them from rushing out the door. Telling them that I'm gonna read this quote because it's great. He says don't be silly squirt only big strong men are wanted not microbes like you. Go play with your toys.
And so the Donald walks out with the Nephews left to play with their toy fire truck and and spare that, you know, they can fight little fires, but but, you know, one day that chance will come. When the page closes out with Donald,
returning in his glorious
firefighters hat, wielding and apps,
and and informing the nephews that he has been made the first husband on the latter truck... A position of gray honor. And and we're gonna get the first
instance of this
running line, which is gonna be the story great kind of common rhythm, and that is lucky
lucky,
lucky from each of the nephews.
A very strong opener any any thoughts gentlemen? Well, lucky lucky lucky business isn't just comic thing that runs to the store. It's also the time at the end of the store that brings you back to again. It's sends the hotel store. Hotel story has the monkey stopping the
into the to the bin at the end of the first page. Very end of the story is back to pounding the the potato and back to the beginning. To both of those job stories have that end the first page thing that runs terms that turns the whole storage in circle, which is the things that makes both of those stories match
Other thought I had reading this from nineteen forty seven is that this might be the introduction to this... What bookmark You've I've talked about is this mass gill. This I big strong man kind of thing that he showed off in the Golden helmet and and I just think this is I neat it a little introduction to only I can do this infants, you must stay back and play with your toys. He is definitely putting himself into his own self important category and just setting everything up here and
my favorite panel is m five. It's where they are playing with the toy trucks, but this is the fore foreshadowing that is done so brilliantly. Because that panel says everything. If you know the thirty, that's right. And I love this story so much, but I was dogs the first comment that I ever collected the around search out as always Al opposed to something that grandmother bought you reyes can't does this particular common. The first comic book where I collect sort cluster. Right.
No was a really special come from definitely place of one or. I think as we go through this one, it's also so important to think of it as, like a wish fulfillment story. Right? Because this is this is almost more of a nephews story than than a donald story. This is
Kinda appeal so strongly to the young readers. Alright attached the second page they pun away the lucky lucky lack again two times more as installments
describing what he's going to do the first signs of alarm like grab my axle and dash to the firehouse. Send the ride the truck to the phone. Lucky lucky before five, this is one of my favorite Barks of the store. Before we fire I attend, I get a brass metal and with every app terrorism
I get Al little sober nozzle with gold hell coils
It's wonderful. But it's like does show the how proud down is going to be about environment. And this page is particularly nice with the black set the the night kinda with kind the placement of the right to makes a beautiful page over with my owning the original
So daughter does asleep and the kids that wake up to wear kim off. So you can see from the start where the problem is going to be the donald saves two months and only the kids are digital and the last panel is Al fire a friend, must shave the woman and children, this is too emotional for any kind of job with responsible three weeks out of that really right there.
It is. It's very funny. I I read it as him being in that, like, just woke up state. Right? Economically
disoriented. Al the third page
as we get into it, We watch donald. This is really the beginning of the this Al change. Yeah. This is a killer page because I'm gonna laugh through this one. I'm just wanna talk
go ahead. I and, you know, this is first of all, from a writing and a story telling x execution. He is just mastering the rule of three's here
everywhere. Lucky lucky lucky, that's the sleeping. But now they're running out the door. And and and watching diamond, the R here is brilliant as well, especially the the elongated dated run. But running out the door wait, and then you hear the the nephews are out of sight the first few frames and you just see Donald ep here as he forgets his hat. He forgets his acts. And oh, absolutely minded of me. He absolutely
admits that in the in this wonderful rush, there's a adrenaline that he's gonna do this. But, wait. Wait. You can't go out there like that. You're in your night shirt, you know? And then he gets out there and and the last panel was probably the killer panel I'm off.
Donald and, of course, we'll let pull let Mark pick it up from here, but I I love this because it is just if total comedy and that one of the great things of all the time for call.
It really is this this page.
So by the end, right, they've they launched him that he's still in his night. And so we get this great mis direct where he he... He returns to fix the problem, but he leaves and he's completely naked.
It is so incredibly timed and so funny. Yep you usually calls stag and group with Barks and one on every page, Generally shoot in this particular store is like three on the page, and then the fourth is the big one at the end Correct?
Poor dad's one.
This might be his, like, funniest
single page. I think the funniest is that the other the... This this page in the page where an fishing store, which isn't too far away really fishing story, where trying to catch it fish with then mike he runs into the store and tries to buy Barks particularly, was some movements in that story too but I think this is probably number one from your space. This has to be in the conversation. Like it enter. And I mean all time across I agree.
So on our fourth page, you know, the predictable thing has happened,
the the Nephews and monica him to get... Get your clothes on before your arrest.
He's finally on his way, but as we would expect by the time he gets to the firehouse,
the engines to host company number six and a half
of have already left and he sees that the fires all the way across town, so he asked to run for it. And and predictably, he arrives when the fire is is well out, the building... The house has been completely burned. There's a very unfortunate homeowner
that is like, in his blanket kit and telling them telling him that the... They wet down the houses
and went back to the firehouse. And he he like offers him anything I can do for you. It's it's very dark, but it's like economically dark. Right? That this guy just lost not donald so incompetent that the guy who lost the house has to help donald.
Right. Exactly. That was the Irony here. Yeah. Why. So so this has been set up just marvelous. With the... With the next page, we get to the first time that a two point to see don. And when I... First time I read this story, I mean we're actually really the first time. And I wasn't really expecting him to be demoted in as funny ways looks time. Know So a really cute way gets each time some more ridiculous than happens to might've downwards and stays upward. So finally wants to see hundred mcdonald's side bet he wants to apologize for leaving me last night. I'll go write down. I've been demoted kids the chief has maybe a escort man don't who it does. It's good. Scrooge already doesn't like the truck anymore. Don't you mean to go right the track anymore? That's a sad story. I do by foot power, and I'll get back on the hundred day you'll. Of course, you see hanging his this spray and right beside the one spill, which isn't not needs to which know gonna be bad news. Right? So donald
determine would one ones light there'll be no slip up or guarantee that. And of course, again the kids wake up first. Yeah.
This is some mass or full setup up. Right? Huey,
telegraph it for the reader
And and your right the motions
are so funny. They were Like the way the page starts out because he feels he did his job with the with the chief on the phone he's eating and the biggest stack of pancakes I've ever seen this guys living I. And the look on Donald faces is glance Barks at his Nephew is just price list. And of course, the passage of time and then the gl walk on. I just love this page. It's great. Yeah. Not a lot of self awareness from
No. Not there. Well, the next page Donald did it again. The boys sort of knew that that might happen he sleeps in. Now Donald prepared, so he gets out of bed, and he knows it's a fire stand Barks and get me room. I'm gonna get my jacket at this time. I'm gonna grab my hat this time. He gonna grab his spray can
now and, of course, Patrick as you already said, it's
set up was absolutely wonderful to to get into this again. He runs out the door holding, of course, the wrong spray canister and heads over to the house, which is on fire. And and he's beat the fire he's is the first one on the scene. He can be the hero now. Right? Yeah Is big woman. And he runs inside and ready to spray the stuff around inside and put the fire out even before the chief arrives. So he's really looking for some glory here. Right. I like again the three things going on my jacket and I had my.
The carl loves to use that in the story in particular. Anything's included.
Freezing. I I I picked that up too. You know, early and when I mentioned it, but the one thing I don't assume this page is that when he's running it a wonderful shot with the house on fire, the exterior. Mh. Beyond the fence. Those are cousins people they're looking for watching reminds me of Al. It does.
Always have crowd seems like the box and matches and stuff and. Yeah. It's took be while to discover that, but he's on stage. This is Donald chance to Shine. The story also has a lot
like Mcdonald's house is a lot of like design stuff in the background. Doesn't matter george
strongly
bringing.
Right I'm not familiar with that one. I have to look that up. That's cool. And it's funny too because, like, Donald is on on to the next page. He's being a glory hog here in a way that his little square could not have handled this blaze. At the point that it is even if husband. Because if it was Al fulfilled with currency.
Right. Right.
He says it's a ke bug spray, which should sound weird to us these days, but I I think that that actually was use
to recent
wipe your baby's face off of Harrison you know.
Better living through chemistry.
So
so, you know, Donald
makes the fire
catastrophic worse and ignites Al explosion And and this time when it's the next morning and he gets the call from the fire chief, he he's under no
illusion that it's gonna be anything
good. He's dread. He he talks himself into saying oh I I can playing out Al little missed deal last night. But again, he returns to the nephews playing with their fire engine, and he has the most solid look because he's been demoted to to a wet sack.
I don't know
who is supposed to go around and beat out sparks from small brass fires. And this this... I think is supposed to evo the... You couldn't punch your way out of a wet paper bag saying is is my thought. But it's it's just funny in general. Obviously funny better words. Yes. Right. And and by the end of the page, the Nephews are resolving. They've gotta do something that help amounts. And it's a requirement kind of thing. The kids are always trying to help for with. They're not like, for roy.
Yeah. We're very earnest and earnest in are very yes area. I'm
story. So the kids are gonna go out right and help dom. So they're going to build a twenty fire someplace that you can put out with his wet website. And one of the kids since you're analog to say place and one says build a tiny five that can put out with one. The other one says, no. Make it a three slot five. But the boost wrong because after Al three things stories throughout. Yeah yeah. Good point. Yeah.
So don around the house river to make sure there's no fire hazards on the premises and has been a good finding. They find a can of fire Al the kids have paid behind barbecue. These things could cause Al holocaust Put them in my pocket one of this panel putting in boxes. I put them in in my pocket and throw them in a creek sometime when I down that way. He's got such a good look on his space. It's such a beautiful drawing about. And you know, ten years earlier over the other store, the hotel story back in point Severino studies is golden age with the panels circles and things Al the time. And you can just tell it from that air from the forties.
Okay. And the kids are uncle donald. There's a quick fire off the alley. Grab your went website and save the city. If I went up to the rescue and running letting like near for the... Oh great expression there. Yeah. Great. And what I love about this page is it really... It it if features donald in those three panels where he wants to do something,
extremely knowledgeable noble as a fire he does. He actually does something good. But of course active.
Yep. Proactive. Yeah. No. He's not he as he rush off, he he finds the little brass fire. I don't know how many spots he had to do with that wet sack, but
he he did finally get it, but then I love the little notice Barks. There's there's three three splash because it says take that. Right. Well, there you go that that that
there's your three. Yeah. So he did it that... But then, of course, unfortunately, on that last Gladstone of the sparks landed Daniel's jacket and as he walks away, he knows he saved the day. In fact he saved thousands of lights. I thought that was pretty incredible, but he smells smoked needs. Quickly looks back and says, help my jackets on a fire help help, and he runs into the yard. To the nephews look on their faces there is priceless list, you know roll the wet grass don't run into the house, You know, they're actually warning him again as more eligible than he is. But he's panicking and getting another great panel when of course, the spark leads up to those hidden fire crackers in his pocket and
just this wonderful series of top and bang and cracks as the fire creditors go off and ultimately
set their house on fire. Boys kind of, you know, kinda roll in and then all of a sudden and call the fire department and know how they're gonna save their uncle by
rolling down in a blanket. And getting the fire. So they're acting like the fire... The environment they they totally keep their heads. In contrast arnold. Just.
The firm and.
Three times. Yeah.
Alright. So so the last page is really our wish fulfillment
fill. Right. We
we get the arrival of the fire
we get to see the fire chief who has been unseen
but referred to on the phone, and he looks like the voice of authority that you might expect. And he's he's talking about his response. Is is there a fire here,
but he can see
that there was a fire
the nephews have put it out. They've they've been totally in control, and he says Oh, you did And how,
say, I'd like to see what at the firehouse.
How about it? And I I just... I love the very proud look on his face kind of the twinkle and his eye.
And we transition
to now the inverse where the nephews
returned from the firehouse,
sporting acts,
wearing
some great fire hats,
donald soaking
still sing and and then we get it transitions to that night where
there is a fire to respond to we we had to see this really great little
systematic business like panel of their
responsible
risk response to the fire
to get this awesome comment from them that fire number thirteen and a quarter, thirteen and a half. Thirteen and three quarters are on there way and and and then the narrator box says and when the engines
roar by,
and and we see Donald the wet Sac man looking on
as his nephews are bravely and Al
riding the fire truck to the fire. Left lucky me I can... Likely lucky lucky there we are... You get that the... And I think I think the when carl went to write this, he decided like, I get the fill early on
the starting story so is the three methods.
Used threes as many times That came through the store because of them. Yeah. Yeah.
You're exactly right, Patrick. This is all about the number three just in the fact that three.
Three is the perfect pattern for comedy and storytelling
and building. But they match truly talk like that and to do. That's what makes this such a perfect
gag story. Right? And I it's ridiculous because we know that no responsible fire company
is going to allow them, you know, these these young kids to come out at night.
My son was fourteen years old. He joined the local files department gone to a fire department. And there's a phone from time that's fourteen to.
Awesome truck got out the middle the night.
Hard believe. But in the world town
Eric is still
crazy enough to do that. I can see it for a teenager, but the nephews are clearly coded as like single digits. If you if you add the changes together
on top of each,
Well that's
right And they
I remember stores try to stack the
the the story where they get a job as a messenger,
Al delivery board with the alignment,
look we stack up tall.
Well, this is a long standing trope of Barks. Right and and it is wish fulfillment for the readers because because kids love to see themselves this way like when they drive the car around in sheriff of Bullet Valley and and we don't... It's not even Barks upon it just a great form of bush fulfillment that connects the reader. But what what an amazing story. It holds up every time I read. It does
I think one of the things that I noticed and in this page, two things about donald himself just wrapped up in that blank and that's solid look in his face on that wonderful full living room shot.
But his his demeanor is one of... He just, he knows he couldn't succeed. So he is
resignation is resignation total resignation. And at the last panel
the color is kept the hat red along with the fire. Everything else is silhouette sort of a reminder that is Barks you said that he kept his wet sac job regardless. He wasn't canned. He wasn't zach, if you will.
And
and as low as you could go. Yeah Lowest Al you could go.
Yeah. He Al his lowest now. And there's nephews at their highest. So
again, it's just a a great story. And this story, like all the stories
ends with donald at such a low point yet the next ten pager, he's on top of the world on Pamela one. Yeah. Matthew. That was a great thing about Carl stuff and he would he would never like
stick with one thing and we stuck right. He left everything open always from stories to store so the could be totally different. Sounds.
The opposite
was no last. Al lot of people appreciate that. It's like it's because carl was the freedom. Do it one.
Stories wasn't anything.
Well can when you consider the number of stories he did, If he... If he worried about continuity,
he would have tied his hands horribly.
Exactly.
This was the only way to do it.
This recently the last couple of days that those stories again back to back. Yeah. I mean you know, there's like it's like so much is the same in this
hotel the the hotel story, even though it's a ten later and the reads completely different. It's not like a copy of it. But right basic
know sound of the construction of the store. Even though the fire story is much more characters driven more it's more just like it's more casual.
So this is pacing much faster Al much more going on in this high
it's still the structure that you'll it's very similar Yeah. I I think they compliment each other really well.
So why don't we do this? Alright. So
just a brief moment of background, of course. Our our next story that we're gonna talk about is the Saga screen hotel story. And this one was
As as previously
cover date was November of nineteen fifty seven, and we're way up in walt Disney comments and stories number two hundred and six.
This is also ranked fairly highly. It's certainly not up to the heights of of the fire story. But it's good for seven point four Inducks,
which is ranked three hundred and seventy six
out of all forty two thousand
when you consider how many.
Yeah. Exactly. Not not too shabby at all. And and again, I think it's just a good sort of,
like this is Carl Barks Story. So go ahead
patrick. You're going to
start this one on. This is one of my very favorite
for sure this this working
is john. The reason I like it is because it's so four of stuff. And a. It's a lot going on the stores. Very busy busy. We sedona peeling potatoes, two like tables and seem to spence. I'm getting sure about this job of the storage day and peeling and potatoes. In the kitchen of one of these hotels north and we see piles of potatoes and we look like french chefs in the background. Sitting on the potatoes, not very appealing job. There's only one job in this hotel was slower than peeling potato, and that's tram the peeling and trash can. They it monkey fell tram the pill just behind all. That's one of my favorite panels in the store is was caught up and that image a guys smoking in data and between the trash. That is obviously angry. I'm not going to stay so close to the bottom of the ladder and going up sample screws and demand the better job. So funded lake school three nights now running title business and deserve better brake
perhaps you right. For once a it seems like the Scrooge is reflecting that as well itself. It it does is deserve about. Right? It's pretty straightforward. I love the opening splash panel. It's a beautiful panel. It's it's a nice panel. You mentioned that the kinds of tate and sp. If I correct, sand
Is where he lived think
little inside humor there. I love how he did that. And and I do like the way the the the professional chefs in the kitchen are depicted there with a long, straight mustache and ones Inducks, You can see. And he often used two tory bur is a city that therapy it's a two big potatoes. I'm not... I'm not sure where a two burger came we use that often. And then potatoes, of course, peeling potatoes is an notoriously
tedious job and and so we see that in a lot of these stories as far back as as the mum ring. Alright. Yeah. And and so so Donald just... Just is adamant that he that has the nearest relative dongle Scrooge.
You'd want me to get ahead. You'd want me to succeed and and screw is just very minimal harry. I absolutely write donald. I should give you a chance to show what you can do. I'm gonna make you a manager and then of hotel, and Donald is just ecstatic that that that dizzy
gl the whole boy boy. As he Barks him...
If you wanna be a success in business, you'll you'll be moved up to manager of the entire chain of nine thousand nine hundred tonight like hotels. Which doesn't guy throws him throws him for a loop and course he's happy. Donald Donald takes this all
extremely well. It skips a head to don the boys
off the train
as they land into Sag spring, but it is a
deserted town
primarily because of the re routing of the highway yet. About... Well, I'm gonna say seven years earlier. And
So Donald has look of concern on his basis they head towards Sag more hotel. This is the point where Verizon however it changed within the highway system interstate. So Al lot little towns that wiped out from those things changed and all there's no longer local travel. Yeah. Yeah. I'm glad you mentioned that. Too because it this is. You're right. This the story. This is what they told. This is the story that Disney told or pixar told in cars. Right? Basically
exact. It is interesting to me guys that Scrooge doesn't really have, like... It's a little bit out of character. This is just one of those cases where Pearl had the story that he wanted to tell. I don't usually refer him as Carl Patrick. This is wrong. I'm being with you. Yeah.
This is the story he wanted to tell. So that's how he
this lots of... What lots of instances where the screws would talk to the boys about and getting ahead, you should be ambitious and you should try to go.
Thought that it was like it's unusual for, but it sort of does fit... You can seem thinking about it. Because it's like his... Yeah. It fits the mold of certain story I that. Yes that's but he did also give Donald the lowest of the lowest hotels. I mean yeah. In a dessert
port it up. And so
we can make this... Yeah. Possible Barks. Yeah. Yeah. So I think there was a little bit of old ones we're shining through. Just get donald out of the office, but but it it worked right. And and onto the third page, what what I appreciate about this story is this is one of the Donald jobs,
examples where he's working really hard, and he's making a really good go of and there something satisfying about seeing him be really
ind,
the Nephews having a great attitude. They're they're all They're getting the hotel ready
They're really throwing themselves into it. Donald is brainstorming
about how to advertise
to get people to go out of their way to to to the hotel. There's a fun little gag
where one of the nephews is kinda covering up some exposed
mattress
springs and saying have Barks guests have strong bats tough hides
probably losing a little bit to the to the title
of of the story. Right? It's a funny title when you think about these old mattresses with exposed springs. Or Al place to stay? The side right this way. That's right. It's a fun little jingle of that donald is is thing to himself. And and by the time, they're resting
Donald is all dude up in his manager role and waiting for either for a guests.
And one of the nephews sees that the train has actually stopped and they've got a potential first guest on their first night. Look at all the beautiful drawing in this page. There's so much going on
hotel does slowly clean it up and fix the bags and buy manager say this is real device.
Even if there's still patches on the floor. Yeah. Yeah.
The whistle while you work a little bit not to Yeah. To some white and... Which is which is again, twenty years earlier than this story. And yeah. I just... I love the painting the designs and just trying to read the signs and what they say to. I mean. So much still. Shelly my wife looked driving in Dating and eventually
story called driving dot, and she will actually worked to then, as manage the driving. And there's like all kinds of disasters that happened like the store, so we actually been story definitely was inspired by this. All cool. That's awesome. So Scrooge steps off the train, and he's dressed rather port out that's whisk.
The funny better come down through disguise and see how well well long running on.
This is like a bunch of two guides with... Yeah. Dog taking
low of each office of hotel. Free bus, bust the S springs hotels just apparently
or
yeah he runs in the bag. You will enjoy your stay here, sir and when by the time screen gets the door, donald got on a
flower. Welcome to the Sag more screening serve.
I can imagine you've changing his voice as a does this the dog Step break to the desk, so and know some clerk by the time
gets to the desk are surprise facing. There's down and with like Al south completely different in the before. The register service. Sign right here sir, and this is the first of the gag where Scrooge is, like, thinking about how well that the dog is or isn't running in the hotel.
I hope the hotel was making enough money to pay for all this higher health. Like I doesn't think to the sky just thought there was hilarious
weird dad
to me the hilarious.
Show this room like and then this continues and each bag is funny is three of and each one is coming up with screws.
Responding to donald, something bugs is funny them will ask you go. Right. That's what you ideally when you run a score to two want you want to those guys
to build upon the last one to be than last,
that's what here it's.
Those Scrooge gap coming up there's two more. And was Al donald in between them.
Response. Yeah system... Yeah. And I think this Scrooge gag of of of dressing in disguise was just kind of wonderful. We know who he is donald Absolutely doesn't. But weird. We're again it is. But the number is is that like the guy in disguise is actually being fooled by the same by his Yeah. Exactly
so you've got this this play on disguise and
really just brilliant story. I think it's a sort of thing only Carl Barks did this particular type of is kinda bad, you know, live... Where Scrooge doesn't know. Even though he's like, way, smarter than Donald businessman,
news stuff and still he follows with Mcdonald's gag somehow because Donald was doing is so fast.
Excellent enthusiastic about. Scrooge believes in. It is a weird gag, and it's very very grinch. I think it's very funny. And the only reason I think it works so well is because of Bark are just... It's... It's... To me, it's all in Scrooge is very like his expression.
It's a very large handle hinge if you look experiences expression, the secure and downtown pass through the whole homepage. Outside Scrooge act don't. Yeah It's it's pretty great. It's tremendous. Well, at the end of the page he calls for the Bell boy. And once again,
She shows up with Al bell boy outfit on in less than a second. I love that. And look Al how screen just heads spun around because. Yeah.
Yes. Peter staying right there. Yeah. Yeah. And you see Al little cloud of of of of speed zip by as they get into the elevator. And here is some of the funniest art. And the funniest visual gag
to go along with the the sag or fights itself on its excellent dining room, sir as they go into the elevator and up been down and they just... It's just brilliant. I'll let you know if I feel like eating after this experience, so they do kinda comment on it. The proud bell boy brings Donald brings
screws to his room. And and and then the next panel
Scrooge is impressed. It starts taking up business and he's impressed with donald
running in the hotel so far. But but then he says But those are the kinds of things
about the way the hotel
for eight. Yeah. It's a it's a it's a Chamber maids jordan. Wanna see how well he manages the business end of the hotel and this is where the money comes into play. He rings, donald, tells the nephews to whip up some winners and sour cloud for dinner. Because this should suit a character of his bill
speaking tears.
I thought it was very funny every time I read this help this
bridges by the time donald lose. It's been called so so many the times the last two pages, but the screen is answering that. And also the sure will, as you so Barks the skewed
expressions
as they
contract
and know the that are awesome. The the proportion stuff And it's really a pleasure to see his art with some of this. It would would have been more contemporary at the time. But some of the old fashioned
appliances
and the the old
elevator the way the elevator was operated. It's it's just a neat thing to see now in twenty twenty two. Alright. So this as you mentioned is the sequence where Scrooge is gonna give Donald to check and he's gonna ask him to store it in the safe. And and Donald talks up the strength and security of the safe, and he Gladstone Al the chat. And he is nearly dumps on the stairs when you realize is it's a bank draft for ten million dollars, So the first thing he's gotta do is to amend his order to the Nephews.
That they need to open a can't turtle soup in Al standard. Boy, there isn't a mask it deluxe. You can't get turtle soup these days.
But...
Yeah. And so he had manages them to clean it to let sparkle, and he he goes to
put the draft in the check and and I can sympathize with this. I can relate to this. If I was holding a ten million dollar check, my.
I I would be freaked out. So So Donald is struggling to remember the combination of the safe and we are able to see him accidentally
reaching
for the combo
instead of the draft as the opened. I love telling he said it's after where my tie was just put away. And is like, we would say that we didn't actually put him on would be like to.
Exaggeration, but he actually puts on time.
Click you accidentally locks accommodation into the safe turns around human yikes. It is in a safe place and locked it in the same instead of the draft. Left two turns the sixteen back and you can't remember and ruins it says, oh, this is the point where the things that are calling the Barks the download but Right. They try to use a crow Barks get the sled hair so slamming
making huge amounts of noise on the safe And this is the second experience got donald excessive noise around the hotel. Must jot that down And you could just imagine how actually.
Al
is very casual with his nose.
This
he's very business life, you know, he's like out attached to the lock on budge, so he's gonna drop it down the yellow elevator shaft. The slip six floors down to the basement down the doesn't shaft. Look out below. Right? It's a.
And it's handy that we've already been in the elevator. Right? Because it gives that sense of of the we Barks early when you first at the time to see how tall that's why it's Al way. You see it
on several springs to You have to have that order to get that feeling for hike.
Yeah. That's a great point about the exterior shot showing the the the size of the hotels. It's a grand hotel. Well, as Donald is poised to bust open that safe by by shoving Al six floors down to the bottom of the shaft I think he forgot that he asked the that to go
get those dishes cleaned up and, of course, great comedy timing,
the safe crashes into the dishes destroying everything and once again, on through
he hear it, and he's continued to jack. I love city. I love the view of him sitting on his bed not moving you know, out of this guys, but absolutely pure business
writing down up if you will. Correct. So that'll raise out again with the safe. What are you trying to do, but I gotta... I'm... The safe door is still closed, but I just remember sure way to open it, and he takes out this welder iron and it looks like a welding torch that and again, dressed in Ducktales. I love the the the right open of his didn't change. He's staying in Ducktales, but he rush to the torch. And and of course, one of the Nephews says, wait.
Are you trying to get the safe open? And
what do you think? I got the torch. I tried the elevator that didn't work. And of course, the Nephew remembers the combination and open.
Yeah. Of course, he does nephews again, saved the day. And he shows donald and donald Courses is holding to torch. In the air. Right. This is one of those moments where if Donald had fought to communicate with someone. He could've well a lot of a lot of trouble. Many times see that happen?
Right
it strikes me too as I think about the last story Both of these a lot of the humor is really about the the rapid motion. You know,
he's always on the move. He's always frantic
Patrick that reminds me of the first story that great trouble with dimes that we did together, a lot of the humor of that one is from the frantic.
Of dawn running back and forth too. So... And and then the Nephew explains, yeah, we keep our merit packages in there sometimes by way to my email. So Donald initially very relieved, but but of course, they realized that the hotel has been set on fire because he's absent
holding the torch
as you mentioned. And and so we get to see Inducks uncle Scrooge room, the fire sprinklers.
Turn on. At least it's up to code in the in the fifties.
And and so Donald tells him, I get everything the value out onto the sidewalk.
Because this this awesome visual. You guys. I love that. That was
seven on this page. Of all the water pouring out of the the Grand old hotel.
Another great one of uncle screws again, very calmly
third one.
Yeah. Just handling his mattress or writing his mattress down
served in the dining
how much that Huey,
his
the water.
They down the stairs and the mattress. She's upset about the fact that there's no wheels in the diamond room. Exactly.
And when I love Al that, Huey, he's writing it down like a ramp and the only thing he grabbed before he left besides his pencil and paper was the happy water.
Last I love how it a donald calls the ten million dollar draft worried ticket. Yeah. That's good one. So I did research on on sprinkler systems, and I wanted to get a sense of when the modern day fragrances that looked like this inspired Barks. And even though Sprinkler systems of one way shape form have been around for quite a while. They really weren't introduced in in America until nineteen fifty four. So we only have a three years of this two new. It was new. And I think Barks loved to play around with new technologies as well cutting edge. Yeah. That's cool. Final page the story. Those spare online. It's
you seem clothing
and the on the mattress. And he's still playing the part. Where's the manager? Where's the manager? If he's still the fat man? He ran zurich
I want a ten million dollar bank draft. I'm checking out and the screen says it shouldn't have given him the draft that to keep but I wanted to see if you can handle big responsibilities without getting nervous of us. And that's always done it's problem. Getting. Oh I didn't get frustrated a bit. I'm sure you you'll find a draft safe and sound. Oh, so. It's the famous line parts ben. I think far
things more invention
and it's a really cool like saying,
and that's heard people... I've heard people say, like, in modern times, just outside of chronic are together, I think so like that. I think pretty sure this coral actual invisible. It sound accepted all the ink is washed off it reads ten cents That's a bad thing for storage to
Good. And so tag. Well we're back in duck.
Scrooge figured uncle donald didn't make a good good as a hotel manager, totally go mcdonald's you get your old job Barks Nope. Not the one killing potatoes.
Gave me a job and set of better suit liabilities
tripping the peeling of the trash. Brings us back to the bottom page. Yes. And and even the... Like the pharmacy.
I don't... Patrick was the art intentional there with donald dragging as knuckles on the side
almost monkey like. Oh, much god.
That could they. I don't know definitely got that low cost
just like
just like in the end of the fire and story that yeah
let's see those similarities between the two that I've Severino really realized until I read them back back out of the... You know, just how the flooding was carefully
designed like... Yeah it's such a beautiful
change.
Between the two stories.
You think that there's nothing like to do about job. But actually they're very
plugged. You
for for Barks to been as productive as he was. He he had to use these sc, right? These.
These archetypes of stories that he could occasionally go back to and tell a different story in a different place but in the same way.
He may not have been even aware of the lucky left storage in similar to this. In fact, I don't think he probably was. I think think you probably just, know, do it this way, and that's just how it was. Right.
Because if you read the... When you read them, they're like, two completely different people. Totally different. Than each other. There's very, very little similar similarity meeting wise to two stories. Oh, yeah. Yeah. I agree. It's it's not one of those cases where he went back and deliberately remade something it's more I Al echo.
Some of them some of
stories, you know, they're obviously lifted. Ideas even said at the end that's very interview
said that one of the reasons and stopped writing wrong was because he felt he's no longer giving his readers their dimes what off
yeah But this in this particular instance, I think this is one of the very stories. I think the point where his writing was absolutely
I think this is a really solid one. I don't know I'd put it near my, like, favorites, but it's it's just a good... It's got so much going for it. It's fun that it's only Scrooge,
donald and the Nephews even though it's theoretically in this huge
hotel, this month monkey. Monkey.
That's true.
And he doesn't really interact with anyone. Oh, it does stamps of the feeling. That's right. It's a great vehicle for uncle Scrooge too because you get to see him be so generous in the beginning.
And then suspicious in the middle
And then, of course, that told and have
about Yeah do I yeah. Absolutely.
Yeah. You can imagine him kinda having a sequence where he reconsider.
Like no I Donald too much. Never mind have been stories where Barks would have chosen to put that in. We just hadn't doing.
Anyway, it was like I love the story.
I think it was
certainly characteristic
of of donald the demand more from his uncle.
It was nice to see that turn and deleted to the story. After a guy... I really like the way that you drew the parallel between that and the fire and story.
It would have been interesting to see the boys take over the hotel.
Alright. So let's go ahead and transition them to the milk
story.
This one
was... We we had mentioned this is a very
unusual
situation.
He created in September of nineteen fifty seven. So, like, almost around the exact same moment. As
that was when this was published, and this was this is what it was turned in. Exactly. So we would have expected to come out a few months later, but it it got shelves it was roughly scheduled or its thought to have been scheduled for approximately walt Disney comments and stories two fifteen.
W like?
Right. But it it was s because by all accounts
He he reported saying that his editors didn't like how Dawn who was put two mean to the villa. And so it didn't debut.
We we had mentioned at Debuted in Europe. It was Netherlands. It was in the Donald duck weekly in nineteen seventy four. Is it first
publication? So, like, almost two decades after. This is such an unusual.
And then it wasn't published
in the Us until carl Barks library set number ten. You guys are holding those up And then the first, like, regular she was a pretty cool issue of all Disney's comments and stories that Disney themselves ran under the Disney comics regimen,
while Disney's comments and stories five hundred and. Yes. Was pretty lucky but It wasn't lost altogether. Yeah. Exactly. You're right. Patrick, that's a good point so many of these stories like back to the dyke
had its missing panels, other... There there's just... There's all kinds of cases of loss starts. So it's it's great that this was completely intact. This one is interesting because it's gonna have a recognizable villain, a lot of the ten pages have I'm anonymous a calendar. Right? But we've got a mix swine who he was using at this point. And
I want to really go to bat for this one, guys. I think this story is is a pretty special one because of how unusual it is and it's It's not that highly
regarded by the community. I've gotta imagine that some of that is just because it hasn't been reprinted as much if people
yeah. People don't know people don't know this one and they should because this is this is a cool story.
It's it's only ranked seven point two, which is eight hundred and thirty eight. It's still a fine ranking, but it's middle of the road for Barks. That's the median
ranking of his stories. Is either seven point one or seven point two. Final fax that I saw I mentioned on on one of the sites is that Bark himself was lactose out and intolerant,
but reportedly really like milk in his cereal.
Kind of a little meaningless
fact there.
Before you kick off the story one, I'm gonna mention that I think one of the special things about this is how
intros it is.
How almost the entire
thing
is told through thought bones ins
instead of word bull,
and it's very solitary
matching
kind of the ethos of of the milk man, which is which is a classic job that really doesn't exist anymore but was such a part of kind of the American
experience for a long time. So that... That's kinda one of the guiding things I want us to think about. Warren you wanna start us off? Yes. I love this story.
In fact, I'm probably one of the few people who still has a milk friend
live in Southern Minnesota, and we get our milk from a farm about twenty miles away. They come to town every Thursday afternoon. So we have milk in a bottle freshly milk the day before. So Eddie.
Great. I have a great appreciation for this. And what I love about this story and I'll I'll kick them up with the first page is that opening things flash panel, it says so much about the life of a milk.
Donald
absolutely
is clear in his
thought bubble storytelling of the life of a milk band by saying I again get up in the morning at three o'clock. You got the of a moon
with the face out the window. And his milk Ducktales and hat are right there in his room ready to go. And I love the opening line. Few people appreciate Al lot. Of a milk, ma'am. So it has the thought bubbles continue, he talks about
how many customers he has on his route and the all want cream and their coffee.
It's cold at this gas hour in the morning it's worse than when it's snowing a raining and I love the Daisy dairy company. I thought that was
not too daisy. Yeah. And
daisy diary. Right? The.
Yeah. He can thinking about that. Yeah. The good catch. And he logged it walked to the truck. He's loading the truck. And he's talking about
all the different customers he has who take the courts and who take the points and the twelve to one butter twice a week, and he's yawning the whole way. What I love about this is in in all five panels his eyes shut. He's actually just barely waking up but he's so dedicated and that's what I I love about this too. He is dedicated to do very well in this job. Yeah. You said it really well worn. It's it's so
refreshing to see this story where he's really good at this job. Even if it's hard, but he's very dedicated. I I like it. Alright. So on page two, we get to see him an action.
We kinda see him gradually waking up a little bit. And and he's talking about how he goes about his job and how he's good at it. And bark Both tall us and shows us, we see him making friends with the animals. It's very cute feeding the cats and milk padding the doggy. We see him tip tone past the
customers on his route to not disturb them setting the no files, quietly.
It's a very... I think it's a very poetic setup. You know? He's talking about how he tries to be a perfect to milk in
It's very touching. He says someday, some please patron may leave a dime in a bottle for me. And we see these really challenging
deliveries where he has to leave his way past creek boards and rattling toys, and not make a step in the dark. Really a beautiful drawing page like designing results. It really is and and some beautiful writing in the panel preceding the one you talked about Barks was and I set down each bottle as silently only Al other falling on silk. What the great line and
you feel it you feel it and you feel this dedication to doing things right to the top of the next page is a q q business with stepping on top whisper whispering now Okay. Must cry out, even though I step on the short pack is really dedicated. Yeah. And then and then it gets
still into the program using support. I can't pay for the milk but brought last month but I need more milk from my sick leave dollar. If she doesn't pay your bill, I will have to pay it. Little sick daughters, they want some know... I guess the treats on the places really. Is noble here. That's really... I... I'm sorry. It don't mean that I I wanna almost treat this it's two separate pages here. Right?
This is such a... This is part of what that sequence is part of what makes this one stand out. To me. Right? We don't... Barks doesn't
usually
like to show Donald in such a noble light. And the only time he's ever gonna let Dawn will be really noble is if he's about to deflate him a lot, have something
happened to him. But and it's it's refreshing. Donald is sometimes a jerk in these stories. So it's nice.
You can tell the call is trying to not handle it donald on the normal way he does usually. He's trying to make throughout this story keep his patient see a lot of patients in this. You get.
So I think the calls carl doesn't have a tremendous amount of material in this store like suppose what? And what he's trying to do instead his for telling, we people kinda this a bad story, you know? And he wants to... He's kinda slow things down. And writing donald talk a lot. Think what he has to say is, like, towards like a moral favor. Good and kind quiet, noble Al is the milk There was still those who, such as the discounted
five zero five.
Works is being
specifically
alex not the word specifically philosophical or something about.
Yeah. Here we are introduced to one the big though or used the lot of yours. I'm going to get that docks job. I'm going to get fired. Then I will be. No stretch the mail with water and cut myself and easy running again. This guy's bad news, you know.
People that are seen
stores And being so red leaving milk apartment five zero five And afraid the gentleman here the gentleman gentleman there, trying to make any trouble. I love what a penny and villainous scheme he has. Right? He's gonna stretch out the mill
Yeah. So he's a sc, but he's also just very little minded. Yes. He's just
facing the next experience. Was awful. Oh, yeah. And I think that's what the editorial business was about. I don't think it was about what donald does took that the end. I think it was more about the guy been so bad for this.
So I think I I really... I'm glad you said that because I'm relieved if that was the real case, that makes sense. Because
we'll get to it, but Domino's revenge is something we look forward to in the story. Al lot a lot of things would ask questions about stores where he didn't
for sure was like problem couldn't remember why exactly suggested that because of
so such a mask throughout just terrible of them. Right. So wife so wife begins his miss shift now. We we've been introduced to him and his evil look and his evil
plans,
but the top of the next page, we see donald
tripping over Al a wire that he didn't see because it was so dark and his milk just crashes to the ground and it's all over the place. And the first thing we see is mix line and the big on the phone calling the Daisy dairy company and complaining about the Clumsy milk Felons smashed is milk bottles at my front door. Yeah. The noise woke we up from a deep sleep. You gotta fire the guy. And the course Donald is just oh I'm he's.
He doesn't know he set the trap. Don't clean it up. I'll have my name do and I thought that was pretty funny
and send you the bill. And he was so acknowledged. I so absolutely agreeable to that. And he even is careful to walk out of their tip towing out of there with the broken last. Cleaned everything up and it goes back to the to the truck. Just wanting to you'll be the perfect milk, but the customer is always right. And I just wanna try to be a perfect milk man again. He's just... You just can't you just loved don here. And, of course, looks wife is looking down and him saying that it's gonna make... Make a hard that shrimp. He'll quit his job. Yeah. That's right. He articulate his whole scheme
And and so on the next page, it's it's really just a repeat of the last. We just... We just see the progression of the story
where he acts echoes his his pad on the head for the nice doggy, a sauce of milk for the nice kitty.
He he touching hopes that the little sick girl is better.
And and now we see the escalation
He hopes that the gentleman in apartment five zero five isn't still after his scalp, which is, you know, terminology, we wouldn't use this these days, but it's pretty not. Give us that then.
And and so Donald thinks he's ready for him. He uses like an extend arm.
To try to do the milk model exchange and but he discovers that the empty bottle
has... It's it's b trapped. It's got a wire
string
attached to a stack of pants that crashing and flatter horribly as they fall. And I think we're...
Yeah that's pretty suspicious.
Yes. Yeah. Go for a Patrick. No. The next page is really beautiful. One again, it's very stressed so long
placement blocks. And just said a really nifty page. The person the first panel shows the pans falling down the stairs plan or crash making just a huge rad hello the pig bones since daisy dairy. The clumsy milk man has knocked over a power of ten pounds on my porch you hear them waking the whole neighborhood.
You can still hear playing van so to they can hear them for But there go been away from here is donald before he club me with another trick after the big dick his been away. Thanks.
By fixed that by saw the spare losing loose and donald trips over the stairs, drops his bottles over the edge gonna be a disaster don't thanks. Oh, my gas day, these bottles
they could crash little finish. And somehow it slides down the banner store and speeds ketchup them before you before they hit the ground break. The pick is angry up on above and says, no you don't Al little shrink Barks.
Yeah. Actually kind of pants page got Al lot nifty drawing. All the the the the silver silhouette of donald that down the stair where Al rail is just wonderful. It just shows his ingenuity to prevent more calamity. Right. You're you're mentioning of the silhouette and the great drawing reminds me, Patrick that, like, part of what makes this story special to me is that it's a nighttime story
It's... The whole world is very still other than this, like, you know, terrible one way battle. Well pot plan land
smack on the the bottles that the dom is trying to protect and, of course, mix wine
again, yell out
that the noise, you're gonna wake up everybody on the block. And and Donald is still saying, yes yes, sir keeping the customer on mind, but this is the first time he says it's really hard to agree that the customer is Al right. Right. Now the next morning comes, and you gotta believe at this point donald shared this with the nephews. And and you know that. And so he gets up again, doesn't give up. I'll I'll do whatever I do, I must avoid trouble with that gentleman been still calls him a gentlemen after. Yeah. With five zero five. But then nephews again, he being just a step ahead
in the strategy have decided to come along with to make sure that nothing happens. You know, we'll catch your bottles. We'll we'll keep you from getting your temper. I love that blind typically. And it he goes up. And if we see mix wine
finally, cashing and on his ultimate plan and that's watering down the milk Right. Except on on to the next page, he's gonna try and use that to get donald and trouble.
Right. And Donald drops off his his new milk. He pulls the old switcher real. Any he accuses donald the planting
wired milk and. He reports him to the daisy dairy company
recommending that he be fired.
And and Mcs wine is just Al his worst here, the pig
He dumps the the water mess down Donald dirty neck as he calls that very close
extremely. And and Barks is really making sure that we hate him here. Right?
I think that I think we have carl included more straight ads to about way you publish. I have a film that all this over business with take the end, like, was put off by...
If he had sponsored gag more in the stories it gotten way with the story, and he wouldn't really publish and then Al would've been well. It just like... I think that was extremely concerned
almost
kind approach the.
So the pink slams the door on donald. Mh donald boil and milk falling. Told me hold my boys and mouth to become Al ex meal meal. Then...
They're... Know they say, you'll get no help from us so about the globe or ourselves about as angry as you see the nephew yeah. And I have
Yes. So the pig
yellow out the window. I want everybody to know that this duck water Inducks is milk. Donald and those steam things. I guess, the milk is evacuating off Al.
Like look and you can see the Curls join so we could eyes with. Yes. This is the change. Yeah. Donald says I couldn't have done that. I've been too perfect and milk and you know it yank the little off the bottle throws the milk and space. Died I offered you another ball, And here it is. The think says why you donald slams the window down on his things so can lose runs in the house and a size, the the... I guess the guy gone like a dressing down. Sure. The leg kaiser legs up. So the dressing down seals at the bottom. And then the... On this page, Patrick and and and Barks, the the the moment Donald has that shift in his eyes. Every panel has him with that that plastic revenge donald. And Right
very resourceful.
So we go into we're inside and not only is as he tied off the bottom of the night shirt for he...
And the boys are not with him bringing in all the food that he's pouring down all the cold whole dairy products down the back of the neck of his
the wine and rolling up filling it up. As a very funny picture. And funny thing is not it's not really a bad revenge. Know as far as there's pigs done to him. So not Al stuff. Yeah. Very minor on it... Especially if that's kinda cheese that doesn't hurt, you know, I know. Be showing down a little bit. So later on, we know that after donald of the nephews have probably left. They call the night boss or our mix wine calls in the boss at the Daisy dairy. And insulted you. What did he do And then, of course, he... I love this panel. He filled my night shirt full of yogurt and ice cold cottage cheese is he fired old goodness gracious, Yes. So time passes is again, Donald Blue his man's job. I love the the way it sets it up here. And the sc five zero five goes down to take. That was his plan of time. Right? Yeah. Yep. Go. Where do I find the hiring boss bob and then upstairs and surprise surprise? It's Donald, who's the hiring boss now? You Yep. Thanks. To you for pho and complaints. But I thought you fired well though it turns out that he was promoted because he's got one hundred and ninety nine x static customers who enjoyed him so much.
And then he promptly throws mix wine out under the sidewalk. And it's a very satisfying and. Right? The...
Barks doesn't always like to
deal up poetic adjusting
Sometimes he does, but he doesn't, you know, Patrick you mentioned it's it's a.
It's a a morality story. Sure
I like how he recruits the Nephews like, near the end of this to make the reader okay with it. Right? Because if they're If they're feeling the same kind of nation, it kinda gives us permission. Even though Donald shouldn't fill customers night sure it's with cottage cheese and yogurt.
It makes for a funny visual and and in the con of this story, it was very just to desserts or just breakfast. Yes. That's practice. I really like this one. I I don't know that it's like one of my all time favorites, but I I do think that it's a a highly
appreciated Barks story that as I mentioned,
deserves a lot more credit and a lot more recognition for being very different
very interesting very notable.
Of the three stories that we we reviewed today. I I love the outcome here because it's in such
contrast to the down and donald who was defeated in both those other stories. And so it's nice to see down with I'm on on top sometimes, I think sure
Yeah. We don't always want to see him. But we get... We almost get to have it both ways in this one. Right? Because we do get to clean louis as.
Then one of those times where it's just. Right. Oh. So you guys we've we've had a really good conversation about this jobs is
As as we mentioned that the,
there's no way to cover every single jobs story. But I would I would definitely like to take a little bit of time to kinda round robin and hear some of your other favorite jobs stories that, you know, likely aren't gonna get their own episode at any point, but but you'd like to go to bat for. Anyone anyone wanna mention anything first? I actually selected four categories that are my favorite if that's okay. Yeah. Yeah. The four categories where I really like to see down, not only the ten pages but in the long story as well because adventure stories, typically begin with him doing some mental job. And then he's rescued from that or he's asked to step away from that to go on this great adventure. So
the salesman stories, the guard stories to guard jobs, I do like the manager jobs, because as a manager, myself I I relate to some of those some of those adventures that they have. Right. And then and then the fourth one probably in this order would be the Arr stories. I love it when he's committed to an airplane he's flying and he's doing things in an airplane. And I I love aircraft. And I think that's those are very satisfying to me. So those are the four categories that came from this list that I chose. Nice.
Any in particular, like, specific stories are favorites?
I like the sky... The the the smokes writing the sky writing. It's still really great that to me is one of my favorite stories. I don't know the
politicians running for politics. Love that story. And again, that it's kind of been that error. And and again, I'd love the the guard jobs especially the the museum guards that were at the beginning of of last and Andy and and then in golden helmet. I mean I mean, little things like that. Definitely great things happened when he is working in the museum,
We got some of kind stories of all time there. What about you patrick? What comes to mind? What stories would you go about for? Some of these job stories are really the job is just in diving board for rest of story they into it. So I tend to prefer that their job stories where the job is the point where he where like the baker store where he's a baker and he wants to succeed is the baker, the real Barks who's gone to vacation and he's in charge making all of the stuff. That's a good one. And I like the one where he's he decides that he's going to... For the summer watch People's pants.
Yeah superb yeah. No one like. Builds upgrade fantastic
these various pets don't spec spiders things that he's got live got manage. Okay. And me
they danny.
And donald that's breaks the door food for the Vanity, which is answered. The
is That's a favorite of mine to that one probably
I probably will give that It's due in a pet themed up it's Al.
And
the ending particularly
fantastic.
And the
story I like because of the fact carl himself is a chicken fund. I
The omni story is one of my favorite as well. Yep. Yeah.
It's great. It's set great. Set up... Donald tell the story about why it doesn't wanna drive daisy through the top. Yeah. I think that's got a great structure. I I'm well forward to covering that. Those are my.
Yeah. You know, I really like... And again, I am I'm talking about something that I'm planning to cover, but I think his true Al officer for job is is a wonderful
story. I'm I'm gonna be doing a full episode eventually on all of the treatments stories because it's just such a wild and now dated concept.
That be fun have I believe I I really... I... There's also, like, the the kind of law enforcement jobs that he gets. Regarding the B chin from smugglers and the border patrol, Donald, that's one that I've been leaning towards giving its own episode as well. I think those Some of the fun of those is like just seeing him work in a solitary
environment.
Kinda like this last story we just talked about. You know, one of the categories listed in the
on this jobs
website that I talked about was the tenant mentioned to someone of the last pages was the twenty six times that he actually was Uncle
Assistant. So that throws him into
a job that he's working actually for his uncle and there's so many great I mean, from poor man to, you know, all the others that you most page. Yeah yeah. That is true. That is... I love and he could put on his resume that he is an official warrior.
Yeah
true.
The salesman jobs, I think, are a lot of fine. Right? What's the one where where sc has him selling that fast acting flower? I read that one. We. I thought that was a lot of fun And then I'm probably gonna... I'm probably gonna give an episode to that one that's called trouble and ind where he sells life insurance to to uncle Scrooge because that one, that's a personal favorite of mine as well. Yeah, we get a lot of good salesman ones. That that
for a bunch of good adventure stories too. There's quite a few of them were Donald is basically independent. Like the... At we store with the path where going on and as makes on like the whale capture and the because it. It's the skin that is gonna capture whale and then charged tickets for people to see it.
Scrooge
the next day, and they're like, oh, no. I'm gonna miss all this site, but it turns out it's so much work take care of the whale and keeping alive in pool. Go ahead to hear the scroll bell to end me, like, so happy because they're all going out almost to depth. So exhausted I'm trying to feed it keep it wet. Take the water deep enough to keep it. It's a horrible. Oh that's... Right. That be one of those categories where he recruits the the kids and.
There's a whole category like our
independent. Those tend to be crazy jobs because Donald that. Right. Definitely.
I seem to remember enjoying the dog catch
story a lot. I know I enjoyed the thing it's called the Candy Kid where he may candy who's done Al lot of stuff. He has.
Well you guys...
Any any other thoughts, any closing thoughts anyone wanna say about Donald and his occupations? Well, I think that the can't along referrals about job stories. It's like Huey, haven't read some of them should go person should just go off make can point to do it because they sure
almost all of them, Almost all the jobs to are really.
I said it earlier, I think from a storytelling perspective, they're just great vehicles,
and the stranger the more bizarre the job that Donald would tackle. What an absolute
joy that this is all done in ten pages. And on the longer adventure stories it's done in two or three pages where you really get to see that set up. And to me that's just brilliant. So I thank Barks for for
send pager again. This is great. This is a great kind of a great tour from the entrance stories, but just wonderful.
Absolutely.
I'm I'm really happy that we all got to really celebrate
Fire and Donald
overtime classic.
Sag Springs,
hotel is a great story and a lot of fun and and like I said, I'm I'm really happy to kind of go to bath for the mans story. Really talks about that story so because they have they have now just because it's so under
underwear. Very few people.
Great. Great. Hopefully, we can bring some attention to it. Well, thank you guys so much. For joining me. I really appreciate it, and
always a fun time.
Drug right now So enjoyable. Thank you, Mark. And thank you, Patrick. This has been lot one. Yeah. And and listeners are welcome to chime in and tell us about their favorite of Donald jobs, if there's something you think we need to highlight and reach out on the face book or Instagram page and stay tuned for
more episodes at the page podcast.