Hi.
Next hours.
God
down Inducks
house.
She's fast
gonna change the
cheese
many
mouse
with the and
Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer Al artist of the greatest Donald Scrooge con of all time. This episode is a ten page podcast, all about one of his short stories. Get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Welcome back to Barks remarks,
I'm mark Sever a Grown man who enjoys Ducktales con, but today, this really is about mouse Comics, mice comments as well because we've got a very special
episode in recognition of Nikki mcgee birth day, we are gonna be covering the doc man's one and only
full mickey mouse story the riddle of the red hat and
appropriately
for for a special episode like this, I've got a couple of special guests.
First, I've got returning guest t Ko.
That, do you wanna introduce yourself and and mention some of what you... Your involvement with the? Yeah. I've
pretty much been an associate of the Disney Comics since high Scrooge, really, oh my gosh.
You know, I I I talked with my fiance all the time. It's, like, oh my gosh. Two thousand six was like, almost twenty years ago now. Yeah.
I I started out local utilizing
and translating a lot of the monthly and, you know, all the international imports And I also did
commentary contributions as I said before,
for the Fan graphics Carl Barks books but I'm also in most of the wonderful...
The that floyd God that that Fan graphics did
that kind of was science fiction. I
never
expected
them to reprint every single one of those floyd god and daily Mouse. Ever. Ever and that is that is David Ge doing who whom we're going to be mentioning quite a few times in this podcast. Oh, yes. I'm definitely
definitely crib from some of the research.
He did. Yeah. This this episode might as well be called Gottfredson and remarks. Yeah.
But that there's just not as much of an audience. I'm afraid for that.
So so thanks for coming back that. And then Debbie, you are a new guest and and I'm so happy to have you join us. Debbie Perry who has some really great insight on
both the Barks
and Gottfredson
pages. And and then you're you're a Disney fan artist and you've got your own web comment. Debbie, how long have you been in to the Disney comics. Oh, gosh. That goes way that. To somewhere in the Barks when Al seventies or something when they had this three pack that you'd buy from the Wit books. My mom would bring those home for us. We have used used to have stacks of, like, mickey mouse, donald duck, bugs bunny, all those wit books and occasionally actually be something good in there.
Yeah. That's where I saw the first saw
parent
and
ancient persia. Holy yeah yeah. Those those two are probably the first ones I remember from Bart. We would... I'd read those every summer because they'd be at our summer cottage.
I do enjoy hearing from people about, like, their first Barks. Because... Because that's the thing most people who get into Barks, they can pretty vividly or actually a couple of tony struggle things. I didn't find out till later. One of them was the weighted create mystery and another was something...
Adventure on Bom bird island or both books that were all in the batches that those are all stories that for better
got launched in my head. Sure. I I can picture that Long island one if clogged up the back issue bins and my local
at my local store. And then you you put out a web comment. Right? Oh, yeah. It's
fluffy and Mer. They're a cat and mouse.
Originally, they kind of... I thought of the cat and I was thinking of tom and Jerry, but then I thought instead of having the mean cat in the the supposedly
nice mouse. He's not very nice at all. Jerry.
About to have why not have this really nasty sort of mouse.
And is really friendly cat, and that just sort went from there that over the years, I think the characters have mellow some in mer gone from being a nasty character
to just being sort of the grumpy character.
Yeah. It it's really cute. I I really enjoyed it. You've got a really nice style that Yeah. Extends to the fan art that you do. Oh, yeah. That I kinda taught myself how to draw those
Nikki and Donald and all that. Looking at the old Gladstone, but mh. I mean the whitman books were wet I first seen the Gladstone books were what really got me into it because they had have the articles about the creators of who did them. That's where I found the names of Barks and Got said and fact, but I think the first god I remember reading was the seven ghost.
Oh, yeah. It was that was and they did. That was a beautiful
introduction that that was... I think, you know, I might be biased because I worked on the I w books, but I always
say that the Gladstone, that first period in the eighties that was the best period of Disney comics
in
history because It it is. It it is established Barks, by name and print, and it also
reintroduced God for.
Right us God had not been run at all for Al least since
forty nine. At that point, nineteen forty nine, I think that was the last time they ran the strips. I don't know in the comic books anyway, they stopped running the serial, all of a sudden in Walt disney comments and stories when they favor the re ons or the the new Paul Murray
stories and serial. But, yeah. And Glad, of course, introduced Al these new artists like Building van horn, Don Rowe
brought
yep to these shores. Oh we yeah those those Donnie Covers like.
Yeah. Those...
You know, and it's funny too because
I've heard... I'm not gonna say their names, but, like, they'll ask, like, the editors, like, I draw like jp? See heard this covers like, no. No. No. No. No. No Is it oh why not?
Yeah. Those those covers were so wonderful. Oh, yeah. Those were some of the... They just jumped off the new stands. The see covers.
Have.
It. Yeah. I I totally agree. You're you're right too that because it's like that period with Gladstone,
it was the first time that, like vans.
Were we're running the show. Yeah. Right and they got to... They got to give these creators their due. I remember reading recently
two that they it was in a hindsight. They realized the Mickey Mouse line and didn't really perform that well and that they couldn't have justify
running it if they had known ahead of time,
how poorly it would have sold. So I'm just I'm so grateful for that I got to read all of those wonderful god and stories. You know, I think that's why they kinda switched over eventually to the Nikki and Don Donald and Nikki. Well, Mickey ran the whole
run, that whole first glad run right to the very end. They never brought Mickey back. They never brought a Mickey title back when bruce Hamilton got the license again. They had
Donald and Nicky by pushing brian the instead of mickey yeah exactly.
Yeah. That was... I think that was the way that they justify it. And so
of course, they were... They would have been very interested and they did
run the story that we're gonna be talking about. You guys... I I so fascinated
by this story. The the riddle of the red hat, it it really to me feels like this big... Wet, you know? Like, why why didn't Barks
do more of these Mickey mouse stories why? Why did he himself barely remember having done it? And and what would it have been like if he had done more of these? He
himself was the first to basically talk about God for
long shadow?
A guess for the for the handful of people who maybe don't know who we're talking about. Somehow, but tell us a little bit about about Floyd God and and why he's so important. Well, so Da, he was to mickey mouse what Carl Barks was the Donald Duck. He did not create or originate the character, but he is probably
the most influential artist associated with him. And what's... What I was fine fascinating
is
that
both of these guys had a bit of a stent at in Disney cartoons.
Both concurrently, and when they started doing the comics, you know, Floyd was there in the very very early days.
Yeah. I gave Christian like, for not knowing but... Well, least not they kill but just gonna be disappointed if they didn't know exactly which days, but it was very, very early days. He he was I know he's quoted in a few things about he remembers when a I works left wall. Yeah So he was there that early. But he took over the strip.
Walt Disney and
Bob had been doing it themselves and a few other artists sat, and then Floyd took it over and he filled that job for some with except with a couple of exceptions.
He did... He drew every trip for some forty five, forty six years.
And...
Yeah.
It's it's... It was quite a legacy,
and he also
did a lot of the writing up until about forty two or so. And what I always find interesting is that Got was probably the biggest influence on Carl Barks. As far as as far as Disney car tuning is concerned,
Bark
Barks kinda lived in a bubble, and that's kind of why this is is the only mickey mouse story. We'll get into that a little later. But Right. He was very much influenced by how floyd Drew,
floyd wrote and pay stories
and I'm sure you've got some stuff cold from David's wonderful article that we're going to quote quite a extensive leg because That is the of piece on this odd
odd ball story. Yeah. Why don't I throw a quote in really quick, and I'll let you keep going. Bark said. And I don't remember if this is from David's article from one of the other sources. But Mh he said, well, we'll look at my ducks and all those other characters. I've been trying to imitate Floyd work. It's plain to me, and I hope it's playing to other people. You know Mh. He made no secret about it. Floyd was a huge
inspiration. Mh.
Yes. And this story in particular,
there are poses
lifted directly from
Ga
strip. I mean, Al
specifically,
the nineteen forty one story love trouble, which...
And my opinion my theory is that helped the find the new look of Mickey Mouse, more than any other single thing. Any other cartoon film because that was not an adventure story at all. It's a very domestic.
It's almost... It's almost like a dis... It's almost like a Disney version of the film of Philadelphia story. And it's it's just the characters
Floyd is
experimenting a lot with how much he can get away with and Al and a strip and they're just... The cleanest
sharpest,
most appealing mickey ever drawn and that strap. And
you know, if you were cartoon or with taste, why wouldn't you be influenced by that? Right? Absolutely.
You guys I I love the got person and story so much. It's it's one of those don't get me started.
I know. I've I've bored friends with, like, did you know there was this error where Mickey was this scrappy
grass,
you know, fire who who
was resourceful
any pee fist fought if he had many foil smugglers and opium dealers
and,
you know, then we got this, like, really milk toast
domestic version of Mickey that
just just left behind, you know, in the cartoons.
So much of the greatness. But but let me ask both of you. Do you have a couple of of favorite dot for and stories? Debbie. How about you? Let's see. That's a tough, but
one of them that immediately comes to mind
is
island in the sky.
Not
pete and Al that. I love Island on the side. I would probably echo that. God
himself. Was quoted as calling that one his favorite of his stories in one of his meetings with Karl Barks, laid and, you know, both in I think in the seven or so. And there's like an amusing note that that I read where both of them both of them
cop to really enjoying their own story called island in the scout because the course will be somewhere. Yeah.
And any others, Debbie? What what else? Let's see. I really like that. Well God didn't do it all the way through. I really liked that first one. Death Valley. Oh, yeah. What. To death Al twice to Al. It's kind of Al a weird start. But then it just says it picks up speed, you can tell when god and takes over the story starting
together a little better. Yeah. Yeah. These really
weird talk things at the beginning
where you'd have strips where it's like
four panels, but it's like it could have done a week's worth of strips with all the dialogue. They've put in those four panels.
Right and it's really worth
emphasis the fact that Gottfredson
was a newspaper.
Strip artist. Right? He who like you, Debbie. He's dealing in the medium of just a handful of panels,
unlike Barks, who got to work in ten and twenty four and thirty two pages. But he did such an amazing job of making these connect did
cohesive
stories that span weeks and months and and had to had a really defined arc that made it possible for the con companies to just kinda cut and paste and present them as common Barks later on. How about you said favorite Gottfredson
or notable ones? The one that comes immediately to mind is the foreign legion story with Trigger hawk and peg pete.
That one just... It keeps going and going. You... It's
Al completely unpredictable story. It's one of the most tightly plotted ones that Floyd ever did.
I I know there are a lot of...
There's baggage with the whole concept of the foreign legion today. Absolutely.
But you you look at it as the piece for what it is. Know, there... It's a little progressive at one point because he does...
Mickey does
team up with the locals to capture the bad people. So so so it's sort of a companion to one of my favorite animated cartoons
Papa by Daily Bob forty t, which is an that is a great piece of animation. Yeah. That's that's my... That's probably my favorite of the pop I cartridge period. And that they they're they're good. They show those all those artists to set their strength. And
other favorites
will love trouble I mentioned that well that one's purely for the art and for it being a domestic comedy
And
what's? I love seven goes too as well. Trying to think. Oh, gosh. Monarch of.
Oh, yeah. The basic... Basically,
you can't go wrong if listeners aren't familiar
with the
with these got and serial.
All of the Fan graphics books are worth buying But if you have to buy just a few get volumes
three through six of theirs
seriously...
You'd have to really stretch to say if there's anything weak in those books, specifically
four. Four...
Four is the top that that is the cream of the crop it has Island in the sky for legion,
seven ghosts and.
So that... Yeah. That four... If you need to cover blue golf
get volume for a that series. It's got goofy on the cover. So...
Yeah. The only... The only week
point is the the Robinson Scrooge.
Is it...
There's a couple of ethnic themes stories
Al that are not the best no sort...
Yeah. There's... I think it's search of jungle treasures the week... Right. That's the name that's the that that story a mess and it's it's funny that, you know, peep people always say you can't be critical at Disney and stuff well,
the commentary in that book, which David Wrote is very critical of that story, not just over the race connotation, but it's very messy otherwise. To Right. Right. And it's not just because of those ethnic stereotype.
But as you say, that that run of stories is truly incredible
as as far as my own taste, I mean, these are really obvious ones, but you guys mentioned the seven ghosts
That was such a revelation to me when I read that as a kid, I I couldn't believe the things that I saw keep doing in that one. And and, you know, everyone loves out with the phantom b. Yeah. Al
for a reason, I guess if I had to pick a couple of kind of odd ball stories,
some of the ones that he did with was it Bill Walsh Yeah. He
they teamed up for a couple of really
weird and un unsettling creepy stories
there's the, like, tomorrow wars. I think it was titled at some point, and then
like, the the ghost pirates.
I don't remember the title that one, but Gladstone collected those two in one of those big albums they did and and they're just so on satellite. I have that one. I remember that. The world of tomorrow was what I think they thought that. Right. That's what it was title that time
title though. Yeah. But but they're just and monarch of.
I re reread that a few months ago, and it just it blew me away in in terms of of how tight it was. But anyway, we could we could obviously
ramble on about the brilliant Floyd Gottfredson
in this Carl Barks
podcast for a while.
This is what I had done with my one of my early episodes where I covered
too many packs, which Barks took over from Merrill D Mari
I was like, this is not a great story. So I'm I'm kinda gonna use this as an excuse to talk about God and his collaborations with with D. But
but this is even more of an excuse to talk about him. You guys before we get into
the the proper story. I wanna share a couple more of the the quotes I have, and then we can kinda talk about how Barks
started out with his involvement with Mick. Because like, he had a little bit more than this. Mh.
So another quote I really like from Barks
talking about Floyd. He said Dot for instance greatest
contribution to Comics was quality. Key you remembered for making
complex continuity
easy to understand and read And adds
a more Al
way of saying what I was just reaching for a couple minutes ago. And
one more. He he said
Barks said it was the Mickey Mouse strip that he did that influenced my drawing more than anything else. Roy Crane, Prince Al, top by. These contributed
small things to my drawing style. It was all to help me adapt myself to Floyd way of drawing. So obviously,
super
super influential. Yeah. If you look at...
If you compare them, you know, a lot of the ways Sparks will draw characters,
profiles, it's very much
very much a child of God
style. And it it just showed, like, Barks did not pay. The Barks did not pay mine to any other of his contemporary
very much
But what what I was found interesting is that G was younger than Barks.
And especially in those days, people
generally did not look to someone younger. I mean,
floyd was only maybe about four or five years younger than Carl, but in those days, that that's a big leap. Because, like, if you look at... If you look at people, like you know,
at the warner studio, you know, tech avery was only maybe about
four, or five years older than Chuck Jones and Bob Lamp but they still saw him as the elder and the mentor.
So Yeah. That then... And it it's probably still holds true today too. So so that just showed, you know, the how powerful and influence Floyd Got was on Carl. Right.
Debbie, would you say that you're you're influenced in your drawing style by by either of the user artists?
Maybe to a small degree.
Certainly,
it sometimes I have to go and red draw Mer so he doesn't look like mickey those. Like pretty much the same nose. And if I get make nervous nose too small, it's like, wait, No. You're just drew nikki. Right. I feel like he's just in our cultural, like, in our brains. He just thinks out.
So you guys
bark as I mentioned, he this was not his very first involvement
with Nikki. So so that, I know that you know a lot about this. And you're you're a big bigger animation buff than I am. So feel free to chime in. Sure Debbie, if you know anything about business as well.
But what I understand is that Barb actually got his star. This was mentioned by David Ge and in that great. Feature. He gotta a start by submitting a couple of mickey mouse publicity.
Drawings
two Disney, and and that they liked that enough to just outright higher him. And and he got to work as an in between for some of the early Mickey mouse cartoons, but I my understanding is he's like, un credited oh, for the. No artist wherever credited. Up until maybe
towards the end of World war two on any of the shorts. So Right. Yeah. No no chance
carl Carl or floyd or whatever got gotten a credit at that position.
He did a couple of things
David outlines in his article that bark did...
What was it?
Northwest mount there was like It was like a story of Mickey as a mount, and it's done very much in the got and style, but a quoting, quoting from that article, Barks said, pretty wild and two logical for wall taste.
So it it kinda was set Gladstone what they wanted Nikki to be in those cartoons.
And it sure wasn't what was going on in the funny page
Right. I think even included the horse tango foot in those story Barks. Oh, yeah. Did. He did. Right that be. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Look somewhere. It was supposed to be tango foot first
animated appearance. I mean, he might... I think he's technically in something earlier, but that just shows how big of an influence was on Carl that he brought back you this
random character from Right. This Barks.
Yeah. Exactly. And
he... Bark ends up using... He recycles a gag from that for sheriff of Bullet Al. Mh. And and so he ended up getting linked
when that didn't quite pan out and that that never got released. He got linked with the story in Harry Reeves. Who I understand was basically a Donald duct man. Right. And it seems like that just kind of set Barks on that path. Right.
And so he he just end up sticking with the Donald staple of characters.
But but he did do, like, a random
pluto
story. I guess Pluto saves the ship was technically
his very first. Yeah. Either of you read it. I I I think it was in the old
Barks library, but right looked in smaller things because Barks didn't do the art. Right. But he did do the story for it and another person drew it. It was mostly a pant month thing, which makes sense for Pluto. Right. Exactly. Yeah. I've never gotten there beat it myself.
I'll have to I'll have to seek it out at some point. But as you say, he didn't he didn't do the art. He just plotted it. So... Right.
Donald Duck finds Pirate gold, you know, his collaboration with
his his jack hannah
collaboration with his fellow
is is more properly thought of as his first story. As can say Barks also did contribute a couple of gigs to the don't Inducks newspaper strip. I didn't know that. That's cool. I don't remember the dates on them. But in the in the
High
library of American comics, they mentioned a couple of day
Nice. What figured
the the gag for a couple of strips. And you're talking about the the A Al fe?
Yeah. They also I fe. Eat, I think contributed a couple of gigs to that. Absolutely
enough. And so I I guess it wasn't too long after he had done Pirate gold that he did get to do this Mickey story. It's surprisingly
early in his career. I my count he only did four of the longer what I call adventure length stories Mh. And and and about a couple dozen of the, like, ten pages are close to ten pages. So this this was pretty early.
I I guess it's is good a time as I to mention the the background of the story, rid of the rent hat appeared in four color numbers seventy nine in August of nineteen forty five. So I guess we are in the the hyatt of World War two at that point. Mh.
It feels like I'm traveling back in time. You know, I covered the early stories last year. This one has kind of an average number of prints. I usually mentioned that. We've got nine of them including the original It's it's short. It's a it's eleven pages. So one page longer than is typical, like, ten page story. But it definitely has the feel of his adventure story. Mh. Yeah. This came at a period when.
It's it's fascinating
to to look at it.
Because go... I I meant to mention it in that
Facebook messenger
threat of ours. Mh. But this was a period where the editors at Western were treating Barks is if he was just any other, you know, cartoon it's like, they did not... I mean, they kind of did know his niche was me was the was the Ducktales but, you know, he's getting assigned this, he's getting... He got assigned a pork pig story. He gotta assigned a couple with
the tech Severino character Droop, and then I what with the Mgm character, the organizing creation, Barney bear. Right. And and and finally,
you know, I think Carl what his foot down and, you know, I'm not doing any of these other characters
I know we were saying that,
you know, those might not be our favorite stories, but
I do love those barney bears stores because you just know, Carl did not care at all about those characters.
And, you know, there's there's a certain level of cy and the Ducktales stories of those years.
I mean, is like, roughly forty four to forty seven, but the barney Barks stuff is just amped up, like all the way. And it's like there's so
means Spirited. And he did... And that was one of the few times.
Carl was complimentary
of the other cartoon and Riders
at Western because a lot of the best stuff
a lot of those best barney stories weren't written by Carl. A lot of them were written by Guild turn another.
I think I don't remember if Gil was at Disney at all, but he was mainly M mgm. So that was how he got that gig. But... Yeah.
This one, I don't know how either of you first saw this, but it my for six exposure was in the nineteen
eighty nine ninety Nikki and Donald
Reed. From Glass. And that's why I first saw that one too. Yeah. It sounds like
meet... Me as well. It sounds like we all got this from the same source. Well, I think that's all It appeared in. I think that it... I don't have the index in front of me, but I think that was as first three reprint Severino close to it. Got it. I I noted this in my, like, interesting fax. This is by far. The biggest gap that I've seen doing this podcast
between the first printing and the second printing. Nineteen forty five to nineteen eighty eight, because it is. It appeared just a little bit earlier in
mickey Mouse color, I guess, that big lavish collection.
As an aside, it always cracks me up that that book, Mickey Mouse color is credited. By Floyd God
and Carl.
Which kind of under cells Gottfredson
and really good. Yeah. That was... It was it was very weird that that advertising, like, playing carl up as if he was like a prominent mouse coming in the same size. I know. It's it's... It was very strange. And they were, like, emphasizing, you know, these They they made a selling point like that it had, like, his in between from the
nineteen thirty six short through the mirror and it's like well,
cares, can you just give it all the floyd just this one time. I mean.
That's a great point, but I'm I'm glad you mentioned that because I saw I saw that mentioned on I think, I d and it just said on credit. So I was thinking to myself. Is that is that not confirmed? Because I love that. Cartoon too. That's right. Like, among my favorite of the Mickey shorts Right. Yeah. Your fan. It's... Oh, it's didn't really
you didn't really need him to have much of a
personality as... It it is just a pure spec. And that's right one of the things they were doing in that period that really worked was they were building up to the a snow white feature that was when they were just getting better and better with every short. Right. Because like was so bland in the questions that you needed like this high concept like username. Oh, the the funny thing too is that Carl
when he talked about this later,
when he was asked about doing this story later, he had no memory
of it. He... There there's a quote that says strange to say, this was in in a nineteen seventy response to a fan letter. Strange to say I had completely forgotten the story reading it I could see my drawing in the artwork. My old pay vouchers prove that I did do the art. So I'll puff out my chest and Brad that I did a pretty fair. Mickey and Goofy. Barks also
did this story for this.
There's
probably a lot... You know, you might read some of it online, like, you know, speculation or that, but I did confirm
when Barks told me, you know, if you wanna do this episode, you know, I made sure I did the research by asking David,
But the David says Carl
records did show that he was paid for story and the art. He didn't he didn't come up with to concept their idea, but he... This is his writing in his dialogue.
Okay. So probably,
probably what's his name
you
I have given him a springboard or something.
Right. But Debbie, what do you think about Karl comment there that he did they a pretty fair, mickey and goofy. Yeah. He the the interesting thing about it. And I'm sure we'll note that more as we go through it. Is that while his nikki and minnie and the rest, the may not always be on model. They're very
expressive.
Is Goofy is kinda weird, but even he's still expressive there too. Yeah. I I think I agree with with you. I his goofy, I find a little off putting, but I do like he's many and Mickey. Alright. You guys this has been a really great pre, but I I gotta a discipline myself a little
We gotta get into the actual story. No problem. So let's see. So you guys rid of the red hat opens up It's it's a very kind of as you say, like, you mentioned it some of the stories are more domestic than others.
It kind of has this domestic
opening
where Mickey and Minnie are doing some window shopping.
Many is doing the window shopping. And and she is Al
a very, like freely
red hat in a store window. And Mickey is looking at it, kind skeptical
saying it looks sorta of silly to him.
And most of this,
most of the first opening page is taken up with her just ad me it him being skeptical
and and her just going in and buying it. And and we get this, like, this feels very much like a kind of a hack need
stand up
comics, like
women be shopping joke a little bit. Right? Because she comes out, it's obviously the latest style or or bark sub position of what the latest style might be And he starts cracking up Al her saying that she looks exactly like a comic valentine
and she is, you know, she reacts as you might expect a girlfriend who's been humiliated
to, and she gives him the cold shoulder and strides away and he kind of for
Barks off and encounters Cla
cow.
Yeah. Al first page is pretty much seems like standard
duffy you'd see and the Sunday page is.
Nikki has some interesting expressions in there. Like, they look on his face in the second panel where he's good Al hand up and got this. Yeah. Look on his face. Mh. And one of the god and wipes in the fourth panel.
Yes. Where he's standing there with his hand,
and even the waist. His Barks are tilted. Mh.
How
leaking from one of the strips
Mh. Yeah. As I said earlier,
this is all straight out of Love trouble, the domestic
situation. And even including the local gossip Cla cow introducing her just for a couple of panels
that shows you know, Carl was paying attention.
I mean, I mean, Carl was a fan of that strip to knew those characters. And he got his job drawing that he drawing them. Is pitch to Disney. And...
Because I don't...
I I my memory is fuzzy on a lot of
the comic book... The original comic book stories of the period.
But I don't think Claire was too regulars
so... And even at that point, she was fading out of the god
strip, but, you know, there she is, he and
clearly, only a god fan would think conclude.
You know, she gives
mickey some advice. You a Must never size the girls hand. You gotta apologize to her
toner down them to get the box of candy.
And...
Yeah. I'm... You know, I you said it's a one if, but it's interesting what if but, you, I'm glad Carl didn't do anymore because, you know, it's... I I mean, he did the best job he possibly could, but it this clearly is just him going through the motions.
Yeah. He he's not really, like bringing anything
new or special to the table. It's it's it's a it's a find opening here. You you mentioned
that oh, yeah. We've so we've got Cla here. It's nice to see as you say, he knows how to use the stable of supporting characters.
It it shows you that he really did follow Gottfredson.
You know, like this this inclusion here. Because there are other times when you read writing about Barks that it's clear that he didn't really
follow a lot of the the work that the Disney studio No. Was putting out later on. So I I find it notable that he like clearly did know and appreciate. Floyd. So onto to the next page as you say,
Cla gives him this this piece of of advice and he goes off to make good and make amend with minnie.
He buys a nice box of chocolate
and and he spots her by that really ga
hat that stands out so much. And and the whole point of this page is to give us this little double take a moment where he taps, mini on the shoulder, and it turns out to be this really
is really unpleasant looking
mouse or rat woman character that only looks like me from behind. Mh. And and she immediately
sc him saying not so loud you don't and and we start to get the inkling that there's like, this case of mistaken identity more than more than
what we're were initially see. What do you guys think about about the rap girl? She's hideous.
She really is.
I remember reading this the first time, It it... It Barks upon. You you do not expect this whatsoever.
And this is showing Barks of skill at... What's the word
mis direction and staging.
Because there's no you have no inclination Al the is not minnie mouse.
And you have this test feature. She's got... Basically got... You know, this is another love trouble reference basically got more to mouse features,
you know, the now
and they go up to the roof. It's really striking to me how unpleasant she looks with so little.
Like yeah. It's got a mad magazine drawing or anything. He didn't go that far, but, no. It it it does the job. And and many is just always coded as so
incredibly feminine
and and soft. Even when she's angry, she's usually soft So I think that's why this is so jarring. The same interesting thing to note is looking up at this page. Look at the third panel on the top of the page. You see some guy riding a cycle oh.
It's a good catch.
That's that's sparks all the way. Yeah. It's kind of pre... Pre dates when he would have characters writing those little one wheel card. With
introduced.
Yeah. Because God wasn't really one for the background. Gag. I imagine.
I imagine that half the time he didn't have the space, especially in the forties.
Yeah.
Exactly. In a in a newspaper strip. It's not something you you can't really distract from your punch line that way, I guess. So you mentioned they go up to the rooftop, she's kinda leading him there and and and I I like some of the little
that are
just reminding us that were in the mid forties here, you know, the elevator
operator. And and Mickey is very confused
she's basically
pushing him into this like, exchange. She's saying, what... What's the problem here? I'm wearing the red hat you're carrying the box of candy.
You know, anyone who's seen like a Hollywood
feature,
a Spy
probably has an ink inkling that this is one of those, like, Mh. Criminal
exchanges
But but for the sake of the story, Mickey has to be really confused. He doesn't
understand what's going on. And she instruct him to take the small package that she gives him to mister Who's
right away. And when he tries to follow her, he is he's stopped by the elevator operator. I like the panel, where did the... Where you see the oven elevator doors shutting and then you see Nikki
at this funny angle, you never see him at. Yeah.
Here in that sort of strange way and is nose sticking up. Right. He runs smack into it. Kind of flattens his ears. That that feels like maybe Barks was like, well, what what can I do with Mickey and his anatomy? You know, something they didn't have a model sheet for. It's like what that look like. Right. I I feel good.
Tell me what you think, Debbie because you probably have a better eye for this, but I I feel like we're seeing Nikki at slightly different angles.
Than what Gottfredson
would have typically drawn Yeah. A few of them, like the third panel there. You have
nikki and not many. Up in the top at this sort of dramatic angle. Where you see the cities escape there kind of at an angle where she's kind of pointing outside of the panel than that one. And again, you see all these city drawings that look like later, how Barks with draw Duck berg Yeah. Mh. And definitely
says, hey. Well, there's a lot more use of still silhouette this story and that was not something God ever
particularly use
unless, you know, he was doing a really dramatic stage. I honestly can't think of one off my head. I mean, that's literally seldom them me used it. But Carl used so it's all the time even to the point where that model that model sheet you get have Inducks in nineteen fifth get a little gag in the corners and Don't try send those so all the time.
Right
But
no. It's it's it's interesting
that
now... Now we see that Mickey got this
package, and he's gonna go to the straight to the police. Now that's definitely a non... I don't know if that... If it's particularly a god a approach to Mickey here.
Because then definitely,
you see a generic policeman on the next page.
Yeah not here. Yeah. Exact that's exact. That I was gonna say no cheap hair or no detective Casey.
So that... That's Al that was an interesting... That... Well, it's a departure
you know, only because, you know, Carl care might have cared enough about Cla, but he didn't wanna put, you know, the usual
got cops in this one. Right.
Why don't you tell us about this page that Yeah. The this is interesting.
Vicky brings the package and, you know, it's...
Diamond ring, and it's like, no, It's not a diamond ring. It's a hun of glass. And he gets dismissed for the
pretty harshly, I gotta say that's it's a very un
type exchange because, you know, he's telling
them basically, stop wasting our time here, and it's almost I'm gonna but he's helping him that Right.
Because he puts the... He puts the... And he puts the police officer and it's so add for that panel. And then Nikki rejected runs into Goofy and as we know,
this is deaf... Val this is beck where. It is. Go little god
influence.
Goofy always through shea stupidity and by accident then, he finds out what's what's up with this ring. And turns out there's something in there, I it's a Gladstone ruby. Right? Yeah. If you mean if you need to move the plot along,
a little bit of of goofy
dipping,
is is what what it takes. What do you think, Debbie?
Than the fact that I think that is probably not one of the best drawings of goofy when he first shows up. Mh. No. Yeah. That that very first goofy panel is kind of on a unnatural pose
He might have had... He might don't have had rep too many references for Goofy. I I've got an I'm wondering if love trouble might have been reprinted around the time he was working on this
story as to why he might have used it to model so many other things, but the Barks he might have had to use might not have had too many usable drawings of goofy
Right. Yeah. You know, I've always thought that of the... What do they calling? The fab five, if you're talking about kind of the main Disney
domestic characters,
Goofy gotta be the hardest of them to draw. Yeah. Yeah. Absolutely.
I've tried to draw a goofy. He is a pain the neck to draw. Mh. Yeah. He's all... He's all like these weird
joints,
and he's so much more stretched out.
Even his hat is life stretched out. So Yeah. It's it's fun seeing Barks version. Of goofy, but
but it definitely looks a little more jarring than, like his... I I settle in.
Pretty quickly into, like, buying his version of Mickey, I think. As I read this story. And and many, I I really like his version of many here. But But goofy just looks a little bit jarring.
Yeah. Goofy is an example of how fat how
unique Disney
design word got. And of course, Goofy was introduced in the early black and white cartoons. I'm not too early, but like, you know, midway through the black and white run. But, you know, because nikki is just a knock off of a lot of other care
really in design wise, but Goofy is a more interesting
combination of shape and curves
and...
Yeah. It's
not really for the faint of heart to try him master. They're they're... And that's why a lot of modern
combinations of goofy looks so unpleasant and sometimes.
But he doesn't do too badly here. There's a couple that
are pretty clearly conference and crib.
That one was, like, kind pretty though ain't it, you know,
that that looks like that's a face from a guy
Scrooge. Right. Yeah. So on the next page, we
figure out a little bit more and
As you mentioned, he surmise that it's a ruby. I always like seeing the word home ding.
When when Goofy asked his is ruby worth a lot of dough, mickey.
He says I'll say it is, and this one's a home ding. And and so Nicky is not gonna go back to the police. I guess that's why the
that cop was so hard on him Barks needed to give a reason for him not to approach the police again. So he
says that he'd like goofy to hide
the the ruby because, you know,
whoever's has been smuggling this or passing it off won't suspect him. This seems like a little bit of a logical leap to meet you guys sometimes
So Goofy
hides it in his shoe.
But this this might be my favorite
panel of goofy here with his yes.
Foot sticking out through his
socks that are totally falling apart. Right. But we definitely needs a new pair of socks.
Yeah. Well, I'm surprised Carl held back. He doesn't really have Goofy patented whole
shoe haul there, you know? Because that was such a common commonality.
And that was true. But I know what the... In mind printing here, it kinda looks like there's a little circle. Yeah.
Color.
Maybe Huey, gotta reach... Maybe you got an una approved re tread since this is still World war too, who knows I was thinking this might be one of those instances of an overly aggressive color.
Right.
Not not realizing that's supposed to be a hold. Yeah. I think that's my be might be right. I'm looking at it. Yeah. That and whoever
the modern colors just went that way. Yeah. I think Carl was trying to draw Goofy
shoe haul. This page also has another great panel
after mickey Goofy
side to go see, mister Hu.
There's this great panel is the one two the... Yeah. Seventh panel.
It's where minnie
surrounded by all these blockers.
Everyone is knocking at her and she's doesn't notice
Pete is behind or she's just to overcome with her humiliation, and she's,
you know,
realizing maybe Mickey was right about this, you know, candy cane months us she's wearing.
And, no. This just shows, you know, even at this is only Barks is third year
drawing comic books full time. And it's just a... Your your eye is on mini, but all this other stuff is going on. A lot is going on. You've got you got this
this
one rich ladies looking back and the news
newspaper boy, Al little kid, and you got pete looking over her ominous
as well. So... Oh and it's also
nineteen
forties. Mh. It's great. You're you're right. That is a great stand out panel. And, yeah, we've got Pete
a costing
mini
say, you know, telling grabbing her very forced fully and saying. What's the idea break in our date? I've been waiting and waiting up on the roof.
So, you know, we were further figuring out that the is a case of mistaken and identity here. You guys, I'm on record Al being a huge fan of pete.
I I love the early Barks stories where he used him as a foil for for the dots.
This one feels a little weirdly off model to me and and
He's a little bit too sm for my taste. Yeah. I gonna say he does look a little off here, but everybody looks Al little odd you kinda makes you wonder if he wasn't like, okay. I really don't wanna do this story, so I just have run it through. Right
the... Yeah. There there's better looking keys by Barks. Even in his amazon's lori board panels when you did, he did several
donald Inducks cartoons with pete. And portia, it wouldn't be a Mickey mystery without a kid kidnapping,
many
is
caused by pete again and taking for a ride
and he's gonna take her to see who it because he thinks they've all been double crossed with the ring. And there's just... I mentioned in our chad this one panel,
Yeah. One two three, four five six panel six on page six
where he's got the pistol and mini face. Don't make any noise sister there. You won't ever yell again. That... This really calls to mind a lot of god
strips where there's been an abduction, you know, because I I can't call quite recall Barks using this again, but it's like you wanted to use it once. There's one beautiful one and the foreign legion story where Mickey is in the back see. You gotta look at that one that that impressed so many of my kirk friends when I just posted the panel, but this one's pretty... This one's pretty
terrifying because many sweating bullets immediately.
Yeah. It is great panel. You're right. Her fear is really Al yeah. I really love that expression on her face. She's like that's another one of those that... Yeah. It's off model, but it's off model for good reason. Mh. Well, I've I had at least one director friend of mine say. It's not off model if you recognize the character.
But I can definitely see where, you know, you don't wanna go too far because these aren't type of characters where you do a lot of distortion with.
And Barks figure that out very quickly and who's our. Right. And I feel like we're not really that customs
to Severino many like this
afraid. I mean... She's been in real danger in the God person's and stories before, but, like, she's She's afraid her her life here. And and so we
transition as as Pete is heading with her to who's it? Mick Goof.
Very quaint looking him up in the phone book as one did,
and they find that he lives at Boulevard and the rich part of town is as Goofy points out.
And it really is a nice stage run
lavish mansion
And I I like what Goofy says here. Mickey says here's the place sure a swell one, isn't it and Goofy says, yep, but the guy that lives in there couldn't be no crook. He must be a millionaire.
And and there's a lot of a lot of things that one could say in response to them. But but I think they're already there on this subject.
Say the building there almost looks like you'd expect to see Scrooge duck come out the door,
shoot them away.
I was thinking it looked a lot like f t alex
mansion.
And. In the guild man, Just.
Out of that, just my memory here. On the next page, we've got Nikki and Goofy kinda considering their options.
Talking about call... Goofy wants to call the police, but then Mickey ends up seeing that really
distinct hat of menus. And so he he feels like he has to scale the fence
while
while goofy worries
basically about about him and gets ready to call the police if necessary.
Mickey cancels him
don't lose your shoe because, of course, that movie is in there. I do like du he's gosh. Oh, he says gosh, not in ga.
He says gosh. How could I lose it? It's tied on my foot.
And, you know, to his horror, he does
recognize the label that it must be minnie hat since it's from the R Hatch shop. And in that moment, Pete
snatch, mickey as well
and
plans to bring him to the boss as goofy runs off. So you guys we've got some
acceleration here. Those a couple of nice panels too with pea grabbing nikki. You've got this really nice. Sweet action there and then Goofy running off at the bottom of the page, both have some very
innovative looking action.
Yeah. I like that one of of pete mid grab with Mickey. That we don't really get any recognition.
If this were Gottfredson in there would be some
back and forth between Mickey and pete. Right? Right. It's pretty much to get us from point eight to point b here. Right. It's says this, you know, now now thinking about now that you've made that point, it's almost as a... Whatever
springboard he might have gotten
just called for a generic
tough guy and Barks just included pete because, you know, well, that's the... That's the guy some tough guy.
You do. And they needed a villain and and anything. They often just went to pee You guys are old hands at Disney. So I'm sure you know this, but one of my favorite fun fax is that pete actually pre dates making that. Yes.
So the next page is we've got a goofy sequence
in in Severino sense.
We've got goofy
running to get help
and he doesn't get very far before. Debbie, do you wanna tell us about this this sequence?
Sure. Got kinda stop. He's got this
ouch.
Must have some little stones and the shoes.
Sure hurts when I run, and it looks like it hurt
I a holding cat in the panel. Yeah. He stops and piece out his shoes, which I'm sure everybody reading the book
snacks there for it going no.
And yeah. Know I can make time.
Just gonna say next jeez. Goes to the police office
there's is like to tell them what's going on. They don't bother us we're busy. The famous v ruby has been stolen.
This this is where the p gets a little
messi
because I have to imagine that there there had to be some real change for, you know, there there had to be some sort of substantial reason why the police ignored goofy
when he's coming to them for help. About, you know, their top. Their top
the freelance detective just been abducted.
So... Yeah. This is where it gets a little rushed the belong. Yeah. It... It definitely feels accelerated like there's a few panel missing moments here. I feel like we could've have had some inkling about the the faith Ruby earlier,
which which, of course must be a little parity of the hope Diamond, I guess. Right? Faith and hope. Yeah. I was gonna say, it's another instance where the story feels a little generic and that it wasn't.
Least off serves from the newspaper strip so they don't seem to recognize Nikki a goofy in this one. Mh.
We talked of Nikki being there
top three vlan detective, but he's not really coming off as that in this store no. It's just
generic
version of Mickey here. Yeah they're just generic police officers.
They see Goofy and think oh, it's that do this. Mh. Yeah. He might as well just be Donald.
Right? Like, he might as well this be one of Barks, every man versions
of of donald caught up in something. I do like the silly bit with Goofy empty
his shoe. It feels very on character.
I like I like that it gives you this as you say that head slapping moment. And and so we transition back to the house on
Boulevard.
We've got this very generic looking tough guy that is... That pee is bringing Mickey to
Pete doesn't recognize Mickey so they don't seem to have this history. He just says I caught dis fella a snoop around a place mister Who's. And as Mickey goes to explain, he hears
many complaining, many mini insisting
she be let out. She's being held captive.
And he indicates that yes, I know her that's minnie mouse. This leads us to the guy wondering where the ring is, and
Mickey says, I I know it's right here in my pocket, a girl and a red hat gave it to me. And
the the two tufts are
distracted and delighted by seeing it is in fact to the ring of course, it's only gonna be the glass. Housing.
Like you said... Like Debbie has said, this is starting to be where it's a little too generic you know, to be, you know, to get fully invested in, this is a great story of any kind. And but it does when they find out that the the ruby is gone. It does lead to probably the best bit of dialogue in this story, which is obviously Carl's Now you don't. Through this portal past the fastest mice in the world that's which is way
way way way, way too clever. For any Mc mouse story published by Western.
So Yes. That is that is Carl's
contribution to the mickey lexicon.
Yeah. Yeah. That... This upcoming page is like the stand out. Right? As as the mice are celebrating and
the two tufts are discovering the ruby is gone. Mickey he get soft that great line that you mentioned.
And then what happens that Oh, well,
there's a quite a horrifying bit of
violence with the door getting
shattered to pieces by the Tommy Guns. Of Pete and who's it, and they jump... They jump... The mice jumped out the window and they try to hide and escape, but
this is I I can't help with reading a little bit of a miso
bit to this story because it's many stupid hat that gives them away. Yeah.
Know So it's all the woman's fault I cast. But that's that's sort of a reading on this and it's
it's not the most particularly
pleasant reading of it
So so
Yeah. I agree. Yeah. But but I do love the team gun. Yeah. We're the Tommy Fire.
It's it's so... It's weird to say this, like Gun violence is terrible etcetera, etcetera, but I I do love to see gun play in my mouse comics. Right. Yeah. It's not Al mouse kinda without a It reminds me of what we had with with Floyd god.
Mh. The bullets going through the door. Almost says something I have been old. Nineteen thirties gangster movie. Mh. Yeah. Definitely evo that sort of feel. I like the sound effects
and, you know, it seems particularly
unfair when when Nikki is gonna, like, glare at her hat giving them away. Because on the previous page,
he... When he's reunited,
he... He's bragging
I even returned your hat, you know? Like,
So it seems it seems like a a weird little dig at
again, Well, Mickey, it's your fault you brought it back. Right.
So that almost seems like a donald duck moment. Oh I get it it's that cat.
Yeah. That little Al of.
Yeah. Yeah. I think you're right. So
the the two mice are caught.
I like seeing key, you know, just holding them both by the neck.
And who's is interrogating them about the Ruby?
And Mickey is pretty
truth full to the bad guys throughout this brief story. Says my friend Goofy got it. I'll get it for you if you let me go. And who's it says you know, he says, no, you've gotta bring the ruby and Al let you both go. But if you call the police, you'll never see her again. And and at that moment,
goofy just very conveniently shows up in the open window behind them And and says, hey, Nikki. The police and and it kinda trails off.
Do you wanna tell us about the sequence that? Yeah. This is this is definitely God
influenced. There are shadows of this and the other stories where Goofy
completely by accident will save the day without realizing it. And Mickey
being quick on his feet uses that as...
Now, it is the cop. So alright. Don't shoot officer
Don't shoot up sergeant and
he uses it so he gets... He gets to take their the villain guns away and tie them up. Because they can't see that just the local local goofy. And...
It's...
I mean, this is a silly story. So it's so... This is okay. I can... I can buy this a little bit of can try and here. Yeah. I can buy it too. It's it's one of those this is a common thing, right, A bluff sequence
The thing is, like, bluff,
it just... It it... It's all dialogue based, so I like, it just doesn't carry over
that well Inducks economic, it feels lot paced to me. I'm fine with prints.
What it's Yeah. This this bluff goes on for half a page.
You... Yeah. I would think if it was one of the golf percent strips it will be wrapped up a little tighter. Yeah. What do you think? Does it work for you, Debbie? Like I say, the whole story really has sort of a generic feel, but then you get these little bits in there that like that and you already said it feels like, oh wait, this is This does feel like a god moment And then you have this fantastic look on Nikki face as he's taking the gun.
Yeah. Yeah. That is the most you're looking nikki. Yeah. Right. Yeah. The only time I can think of that is like, when he's supposed to be in under, like, mine controllers something Right. You're right. He looks...
He he looks very
like, he's b. It's it's a fun expression though. And then, you know, the the next page is the eleventh. This is like, Carl bonus page, I guess. Usually has ten badger
of this length, but he's wrapping it up here. They're tying up the two bad guys Goofy is questioning
where's the police. I don't see no sergeant and He explains you are the police and sergeant and the the bad guy is predictably
outraged.
And
goofy kind of
unnecessarily wraps it up saying I'm just goofy. The police wouldn't listen to me. It feels like maybe a little more explanation than we need. Yeah. It almost feels like a drawback throwback to or I'm mickey mouse, and this is Goofy. Yes. It is.
Alright.
This guy.
Yes. And and then the the story wraps up mostly in the police station
where Mickey
gets his, you know, just
congratulations and apologies from the police.
And
they
try to figure out where the ruby is.
Mickey says give us the ruby
goofy. And Debbie, what how does this play out when when he goes to get the the ruby? Oh in typical Goofy fashion,
gone, I must to ship it out of my shit with the little stones that was hurting me and, of course, making like what?
And then, of course,
something that would only be a good that point
It's carlin a soc. Mh
packets.
Yeah. Right
I I like that. It's it's a little... It's gross, but it's it's also
completely in character. That... Once again, it's completely by accident that he didn't throw it away. It's it's saved by that disgusting sock that he's never gotten replaced. It's really cute look on his face one the Al and that's the closest it looks to a a with traditional goofy there. This happy look on his face. Yeah. I have the same thought. It feels like he's
it feels like he's kind of gotten goofy right by the end of the store.
Just in time to never have to draw never again. Right?
And and so he...
They returned the faith Ruby,
the police officer allude to a big reward. And the story closes out with them walking past another hat shop with mini pondering buying another hat
and he says, not another red one I hope And
I'm not sure this is aged that well, but she says no indeed, I'll never buy another hat that you don't like mickey. Mh. And it is otherwise, a cute little closing
silhouette of the two ice. So it looks very sweet. It's almost the head of our barrett and oh
not another hat.
Right.
Right. Exactly.
Yeah. So so you guys that was it. That was a brisk little
eleven pager. There was obviously a lot to say about it.
But what what are your what are your overall thoughts
about the story? I see it's a pleasant
yet, really not outstanding.
Story. I mean, it's it's a fun greasy want to read through, but it's
despite being included what called Mickey Mouse classics. It really isn't
Right.
Completion this.
Right. It's it's as we've been saying, it's just a little too generic and you just can clearly tell Carl Barks as her was not in this.
One thing as I was going through the story just now,
he did not draw a single flash panel in this entire story. Other than the opening panel, they're... It's
it's strictly just, you know, it's the fort tier story. No, not no no change up whatsoever.
And I'm just call... I'm just reminded of what Carl said about that one ji
piper story never finished is like, well, you're not gonna pay me what this is worth. So I'm just not gonna draw it. And this is... This seems to be it. I mean, there's... I mean, of course, Huey,. He's just too good did not draw something, but
draw some interesting panels. But Right. You know, this is just going through the motions. It's he's just doing it. It's an assignment and
you can sorta of be grateful that Chase Craig and though the other guys never gave Carl another store... Mickey story to do because I mean this is perfectly passed
and perfectly fine. But, you know,
you you wanted this guy because he wrote Donald Inducks cartoons that walt disney me approved. So keep them on that character. Yeah. I mean, we we know how it turned out. Right? And And I guess, like, I'm thinking I'm sitting here thinking we talked about, like, the what if. Right? What if he had kind of branch out and maybe done more I have no doubt he would have come up with some classic Mickey stories. Right. And I also have to think to myself, like, his very first
plotted and written and drawn
adventure was
the mum ring. Mh. Right. Like, and and, like, it's not a perfect story. But for his first independent story, it has some real greatness to it. Mh. Like, I think it's an rat
worthwhile first effort. In a way that this just isn't. Yeah. The money ring has one of my all time favorite panels.
Where you see this terrified terrifying donald Inducks screaming
the mum, the mum they're sitting up in their case is eating my family.
Yeah. Yeah. That's a great one. I I'm I'm a big fan of that too. There's a lot to really like about the story. With the absurdity of they're eating my sandwich.
Right. And his pal fear. But but... Yeah, he kinda hit the ground running with Donald
in a way that he just he just didn't with Mickey and... Yeah. He he just clearly found something that was a character and a stable that was
more interesting to him than this, and it's also... Well, you he's probably think Carl Barks is probably thinking well, Floyd already perfect this why why should I
try
let let me try this other character that nobody else seems to get. Yeah. I find that totally believable. Right? Like, like, Mickey
has been done.
I
I'm good at Donald. I will see what I can do with him. I'm sure you never, like, sat down and thought, I'm gonna be the duct man, but that's that's what happened. Yeah. I it would have been nice. To see his classic mickey story. I'm not gonna lie. Would have been... It would have been fun to see it. Like, if I could pick and choose, there's a couple of non classic that I might trade of the dock stories, but I would I wouldn't wanna risk, like, miss I'm one of his his true class.
I will note too that he
participate in the ever
ongoing eras of horace horse calls.
Like, Cla without Horace, that that becomes the norm at some point, but I think it's a shame. Yeah. Won't even clear a belly didn't really kinda have her voice down when he wrote it. She just comes off sounding like some generic
glitch with her dialogue if you looked at the god
never quite rode her as
sounding like something out of the lavender the way Right. Router there. Yeah. And I... I like the dynamic.
I like the Al and Horace.
Stuff in those...
The that reg rich stories is one of the best do. Yeah.
Floyd did.
No. What's just say... It's it's a courier.
It's jeff... It's definitely
one of the better Carry
but, you know, it's... Yeah. I might have liked to seen what Barks would have done with Mickey when he was real... Like, he just went off the adventures... The Ducktales. And he just went off the duck adventure for one month and then a mickey But who knows it might have been just as, you know, detached as this. Right?
And and he himself, I didn't type the quote, but I saw something where he he said he he couldn't do Mickey and donald.
Together for some reason, which of course god
did do. Right. Not me... Donald was never that memorable in in the got. And the stories.
You guys I find it very interesting. I'm kind of gonna transition now into what the community thinks about this. I I always like to check on Inducks
to see where the the rankings are. For Inducks.
And you guys... This is I think, Huey,
unfair.
This one has one of the very lowest ratings. Of any Barks story. It's a it's a seven point o on index.
That eye.
Well, like, there are so many stories with that ranking
that it's more useful. It's more instructive to look at its like, or ring and it is not story nine thousand nine hundred and thirty eight as of, you know, today. Out of the forty three or so thousand stories. And and that's just so out of out of the range of his other just adequate stories that I I I can only assume that people are like,
it's his mickey mouse story. I don't like his mickey mouse story. Like to me, this is a fine story. Is nothing special. But but it's not markedly
worse than most of his, like, standard Ducktales page no. But but it's it it's
the the words probably un remarkable.
So that's probably,
you know,
that's probably the major factor. Right. Yeah. I think it's just kind of a footnote
really in that
kinda like how we did one party p. One anti panda,
one mickey mouse. It's just kind of something there that maybe completes slight seek out.
Right. I agree. I just don't think there's any... It ranks below some of his pretty weak later Inducks stories, I think. So...
So I just... I just don't think that's too fair. But but it it really is what it is. You know, it's a fine story. I would think it odd if it ranked below things like grandma Inducks
farm friends. Oh, boy. Right.
Well, least Karl wrote these, this one too. Yeah. Yeah. It's got some decently sharp writing. So Let's see. I... Yeah, I'd wanted to make sure that we touched on kind of the hypothetical the what if.
And and it sounds like we're all in pretty much a agreement that we're glad he stuck with du. I think it's just he worked with Donald so long but the fields that he just
understood the characters. Yes.
Exactly.
Exactly the character in ways that even the people doing the films didn't think to do so.
If far didn't think to expand donald from being just this little guy who uses is temper to sort of an every man and into a zone specific character. Right. Exactly. Yeah. That's well set. I think he he elevated him from
from the films. For sure. So thank you guys very much for for joining me to, you know, do this
unique episode. I really appreciate it
hopefully, people will check out your your web webcam. Debbie. You wanna tell us the
the web address Oh, sure. That's super easy. It's w w w dot fluffy mer dot com. And Mer is
m e y yeah. Right? M e r v I n? Yeah. It's an odd spelling it digitally, but it was an odd name.
Right. Sad anything you wanna promote? No. Not nothing off offhand. But thank you.
But
like you said, by those buy those Gottfredson and. Yeah
Absolutely.
Get get them all there still in existence.
That's right.
Alright, guys. Well, thanks, again, I really appreciate it, and you can check out Barks remarks on the various socials, Facebook,
Instagram, and
will catch you guys another time. Alright. Thank you. Because so much us Rae. I never done this sort of thing before it was fun.