Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of sc Mc Ducktales and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge con of all time
This episode is a ten page podcast all about one of his short stories, get ready to enjoy our remarks. Welcome back to Barks remarks. I'm Mark Sever marino, a grown man who enjoys Ducktales comic books and enjoys talking about them with the guests that I've gotten to meet as part of this podcast project. And I'm fortunate to have a new guest c hosts today, and I'd like to have him introduce himself. Thank you, Barks. Yeah. My name is Ruben. I'm
barely grown man that also
enjoy the the comics and have, course done since I was little kid because I am Scandinavian.
Yeah. It's I've said before, that I I feel like the Scandinavian scandinavians
have kind of partial ownership
of the bard comics because you you folks do you appreciate them so much more out there? It's really a part of culture. Where you sc as a see like
an image of a rich
greedy man, almost a capitalism
itself sometimes. And guest goose he's... Whenever you say that someone's lazy,
you called me some gender. Yeah. Pretty much. That's awesome. Yeah. It's really embedded in culture. That's my impression, you know? That you could you could france,
the the sc and and Donald stories and and people know what you're talking about. You know, I grew up being such a big fan but never getting to talk to anyone about them or or
sort of shared recognition. So it's it's it's a real pleasure
to get to to meet people. And
today, we are doing
an episode of the ten page part test where we look at one of Barks many
short ten pager. We usually do the adventure length stories here, but I like to... I like to take a break and really enjoy some of these funnier ones because, you know, Barks parks did a ton of these. And today, we get to talk about the master rain maker. I I'm a really excited ruben, and I gather that this is one of your favorites.
I do. I do I do... Because as a child, that I actually was more into the ten than the adventure length stories. I don't know why I was probably more of a comedy guy as a child. I I wasn't in for the trail. I was in laughs. So I really love ten. And of course, I love the series where the stories where Donald
mastered some profession
and well, we'll all know what happens at them. Oh, yeah. That's a great point. Right? Because this this story is one of those stories that is where he gets to master some profession. I first read this one in a collection, one of the albums that glad stone comics put out in the... I think it was the late eighties, and they called it the brittle mastery
of Donald Duck and they curated
five of those
stories together. Oh, that would sure be a to have. Absolutely.
And they went together perfectly
because they all have this sort of story structure
that that you were just talking about. Do you do you feel like you can kind of summarize what those mastery stories tend to be about Well, of course, there's always like, donald. It stocks off. It doesn't explain why, but he somehow
mastered a profession of some weird, like he's he's a hairdresser.
He's a gardener and rolls story. Like, a really specific profession. And this one is a rain maker. Most of the time, he's doing great. Barks is showing various ways of how he masters this profession in really a really
way and impressive, of course And it ends
mostly with him trying some really hard but his ego
or something like that. Knocks him over and it ends off with him. You're absolutely right. Right? He's he's at the height of his success with it. Exactly. And then comes the downfall. And it takes over. Yeah. Yeah. And and it's great. Like you said there they're these really
obscure
or
unexpected professions And and this one is this might be the best one of the Brittle mastery
stories. Maybe. I I love the master record, I think. Yeah. That's the contender, but this one is just such a joy read I've got a wonder. Right? You're you're Scandinavian, you're from Norway. Does this story feel like, relatable?
I know that it's very cold and Norway, but obviously, you guys do get do get some measure of rainfall. Is there a lot of farming? It is and I live in the southern Eastern part of Norway well there is a lot of farming in Norway. Right. So It's it's mostly farm phishing and
like,
woods Yeah. Lumber jack. Lumber. That's yeah. Yeah. So, like, this is To me, this always felt like a very
quintessential
american
story. Right? Because it it feels like such a there's such a focus on water and rain. You must remember that Norway do have a really long coastline.
So yeah I'll actually live really far from the coast, but many generations are really are they really do know hard weather. And rain and wind and stuff like that. So I believe this is really relevant. Actually really as in Norway and Scandinavia. All I believe. That's awesome. Yeah. So I generally give myself permission to go to research these a little bit less, but I know I did some some research about this because it you almost have to learn a little bit to talk about something like rain make So we'll talk a little bit about that, but I do wanna...
I do wanna talk a little bit about the specific comment. I jump around a little bit with the ten page punch So this one is a little bit later than where I am with the regular
chronology
for the adventure length stories. This one was first published. It has... It has a publication date of September nineteen fifty three. And this this of course came out in walt Disney's comics and stories
in the United States.
And yeah, that's about all the backgrounds.
Oh, I do like to mention how many reprint it has in the Us. This one's been printed to nine times total. Anything you wanted to say about the
publication of this in Norway? Well, I have to check this up and it has been reprinted
Al really big amount of time. So I I didn't check up the exact number. Actually, I have all of the publications I own in my collection right in front of me. And I was surprised to find that I do own a complete Carl box library. I do have about a third of all the weekly
down dot comics that I unpublished
throughout the years. So
I was really shocked to find... I'm not that big of a collector actually. Just bragging about my huge weekly collection, but I do not own everything. That's the... That is the point. And still, I do own five copies of this. Nice. And that just says something about how times minute times has been printed and how popular it is. Right. I only have... As far as I know, I only have three copies of this. Yeah. But like I said, I I read this one just over and over as a kid. It it has such a delightful
concept, you know? Just just to
give a bit of a synopsis Right? The the job that Donald is very good at in this one is that he is a rain. He pilots a crop dusting plain. And he seeds the clouds to produce rain for for those who need it. And Carl Bark has like, such an interesting version
of this job, which is technically a real thing, but obviously, it's very exaggerated in this or absolutely.
So before before we go ahead, mark, I would really love to go through some of the translation of the Norwegian titles of this story. Oh, yeah. By Al it was first published actually as early as in nineteen fifty four on the year after its first publication. And then it hadn't had no title as usual. And later in nineteen seventy two, it was translated
it got pile of sol very.
Which translates to Jealous Whether. I like that then. And then the title in nineteen ninety three came that i
familiar with Nine marketing. The rain maker. So that's the very, like, exact translation. But I was curious so I also looked into the other scandinavian
translations of this story And the swedish called it landmark,
the rain maker.
And also called it then free. Down the the rang marker. The flying rain, Denmark, nineteen seventy two,
invest
the the pilot of Rainy.
And this one I found really interesting. The danish title from nineteen seventy nine, I'm gonna try this danish one. Scheme seems glen,
the green monster of Jealousy. That's great. That's and we to come back to that.
Yeah. That one plays on on one of those the the more memorable. There's a lot of memorable parts and this really quick.
So let's let's do it ruben. And let's go ahead and talk about what happens in this story
i'll I'm gonna summarize what's happening on the first page and then then we're gonna alternate. And and as we have comments, we're gonna go ahead and make them. So right right off to bat on the first page of the master rain maker. We see Donald. I I like this. We we already see him as you mentioned like in the middle of it. You know? We don't... Barks isn't interested.
He only has ten pages. So he doesn't wanna show him getting good at it. He's already good. And we see him in the process of taking an order
or reign
from a very stereotypical
looking farmer. It's the works farmer.
Yes. One of Barks pro
farmers.
I like that in the narrator box, he refers to him as donald duck m r m. As though it's like a degree credential, masculine
maker.
And he just he editorial in the narrator box. He says the boy is good. So Marx is is being very economical.
He's telling us exactly what we need to know at the beginning. He is perfect
making rain and he's very good. And and so he's taking an order from this farmer for two inches of rain on an x shaped field. And there's this great bit of,
like, almost menu taking where Donald is telling him his prices for
square round or s shaped and and he gives him a price based on the x field being a little bit more difficult. And the farmer is very specific. He doesn't want any ring to fall on his Huey,.
Next door. And and so we see a little bit more of the mechanics of Donald setting up and and Huey, dewey Louis are clearly key assistance. They helped Donald set up and he prepares to take off. Any any comments on this great opening page ruben? Not anything more than you really see how like, confident don here. It knows this stuff. She's still on the earth. He really knows the stuff and it's not like, over the top. Yeah. He's proud of it, but it doesn't show that show it that much. Right. He's just someone who who knows what he's. Yeah. Okay. I'll go ahead. So we see Al typing off. He's see a couple of clouds I hit news
but these are some real stubborn clouds. He really does have done is pushing into the clouds, but they're stubborn are not moving. And the plane is loading up like a fist. I'm going for it one second time, but the clouds still won't move. There... So he backs up and he uses the propeller to drag the clouds in the other way. Maybe you could describe it a little more
detail.
I think you caught it. Right? They're very stubborn. So he's like anchoring the plane with like a toe line and using this propeller to blow them backwards.
Exactly. And we've got this great element where the the clouds are much more physical
than
than true clouds. Are. Right? Like like, they have...
They have a real sense of
like marshmallow. Yeah.
Yeah know, i like Marshmallow mel. And I love the little, like, almost bull or blade that he's got that he's trying Yeah. And I really love how the gold are blade is right in front of the propeller. And
you actually just, like block what make the plane go forward. We just ignore that. It looks great. It's good too way. That's our... That's our cartoon logic there. So Donald on the next page, you know, he manages to to heard the clouds where he needs them to be over the farmers field. And we've got these great panels of him using the plane to essentially
shave
bits of the cloud off so that it forms this perfect
x. And then he...
And then he sees the clouds. He drops some stuff on the clouds to produce the rain. And
and the clouds start the rain and we kind of cut to the the farmer
and his wife, I assume also a farmer and they are ad
the rain and there's this just
fantastic dad
where the the drops that are falling on the property line even have one flat side to come right up.
Sure is a favorite of my. It's really memorable.
So it it'll drop the falls on the top of the fence, they they won't cross over to the other side of the
they stop in the middle. They're not going in photo, and I love that. I think it's one of the most memorable things in this story. And it's it's delightful. It's over the top. It's super cartoon ish,
but it works within the context of this story. It does...
So on the next page, the first panel we see is the former
stereotypical k
Barks farmer with the overalls and a goats.
Beard looks as it looks at his
reign measurement
tool and it's precisely
the amount that asked for not even a millimeter over or a millimeter this just what he asked for. So this really shows out of a perfection
don't in this. So he's back on the he has ladder the plane he's background the ground, and
the nephews are giving him one other job. So it's another farmer that we will... Could you do the pound? Could you do the word to text extended this panel with third panel? Yeah. Because I'm kinda curious what
how they call it in in your printing. So the farmer is named farmer pumpkin deal. Which is a great Barks name. And he's put in an order
for an inch and a half of slow rain on his goose berries.
Yeah. And I would... I will I really have to disappoint too. It's not a good name. His name farmer Pumpkin.
That's not a good norwegian
name and
to be honest. What's the crop? Do they keep it Goose berries?
I'm really not sure what these kind of berries are in or where art English. They're called in Norway, They are called sticky by
barriers, Is that something that we were say? No. Never. Do not. Oh, okay. I'm no way. You typically know about Lingo berries only because of
Ikea. That's... Yeah. Okay. Sorry. I do not know the english name of these kind of coronavirus. Yeah. So so Goose varies is weird too because those have gone out of popularity
in heard.
They're... You do not see them. I think that they were more popular when these were first published.
Okay. But I don't even know what they are. I... But I'm never
or eating a goose barrier. Yeah. Okay. So it's a square plane, So it should be easy.
But in the middle of it, his wife is having
their wet
cleaned clothes out for dry. She doesn't and the wife doesn't want their clothes to be wet. So the the nephew put the tool on the plane, that make right for another flight. And we fly over the
the property and it's really simple. It's really square. It has house in the middle of it. We can see
the wet clothes in the middle and that, of course starts... He finds there clouds right nearby and he starts pumping and funding and to together able to just a perfect square size. And then it do... That's the same thing as then last page where he is shading off the top of the cloud. It's just like how i it pushes the top of the and goes just like for lovely see. Yeah. I I love the art. In general
and manipulate the clouds. It's it's a delay to look at. And
so on the next page, you know, we get the little payoff of that tool you were talking about that they put on where he he turns into a corpse screw
maneuver and he just carve out this little disc shaped empty spot to address the farmers
wife's
laundry that's out to dry. And we get this perfect
rain. This farmer has ordered a slow range Right? Yeah. There's a great gag in English. His wife asks, is that rain slow enough for you hi, and he says yep. Them drops even stop and look around before landing. And and we see another great gag that's just so over the top about what a good job Donald is doing, the little space that he's cleared for her laundry even accounts for the ruffles on her party dress. Yeah. Yeah. It's it's it's hilarious.
And then the very end of the page, you know, is where Barks kinda sets up the downfall. He has a narration bot that says like every other genius. This this fabulous rain
has a weak spot. It is of course a girl. And we see Donald with the t balloon thinking about a giggling days. And it's a hard shaped thought balloon as well. Yes. Which is a nice touch. Yeah. Oh, man. This this next page is great. Tell us, tell us about this one. Before we do that, I would just like to comment something about the Barks group. Yeah. Because it kinda bugs me in a way that... But in norwegian translation,
we see a here. Well, it drives up. It's Scrooge the
The waves go screw as i go up and then... In on the next panel, you can see in coming on the side of the cloud with that big... It looks like a cor. But in an norwegian translation, it basically says where it says, I feel just like a cork group. And I kinda think that that's just that it's too much you don't need that. That's what you see. Yeah. It's it's a little.
High. Not it's not showing tell. It's show and telling. That's kinda... You don't mean that it really reload me that a couple times. Yeah. But yeah, The next page, I'll go ahead. So
we're back with donald. Obvious as a break. He's not wearing his pilot goggles
and it's talking daisy and asking if she would like to drive on a trip and this is in the next panel saying that, oh, I'm sorry. Actually have other plans because I thought they were busy, and i love this speaking balloon coming from the from daisy phone, being dull
we're saying, what are plans that really just the speech bubble is just dropping. What how would you describe that next? So to me it looks like it's it's being covered with ice. Right? Like Yeah. Exactly. They're forming,
you know, just the cold.
Yeah. In and how Donald demeanor has turned has turned cold and upset. You're you're right it's a great. That's a great way to show it. So obviously, he's feelings just turned from being hard shaped in his eyes, and we don't see it, but now it's stone cold. U. And it doesn't get in better. When he learns that daisy say is data plans actually are with Gladstone.
So we see that green and ghost of jealousy.
Degree... I'm sorry. The green monster feels Jealousy, poking tunnel in the back with
don't been furious.
And this and
that jealousy
master just... It's like... You know those good old cartoons where like a devil on one side and the angel one side. This is obviously the devil. Yeah. Talking down and... Are you gonna take this? Alright? Or you gonna... Aren't you gonna fix this and don't ends up, of course, few minutes thinking, oh, yeah. I'm gonna fix this. So it jumps right into the plane, not knowing where they're going. But unfortunately, it does see
Glen car from the sky, he decides to follow them to their location. Yeah.
This
this page room and is
great. It is... Pretty wild. Right? Because Barks does that's a lot going on. There is a lot going on.
The this eyed monster is how it's labeled.
I don't know if this is the same
in in Norwegian, but this this is like a reference to jealousy.
In English, it's a little old fashioned. But in English, you can literally call jealousy, the green eyed monster. Yeah. Okay. That doesn't doesn't translate as so. But it basically says, well, fortunately, Marx does have a little here's the text and it's pointing at that monster telling the reader where. And in my addition, it the green ghost of Jealousy or the grain monster of Real. And that's very
be. You know it started it from this too as a kid, because this was probably where I learned about this whole saying. When i read this when I was say years zone So it's not a good
norwegian term, Rna and any case, but it just works in this because it's obvious based that it's fictional and
that is it it's very clear what is happening that it's like this
representation. It's so funny though. This this monster that's
him,
and and amp up his jealousy.
And it looks like though as well. It does. Yeah. It's like if it... It's like a dull cross with a dragon. So Yeah. And and the devil.
Can I ask you what do they call the group? That Gladstone is part of and this? Oh, yeah. So
translate well. So it's translated into... I'll just go ahead. It's it's the golden idle dam this english. And in norway they call it dog delivery recruitment, which is basically the day driver club and the day driver. I believe that's the term that doesn't work in English. I mean, if if I if I had to guess, it's someone who doesn't have to work and just goes off for like, a for like, a nice pleasant drive. Yeah. It's a person that doesn't not want to work. Actually,
so... yeah. They're just like they would rather just lie on tree and looking at the other people who that sounds like a pretty pretty good translate addition to me solid at least. Again,
going back to
when I send at the introduction about these characters being so
implemented into the Norwegian culture actually Gladstone other, and goose again are excellent
examples of day drivers.
Right. It's it's such a weird they're called the idle Dandy like you said. And it's such a weird old fashioned term, You know
it is like someone fancy.
Exactly. But it... But that term is is well out of bone. The next page, you know, has the idle dandy that they're pit and and Glad and Daisy are having a nice time. And at some point, Daisy notices
what she's
recognizes this as Donald plane lying about overhead. And, you know, Gladstone
is talking about, oh, he's Jealous, he should he should get out of here. And Donald does head away,
but it's just so that he can w up some
really men
clouds. And he clearly spur them into
creating a pretty spectacular
storm over
the the idle picnic
beast stick. You did find a lot of bit bad films. It's a really impressive it's just a big storm.
Right. And it and it happens like, very suddenly, it's very clear. Absolutely.
So I do really enjoy how the comments. Really early on this page where they says that oh, isn't this
federal whether just lovely and go glad and, of course, just. Would you like to say the got Gladstone offline here? Yeah. He says it's always perfect. When I'm around, you know, referencing with Gladstone still look. But you're right. It's a nice... It's a nice setup for how the weather is great and is obviously gonna take a turn. And also right before we see donald and what clouds they found we can see the Club. They're really having a ball there. They're really hungry.
Yeah. Is yeah Throw throwing themselves over that food. So, yeah, don't now have gather rid the clouds and the club down in the valley is now really feeling how that storm is gathering up on them, and they are finding it better to just leave because this storm is not a place for a good picnic. And Doll doesn't think of this storm is enough. So he is dropping that weird powder on these clouds again with blizzard.
So now that that's though there... And all the other people club. Oh my god. Knowing they really do have to get going now. But unfortunately,
Gladstone really fancy the car won't start
because the model has frozen. So even though
the idle dam is really hate this, they find out that they would have to stay and do the job of making a fire. Yeah This is really...
It really shows a crisis scene right now. Yeah. You're right. This is
me how it's shown how quickly Donald been able to turn the weather. Absolutely.
And and this Al happens again so fast. It's just a couple of pages. He's working so quickly with this.
Onto the next page, you know, is where it's it really takes a turn. Donald decides that he wants to look at his work. And so he prepares to dive through the clouds and his plane just crashes
spectacularly. As though it's run to the ground because it turns out he has
oversee and the clouds have turned into a solid
dome of ice.
And and so now we've got this terrible
situation where Donald has gone too far. He's
he's mastered his craft, but it's back backfired on him because he's led jealousy.
Provoke him into this.
Where
everyone below is in danger of the clouds
shattering and crushing them. And so he's forced to parachute through this one hole
the clouds and warn them to to get out and and
they initially are ignoring his warnings. Because they've got a fire and and because they are the idle dandy, they say, we're just gonna wait here for the highway Scrooge to rescue.
These people didn't don't. They don't they are lazy people. They only use their Barks if they're moving somewhere. Right.
You know there's... I just noticed this. And I haven't i didn't check this against my other reprint. But
the dandy that's in the background
on the last panel of this page has a
shirt that is colored
of of Charlie Brown. Oh, it's the charlie brown.
And. Never know it doesn't matter that as well. Those little zigzag. So I guess it looks like that on yours as well. Yeah. And it's colored yellow as well. Yeah. That's interesting. And the peanuts
did exist the time didn't? Yeah. I think Peanut started out in the...
That's poised. This... I I think it must've have been about a contemporary here. I'll take a look, When did Peanuts start?
Yeah. First published in nineteen forty seven and moe
renamed Peanuts in nineteen fifty. So that's a fun fun little gag apparently or or
and coincidence.
And we also should mention that
these clouds to have frozen and the reason they're not dropping down it's because the resting thing on the mountain tops. Yes. That's that's an important catch. Right? Yeah. So they're not just hovering in the air. They're kind of resting on on mountain tops like said. So when these these clouds will melt, basically,
a bunch of big ice Barks crashed into the valley. So really don't really put people in danger here. The He's killing is girlfriend for this this was a a big
catastrophic mess up. Absolutely.
So we'll see how it goes. I'll go over with the next page. So donald now has gone into this he's parachute into the valley and it's saying that we really do need to get out of here. Do these ice they'll collapse they don't care until they hear a really big crack up in the sky and it's just great expressions on Barks faces right there. Now they really understand the danger and they're running their actually ice skating. With that very nice case. I'm not sure how how much that will work. But actually that are getting out there there, just in the last moment before we see just a big blocks eyes are crushing on the top from the... It's like actually a roof on top of the Al there and it just collapsed the skin to the valley. And all the
members of the
Club are really sorry now because their cars have been ruined. And one of the members Gladstone though, why did this guy know the clouds being in danger of us.
I read the bit of dialogue in English. Because i had ahead...
Yes.
How did that duck know those clouds where I and Gladstone
sm, and he says,
I've got news for you Chu Al Donald
s guilt over.
So in the last couple of panels, we see another farmer. We're back with the voice at what seems to be Double dutch rain maker headquarters. And he really begs for the Ducktales. Where is that master rain maker? I really do need some some water on my fields. And
nephews have to apologize.
Because though he's location in Tim. Yes. Yes. Really it's a it's a classic Barks ending. It it is. Right? Tim too is one of those
place names that is just funny to people. And so there's a tradition in in at least American pop culture of if you have to, like, run away and escape to somewhere. It's a good... It's a good destination.
Yeah.
And you know that farmer in in the English printing. He's named mister Corn silk, and he's begging for water for his Vegas.
And and in and in English at least Rut vega is just one of those, like, funny words. It's almost a punchline.
Yeah.
So so Ruben this this is just... This is some incredibly tight story.
Right? He and he's he's so small practice with this and he's he did so many of these ten pager.
But to set up this story structure where he's got these two
demonstrations of this complete mastery and and then this
incredibly memorable
failure is is so awesome. You know what I love about all of these brittle mas stories is that it's it's almost always his own fault. And if he just if he didn't let himself
get carried away or let his jealousy get the best of him. He could have had a very successful run of doing this. Absolutely. And it also
mostly kind of bug me that, yeah, he did make a big mistake he he really screwed up he erased people lives in this story, but it's still a good rain who could he can still handle that profession. Yeah. Got
It's a double story. It needs to the round up with Well, he doesn't do that anymore. He's back into doing something else. Right. Yeah. We've gotta get that big reset. He's gotta finish
Exactly.
So you know,
I I mentioned that I... This is definitely one of the ten pager that stands out for me. Obviously, it's it's a favorite of yours.
I I like to check and on what the community thinks about these, you know, by by using the site in index and they let anyone vote on their stories. And and they usually get enough people voting that it gives you a pretty good idea. And so this one is ranked very highly. For a ten page or at least it. This one has a seven point five out of ten, which is good for rank two hundred and forty nine. Out of all like, forty one thousand some... Yeah. Disney comics.
That sure is impressive Yeah. It's a high one. And I am
obsessed enough that I actually went and made a list of the ten pager. Just so that I could reference those how they compared to each other? That's interesting. Yeah. And so this one, let's see. So as of when I made this list, This one is the eighteenth
highest rated of all of his ten pager. So
sleep very highly regarded very well. Remember. And and it's such a great high concept, you know, the the rain may i didn't really talk too much about about this. But rain making, I I I learned a little bit about it. I don't know if you looked up too much about it. Yeah. I have... I I look at the a couple of youtube do videos. To me the interesting thing about rain making is that it's a very
exact
science. Right? There's Al there's a lot of disagreement over how well it works.
If it works at all. You know, I I learned that they used a rain stuff to make it the silver.
Can't remember what kind of silver they use to see. They use like C two. They use silver Huey, use even just dry ice. I didn't see any like being and Critical little about it.
Just telling about how it works,
why people doing it. And it's well it's called cloud seating, and Cnn described as adding a chemical to clouds to increase rain or snowfall. And I really learned that the way box
represents this the story. Even though it's really comic with cuba a comedy in this, it's really actually pretty
an good representation because we can't make clouds. We can only target clouds that we already have a voice sure. And then actually do put some chemicals on top of this. So it's just like Barks represented in the story. Yeah. Other people And people always ask why they don't use this red drought or forest fires? And that's because you can make clouds. And what do I use it for? Well, the only thing I could find is that power companies would like more now more snow up in the mountains that could fit the streams and rivers when there's no melts. Yeah. I I read a few uses for it.
One big one is, like ski resorts, I guess, well
use it to get more powder or snow on their slopes.
But apparently, the Chinese government used it because you can use it in advance. To try and make the rain happen early
instead of it happening on, like, the forecast today, so they they used it in advance of the
Recently.
Yeah. Yeah. I I didn't see that. It was the Al Olympics. Yeah. That's right.
You know what I found that that was really interesting into to me Ruben.
There's someone
someone put up a video on Youtube
of
images from this story. Pointing to it as like a conspiracy theory. I don't know if you're
with the people who talk about
con hem trails. Do you know what Chem trails are? No. I don't please go ahead and explain. So there's this big conspiracy theory. I think it's widespread around the world, but I know there are a lot of cra in the Us who subscribed to it. That say that the government drops chemicals
Oh yeah. I've heard about that. For, you know, like, mind control purpose.
Exactly.
And and it... It's pretty hilarious there they're basically accusing Barks of having been somewhat
I don't I don't know what the conspiracy is. but there there's some very funny, like, comments about oh, look at this. You know where to look. You you can find that they've always been trying to control us. So Yeah. Even in the Du universe, they did. Right. So that's why... It's why all the humans are black.
Yes. Yes. Exactly.
But also in my research, just Al a little short one at the end, the same cnn m video said that this technology cloud sitting, was this actually discovered in nineteen forty six. So it did exist at the time that Barks may distort. Yeah. It goes back. And, you know, Barks is really
in some of the stories, he's really at the cutting edge. Yeah. Of there's a lot of, like, new technology
discussed in a lot of these. And and it's interesting. I I grew up reading these in the eighties and nineties.
And by then, a lot of it was very old and and quaint, but But at the time, a lot of it really was very cutting edge. And cloud isn't actually real very known technology. Not nothing's not in my country at least, so I still believe that this seems a bit future taken away. The way I can control whether and the way it's presented. It's in a comedic way. Of course. It's hilarious. It is hilarious. The the the concept he has, you know, the seeding in the clouds obviously is something that people do. But the way he w
the clouds around, like, like, he's almost in a rodeo or or hurting herding cattle. That's that's the Huey, yeah. That sure is my favorite aspect aspects of a story and I believe that's why I reread it so many times when I was younger is to see that playing fly just like a fist into those to clouds and cork screwing, the shaving, forming those clouds to be the perfect way for make it rain on top of the farms, just marvelous.
Yeah. It's it's incredibly
clever.
Well before we wrap it up, you know, we talked about... I you like to to ask if you've got any favorite panels. I know we've already mentioned some that stand out, but are are there any rubin that you wanted to really highlight? I will say the first that comes to mind is on the it's on the fourth page and it's the second
last
one where it says fun bump Al donald pushes this shape into this cloud into the perfect Scrooge.
That's just Marble. And of course, the course one I already talked about.
It's such a great
way to show this. That really shows off how Barks really used to work with animation at Al business studios videos. Really it feels like animation
when reading it we mentioned a bunch of great panels in this. There for such a quick story. There are just a ton of great panels.
But the the bits with the Green eyed monster are awesome some and all of the bits with the clouds being manipulated into... Absolutely, I love every one of them there's how much by And then when the plane when the plane crashes...
Oh, yeah. Locked. Device. I I mean, the art is good. But it's more of the that little shock when I originally read it, you know, it's such a great surprising moment. It's it's super unlikely, but it's it's a great moment. And also the panel before it's actually just showing how he's really diving into the clouds. It's moving vertically on this.
And it's moving really fast. Yeah. So you definitely feel his impact. Absolutely.
More room and any other any other thoughts on this straight story before we wrap it up Not the anything thing mentioned and we'll thank you so much for joining me. Thank you so much for having the Barks. Just have been such a pleasure. Awesome. Alright. Have a good one, and we'll we'll fully have you listeners join us for another episode of the ten page podcast
soon, as well as our regular adventure length
episodes,
feel free to reach out to us in the mark's remarks Facebook page or Barks remarks. At g mail dot com. Bye bye.