We have
Hello, and welcome to Barks Remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comics of all time. This episode is a ten page podcast, all about one of his short stories. Get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Welcome back to Bart remarks. I'm Mark Sever, a grown man who still enjoys du comics. And talking about them. And I also really enjoy ringing on and getting to meet creators who are involved with the dot com and I'm so excited to have a new guest host joining me today. So I'm gonna let her introduce herself. I and again. I'm grown woman who likes Barks sk, which is probably a first word his I think.
Outstanding that's right. I've had... I've had a number of grown women on the podcast but they've all been, like, totally new. To to the to the comics. So it's it's true. You are the first grown woman who loves the comics,
and and then you've got some some background in them. Right? Why don't you tell us a little bit about your work? Yeah. So I'm actually a comic artist store living. I draw a lot of different things, but I'm also... Are you lucky to draw that com as well. So this year, I'm I haven't been drawing them for a long time but this year. I'm
drawing Al lot of one pages for the Barks of the Dutch donald black weekly. So I'm drawing more Inducks than ever, which is great.
That's awesome.
Well that what a huge
thrilled that must be, you know, to grow up loving the comments and then to to get to to work on them. And not just Ducktales. Right? You work with a number the Disney characters? Yeah. I've also drawing a few other character seth
for Disney
stories. I've also drawn
for a few other franchises. So I've recently drew with Lu tunes, but those haven't been released yet.
After not don't boost
here Ba or characters said are only any in and, but they're also
we're published into donald doc magazine. Oh neat. Yeah. I've off to what come up. I do really like the the old rabbit comment. So sir, those are a lot of fun. And I know that you you had at least one cover that was published in the states. Right? Yeah. That's right. I think the first one was a
mickey mouse one. I think I've done two mickey mouse ones and there is one all this new and store got.
Yeah. I think that's the I saw. I I really like your style. I like... First off definitely to me is a evo of of bark. I assume you're going for that while also trying to, you know, have your own have your own flare. Yeah. Get vincent bit I'm the drawing. I'm I actually have a really hard time deciding what I want to draw each each time. So sometimes, it looks a bit more like bark and sometimes it looks more like, something like Pulmonary.
Yeah. Maybe one at one point they'll have
more consistent stuff. It's hard to decide. I like so many different Barks.
Well, I'm I'm really excited to get your creator per perspective on the couple of stories we're gonna talk about today. And I've definitely buried the lead here, but anyone who's pressed play on the podcast knows that this is gonna be a Gladstone
gander.
Focused
episode. How do you feel Henri about the... About the gander about Donald Cousin. Love to Hate him.
Nah I really I really like the stories request, so what, of course, you're supposed to You're supposed to hate him.
But that's right. Character. Yeah. He... He is a great character, and he's fascinating. Right? Because he's He's a foil for Donald. Donald Lucky cousin drives him crazy. And I've always been interested or or at least since I started doing this podcast, and started to make myself like over think about these stories. It's been really interesting to me to think about how much Barks
dislike Gladstone gander. Yeah. Because that that really comes out. You know, here he is. He's got this character. It's one of his probably one of his most famous creations. Right? Like Scrooge and gyro
and the B boys arguably
maybe a little bit more famous, but Gladstone gander comes pretty close. Yeah. I guess glad something get featured and Ducktales deals too much, so maybe in the state he's not a well member. But yeah. It's definitely one of the most famous characters I would say. Yeah. And and so it's interesting to me to have this like, really notable character that you don't like very much. And anyway, he was... He created him around the same time as he created Scrooge mc dot, right? Pretty pretty close. And he was featuring them both pretty heavily, but, like, sp took this out of return where he became a featured character and and and Barks
What you can tell that Barks really like screwed even if he doesn't like every aspect of him. Yeah. And with glad, you would always
I a hard time imagining
a comic series that is really focused on Gladstone he would always have to go up against the mostly. So of course, that's been more recent short stories
that just the about sending.
Yeah. It's really interesting. There's a lot of Barks characters there actually in in a lot of ways very easy to dislike because when you think about Scrooge, it should be a character you dislike, but you still wrote for. Yes. Yes. Exactly. It's a great trick that we root for this quad,
Ty, Pluto crap.
But be too. We we love him. And that was a good point you made about, like, Gladstone
doesn't really work without Don right? Scrooge. Sp can work without Donald, but Gladstone is like the not the opposite, but Huey, he is kind of another version Yeah. I also find really interesting
because they're still
stories where Glad is not really
the Foil Donald, but he just says it's very specific role the stories. It's... That's always what I'm really interesting if the Barks characters is that historically creative with them, you could not replace these characters for anyone else day there's such specific traits. Yeah. Yeah. For sure. And so we are talking about two stories today, because I I like to pair stories when I can when it's appropriate. We're gonna be covering glad stone returns
and then we're gonna we're gonna be covering glad stone terrible secret And Henri, I think these are good ones to pair because we have one story that is glad stone before four Barks figured out what he wanted to do with him. And then a story that has him the way we know him and think of him Al lucky glad gander. Yeah. And it's it's funny when I when I read these the early stories as a kid that I often didn't even really notice that this luck wasn't there. Because
a lot of the short stories, I grew up reading short dutch comics, one pager Of user for for Donald, and the factory that is lucky doesn't even always come into play. So they really take this version that you see in this in this story where it's more is rivalry way donald, but not necessarily his luck That's really the focus of the story. So it's it's interesting how he's old. This is only a second appearance, but this is
personality is already pretty much their not not Al easy going yet. Yeah. I I think you're right. That's the more salient thing about him like as as memorable as his luck is,
it really... The character really is about his arrival re Donald, you know, whether he's like,
competing with him for daisy
or just competing
to to kinda one up him. That's... That I think is is a very memorable thing about him. Have it what's interesting when when is what changed his personality when the lock is added is that he becomes almost more laid back and easy going because he doesn't have to worry and that makes him even more annoying. Right he's almost less. He's less mean, but that makes him worse in way. Yeah. It's true. He's... Because there's a little bit of an era of desperation
about him in the first stories. You know, this first one we're gonna talk about. You you actually see him worried occasionally.
And same thing and his great first appearance in winter time Wage, which I covered
some months ago.
To me, that that's just one of the the all time funniest Barks stories too. I love that one. Yeah. Great. Either way, did... Have you ever used Glad stone in the store that you've drawn?
Yes. Actually,
my my very first comic. This was really long but when I was sixteen...
I got to do a a test page for the for the magazine and they gave me also a really old unused one page bottle of that song. And
a few later actually week got published. So, wow. That's awesome. It's cool. He's only one panel Think but But still you and you and Gladstone go way Barks. Yeah. I mean, I have a figurine nothing him on my desk. So oh nice. I can't say I hate to go.
Sure.
As always, you know, I do like to ponder to our international listeners by mentioning some of the fun
translations of the titles
We won't do a ton. Henri, I think you wanted to share one for we're on on glad returns. Yeah. So...
That's interesting that one of the dutch titles for Gladstone returns is a think for train, which means
basically a tenor, like ten dollars for daisy. So it's funny that in the in the multiple translations we've said over the years, the amount that's that day he needs to get keeps getting higher. I thought this one from Spain was interesting. It's called Dos P. You press Viva.
I mean, literally, that's two cousins and three live ones or three living one. And I don't know exactly what they mean. It's obviously referring to to the Nephews,
but I don't know if if live ones is like the term for for a sucker or a Target in Spanish.
That that's my best guess. Yeah. And it's was funny. I see that in France, they've had at least three different titles. So my my french is terrible, but the first one is
ada there, which would mean the fake
And then there's one that's additional too much, which is basically the prediction of the stage. And then the other ones are all basically
on the hunt for dollars.
Right. And then how about
for the second story we're gonna be doing
we'll just cover these all for Glad stone terrible secret. Any any of that interest you? Let's see. Okay. I see German is and pine and them, which is a painful... It it means a painful refill.
Yeah. That's a pretty good one. It looks like they were pretty consistent. And and then in Spain, that one is titled at one point it's Let, the amulet and the most recent one is
So I'm guessing that not na
or Na is what they call glad.
And. And I'm seeing something that's addressing to me because I'm seeing that the really
old Belgian version, so it's in Dutch, which is my language, but it's a belgian edition, and it's called the soul
on. So a apparently Gladstone
used to the called jonathan.
See if there's a touch title. No. It doesn't really seem to have a title and any of the dutch versions.
Yeah. Excellent.
So
Gladstone is terrible secret. I'll just... I'll mention before, each story where the back ground of these. This was originally published in the states.
And walt disney comments and store ninety five and cover date of August nineteen
forty eight. And
this one is very well regarded on Inducks. It is for for a ten page very highly ranked. It's
ranked two hundred and ninety out of all, you know, almost forty two thousand stories. And it's interesting to meet, Henri that both of these are gonna be very close to each other as far as how the community thing and we are in that mode where Glad stone doesn't have his luck yet. Right? So this is only his second story. I think about six months or so after winter time wage, you know, Barks decided to go back to the well and feature him again. And so this is really gonna be... For a while, it's gonna be all about the rivalry re with with Gladstone. And Donald and and then Gladstone gonna kinda leave the story. For a bit. Let's let's do this. So this story starts the way that I think of some of the best Gladstone stories
Start Gladstone and Donald are kind of like marching through the city. Just trading barb trying to wanna up each other and they're they're immediately at lau heads. And in this case, they're they're both being total brag Barks and they are bragging about the the wealth. That each of them has.
And it is an awesome opening because it's so over the top and it so ridiculous what each of them is saying as they escalate how well they are.
I I'm I'm interested they keep the the translation in in what you've read, but they start off by talking by bragging about Donald starts off by bragging about owning
three brass minds, which he's just sold for a million bucks. And then Gladstone
escalate that to selling six rad
stations for a billion bucks. And and then they, you know, advanced to talking about the the features of their yacht
and it's it's it's great. It's it's so over the top. Yeah. I I just... I love how this page He doesn't even really get
introduced in any way. They just introduced themselves by what they're discussing. It's not really relevant that he is cousin or anything you you can just tell immediately what the relationship is and Right. Yeah. I love how incorrectly over the top it is right away, and then almost every every panel on this page feels icon somehow just did the. Post taken. It really does. These poses are incredible.
You probably have even more of them and appreciation for them than I do. And... But I I especially love the one where we're looking at them
from from behind the the back. And we see them kind of squaring off against each other from from behind. It's it's hilarious. And something I find interesting in this few early stories just visually that he's still Al lot taller and adult. I think it's more supposed to be the fact that he's stall and hand some donald this more, like a little right but
also interesting since he's again there so Is he even at that not?
It's also interesting to me that we get that like mention of a rad station, which is I think felt must have felt very timely and very cutting edge
back at this point when when that was such a going concern. Yeah. So that's something with the translations I could I could talk about later but that. So I I also been looking through
I own three different dutch copies of this stomach. And so there's three different cancellations and the only ones from the fifties they'll talk about rh, then the second one, they talk about platinum them because radio isn't really relevant anymore. Right. Then final on the nineties one, they go back to being close to the original comic and they turn it back into radio again? That's interesting. That I I I like hearing about
translation and and that sort of thing. So the next page it kind of introduces daisy into the story.
She's often gonna be what they're competing over.
And it's it's it's been perfectly set up by Barks. He's gonna allude to her having being part of her woman's club and that they have a fundraiser.
And so she has a quota of five dollars. And
shocks by the amount.
Alright. And I I love it. And and five dollars
inflation wise, I'm not using the inflation calculator, but it's it's about ten times but it is. Yeah. Think it's about roughly
fifty bucks. So, you know, it's it's a decent bit of money, but it's also... Something should be too shocked though right. Right. So I love how both of them are immediately horrified at this ask and how it completely
exposes them both as fraud because they're both... They're both pointing at the other
the other, and they immediately are talking about what a fraud they are. Glad is just a lot better Al keeping up appearances
this looks. Right. And I I love their reaction where each of them loses their hat. You know, the good the good old cartoon logic.
And and, you know, Daisy realizes that they're both bummed, but then because they wanna keep up appearances
Glad stone vows to have that money for her at this spot in one hour and
and Donald always has to one up his cousin. He's always gonna let him himself get into trouble. So what does he promise? Yeah. He'll promise. Five bucks and half Al hour. That's right.
And and Daisy gets off this great line that really does a good job of establishing the steaks, even though this is a pretty low state story, she says one of you had better have that money here, I'm gonna be terribly embarrassed. Yeah. It's.
It it is. This is just two pages in and we know exactly what the story is gonna be about. The only unfortunate that thing is that we leave Gladstone here for the next sequence because I was enjoying so much him and Donald that log our heads in this one. And there's there's one thing That would just want tiny that's... Yeah. Love to point out is the on the third panel, you barely see it, but there's a random character walking up pittsburgh.
Oh, yeah. Yeah. That's true. That's Al that's a weird little site gag that I never really paid much mine to, but it is fun.
Also love characters are... These whole two pages is basically just two characters talking to each other. And then three characters, but they're just standing on the sidewalk talking to each other, but not one panel is ever boring every post is so so interesting and every pose is funny. Right. And daisy is, like, so incident hold to this. Because you're right, it is really like the two of them. They're... What even when they're talking to Daisy they're really talking to that to each other. Yeah. They're talking over Huey,.
So I do think it's a shame that that Glad stone disappears for a lot of the rest of the story, but it is a really neat sequence.
Because the next, like, three pages or so are basically gonna be all about Donald effort to like scare up this money, and most of it is gonna focus on him targeting the Nephew piggy Bank. Yeah.
Stealing from the kids is pretty pretty low.
Right. It is pretty low. This is one of those I think this is really appealing for a kid. Right? I think he it makes you feel powerful
in a way as the reader when you're reading this as a kid. And and there's that element where you like you love to hate Al adult for doing something like this. Yeah. It as also... I remember being weird reading these stories sometimes because, of course,
you see him as a parent and the idea if you own parents stealing for me would be would be nuts right.
I also wonder if I'm not sure if they're earlier Go Barks stitch where donald is taking money from the kids. There's
a short I grew up watching a lot that from a few years. Earlier
where also the...
It's called Donald crime where he's also
robin the kids Barks. I remember that one. I wonder if Barks
Do you know if he was involved? That one? I think... And I think this short is from ninety forty five, so he was already working on it mixed Maybe... I... I'm not sure if Barks ever maybe got to see the cartoons. I think he was really working in bubble Al love town. Yeah. But then definitely an element that I think has been used in a number of the comics.
And you're right. It's such a weird, like, dynamic for there to be with this parent figure. But Yeah. But it it works. It it's a great lead to the rest of the action of this because they have done
this amazing job of burglary proofing and boo trapping and uncle donald proofing,
they're their Piggy bank. I'm not gonna go through every beat of it, Henri, but
are there any... There are there any moments that really stand out for you as their as Donald is trying to get into their piggy Barks. Just from the start he's basically... He's not even walking how we his literally flying past the bird and almost getting hit by a car. It's full of site gigs.
Really seem to have fun with this page. But... Yeah. Almost every other panel or so. Yeah. The all whole sequence is just kind of nuts
rep are so advanced for a bunch of kids. And the fact that they already
anticipate that he's going to do this is concerning. So know this before. Right. They've learned from experience Hey, what does the note
that he finishes out? Say and yours?
In the English, it says nurse to you. And. Sometimes I'm not really sure that's is also probably because English is my first language. I don't know if Barks uses archaic or some because they're funny.
Yeah If that's just our people talk, I think it's combination of both. What right. And and I I like being... I like keeping the
the listeners in mind who have read these other languages. I like... It excites me a little bit to be able to tell them that, like, this nurse is in English. It's one of those words that by itself is kind of funny. Yeah. And that's also a thing that's
really with the
the German and the dutch come
because you can't really do the... Or you say it it's not really dialect that donald speaks, but Al lot of more...
Write it more like spoken words. Right. But in in the Dutch in German comic, they speak very proper dutch most of the time, but they use words it or so archaic or silly
almost corny that it that is funny. Right. They'll say the same thing they say
which is also
that's more little childish thing to say and also a little little bit archaic. Alright. So So they finally catch him in the act
when when he figures out they've had a d deploy peggy bank, and he eventually figures out that their money was really in a lamb. And that kinda clears them in that they've gotta get it to the bank and
This next sequence is the is the swamp sequence.
And this one hasn't aged very well. It would have been... It would have been thought of as pretty harmless
back in the fifties. I don't think it's means spirited,
but it it just is not something that we would do today. Right. Yeah. And it's it's something you could you could basically easily just replace the word and the joke would be just as funny. Right. But but the idea is a Swan is like an Indian mystic. A hint a hidden.
It's a term of respect, but you see it a lot in comments of this year. If you need someone to be like a fortune teller or to have kind mystical You just slap a turban on them and call them. Call them a salami. And and so what Donald does is he...
He heads them off with this, like, fake get up and and this little tent
and he lu them into believing that they should invest their money
with a man who's wearing a high silk cat. What is he actually... Ass? So hi cell cat? Planning to, you know, cut them off and be that person, of course. Any comments on this sequence and then tell us what what happens with an nephews.
Yeah. So the outfit doll puts on looks absolutely ridiculous with them the nephews fault for it.
Right. Is dirty work... I think it's a mock he's wearing a four bed.
Yes. Yeah. I guess in a way, we get a hint of glad slack because he tells them to look for a man and a top wanting to dress up that way and run ahead of them. But glad happens to we wearing a all that for... Absolutely no worries. Yeah. I.
Getting a it lucky. I know. Right. Even though it's not really...
They don't really... He doesn't call attention to it or anything.
We also see that he's trying hit his attempts to make that five bucks is to sell gold bricks as well as possibly the Brooklyn bridge. And this is
best looks in.
And this is something that bark kind of... He he abandoned it a little bit, but... But then even when he makes him luck he'll occasionally reference some of these, like, low grades sw that Glad stone, I think must have been doing early on before He figured out as kara The these are classic, like, twin windows. That's
day by day it seems so... Right. But yeah. I I love the gag where where it says Gold for so also Brooklyn Bridge. So
you have two good ideas that he can choose. So it's it's just gonna be both. Right. He's gonna throw it against the wall.
So so of course, the Nephews do the predictable thing, and we transition to Donald
the reason that Gladstone beats that they beat him and find Gladstone is that Donald got all tangled up in his tent. When he encounters the nephews, they've already given the money to the man that they encountered in a high cell cat, and he is
outraged to learn that it was Glad stone. He leaves out of his silly disguise
and the nephews,
he he heads off to try to beat Gladstone to Daisy and the nephews figure out you know, that they must have been sw. So we've got this neat little, like, almost race at the end that I really like. What do you think about the the way this route stuff america that. Yeah. So he is so so shocked to hear that it's Gladstone somebody immediately just forgets all about that he wants to keep descending from the nephew so they and let me know
uncle.
He lives out of his costume and I love that you can see for a sec that his hair is just a bunch of grass
Right. You didn't already try to harden these costumes, but the nephews are bit gullible and this sorry. Right. It's one of those times where Barks is gonna... Bark is gonna adjust how clever he needs to be to fit the story. Yeah. So they're both very clever and very gullible at the same time, which just always the thing with cartoon costumes for. She should you somehow don't recognize your own uncle right voice. Yeah. So so eventually, you know, Donald
does beat Gladstone.
To Daisy,
and he doesn't have money for her, but he blisters about how Glad stone has my five dollars, so he's clearly gonna wait there. And Daisy gets off a great, like bored face where she actually says h home. She's... You know, she you you sense that she probably knows this is not gonna turn out well. Yeah. She already kind of gave up and out how Donald says don't be impatient daisy but, he's actually being a extremely and. Right.
Right. And and so when Gladstone turns up, he too does not have any money. But he's feeling very confident because he has also
encountered the kids
and has a story about a Swam telling him to invest that five dollars,
and he's done it He has bought an Envelope of pearl seeds.
And do you wanna tell us what what the pearl are And Enrique. Yeah you you'll throw them into oyster shells and it'll grow the biggest pearls you Ever saw. It's basically Al beans stock story because it's actually grain of rice. Yes. That's right. That's a good point. It it is very much jack being stock. And so, you know, they point out that he too has been sw
and the three of the older dots go to look for the Sw door. Gladstone gets gets off a description.
But, you know, Daisy gives up as she probably should have done from the start. And and she heads on off leaving the two of them to fight with each other. And and the story wraps up in a fun. Maybe slightly off putting way but he do you wanna wrap it up for us Henri enrique? Yeah. So daisy he runs into the nephews, and they give her back her five dollars.
Or actually there five dollars. But but I guess they felt like they deserved it after dealing with these two guys. Yeah. I always thought that was interesting. You know, I I always felt At the end like, it was a little unjust that they gave up their money to a grown up when I was the kid reading this. But as you say, it's pretty po at Right Maybe... Yeah. They're probably pretty sure that they see all paid paid forward to pay Barks them. Exactly.
And there's that little reference to her not accepting money from strangers,
which which I thought was interesting, you know, that that was something people were worrying about even at that point. But, yeah. This is this is a fun one. This is a great way to, like, kinda kick off the the the ongoing rivalry
between Donald and Gladstone.
It has a lot going for it. Yeah. Overall, it's it's not the the story as a whole. It's not maybe the most amazing on my,
but it's more the way it still just... It's... We're we're under selling it by just going for the bugs because the the the interactions are just so so grade not it's it's such a fun story to read even though the story is quite simple. It's.
I think it's really
him being Al at this best storytelling.
Not not the story overall, but just the way it still. It's a bit hard explain. You're totally right. It's... It is
incredibly tight. Most of these ten pages are incredibly tight, but I think the ones that really stand out are are constructed even tighter than the typical one. It's book so nicely because it it starts the same place that it wraps up. And, you know, I'm gonna just commit the cardinal in of podcasting, where where I'm talking about a visual medium, and I tell you you just you've just gotta see it, but you really do
Because the poses in this, are what makes it all of the the hysterical reactions, the the wind saying everything
every every face and I'll just eat himself up all the time, and when when the left... When he's hiding for the nephews in the house when they're hiding everyone they're putting a weight of money, just just to... The way picks the curtain is already enough to make me off. This is also why... As long as these stories already started reading them, before I could actually read, but I just... They're just so funny even when you can you can tell what's going on, it's just so much fun to look at. Right. Yeah. Absolutely. That that first page would crack me up even if... Even if I saw it without any of the word balloons filled in. Yeah. The the faces are just especially dogs looks so angry, but just the the faces then like, when they're bragging, I just just so disagree. They're they're golden. Excellent.
Alright. So let's transition into the the one that we're we're both very excited to talk about. Not again, not that we don't appreciate that previous one. But I think, did you tell me that this is one of your all time favorites? Yeah... It's really hard to pick. I think my old time favorites are the ones that make me laugh the most, but I think this story is just... It's one I I I like to show people Al lot to really... Or maybe not really that much into the dot comments because it's really just dis still the characters down to... Everything really comes together with how we... How in a few just a few years, you develop these characters they're are so unique, and you could not Al story like this with any other
universe of characters. And so it... Yeah. It's it's almost... When you when you grow off with this character, she almost take them for granted, but I really like go ahead these early stories and thinking about how completely absurd the plot actually. Is when you think about it. Yeah. And and you know what's really interesting to me about this one is that it's such a rare example of Carl Barks like thinking a little bit about the mythology of his characters.
Yeah. Right? Like he almost never does that. He usually just cuts into a story. This is what the character is about. They haven't really changed from the last
the last issue that he did about them. He doesn't really worry too much about continuity.
But this is one where
the Inducks kinda get to serve as, like, an audience surrogate.
Donald and the nephews
because they're wondering,
you know, where exactly
does his luck come from. And this is one of the things like, if you Google Gladstone gander, you get that when you're looking at the auto complete. For for Gladstone stone gander. That's one of the questions that people.
Because it's such a great hook. It's such a great gimmick that it feels like there's gotta be some kind of origin or secret to it. And
and, yeah, and he's also gonna bring uncle Scrooge into to this one, which is which is pretty neat too. You know, he's not a central part of the story, but I I really like the stories where we get to see the extended Inducks family
interact with each other, not just donald. To Scrooge and Donald two Gladstone, but, like you know, I just recorded very recently right. I've just put out Christmas for Sc town, and it's it's so neat to me. I don't know about you. I love seeing the other. Yeah. That's really one of my favorite Barks. And that's that's that's an interesting story because they're less son really one of the good guys in the anyway, but he just serves his purpose the story. Maybe because it's a Christmas story. He wants to to be a little nice
other than interesting that in that story he's actually just being really nice to donald. Yeah. That... That's what I I thought a lot about that one too and Hi. Actually I really liked him and Al. You know, I like him being an inseparable jerk, but I almost wish that Barks had softened him occasionally like he did Scrooge. But in in this story too. So maybe it's more something to discuss afterwards, but glad actually doesn't really do anything
wrong or mean in this story he's just living his life, but he's just so inseparable
just because he's so lucky. That's true. Yeah. He's not actually
anyone. Oh he's he's smiling his own business.
Right.
For it. And it's also a story structure that we don't see a ton from Barks
right? Where we've got these other character, we've got this one character that is like Al oblivious
to the other characters.
So that... That's an interesting thing to see as well. And
it's also this So this is only
three or four years after the previous comic. I'm not sure how many comments we've flights on in between, I think it's quite a few, but I thought it was interesting, looking for them how quickly already established is glad also Al a I think already unlucky character by the fourth by the fourth like so. Barks on yeah.
I think I'm race to the southeast is probably the first one. Yes.
From what I can tell you've nailed it race to the Southeast was his fourth story
you know, one year or so after winter time wage, and that's the first one where he's overt locked and and I think he does like a couple where he kind of forgets about that afterwards and then and then he never really looks back. Yeah. So what I also was wondering about
also I'm thinking of the the Dutch comic his his name in Dutch literally his last name means lucky or lock. So because by the time when they first brought this comic student Al, they were births two years in or so. So he already they already knew that the character is going to be lucky so I'm curious if if Barks are known from the start Right. That doctor would be lucky if you would've have picked a different name. That again, Gladstone
such a. This such a good.
It is such a good name. And the Al
that you get was Gladstone gander sounds great. Too. And I wanna I gonna make a point. I wanna remember when we talk about the... Room when we reflect at the end to
kinda talk about Gladstone and ten pages versus adventure story. So I wanna put a pin in that. But this story, this one starts off. It has a really great attention grabbing. Opening.
Like I said, we've got the Inducks kind of as audience surrogate.
They're Barks spying on Gladstone gander.
Because they want to figure out what is the secret
to his luck. And they would wanna see if he's lucky
when no one's watching, you know, it's kinda like the old adage about... Does the tree make a sound if it falls in the forest. No one's there to listen. And they and Barks sets up immediately this great little test
to figure out where the Inducks can establish if he's lucky.
Because he's on his way to the market,
to do his grocery shopping,
and he drops his list.
He drops his grocery list. So the dots are able to see what he's gonna get and they're just gonna find out if he's able to get everything on his list for nothing for free. What do you think about the opening here? Yeah. It's it's Al it's an interesting setup so it starts off with the text where they just you just see that and and know you should don't even see that stone. Yeah. It's it's really one of the stories where you I think you're already kind of supposed to know the characters, but even if you don't, then you're maybe even more curious about who is mysterious characters. So there's a really a few panels build up on until you see him. Right. Yeah. So. Is it is interesting actually because every time I uc see Gladstone normally, he's just there to annoy donald. So is... What does he do?
Right. But you guys see? I wonder if he's always this is jolly when he's by himself Right. Because he's gonna be very john
for this this whole.
Short. Story. And he's he's pinging his little song to himself, and I was wondering if it's an actual song that exists, but I couldn't find any
Yeah. I I didn't look it up, but I'm guessing that Barks just made the luck sounding. You know, it's got these little lucky tote yeah. Course shoe valley and fur clover. Because the Dutch version sings Al song it actually exists. This is really
Al time song and the singer the singer actually looks a little bit like, like, glass somebody else's a str internet, But it's a song from the ninety twenties or something. So if it's interesting. It it does... Character to so.
Alright. So the Ducktales do get to see his grocery list. And it... It is quite the list. As Donald says, it's it's a dozen eggs a loaf of bread, leg of lamb, Apple pie quirk of cream, and a poc. Stick.
To tell us about the Bog stick, you know, what's what's the purpose of that? Oh, first of Al, she's funny you have such a ridiculous thing on a on the list. But... Oh, yeah. That's that's Al says basically, if... Because basically if he manages to get all that and stick, he's an absolute freak no less.
Right. Right. We've thrown that in to to be the real test of of his luck. And and so, you know, most of the meat of this story or a big part of it is gonna be the unlikely ways that Glad stun does get hold of these things
in in the sequence that they are on the list.
Tell us about the dozen egg, Henri. Yeah. So he
Glad. Is just walking about and he's straight hand walking around and he follows it. And just finds it doesn't act again the bushes also not one egg more or less.
Yeah Exactly one thousand eggs. And
Donald is already pretty disturbed by him finding the eggs after just such a short amount of times, but it seems did he's still a bit hopeful.
And and then this... The next sequence,
I don't know about you, but this is one of the funniest parts to me.
It's really one of those things where we have find a lot of of with Barks said he takes something that's actually not funny and all.
Because it's really tragic, but it's just it's just hilarious in this context. And I think this is also... I don't know too much about Barks personal, but I think he he was... He just went through a divorce himself My is writing this. So in the next sequence, Gladstone is walking past
a neighbor's house, and he can hear her fighting again. So bear happens Al the time. It's
It's those newly wet Murphy's in in the English. Yeah. And that's she's screaming at her husband's. Dodge actually smiling here it just. You see. They're like pretty
statistics.
But yeah. She she also at at husband it says you're three minutes late for lunch. Just for that I'm going to throw and hold meal out of the window. So Of course, every single item she's throwing is exactly much on his list. Right. He gets his loaf of bread fresh baked, he gets an already cooked leg of lamb with cream
It's with just ridiculous things too forward the window I how it's Right. It's the whole leg of flaps that just ready to go on a plate and and then the cap is that a pie comes out the window, which which was on the list, but but he du it, and it and it sp onto the sp Donald face. And Donald immediately knows he's like, oh, this is Blackberry. He wants apple,
which which of course is the next item to come out Now, and I love this the... He continues singing the song as he walks away. And the Lyrics are great. They'll the... Do you want read us the Lyrics, I won't make you sam. Yeah. I wouldn't know what melanie is.
Now my first to you when you and you is the throw divorce away and keep his shoes
Such a glad stoned thing. It's so awesome.
And so the Ducktales, you know, they're They're ready to give up. One of the nephews is talking about how his luck is clearly un unbelievable. But Donald points out that he hasn't quite got everything on the list. Pointing out that there's a cord of cream and a po stick, and he's nearly home. Yeah. There's some left. Right. And and this next sequence is really notable. Right? Tell us tell us why it's so it's so notable, Here we go. Yeah. Because somebody comes jumping in to the frame on a Purple and it's Ge.
It's this very first time we we need to so... Yeah. That's right. It's this
Silly little
appearance,
Da has been trying to develop a new way to churn butter
by po sticking around town with it. And so in in his discussed at having it still be cream, He gives Gladstone those last two items, the cream and the stick on his list and and heads off to invent butter buttered popcorn.
Yeah. You just hear the Ducktales scrolling in the background.
Yeah. It's a neat little
it's a neat little cameo, and I don't think anyone really knows whether bark knew that he was gonna
turn this other side character into a major character that that actually would get his own comic books even okay I feel like it's almost never the case with maybe maybe
character sometimes you would have multiple ideas at once, but I I feel like almost always...
It's just an incidental, and then when he's trying to think of the next stories like well maybe why what it is. But that's also often makes me wonder if if he would have picked different names or different design Severino known that it.
Character. Because when you think about it, screws deck is a very so sweet silly pun.
But.
Yeah. And and the names catch on so well, but is it's more maybe about the rep repetition and how familiar the characters. They come to people. Yeah. I mean, July news is Al.
Just a great name. I mean, it's is clearly in the beginning it's scary supposed to be more of a useless offender. I mean, it's in in the latest stories. He's still growing, but he a lot of mostly useless intentions. But every time, he becomes more more capable Huey, here he's clearly. He might Al well up be inventing anything
that works at all. Right. She's more of a cook cookie character.
Right. And he'll definitely,
again, Barks is gonna treat him how he that treats most of his characters, which is sometimes he needs them to be a bit cookie. In general, he's gonna evolve. But but even in the later stories, sometimes his inventions are are pretty ridiculous. What I do lu it's already here
is that... Because general four was pretty... Is a really gentle character especially for for the Barks Universe is one of the nicest
characters. Yeah also gets really frustrated?
That's true. That's... You don't really get see this version of Chi
much going forward. Yeah. And so the next page starts off right away with one of the best in my fan. That look the doctors look completely
defeated and tired of life. And they say the the nephew you say
why guys like butts ever want. Just just...
I'm just trying to imagine a child saying this
it is great. And and he really needs the Nephews
with Donald Here. I don't... Usually, they're not so affected By Gladstone, They kinda rolled their eyes at him, but but there are definitely stories where they are right on board with their donald
and hating him. And so the story takes a little bit of turn here. It's it's the first part where we actually see the characters
collide. Right? Where they decide to confront Gladstone and they tell him that they've got... They've got it test that they wanna probe his lock and see. If if it's really all it's cracked up to be so how do they wanna test Eureka. Yeah. So they're going to go for the ultimate test something that's way more impossible than getting a go stick from a straight, which is trying to get money from Uncle Scrooge. So yeah. I love that that this implies that getting all this stuff in a row is easy, but getting money from uncle Scrooge is what's getting bugs and really worried. And the actually has to literally grab him but a caller and and drag you out there. It's a great setup and and you were talking about how potent, like, his
characterization is with these this these characters of his. And and you're absolutely right, because this only works.
Because of what we know about Gladstone
and what we know about Scrooge. If if these were just random characters, this wouldn't matter. But we know that sp is Al legendary tight
and we know that Glad stone
has the supernatural luck. So it's very exciting to see them collide and see what's gonna happen.
And
how does it how does it pan out?? Yeah. So we move on to Scrooge
again, just sitting
in a room that's entirely covered money. But he's having a streak of of bad luck because he's his income has dropped to only a billion dollars per hour.
Which is I calculated it. That's two hundred seventy seven thousand dollar a second.
That's pretty terrible.
Yeah. And...
Yeah. I love how there's... He's he's walking around waiting in his money saying, I've never been this Inducks before which all of the that contrast that he always puts in these these Al where... It just doesn't match up before he's saying at all. Right. Right. Literally waiting through money. Yes. You're gonna meanwhile, the text actually says Al bell Gladstone to more chunk of
meanwhile he's physically pushing him towards closer to Watch the office.
Scrooge ones to
find a way to turn around his slack and he reads in some old book that he has to do something is never done before. Which it only takes him like, a few seconds to think of it because, of course, it's giving away money. Right. Yeah. That's supposed to be the antidote
to his bad luck. And so it's it's very predictable. Right? The Ducktales walk in the door and Scrooge immediately says bloody old boy, I... We... Will you indulge me and let me do my best worst accent and I I can't resist it. It's it's how I read these to my to my kid for Bed bedtime stories. Glad boy, I just resolved to get this sack of money to the first person that came through that door. Here take it is yours. And
that just looks terrified.
The reaction.
It's it's it's as old as dirt. Right? Characters like faint dead from shot, but somehow Barks makes his so funny here to me. Yeah. It's also all of them at the same time. You don't even see half of the nephews because they're just lying somewhere in the hallway.
Right. They they've all just faint away. It's it's hilarious. It's great. And so
now, we transitioned to the the last phase of the story where they're kind of, like, stew over it the Ducktales, and they they come to realize that he must have some kind of a good luck charm, some
very powerful Ducktales Al. And so they decide to
snoop in Glad stone house with him with him actually there. Yeah. And you can tell they only get away with this because they're actually family members, because absolutely
terrible to. There's just been completely rude for no reason. I mean, they have a good reason. But honestly, you why you don't feel sorry for god so but you almost should because they're just treating them very poorly and everything he would be well within his rights to kick them out as they... As they look under
in in every little base and and drawer of this house.
On other hand you just just get a huge sack of money from Scrooge jenny. It's just lying on the floor.
Right.
So they do see a safe. In one of his rooms near that sack of money and and it's it's pretty weird, right, that that stack of money is lying.
Outside of the safe
instead of inside of it. Yeah. And but some says line, of course, immediately,
once you turn the other page and raises have everyone's suspicion because he says, none of your oh well, that's safe for something else. Now we're home.
Right. Right. So he he does a great job Bark does of getting this level of intrigued and all these twists and turns and and this very short story.
So the Ducktales get kicked out of his house, but at least they have a good lead on where that luck charm is likely to be. And
So so they do as they're talking about this lead, they encounter their uncle Scrooge
looking extra guam. And he reveals to them that the reason that he had given glad on the money is what we the reader knew that he was trying to, like, d jinx himself
And Henry, it's always interesting to me that, like Bark
presents Scrooge as, like,
usually, he's pretty rational. Right? But but his version of Scrooge has this, like,
occasional
weakness for stuff like horoscope
and star charts,
How I thought that was pretty weird? Yeah. Yeah. I think you also discussed that especially with the...
What's the calls worth... The the the magic hour hourglass. Right. But that feels very out of character. Yeah do. Maybe he's just try you think feels desperate, but it's really one of those things where it just works for the story. Right. And and it definitely does. But if I'm I'm kind of paying attention to it, and I think there are more stories
that have screwed into this sort of, like
almost hippie stuff than you might
expect. Right? Because there's, like, the
the back to long ago story, and there's the the one with the, like Giant Emerald,
where he's like very worried about his bad luck Inducks Horace. Though Yeah. I I think it's maybe There's these certain stories with screws that are really well remembered and maybe also because then don't also have took this version of the character and build on that so that's something that people remember a lot.
Right I kinda left behind
that some of that other stuff. Yeah. Because, of course, I mean, it depends what you grew up reading. But if you... Like, me, I I read on bark stories as Inducks, but I mostly also read... All the stores probably the create set they their on on his come, but they always take a certain version of the character. So this aspect of the character kind got left behind so that's probably wipes still sort of character. Right. And and Barks really seem more flexible with the characters and than our fans are. Yes.
That's a very good point. So at this point in the story, Scrooge and the other duct come together as
the Ducktales Scrooge what they've discovered and that, you know, whatever that charm is could potentially turn his lock around. And so, you know, what they're proposing here is like obviously burglary
But...
But we we kinda gloss over it because they they are our heroes, but but I I guess it it does bear pointing out that this is wrong. They should try to. They're honestly being terrible.
Really awesome stuff We we don't like Gladstone,
so we'll forgive them for it. But when glad stone heads out to a movie later that night,
The Inducks get the opportunity for Scrooge
to
practice his safe tracking skills I I guess he never explicitly states it, but, I guess we're supposed to assume that, you know, Scrooge has a facility
around safe just because of his experience with money involved. Yeah. I guess he is into everything that involves money.
Of course, he would need to be an expert on safe. So I guess, he also forgets his own combinations all of the times. Right.
And and I love the little side where a Gladstone is that a Al clearly a western movie called Red Hot guns,
and he ends up leaving early Do you mind telling us why he leaves early? Yeah. He says pump movie. Only been six reagan trains bush. I'm going home.
Love that.
And and so Glad stone arrives
just as the duct have managed to crack and do is safe. And they
come to to discover that it's nothing but a plain
ordinary dime.
Which is... Which just funny that that Scrooge. So surprised that it being just a time because the number one then didn't exist yet. Right. But maybe the Barks got this idea. Yeah. Barks keeps going back to, like, these dimes that have power. I I wonder why a dime felt so much more potent for him
as like, it says number one dime. It's... There was a dime and the great trouble with Dimes
story. You know, is is the one that causes the problem. This the domino also the smallest coin in not in value, but in size in in the Us Yeah. It is it is physically the smallest and and I've I've gotta a think too that maybe the dime has a little bit of cultural relevance because it was the subject of the song, brother, can you spare a
during the great depression. I don't know if that's something
Nicely too. Yeah. It really does.
Yeah. The the lucky nickel certainly doesn't have the same.
But but then, of course, he will go with the quarter for the... That that famous story in Lan, so there's that. But Glad, you know, he he acknowledges yes a dime supposed you burglary
explain this outrage. And I like.
Yeah. It is It's totally fair. And I love how they just ignore.
There's rat that they they forget about all decency see. So they they en a confession out of him. Right? Donald
Right quite literally because it really just strangle
he just less.
That's right. Because... Because Donald asked If that dime is you are good luck charm, why don't our dimes bring us Good luck and and tell us about Gladstone
confession, Henri. Yeah. So it isn't a good luck charm Al. He still doesn't wanna come test something we get strangled, but then we'll finally say it, but so it's basically already crying at this point and he says once long ago in the very weird moment, I took a job.
At this point the the orders are already all just baffled. Yes. I actually worked. I earned it and and glad services
solving and just he's just breaking down. Never seen him this desperate in any other stories. He's been so ashamed if it ever since that he hit it and in the safe and never looked that it again. And while he says dis doll and one of the nephews just... I just looked at inside basically. I I love that like blank dead a gas
overwhelmed looked that Barks does
every once in a while. It's it's a great source of comedy. Yeah. These last worked for panels and just So great. And then that way it ends... You don't even get the cedar expressions this... It's just a silhouette panel because Mh. Early their expressions are just impossible to draw and donald ask screws for any comments and scratches says nothing that could be printed in the paper. It's it's excellent. And and I'm gonna I'm gonna ruin the comedy by analyzing it. But it's that perfect, like,
that lack of of matching
between
glad stones,
you know, his
interpretation
of it with with how they receive it. It it's just such great. Comedy, that mismatch of expectations.
Yeah. I think a lot of my favorite stories, the ones that are the most memorable to me and they're they can often be ten page your so it's just how absurd the concept of these characters is? And then
any of the adventure stores or any of the any regular bots can be great just because the characters are acting so well, but this is the stuff that you really remember, and this is what that whole... Basically, you go back to the first story where the whole
universe is based on it. It's just... I tried to think Barks and I always wonder how somebody comes up with something as crazy as this. But yeah it's the same with
which is... I think my favorite Barks story, which she just went through with that is
Terrible big boys. Oh, yeah. The
care of the be
the concept of the characters is just completely absurd. And I I love that with this story too. It's you could never write a story like this with with any other set of characters and I think that's what what makes it sticks out to me so much and just fact that the character basically also being terrible to reach check.
This is really funny. You feel like he deserves it even though he just nothing wrong in the story. Right.
Right. He he sets it up. Bark sets it up in such a nice way that you can kinda hand wave the characters behavior because hate his own character just for existing.
Right. Yeah. You know, it's interesting to that
as I've been talking to, like, some of some of you people who are creative or involved with to comics or or just have a a keen understanding. I think of the comics. It's... I've noticed this like, breakdown where you guys are more likely to point to some of these ten pager
as your favorite story. It feels like kind of the sophisticated
You know, it's a o o a ten pager is my favorite. When when for most fans, it's probably the adventure length stories that, like, stand out in their memory.
Yeah. I think I think a lot of people will still consider something like back to to gun or only,
those comments they're so great, But I feel maybe it's more feeling of the other one being appreciated
because health there. Yeah. And it it really is something to be
to be this funny and to create such a tight, tightly constructed story in ten pages. It it's it's incredible. Yeah. And let's just the fact that he does both is also... It just makes it so great to that you can do anything with these scared. Because I I love comics that are funny the most. Mh.
Fact that they also gone these adventures makes it, I guess, more more exciting to read the economics and
and it also really rounds out the characters. So, yeah, just to converse it down. Right. But, yeah. I could I could go through any of these pages and point out so many things that I think are so... So great both in the art and and the writing thing. Yeah. You don't talk about this... Each of these stories for three hours easy.
Right. And and there's so much about this one that works so well. But but for both of these, I think the thing that stands out to me is like the expressions and the expressive
he uses.
So much of the humor comes from the great faces that he makes. Yeah. Is something that you think
No. You're you're right. You were saying that talking about it just doesn't do it justice it's true. It's it's one of those limitations. That's why I tell everyone to get out there reprint or more likely just use your, like, memory of reading this one dozens of times if you're like us. Yeah. And that's what I... Maybe that's also why our
maybe like the ten pages left because they do really
rely on the acting because the the locations are
actually, parks in is in his big splash penalty beauty likes to go out with the art, but he's just more like the the regular pages his art is actually very barren in a way. He really goes with the bare basics,
which is actually makes the stories easier to read, but it's just a lot of... It lot of pretty smart drying. I think also because he had to produce so much art such to then. Yeah. Yeah. It's it's quite quite the brake neck pace
to put put these out at the at the rate that he did. I mean, I mean, the whole Disney Comics line was him for a little while, basically. Yeah. I think he did about half a page per day, which is not something I can manage to do and I'm not even writing these stories. So Yeah. That's something else. So, you know, these these are timeless stories apart from the swan bit that doesn't quite hold up. I think I think both of us probably like I... I'm assuming that you like the second one.
Glad stone terrible secret a little bit more.
I think story wise, I like that one best. Probably for the art. The first one makes me laugh more because the the the face is that one are just crazy. Right. So why don't we... Why don't we go through some of our favorite panels because I do like to highlight those. What what stands out to you from
Glad stone returns. Yeah.
The whole first page already just feels iconic to be think he's done more stories that start this way, but it's hard to take a favor.
It's okay. If you need
the pages is already at. Basically a favor than something else I love in that whole pages is in the background, you see a a number of characters and they're all staring at them sort making a whole apparently. Right. But I think if I would have to pick one so difficult... I it the panel as a whole I lost the last balance just the close of of that faces.
I also love in the... But is it the fifth panel? Just the way Gladstone Barks
such a this arrogant expression on
and Al just just You just can't stand it... Oh, yeah. Donald great full body winds there. Yeah. I I have to just disagree with you because that whole page is so great. It's and it's like very much one unit. You know? Yeah. And I do I do wonder what my Barks decide to draw a very detailed clock tower on the first dental for some reason. Yeah. Yeah. He he really did that. A lot his era he went a little bit more in detail than he always had to. Yeah. Likewise, but that's just also and I also remembering what I what I love as a kid because in the on the second page too you have they're fighting again. It's just glad pushing as face as foot into donald face and dog immediately jumping out and kicking kicking gloves in the rear. It's just so over to though. Yeah. It's excellent. Yeah. I mean, I love I love that first part of the story. I think there are plenty of good panels throughout the rest of it, but it is really that first page that stands out to me. Yeah. Yeah. That's that's such a... And it's it's also something... So in the balance, a lot of them are grew with a lot of the Dutch art were
inspired by the certain period of Barks is Al style so when you look at a lot of the dutch Come day, maybe Glass isn't,
but the art style is really based on this period so you get dialed with a really long beak and long neck And This probably feels like very comforting like the way the characters are supposed to look like to you. Yeah. A lot of the comics I grew up if they were made in the nineties. They look. They look almost like this. So it's just something in the dutch taste that apparently makes people
And, you know, there's some great energy too and his in his searching through for the Nephew Bank. That those are some great panels. As well. Yeah. And also, right after he gets electric heated by the lamp, and he he walks away from an nephews, and he's just I I would have to look up what he says in what he says in English.
Well It just looks so frustrating. It's a ten the basic making great. I gloss over it when we went through it, but he says me,
hoard,
shi locks, a shi lock, of course is is a little bit of a That that's a term that we wouldn't use today because that definitely has a connotation. Yeah. And it they bring back that word in the in the final... That's how we ties up the story at the end day they call themselves She logs. Right. And there's words in this comic that didn't age very well but it would be... I feel like if Sparks was living today and that in a different context you would've have just picked other words because it's... I feel like it was more or it shouldn't have been, but it was part of of common words to say where people didn't think about the origins of the words? Right. You're you're right. This was, like, in in I'm not gonna pick on him for using it because it was just common usage. We just know better essentially. It's it's the
name of the character from Shakespeare merchant of Venice. Who is a Jewish money lender.
That's just, you know, something that was in common use at the time. But... But, yeah. There there's some excellent panels and that one. What about a great dental is the one
where the jumps out of this costume you and he runs away and s... Oh, yeah. Runs towards the camera,
almost flying vertically sideways. And he... Every piece of costume which is flying in mid air but farther away from the gamma. It's also one you have to to see because my description is not really working. Right. No. That but you're right. That's a good catch that I'm glad we didn't miss that panel. It's a great one. So and about what about the next story? I know that I really like some of the motion of the the New newlyweds fight and how we don't actually see them where we're just hearing them. Yeah. It's lot into just smiling,
smiling at their fight.
Right. And and especially when the pie strikes donald fit donald those space I really like that. I also
really like, you know, you meant you highlighted at the end Right. For the previous story, it's kind of about the very first page for this story, it's kind of all about the last page.
You mentioned those last four panels. I don't... I hope I'm not stepping on your screen on your parade stepping on your thunder by saying those are just Have a good taste I would.
They're they're awesome. Yeah. And I also... I also loved it, then I think I was disappointed that one out there
when the nephews are wondering why people like Gladstone I ever born and they just have this after look of the feet under faces.
Right. And again, the the
bit with the Ducktales and Gladstone all faint.
For for such an overused corn gag, I think this is one of the best I've ever seen. Yeah. Also love to panel that comes right after it where he does thing where he uses Silhouette, but it it looks so dramatic they're they're sitting on our tree looking defeated, but because it's silhouette it makes the scene
really dramatic. They're saying, why, why is he so lucky?
Yeah. The Barks still silhouette is the thing that I didn't really pay as much attention to
until I started doing this series. And now now I'm finding that it's so notable and interest thing. You know, here and there, he probably did it to give himself a break. But a lot of the time, just as you said, he's, like, really highlighting a a moment and making it feel more Barks and dramatic. It's a combination of both, and that's something that, again, with he's being very
economic with how we set things up because in the same page where they faint You basically
did the four panels after the the dexter are just judging, but he drew them on a hill, so he doesn't have draw any background. But as you read it, you don't notice it at all? Because it just... You just gives you the information you need. So you see dialed walking
towards glad house and all you see is a tiny bit of grass and a roof of a house, but it's all the information you need. So it doesn't waste this time. Spending off of day drawing this whole city and perspective. He only does it when it really helps with the story when he he he wants to make an impact Right. That was very interesting for me to
to study that with how he draws in every time saving way, which you he just have to do it for producing this much art. Yeah. And, like, I... You know, we're in his golden age because these These are pretty much tied to the the adventure length stories that I've been doing around the same period at least close.
And some of those he really want all out, Like I I think about some of those pages that you did for in old California.
Some of those panels must have taken him a day to draw. Yeah. That that sort really feels like self service to me. It's just... It just really want to draw that. You... The the characters are ten times his details as usual Al will follow the the clothing he just. Yes. Sometimes she can really tell when art is just enjoying himself. Right. Right, Doing it Do more for himself than anyone else.
This is a bit of a tangent, but but what other stories kinda strike you like that that he's done.
Well, I mean, probably think dentures this disguise is also very self serving.
Right. Basically,
anytime when Huey, draws a lady instead of Inducks. I I honestly always feel like if it was up to Barks if it it's just been drawing ladies.
And we wouldn't have got many any Inducks at all. But I think that's right. If someone... If someone had paid him the Ducktales rate for for ladies for pretty ladies. I I know what he have been doing. Yeah. And I mean, there's panels that come to mind... Of course, like there's there's huge splash panels something like
as an ar you often want to drop fast and be done with it and be economical, But sometimes it's also kind of like to really get into drawing something detail. So when I think about in only a apparel man that dam breaking through, he did not have to make it that detail, but of I mean, of course, it makes the story work much better too. But
Definitely.
You can tell Huey, you probably really enjoy throwing that Yeah. Yeah. I got the feeling from... This is kind of a random one, but I I recently did
no such environment
and and I feel like he did so many images of that serpent
dancing. I I think the idea of it just tickle him, and he just loved drawing that sharpen right. Yeah That's I often wonder
how
how you got the ideas for stories, but I really think in a lot of cases he probably
thought of some scene that would be fun to draw. And with this story to the seemingly random shopping list, I'm I'm going to assume that he just follow seems that would be funny and unlikely. And then thought of the ingredients that we probably sound the fund in that context, I've now. Only came up with a stick.
Yeah. I think that's a good point. That's another thing that I've been having fun. Is kinda trying to peg the moment that he started with for some of these stories because you can tell that, like, he probably created some of these backwards.
Just just so excited to lead up. Yeah. And what I... What... So I'm personally not much of a right but would I always noticed is when you're sitting with multiple people. You have an idea and you start ripping on it. You come up with very
outlandish and funny things. And somehow Barks managed do it and entirely by himself So now r on his and I'm always just baffled by how it comes up with completely
new and crazy ideas like these say. That's a great way to put it. I love that. That's awesome. Excellent.
You know, I think we've done Al a really nice job of covering these stories
The the only other thing that I really wanted to cover, I just wanted to ask, do you have any other Gladstone
favorites that
pop to mind? And and they don't necessarily have to be barb. I will also mention
two that I I I've always found it really weird.
That, like
you mentioned Ducktales didn't really use Gladstone stone very much. That that's true. He he only appeared in a couple of episodes.
For both of the series. And I always five
seen it. I think That's not... But I never watched
Ducktales said much, and I think it in a new
they used him too, but they're not really the same character. I think. Yeah. I mean, he was he was lucky, but I think he was He was only in one or two episodes.
I do really like the act that they got to voice him. He's he's a funny comedian in English in the new...
In the new one. Yeah. Yeah. I'm not sure if I seen any... I know I I noted in one of the old
the quality in one of the old ones, he's basically more like a plot where he... I think it gets abducted or something like that. I don't I don't remember. Because basically, that's the thing. Maybe I could also still mention it with
howard grew up with these economics because
I've been reading these for actually longer than my memory goes back. U.
So I do remember we we got we got subscribed to the magazine when I was h five because there... There was a whole stack at the waiting room like the doctors, but I have photos of myself from earlier than that where I'm already wearing duct shirt So I literally really do not know any different than me that you liking these characters? That's great. I do remember the so it's funny because I can't remember reading like, remember which ones were the funniest to me before I could actually
text nice. But... Yeah, that's it's hard to explain these characters to people sometime when they don't know It's such a part of life almost for so many people here, but that was the thing with Ducktales. So I'm actually a little too young for Ducktales, but it was on Tv and reruns. I was born in nineteen ninety. And I was apparently at age five too much of a sn for Ducktales
because I was watching a show and I thought it's not... This is not screw. So why is this so nice? Right. Wait. Very Al.
Doctors is actually
great, but it is really tone down when you compare it to Barks comments and then especially the a lot of the European economics that are based on Barks he's even me and those stories a lot of the time. Really feels like a bit of a flat than. Yeah. It's easy to be a sn about duck if you're a Barks fan.
Yeah. And it's funny how I was more of a small as a child, and I am now one right.
Mom I know. I feel like I've loosened up a bit because, like, as as a kid there was a period of time where if it wasn't by a very limited number of creators.
You know, Barks and rosa and Van Horn
and and the my beloved
donnie Yep covers. I didn't really get to see a lot of his stories. But the covers like, really informed to my childhood and Paul Murray and God
for some of the mouse stuff, but the other stuff just didn't feel right for a long time. I figured out eventually that that was a very limiting
way to be. But with duck, I discovered it only about six months after
the comics, and I did a pretty good job of, like, separating them and being like, okay, I love this show because I did But it's not as good as these. The the comments that I that I love, and I'm so glad that I discovered the comics just a little bit earlier than the show, because most people in in the states definitely have the opposite experience.
Or more likely, they never... They never knew anything about the comics at all. Yeah. It's just it's so hard to imagine you think Barks of how popular use to be, but... It's funny Out Europe this... I mean, Economics... Of course, the the leadership is also going down here, but the amount is still... Yeah. So crazy, I think I'm not sure. I think they still have estimates.
There's almost a million people read every week. I think they current three hundred thousand copies and they
estimated a million people rated in our country has maybe seventeen or eighteen million people in a total. So that's that's something. That's a pretty awesome. Of the population. But...
I must be thrilled to know that when you're published in it, you're you're being seen by such a such a nice number of your fellow country. Yes. It's a it's a really strange idea that you walk into into supermarket and it drawing is just lying there. But...
Yeah. The now is also a bit odd because we don't have the joint credited here, so it's just like the old days where it. Basically, you want, like, who is this this art stands at. It's funny to think back of which stories I remember.
Standing out to me as a kid and also not now in new you're. And then you also do notice that you do a favorite artist because I think
lot these kids can extra detail the difference even though there's also large of people we just think well disney need through and appreciate. Right. Yeah. It took me... It took me a while, and I'm glad that the glad
company
went out of their way to tell me who was making the ones that I really loved. Yeah. I I'm still trying to think of
favorite glad stories, but I think I also have to be honest in that they a lot of them a lot of these ten pages kind of blend together in my you know have read them in a while and it's it's often the the character interactions that I remember run the overall. But at some point, I'm I'm gonna be doing a follow Al with a couple of my other favorite Glad stone stories. I'm not gonna try and cover every single ten pager.
But but for my part, I do love the
Gladstone
hunters. I think it's called with the media that lands when they're
sw each other over gems.
And then there was, like a phishing
contest that or Donald was was competing against plaid. I don't remember the name of I really like that one on. And I look forward to covering that. And. Also just remember a lot of specific panels.
That
the the the
story where they come to Beach and they're just fighting and something on each other and there's bunch of birds sitting to the site looking on. And then, you know, the only other thing I forgot talk about is that...
What do you think? Is is ten page or Gladstone better than Adventure length Gladstone?
I'm trying to fix... There's not even that money, long stories were
because there's not a ton, but there's, like it's mostly early ones to us
he's really mean and all of those. Like, he's a really like
very unlikely character in rest South sea. So... Oh, yeah. She's terrible and
I mean, lack of the north is one of my... Mh. Top favorite stories too, but more because of all the mental turmoil donald goes through. Right. Because they're... He's also just very unlikely in there even though it's it's donald to get him into the trouble, but he's just... Takes advantage of them and It's true. So I'm I'm trying to think if there's any... If there's too many later stories with him other than the the Christmas ones?
There's that billion dollar
Safari. I think that's a bit later, right? Where they're looking for the elephant And it might be one. So I still there's still quite a few stores even from my favorite period that I haven't read yet. I never really wasn't a rush reading them because I like the idea of still having
discovered Barks that I'm going to to love. So... Oh, yeah. That'll actually one I think I haven't richards. Nice. Yeah. That's a pretty good later one. Yeah. For my part, though, I I always picture Gladstone is more of a ten page. He's he's been in a decent number of ones. But, like, to me, he is a ten page a character. Yeah. I'm also... It's not necessarily one of my most favorite stories, but the easter parade story where he's he's literally just poisoning the kids with for I think it's for gasoline and dude kids can. Oh, yeah.
How long I've age well.
I think it's hilarious. But
excellent. Well, Well, I I really appreciate you coming on. I think this has been an awesome
conversation.
Thank you so much for you know, just having this great fan conversation and and letting me talk to you about your art as well.
Hope to have you back on at some point. Yeah. You're welcome. It's
anyone who has to sit with me for an extended period of time well well now that I'm happy to talk.
Yeah.
Listeners can stay tuned. We'll have more episodes of the ten page podcast. Thanks again, and we'll will be with you again soon.