We have
Hello, and welcome to Barks Remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comics of all time. This episode is a ten page podcast, all about one of his short stories. Get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Welcome back to Barks remarks here with another episode of the ten page
podcast.
I'm doing something little different. Today I've never had two guests for one of these. But this is a very fun story we're gonna be talking about stat
spend thrift
which is a bit of a trick to say. And for that, for for this story, I've got a couple of returning guests
I I'm gonna introduce them and then I'm gonna ask them to tell us about the first comment that they ever read. So we've got Ryan Bailey and Eric Hart. And Ryan, do you remember the first comic you ever read? I think I do.
What I was I bet it was five or six,
and I saw comic at the gas station, and made my grandpa buy it for me. It was a spider. I didn't realize until I was in adult and read a lot of comics
that this was like a reprint that it was not that week's issue of Spider man. It was from the sixties or seventies or something, and I think it's issue number is in the sixties somewhere, but it's... On the front, it just has a guy named Joe, and it's like this one off one off comment about a guy who's robbing banks or whatever, but then you find out that it's because he has some kind of problem the, you know, some Illness or someone in his family is sick or something you get the sympathetic billing kind of thing, which was pretty revolutionary at the time. And Spider man figures out a way to help him out he doesn't have to commit friends anymore as I recall. I I think I remember that one. I think I've read that. But so I think that's a classic issue. Yeah. I think the guy got like a power suit or something. He had something that kind of soup him up, so he was a little more dangerous. Right. Yeah Yeah. Excellent.
Yeah That's that's a good Spider man is a good one for your first comment. How about you, Eric? Do you remember?
No. I don't.
Then that's because I grew up with older rollers and siblings that products all the time. I can pretty much get. Though it was gonna be Disney comment
because every summer my family take the road for summer vacation. And my dad would always start a little bit and buy a whole bunch of one shot disney comics for the car to read. And still the always pass but me a mickey mouse to the super good I ingredient and those. So I a kid or could
Inducks one as well, but there's always four five east Disney when shot comments floating around with Al whenever we're driving back and forth. And so I don't know what comic it was, but I remember reading lots of charges
when been during the numbers as a kid. Nice. So So for all you know, it could well have been a Barks stomach Even. Possibly. Yes. Yeah. That's great. Well, you you might have guessed the reason that I asked is because this story actually happens to be the first comment that I ever read. Not just
first, you know, Disney or Barks one, but this is, like the first actual comic book. I don't have the original
anymore because I think it was in tat from so many reread. But,
obviously, that means that stat
spend drift holds a bit of a a deer place to me. It is... It is a very famous ten page or two. You know, it's been it's well remembered by Carl Barks fans and he he wrote it in in what is considered widely considered to be his, like, golden age of putting out these stories. So
this is a good one. I I love this one even
apart from the facts that, you know, it's the first story, first comic but I ever read. You know, that... That's funny too because it means I can kind of track when I actually started reading these. So this one
my reprint from Uncle S two twenty six came out in May of nineteen eighty eight. So I was
roughly eight years old when I started collecting these. And
we should note that the the titles Barks himself never came up with these titles. They gave these titles after the fax for the ten pager. Most of them were just released un title.
When did you guys think of the title of this one?
For sure. Yeah. Yeah. They like the laurent and they like a a little word play, you know? Right. Yeah. Yeah. I always like the title they picked for this one. They they don't always go to such like care to make them as clever. Let's see a little bit of background about this story. This one was published
in
Walt Disney comments and stories like most of these ten pager are and this one came out in March of nineteen fifty
two.
I I mentioned that it, you know, this is kind of during his golden age So this this actually comes out the very same month that Carl Barks gets the
gets his first stand uncle Scrooge story published. It was later considered uncle Scrooge number one, the the famous story only a poor man. That is kind of like his origin story more or less. So
very notable. And
if you look on like, the index. You know, I talked about those stories and the the the stories and how well they rank on that community on the community page Inducks. This one, when I checked, this was actually, like his fourth highest
rated of it Al is ten page stories. There's just a handful of them that the community likes as much as this one. Does have a couple of notable first appearances, you know, this is the first time that
kind of legendary
town found or cornelius who is gonna get referred to.
And then the mah mirage, how do you stand is gonna be used a couple of times in in his other stories, he'll look a little bit different. I think he liked the name, but he probably didn't remember how he showed the guy at first.
And, you know, I I like to talk about kind of the cultural
context of these. This one is really... First off. This is a weird story. Right? This is like There's some... There's some definite cartoon logic. It it really pushes the boundaries of what's possible.
It's pretty wild, but I feel like this one really also has a lot to say about kind of capitalism
and.
S. Thank you. Yeah. If I feel like it has some some weird things to say some some interesting things to say about Land to I don't know, Eric. What what is your kind of, like what's your take on this story before we get into the content Well, it's Okay. I... I'm sorry. I I have to bring in current events. I apologize when you talking about the and the world were just stuck and then this past week, you have one of the world's I'm using get go to richest and decide he wants to buy twitter and spend forty one billion dollars to buy a company and five times it like, this it's even real. I mean, it's just the figures years and the concepts that the turnaround around it seems hard,
and then to read this comic to realize yes, it is. It's very finished for what a bill giant statues they up into to each other. I mean you could also use that the metaphor of the billion space race. Trying to get there first who's gonna spend the most. And doing it from the benefit
kind, doing it for everyone, but I'm gonna do it first. Right? And there's some length that we do it, but
more ego. Oh, yeah. Before I launch into the story, I I like... I like it when I can find quotes from Barks about his specific stories. And there is a doo of a quote about this one. He said that well, first off, this one's more inn. But in nineteen eighty three notes, for the Carl Barks library. He had commented about this one that he he said I used our a cartoon
license to carry the statue building contest to the ridiculous limits of nonsense.
How will the world ever get along without
shots? So that's that's fine. But then he had another quote in response to a reader letter, which he would get occasionally. So the the publisher
received a complaint basically, Al a reader who thought that the money contest was over the top it was a gross misuse of of money that, you know, obviously, it's a fantastic story.
He said, I don't blame that woman for writing a letter saying that she thought it was a gross misuse of money to build these enormous statute all crust with diamonds. When there were so many things that could have been done with that money, like building hospitals
and schools and better jail. I wrote back to the office, telling them that the woman missed the point entirely. The money that had been spent on those statues had bought labor and materials and had all gone into circulation much better than if it had continued lying in the mah raja money then. Or uncle sp is money back. And have created a tremendous amount of work for jeweler and gold smith's, and concrete men and hydraulics experts, everybody had a job out of that. So the money hadn't been wasted at all.
Wow. I can't even tell if that's Barks sarcastic or not.
And you think... I as I was reading it I was thinking, man, they could've... This is obvious billions of billions of dollars that they're spending on the biggest monument in human history history. And and they could have done anything with this Anything would have been better, not even like curing cancer, but even like, during athletes foot, like anything would have been positive, you know? And you could be like, This is a thing we achieved, you know, instead of just nothing.
Right. Yeah. So I mean, that tells us something that I I'd have learned about Carl Barks since I became an adult. Right? Which is that he is a supply cider.
He he believes in supply side economic. He's...
He he comes from a very, like, right wing economic background, which I I am not
to. But
but but it's it's interesting to me to think of that perspective. Right? That... That's this whole philosophy of of people rich people,
spending money creates jobs. They are job creators.
And he thought Eric? I did
Yeah. I I learned a little bit about that one, and saw my
people in the world nowadays.
They're not spending money They're they've done assets
that they're borrowing against. So that way, they don't have to pay taxes and then you know, get debt to offset whatever money they're getting And they're spending money that's already out there. They're borrowing from banks. And usually it just goes other rich people anyway. It's not like it's gonna trick if you're gonna know. It's is not a thing Right. Right. This is very trickled down
economic. And there's a couple of of... There's a small number of stories where he really makes that explicit too. I'm gonna have It'll be interesting talking about those. There's gonna be some stuff I have to grapple with. Anyway, you guys ready to dive into the actual
action of statues because spend.
I born already. Sweet. So.
As always, I'll go through the action of one page and then tell me what you think.
So
statues
spend trips kicks off with one of the my favorites.
Tropes.
Someone getting kicked out of a building, someone getting
rushed.
And had donald and his nephews
see that it's not just It's it's not just anybody. It is the mayor and the park commissioner. I like that they can recognize the part commissioner.
By site. They have just been kicked out of their uncle Scrooge office. Oh, I'm just noticing that this Nephew says uncle Scrooge instead of Un Scrooge.
And
must be a typo.
And so the two lu are calling Scrooge Inducks out as A phony. Right? They're saying that he's not really the rich man that he claims, and Donald approaches them and asks, you know, what what did he do? Had they explain that he
refused to give them a few call thousands of his moldy dollars.
For the purpose of directing a statue of Corn cornelius
coupe who is the city founder.
And they blow
about how important it is to to pay off the debts,
the humidifier debt to their town founder.
And sp hears from the window and,
you know, basically says to go away and stop saying I ink the world's richest man where I might get mad and prove that are f.
Yeah. It's good. You can even see the Barks commissioner is still kind of mid air in the first frame. Has not quite hit the sidewalk yet on its way out, and they both have... They both have coats Ducktales and top hats.
There has... The mayor has a king naturally, and they have some fancy shoes
so that everybody knows how important they are. Right. Yeah. I I love the signaling.
And thought, Sarah? I just trying to figure out why Barks from make should be was Inducks tu pale and middle today. But, yet, he's got these dressed of the nines
So I think it's pretty hilarious. I also like other both highest matched their pants When you're when you're ray in that civil serving salary, Eric, you gotta you gotta flash it. You know, you gotta show people what you're what you're about that you're stuck that cheddar. You know? He's with some there, so I'm sure they could benefit it as a as a
right. It is right. So the next page,
basically, this sequence is all about the arrival of the mah
of how do use stand?
That's how I've always mentally pronounced it. Yeah. That's looks like pretty much a phonetic pronunciation. Yeah. Inducks
is basically all in t because they've got this foreign visitor,
and he is
quote some big shot from the orient that's vacation named Inducks,
and then they're calling him the richest man in the world and we close in on him from moment and basically
wanting to stop and show off as well. He says that actually,
Eric, you wanna you wanna read the my
quote there? Plain are all the like splendid stoplight white tossed thousand droop of the.
I likes that little,
you know, play on rupees. The currency name that he picked. And so the
the mayor and the part commissioner
see see this sky, and they view him immediately as like their pigeon. Ryan, you wanna tell us what the mayor says.
Call out the city band. Some of the Parade Marshall We must greet this royal visitor and a style be fitting his bank role I mean, his his importance.
So they're obviously gonna try and suck her the money out of him.
And we we end this page with the Nephew wondering if
if this guy is, in fact, richer
than An Scrooge. They do say this time. I didn't notice until this past
that the hood ornament on the Mah rogers car is a pink elephant, a fairly large pink elephant. Yeah. Since that interesting. Yeah. The in this coloring, it's pink. Barks didn't have anything to do with coloring. So...
Oh, I don't I don't know what it was in the original. I've got I've got a reproduction of it around somewhere, but I thought I'd grabbed this you know, this one since I've got the nostalgic cake for it. But, yeah, it's it's a pretty cool look and hood ornament. It's a neat car too. I like Barks over the top flashy Barks. He's he's Al a few like this. I like that he brought his fancy car with him on vacation. That's right. Yeah. Be be fitting the richest man in the world.
So on the next page, it's... We've transitioned to the next day and Donald reading in the newspaper
about the gift that Indeed the Mah
has promised to the city fathers.
Twenty thousand dollars
to e a statue of corn cornelius K
Eric, can you tell us Donald,
the the panel where he reads the Mah mirage has comments about his gift twenty thousand proof are charging some says the immensely what the visitors mh lush orient. Right. And so Donald Rush is off. Basically, he's he's being a bit of an ins here because he wants to gl. To Scrooge to see his reaction. And we we enter on Scrooge
doing what he's often doing around this era.
Of Barks showing him trying to hold up his
overflowing safe. Ryan, how does Scrooge react to what's in the paper?
He says.
Oh,
oh, which is the famous, you know, scottish people say that all the time.
World's Richest van, twenty thousand dollars.
Try some, and then the ups start, the blessing tin horn, he can't be the world's richest man. I am. Right. So he's had exactly the kinda of react
you assume that Donald was hoping for. Right? He's he's kind of wound him up here. And Donald points out that, you know, this guy is showing his money. So that's that's how we know that he must be the richest. And and this is gonna be pretty weird
because Scrooge dries to the bay. What did you guys think of that? Was that? Did you think that was on? A little bit? But it's not... It's pre character foods just he wants me that we're just done purchased just man in the world and Barks then you didn't have, you know, his computer's with porta, but it wasn't like someone not well but, you know, whatever net worth was something, like update, like, nowadays. There's lot showing in bragging. And screws me now when spending just wants to save and show that he's done it but it paid that said and been cool. Yeah. I did notice that on the first page
outside Scrooge office when the the
officials got thrown out of his office Scrooge chat sign front. I'm not gonna mis it here. It says Scrooge Dot World's richest man.
Like it's his like it's his title, the way you would have, like, agent or secretary or president or whatever under any anything else. So least in the context of this issue, he wants everyone to acknowledge that he is the world's richest man. Right.
Gonna be very important him. I love the fact that he's willing to have sp like he worked, but donald.
I know you too cheap to buy a paper. So let's tell you what sense. Right.
Reaction. I'm gonna go spend thirty thousand dollars up spend going.
So the next sequence is basically
all about screwed resolving that he is gonna out spend him to build a better statue. So he sends Donald off to find out the details, how big it's gonna be and what it's gonna look like. I really like the panel where he kind of
reflects and he says a crazy world. A man's wealth isn't what he's got. It's what he spends. And we transition
to
a dedication one week later. This is some pretty quick turnaround and statue building world Al I've gotta imagine.
The There's a dedication for the unveiling of the statue
and as the... As the statue is un unveiled, you know, his nearest narration box is great here. I'm gonna let it do the work. He says, but as the vale falls, a great guest is gas. For there on the left another veil falls and it's another
larger
identical statue of Corn cornelius to So I Gonna say, I think it's weird to have him spending big money just out of ego, like spending... I guess that's the point of the comic. Spending the money doesn't make him the richest span in the world. He just is, or he is not.
And spending it if anything can only make you the second rich Man wants. Eventually, if you spend enough And so it seems really contrary to all the past appearances I've seen of him and everything I've seen of him, you know, in cartoons and stuff.
You know, we've read issues where he is willing to, you know, kind of throw his family under the bus throw donald under the bus to save five dollars or whatever try and, you know, make a profit at Donald expense
or whatever, and I don't know, get he eaten by Barks or whatever he's been doing to Donald in the recent years. Right. And so,
you know, being so so just
sting just where you just have sting turned up to a hundred it seems weird then to to have an issue based around him trying to out someone else in the opposite of that. And that's that's a fair point. I I I like to do this way though is because he knows donald port, and they're also run his four. This is the person you seen interact with someone who claims to be here. And so now somebody that's disposal on his level. He's like, well, now, I gotta show it. And it's it's it's the whole idea. He's been working hard for his whole life to be rich in the world. Now there's some try to take that title and the public at the news and the papers are gonna say one thing, I have to prove them differently. And so if it's spinning this way, we have to do it. And I think as always screws as a plan. I I just love the idea personally.
They're surprised when was another statue. Twice as big. We didn't see that before. Oh, I know.
No. Wow. What be? Yeah. I I love the cartoon logic they have to
overlook here that
he's somehow hiding.
The second statue
at least for these first couple. And that it looks like there. It looks like they're thirty feet apart well like surely you have one crew building away to get one of these done in a week and they didn't notice the other crew chipping away Al something even bigger right behind them.
Right. Yeah. The story falls apart. Obviously, if you think about it too much, this one is like this one's definitely chronic buck logic.
It also really falls apart too if you like think about as you said, Ryan,
sc and who he is. This is just one of those cases where Barks had this story that he wanted to tell and he has this really rich character.
So he's gonna be a little bit flexible.
This is also, like I said, just before he really kind of hone the character and fine tunes him to give him his like long running uncle screwed series, you know, He at this point, he's still... Like, he's a recurring character, but he's still this one off side character. So I'm gonna cared too much
up until now about being persistent. Even even just beyond Scrooge
characterization, like he's also been given this name from a literary figure. Right. From a Christmas Carol, who's, like, only characteristic and his whole character arc is about how he spent his whole life loving money more than people and has to learn how to, you know, get the Christmas spirit and... Right. So they they're really... It's not it's not a subtle
character
Scrooge here.
So
after the unveiling, you know, the the Mah
is
outraged, of course.
The town couple of the members of the town look at the the plates, which says that it's erected
Ryan you wanna read what whether it says there. Directed an honor of brave old Cornelius by Screw Dot world's richest man. And Richest is spelled with twenty two karat gold. Right. And and so the Mon asha has outraged. And so He does the most logical thing you can do when you've already got one big statue and one much bigger statue, of the town founder, he commissions another. As one does as one does.
And and Scrooge and Donald are hiding in the back around, and Sp is telling him to again get the dope on the new statue. How big and how fancy and we get another week
another
unveiling
And so the the story is escalating and and what is immediately this pretty predictable way
But it works for me. It's totally ridiculous.
I love it. It's so much says he thought that the Al you stand calls them at Saint as well. Right that's a pretty western
Us western turn, but alright. Go for it. Yeah. It's a weird turn of phrase there.
Yeah. That... That ups start that bras tin horn. So
again, on the next page, it escalate and the the my is is kicking his
his servant or whoever around
to cable is treasury for more funds to build another statue And again, we've got the Inducks in the background.
You've dropping on the details,
and this one takes we
and I love the unveiling of this one so much because the narrator box... The narrator boxes are just great. Ryan, do you wanna read the near... The two narrator boxes there? Okay. For weeks, machines rumble and roar behind huge screens. As rival Scrooge labor in the gigantic race for whatever honor the biggest statue will bring, then the camera then
the camera must pull back to an extreme long shot to show the awesome finish of this third round in the battle of the titans.
Close parenthesis.
And then we get... You can see in the distance is the tiny tiny skyline of the city, as these buildings which must be a thousand feet tall. These statues
dwarf the city beneath them.
Right. These these statues have clearly
caused a massive depression
Al global depression as Every bit of concrete has been totally mono.
Do you guys remember a few years back when, like, China was building that enormous dam and it like... Yeah. The three gorge to damn. Yeah. And it like, it sucked up some ridiculous amount of of concrete
and like the Skyscrapers
that they were building for a while,
occupied some huge percentage of the world's frames.
That's kind thing that I I can't help but think of like, what it would actually take. How many how many thousands of people do you think it would take how many years to build these stat. I was just going to say, maybe if China had been Al rich as Scrooge, they could have just built the three gorge damn in a few weeks. You know? Yeah.
I I should ask my architect wife, how long it would take even to this to cure
I guess, I guess they're using... I guess, the this is granite. I don't know.
At some point, they mentioned Marble. I don't remember if they've made marble yet But... Yeah. This is like, all the marble italy, yeah. Yeah. Just Make it make it ninety stories high of imported marble says the raja earlier on this page. This is well over ninety stories by way.
Yeah.
Yeah. We've all seen skyscrapers,
and these
But it's just such a great panel. We've got these, like thousands in the four
that are reacting to
to the colossus.
The new doc c here. Also, I love the name Corn cornelius K. It's it has kind of an old time you sound to it. Look because for someone who would have found it in the eighteen hundreds or something. Right. But but also, k,
especially for our readers for whom English is not the first language is kind of a slang term for, like, kind of a kind of Al an eccentric old guy, you know? Yeah. A little bit disrespectful, I would say, probably.
Right. But it is also a word for an actual
aquatic water file.
So in itself, his name is just kind of interesting. It has some layers to it. There really does and and for this, like, little one off, it's not even a character or it's an illusion to to a a a person that must have been dead for generations. Right? And a historical figure. And like Barks really creates some eye icon
with him holding up these ears of corn.
I don't know. If it is iconic. Eric, you you are familiar with him already. Right? Yeah. Yeah. No. It's...
I mean, he's a he's a famous person in That there's mortgage to about, you know, that being his family that sold uncle Scrooge the the the side of the money Bin, the... You, side of
kill at the time kill me with little. Has. To motor him. But... Yeah. No. He's he said I kinda figure, but I think it's mainly... I don't know. I idea Al. They don't want to how to be,
you know, screw dot bill. They wanna maintain their their heritage and say, okay. It's While that runs everything, this is the first time of the town. Yeah. And that's that's my thinking of it. Maybe that's one reason my screwed you don't wanna give them any money to, like, what don't I care? I mean, I... I've been charge. I like all the, you know, close through that enterprises. That's true. I just think it's it's it's worth mentioning that it's a it's a pretty cool bit of world building. Right? Because Ryan, you probably weren't familiar with this. You can he can barely even call him a character because it's a statue of the character.
Yeah. Yeah. I'm I've never heard of him before. So, I mean, like Eric said, he's gonna get used in a couple of later don rows of stories where he kinda Rosa will kinda piece together his, like, biography Scrooge,
and and He'll referenced a few more times in the Barks stories, but this is his first appearance. This is where where he came from he's gonna used in both iterations of duck
there was actually a a real corn cornelius
statue in Disneyland for a time.
I never got see it, but apparently, it was in, like Mickey Hometown for a while, you could see this statue. I do really like this. It feels very iconic. Corn cornelius to with that pose holding up the corn. Yeah. I like the fact that you can see one of the statute up to the right of
gate lens and then there's a little well
just kinda hang up shutters I was gonna ask if the statue and two town Al Disneyland had... If the air was thinner at the top of the statue then it was at the base Al the statute right.
I I think it was only to scale. I'm unfortunately okay.
Alright.
To think what history will say when later on the
the ruins nature or the duct
funny
six statute love this guy.
Important.
Yeah. You talk one are gods.
Alright. So
the the raja after this latest unveiling
remains furious, and he
he calls for more elephant loads of droop rupees and more ship loads of marble.
But the the mayor is like desperately trying to stop him. He's pleading. No more stats. She's cornelius too. We're overwhelmed. And and you feel like this is a hail Mary. He's like, why don't you make a statue of yourself for some variety
because, like, apparently, he's powerless to stop him from just
taking over the city with these Ge statue. And and so the Raja, being a vein
multi trillion
likes this idea
and thinks this is his opportunity to out him And I I like this sequence this segment here where again, Donald is gonna Ea drop on his plans for the statue.
Eric, do you wanna tell us
what he hears the mah raja commanding? Make my that you solid gold forty feet high and turn my trim and make my treatment diamonds sit lizard pearl and dry, I want
And the Nephews who are over hearing this are all just looking progressively
sicker and sicker. It's pretty great. And
the next page of the story, this is just a random little side. But in my comment, it was a double fold glad stone was advertising a bunch of their own back issues.
And for the first couple of times that I read it's it didn't know that there was more comment So I just like, oh, this is a really good story, kind of an abrupt ending.
Then I read on.
Like the third or fourth time I just vividly remember having that a epiphany and like there's more to the story. So the the next segment is basically donald starting to regret that he's egg Scrooge on the Sees eyeball his vol his notice that it's actually looking starting to look pretty empty,
Scrooge looks totally bothered And we we kinda see citizens of duck
starting to
debate who's gonna win this ridiculous money competition and and eventually, the big day does roll around. And Donald than the Nephews are
upset to see that his statue from from the cover appears to be no bigger and the mah
and
we do see the mah
get un unveiled first, and it it looks as spectacular as that description of his planning
suggests
the Mo raja thinks to himself let that up start mick
that. Just let him try. And
we should go on to the next page. Right? Yeah. Ryan, you wanna tell us about the unveiling of bridges statue.
So he unveil it, and it's just one diamond top hat
under the veil and then
Scrooge
for show ship, pulls the lever and reveals that it's a whole statue, it just springs out of the ground on hydraulics.
Just for this one off presentation too whatever local
are watching this.
And it's eighty feet high, and it's solid diamond Severino platinum. And eyes that are star sapphire fires as biggest as football and and donald fe away overwhelmed by it. And some raja
is also
overwhelmed. And we've got this this really
sad turn with him where he's he's
spent himself into
oblivion,
and his servant who he... He refers to as his dog of a servant
He asks him, can I afford to try again? And the servant tells if you can't afford beans you bum? You're broke
And what do you guys think about the mayor,
suddenly having a mortgage on the Mah has has fancy clothes.
Was trying to figure out how that would even work. But I decided you know what? That's not not the weirdest thing in this coming.
Everyone everyone turns on the
raja of how do you stand. Maybe they're just all upset and all all these Eyes
but they turn on them so quickly.
So the the last page of the story is
basically
has the mah raja paying a call on Scrooge,
and he is he's in that old cartoon trope. He's wearing the poverty barrel.
I guess this goes back to... I I shoulda looked to this up. I don't know who is the first person who decided that when you lose all your money, you wear a barrel, I can think of other better things to wear, but but it's a great trope for whatever reason.
And Scrooge greet him pretty warm and
is telling him how much he enjoyed his visit, but the Mah raja sees a silver lining. He notices that at least Scrooge is vault is empty, and he appears to have earned through his fortune, just like he did. And then and then we get a little payoff off at the end. Eric, you wanna tell us about what Scrooge reveals? Well, my husband is a hi. You're saying empty broke two. Weird like broke me. Now on my pay cash state. My big money then is in the three cubic acres in the basement and the door... The tractor door floor seems to open up and
said mountain of cash that has underneath. And then makes you realize that true was just clearing on his petty cash. We got from the good one cash in. Al earlier, he was... The same the state was busting out. And He's was like, boy, I just something with his money level. Well giant statute Yeah. I never thought of that is kind of a justification for it. But but either way, it's a great... It's a great way to show us
his over the top well. That, you know, he could empty that vault out not really care even if it's a little bit out of character.
And we get a little comic sting where Donald Scrooge are walking past the rush literally, literally begging in the park
and Donald Cha he him says you should be big hard and give him a dime for a cup of coffee, and Scrooge
Chase is him saying a dime, what do you think I am a dog on spin
and and that's that. So
that is stat
spend trips. Like I said, this is regarded as a as a classic of Barks ten pager. I suspect that it stands out to people because it's such an over the top. It just you're if you ever read this one, you will always remember it. Right. Like, the the statue two building contests contest. Even if it doesn't have a title, you can describe this one. Pretty easily.
What what do you think, Ryan? How does this story stack up? Compared to some of the other Barks stories you've read or just as as pond. So I don't think it... I don't think it holds up to like, the the standard Barks level of writing quality
because
they set up... It's like setting up a a comedy sketch or whatever they set up the situation. Here's the ridiculous situation. The two richest men in the world tried to prove that the richest by building them a more, you know, luxurious statue. And they take it several levels until it goes way beyond, you know, to its logical conclusion of how how expensive is statue you could one human possibly make? They have both done it now. And then you need, like a twist you need like a punch line to kind of take it home, you know? And they're just isn't one. Like the the punch line is just... It turns out Scrooge which are
like that's that's just how it ends like. So I was as it was building up and and building to this cr, I was actually waiting and, like, anticipating a little bit, like, once you gonna to do? There's gonna be something crazy. They unveiled these last statute, the mah raja is gonna drive himself into bankruptcy on this last one. It's gonna turn out Scrooge is gonna build one out of butter, or he's gonna do need do something to kind of twist and knife him and show that he's five steps ahead of everybody else. Like he is at all the other comments, you know? But he isn't he's just Richer. That's
that's the the punch line is just East richer. They played poker and they just kept pushing it and... Pushing their money into the table. And at one point one of them ran out. The other one didn't then the game ended and.
So I was waiting for him to, like, really out smart them my raja like he does donald every other time I've seen him. And and he doesn't. He just has more money. Alright. So this one doesn't work as well for you. What about you are?? What what are your thoughts on this?
I think it's I kind of yours running a little bit regarding it's not the most complex one he's ever written. But I like the fact that this was stu plan all along was to the guy. But I'm gonna make this the said richard with me. I'm I'm so confident my well. I'm gonna make this guy broke prove, and it's gonna be great. And Scrooge fruit is more than had to do that he just and just re it. Because it's true Scrooge
and that he is a me and wants to proving he is better than everybody else. And now the town came come back and say you.
He's like no listen. Under guy. Shut it. Remember that how to do How do you use? I? I drove to the poor house. I
dropped. It's like a drop the mic moment. He doesn't have that smart. Here's anything it's it's the easiest contest for can win because he does have the most money. He's happy to prove it. But, yet, only on his terms. He's not gonna go give it away even dying at a charity, but this guy go, you know, take a chi one of the statute and get some money. Yeah. I mean, this one does feel kind of like weirdly petty
this one's heavier than some of them. Right? That he's just trying to try and to make the guide go broke. I I really like this story. I don't know that I can like give it an honest
appraisal just because it literally is the first comment book I ever read. I read it so many dozens of times
And I do love the audacity of the... Just the very concept. You know, this like, over the top stat building, I I think you've definitely got a kind of like, except that this one is
impossible. This one is a little bit more comic logic
than than a lot of his stories are gonna be But... I mean, I like the story telling this when I I accept your criticism of it Ryan because it is kinda simple. But I think it's got some really, like fun terms of phrases
in it, you know,
And and he... In the course of only ten pages, he's got like these three rounds of statue buildings
plus then this fourth over the top one
and just that Al little bit of world building that he does with the town founder. I I think I think this is remembered for a reason. It's It's not maybe as clever as some of the other ten pages from this era. I'll show you guys couple of the ones that I've done re there they're really something. But I I like this a lot. According to mentioned
the
barrel as a show of poverty,
dates from, like, political cartoons in the in the depression the nineteen thirties. Nice. And people started using it to to show that they're very poor. But that makes sense. Yeah. I I couldn't help but think about some of the, like, stuff that the turn of the Century ty were doing, you know, the Carnegie
and the
Rockefeller failures and just how... I wonder if that's what Barks was thinking about when he did this. Because like, They they built largely useful stuff, but it was also a way of just trying to, like, rehab their image. So maybe this is
supposed to kinda reference that. It might have felt more timely at the time. Well more say I I kinda agree you. I think this is a fantastic comment. I mean, it's again, the some Barks that other things Al with fantastic, but I think it's just a great trail of Scrooge and and what who is as a character.
Feels like a fully formed Scrooge Inducks, not, you know, just the bridge gentleman we don't know about, but, you know, he has... He has as pride of being registered
that's his goal, and he's gonna fight it, and he's gonna absolutely give can to show that he is. But he's not gonna give money when he's only gonna prove it in the ways that so we have to prove it and it would take on all of Al. And I think I think it's... I think it's a great expression of a fully form Scrooge Yeah.
I mean, I I think it works
extremely well as long as you accept it as kind of kind of an odd ball story where he just... You wanted to toss out some windows tossed some rules out of the window because he wanted to tell this this weird over the top, statue your competition.
Story. Excellent. Well, you guys thank you so much for joining me for this one. Look forward to having you back for another of these. And...
Yeah, That's all I got.