We have
Hello, and welcome to Barks Remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comics of all time. This episode is a ten page podcast, all about one of his short stories. Get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Welcome back to Barks remarks. I'm Mark Sever a Grown man who enjoys Inducks comics,
and I'm joined by a new guest, and we're gonna be talking about a couple of
giving themed stories.
But first, I'd like to introduce my guess David. If you... If you can introduce yourself, please and mention kinda your your background as box fan. So, yeah, my name is David Wi. I live in Connecticut.
With my family.
I
have known about Carl Barks comics since literally before I can remember my father
grew up reading them
and he would raise
when I was a kid about how great these comics for and would reach us before I could even read.
And there was a a real robot experience with him was to, you know, kinda snuggle it with him and and read read the comments. And I remember the...
When I was first wanted to read in elementary school, one of the things I was really excited about was to be able to read the comm by myself.
And... But the Barks is very much a part of my use in in terms of the humor the the references to various.
Storylines lines
remarks often, you know,
donald or Scrooge
biting sarcastic with
would come in
to
regular conversation and our family. So I definitely was was raised in a very Barks household That's awesome. I I wish I'd had the experience of getting to
enjoy
the comics like, with other people, but but I I kinda discovered them on my own.
But But I know through doing the podcast, a lot of people have had that really nice experience of getting to
read them with their parents, you know, their parents sharing them and learning to read from them. And
I have course have been leading them to my own kids.
Do you do you have kids data? I think you mentioned having? Yeah. I have four four kids, my youngest
daughter is...
I... I've gotten into Barks. She really really enjoys it. The others
I might have shown them Al once once in a while, and they they kinda never really never really click with them
but she she loves them. And so she we read them together and And when my my father also will read with her sometimes too. And it's it's it's a lot of fun. So Vaccine have absolutely. Yeah. That that family connection is is great. You know, it's one of the things I really love And and, of course, here here's a nice smooth safe.
Speaking of families
how how is
Giving your household, David? Do you guys thanksgiving you important to you guys?
Yeah. I think like, a lot of people we try to get together with family
Al little different every year, which which family we're with and and who who were able to be together with. But
Yeah. That's definitely an important thing. It's Yeah.
Absolutely.
It is a good one. And growing up, you know, is a big deal in my household. I'm so far away from family now. Unfortunately, I don't get to have the big thanksgiving. But but it's it's always nice having like these seasonal connect with the economics. You know, Barks.
Barks had a great hook. Of course, you get you gotta assume that Wes publishing and an publisher and editor naturally is encouraging
artist to do seasonal tie. So if you look at the list of Barks electronics. He had just like a a ton of Christmas ones and a handful of them for other holidays. But the thanksgiving was pretty reliable. You got to put out. Five ten pager
connection to the holiday.
And we're we're covering two of them, David,
and
I let you pick them. So do you wanna tell us... I mean, we kinda... We kinda collaborated. But
but you wanna mention the two titles that we're gonna be talking about? Yeah. So the first one we'll be talking about is
the terrible turkey, which is number eighty seven.
And stories. And and the and the other one is a charitable shore, which is
my favorite
Thanksgiving
story and honestly, probably my
top twenty, it's not top ten
stories of all time. My personal. My personal list. So.
We'll get to that too. Yeah. Yeah. I'm I'm excited to talk about that and so I I guess. That a charitable chores is gonna be kinda like the main course Right? And the terrible turkey will be kinda like one of our things giving appetizers.
Sure. That sounds good. So you mentioned there they're both walt Disney comics
publications. I think I think title was just call Walters these comics at that point.
Appearing in eighty seven. The terrible cherokee was was a fairly early one December of nineteen forty seven is the cover date.
We we Al the podcast
already covered last year.
Listeners if you're... If you really like one of the stories called turkey trouble. We covered the early one that goes by that title.
And then the the remaining two stories that will we'll save for next year our the custard gun and another a second one that's also called Turkey trouble. One of a very few instances, I think where they doubled up on the title.
You know, he Barks didn't really pick his own titles. A lot of these titles were just kicked over over the years by other editors.
Where were those titles were they on the the cover of the comics or where were some of them will have had
titles
above the first panel.
Right. In in some cases, but but more often than not, they're just un title.
And so, you know, different publishers have given them different titles,
right throughout the years. And at some point, I don't know how they made it official. But, like, they all have their own... I think I think it was done for the for the publication of the Carl Barks library is when they really went ahead and just kinda made certain titles canon. Yeah. So I I like you, I think
I think the charitable chores is gonna be a little bit more interesting to talk about.
But there's definitely a lot to like about the terrible turkey.
So So. I'm,
you know, this this is one of our episodes that I call the ten page podcast, and and it's a little bit more lightly research. So what I'm gonna do is I'm just gonna mention the rate... The ranking that you see Inducks right now for this one. So this one is
loaded on by the community on the side index. It's got a seven point two. And that is good for a rank of eight hundred and fourteen
out of all like, forty two thousand
titles, disney comics stories that are ranked on the side. So, David as far as where that plays is it? It's a pretty well ranked Barks story. It's certainly not like one of the highly ranked, ten pages. I being a total
obsessive nerd. I went in and and put all the stories into a spreadsheet so I could kinda find, like, the midway point and get a good good median ranking. It turns out that the median ranking for the stories is seven point two two. Right. So So that's where this one Barks by the community. I think of it is is pretty much an average Barks sure. So let's let's do it. We're gonna launch in, and and we're gonna go ahead and just kinda summarize this story page by page and and offer up some commentary in between.
Alright. So the terrible Turkey
starts out. This this is a pretty good setup up.
We see Donald at at a Butcher
shop, and he is
he's arguing with the butcher
insisting that he wouldn't pay as much...
The the man wants to charge from seventy cents of pound for Turkey, which Donald says he wouldn't pay that much for diamonds.
It's a it's a pretty pretty good bit of donald. Spout off. And he heads on home encountering the nephews,
and he's basically thinking about another way that he can get himself at Turkey. And as he slams his way into his house, the nephews mu over what what he's gonna do maybe he expects to win a turkey and a raffle.
Kinda wonder if that's almost like,
Barks.
Bark is gonna
go with that idea a couple of times. So I wonder if you know that in the back his mind. Right. Right. Is with Thanksgiving,
specifically that thing Al those Thanksgiving Turkey. Yeah. Yeah. And I guess,
I guess that he already got to use the idea of the Turkey, because he nickname that raffle and the the turkey trouble would have been the first one. So so, yeah, maybe he was thinking of that. I guess it would have been just one year before.
And, David, we get this really
kind of fun
silly
dated
image of don on loading an old, like, is this is this a blender bus? What kind of gun is this? It's like... I think it's... Yeah. It's it's the kind of thing you you would see in pictures of the programs. I I don't know what error that stop. They stop using that type of...
Right. You,
but it's... Yeah. I mean, it's it's definitely and you'd seeing the in the the drawings of the the power the pull.
It's not that
displayed
that's blade that played shaft and Yeah. And he's, like actually pouring gun fl gun powder and using the flint and it's got a flint lock. So he's kind of... We get... We get this case that he's... He's got it in his head that he's gonna get his
meal the way that the
might have. Any any thoughts on this
intro here david? It's it's a nice... It's a nice setup up. I I like it, and it it's it it's, you know, very typical of donald.
Something gets him really keyed off, and then he has an emotionally exaggerating in response to it. You know, he has a remark in the second panel.
One don't butcher carry a black and be done with it is if, you know, charging this much for turkey is equivalent to, you know, beating someone up and robbing.
And in in in typical bible fashion, and he wants to, you know, have some wacky idea that he's gonna gonna, you know,
find a way around this problem.
And and he's diving right into and he he's gonna make it happen.
Okay Right. Yeah. I I like this.
The the nephews are kind of a non entity so far. This is kind of typical of the plate forties where they're just... They're a little bit background
in favor of of Donald
anger. Yep. That guy had tell us about the next page. So let's see.
He comes out of the house
dressed as a as a... Basically, you know, as as he said, like a like a program,
in the same outfit with those... Who do you call that a stove quite hat or or or I'm not sure what what that would probably called it a pi hat, but program add and I'm sure there's is proper
it's basically what we saw in the stored books and when we learned about Thanksgiving in in elementary school. And, of course,
the kids think this is hilarious
No and they're just enjoying it. Probably just as much as the reader is.
Donald is, of course, too serious to realize the absurdity of it all and he's he's he's in... He's living in the moment. He's he's gonna be a program, and he
thinks he's got the stuff.
Right. And
they continue to laugh and he he branches off into the into the
forest prime as Barks sprite it. I I love Barks a little
you know, descriptions he has in in the corner boxes that often Very very clever
writing. And... Right. Instead of just saying in the forest during the, you know, it's the four four needle. And and to me, it's especially funny because you can, like, see a house in the back around. So it's it's yeah it's dead start. It's like... It's it's like a visual verbal punch line. It's that kind thing you can only get in the comics.
Sure. Sure. That's true. Yeah. Yeah. You get you get a little bit of Donald anger there and, you know, including his teeth and everything and he's completely immune to their ridicule I mean, he he isn't even...
He's not even feeling it, which later on, he does. But at this point, he doesn't care about being last at because he's he's two series frame and he's gonna show that. He is fueled by his determination. Yeah. As you say, this is our idea of how Pilgrims dressed. This is very like, grade school Thanksgiving Yep. Agents
and and
I don't think the pilgrims really
hunted cherokee like this. I know famously, like, the the revision mistake is that they probably didn't even have turkey at the first Thanksgiving. But but this is Donald childish understanding of it. Yes.
So on the next page, we've got the Nephews
getting bored waiting around, you know, they kinda resolved that they wanna see the act and and they decide very quickly that they wanna go in the woods and place some tricks on on Mcdonald.
We've got a really neat little time capsule of kids in the late forties, David. We we see them playing with their pocket I basically.
Is that mum peg? Is that the name of that? Came. I think it may be... If I'm correct, it was this game kids in the fifties played where they they basically take your, you know, your army ish or whatever
open whatever you call an knife the pocket knife, and you could flip it around in the air and try to yeah. Around behind. Like it I don't know how get. But but it's said it was a game they played back. You know
you know? Yeah. I'm I'm so glad I've got
guest on who knows this stuff because I I would have lost right over that, but I I opened up another tab and sure enough mum.
Yeah. No. People can look that up and find out about the knife cams the kids played when they didn't have
tablets.
Yes. We're also very much
comment on, you know, how things have changed whereas if you saw it kids playing with knives these days that I think the you'd be calling the police and there'd be a whole thing.
Right Right. So think things just kids. Yes. Yeah.
And so we we transitioned to that is gonna be a pretty predictable sequence. Right? We've got we've got the nephews basically stationed in in different spots in the forest.
Implementation a turkey and getting mcdonald's to run off after it. I I like that they they kinda kick it up and notch and they get clever about it by the end of this page where they use Al little
wheel device
to make Turkey tracks.
To find. A very visual page. You know, this feels kinda like the cartoons.
Sure. Yeah. It it kinda sets it up. It's the beginning of them playing plain tricks on him. You know, in the previous page, they had been just used by it. And now at this point, they they're they're born playing their their knife game somehow they're just gonna have funded at mcdonald's expense. And
they did do it in typical,
you know, a clever fashion just
making and run back and forth having fun with them.
So in the following page
you, he's he's following the the tracks and the tracks go into a hole, which, of course,
you know, this displays mcdonald's ignorance of turkey and how they live because they don't live in holes like offers.
But he's,
you know,
so much.
I guess he doesn't realize that this has to be some kind of trick at this point. He hasn't quite figured.
Thanks do pretty good job.
They do a pretty good job of railing him in here. Right? Because... Yeah. He briefly considers it's impossible.
Yeah Then what do they do? They have a little have a hose hook through the other end of the hole, where they say Got gobble. So now he the gobble from the hole and things
my goodness, there is a turkey in there.
Right. So, of course, he's... He starts taking, like like crazy as if he's, you know, digging to the center of the earth. And
throws up a heat dirt trying to find that turkey. I really like that gag. I think that... That's pretty clever. It's pretty funny.
And on to the next page,
you know, he's exhausted, but then he sees
a fan of turkey feathers behind the a log,
But it turns out to just be
another gag. And at this point, he realizes he sees the kids footprints. Yep. So he clocks what they're doing. We do get a a little moment where he uses the the the very outdated term. We... We wouldn't say He says that he's been ji,
which is, you know, something that we we don't say anymore but would have been...
You see it. Just constantly
in these economics. Mh.
And
you know, he he strides off. In
fit of range, basically. Right. Yeah. That's that's true. And that was definitely
word that, you know,
we heard a lot back way back when, and then now it's not not used anymore because it's the nature So he storms off
and in the following page,
he
stole he sees and what he's gonna do because he's furious with the kids and he runs in a real turkey, which, of course, he is another one of the kids gag. And and this is an old trope if I'm not mistaken and the idea of someone being fooled and then they see the real thing. I believe in I'm I'm mistaken in in Christmas on Barks mountain. Wasn't there a similar thing where they think it's a oh yeah the there.
The Barks, but I think it's Scrooge screws crust is a bit it's one of those things that it turns out. The real beer, and, you know, it's a similar type of... Yeah. But like like you say, this is an age old trope and you could probably count a couple dozen of Barks. Right. And Barks and and else elsewhere a literature as well. I mean, right. So he he storms past the actual Turkey that would actually
make a very delicious thanksgiving meal. I'm not really realizing what's going on. And then the kids come out of hiding. They see that Turkey and go wow real turkey and they try to rest to the ground, and basically, the turkey beats the stuffing out of the kids.
Chases them away because it's a pretty tough turkey.
And so it... They're they're running for the hills in the turkey chase and after them. Yeah.
As you say, it's it's all pretty predictable stuff. These are tropes that we've seen a lot.
I will note that I really like Barks is like, actual
illustration of the Turkey.
It's it's a very well drawn bird. It really is. That's a really...
Yeah. I I I imagine he had some
magazine article or some sort of
some book had a nice
photograph for something of a turkey that he putting through from. And as I know he he used to do that a lot with some of his with many of his drawings. He would draw from something that he they had. Right. And so on the next page,
you know, we get that kind of
Donald direct reconcile that I'm seen...
He he realizes that indeed. This is a real turkey as he sees it chasing the kids.
And and they narrow
escaped him by
jumping Creek and he gets lost and He loses the turkey and a thick. And so he resorts to using that fan of feathers to lure him out and tries to sound
like a Love turkey. Yeah. Exactly. And everything here, David is it's it is admittedly a a pretty
conventional
predictable story at this. Yeah. And then...
Yeah. Absolutely. Yeah. I I agree with that. And unfortunately, for him and in the following falling page, the kids
see that
he the feathers that he's pretending
turkey, and they they fire their own arrows at him.
So it's interesting the way, and and he gets...
He he gets
struck in the rum with the those three arrows. I guess they're very accurate.
Might they're both interest. Which I think they can construct on their own and you can see that They
that very quickly.
And it it it's great. I mean, look, the the kids play fritz and donald and donald gets made a full of and then donald trade placed tricks in the kids in. Donald gets made of full locksmith right.
It's
this isn't one of those back and forth things, which
when you have those the those comments where they're some of the stories where they're going at it.
Sometimes the kids end up and losing end and sometimes mcdonald's ends up and losing them and they go back and forth. This is one where just donald on the louisiana end, and that's that's it. The story. Yeah. Barks generally knows that that's what the readers like to see.
Yeah he he chases them away and
and then goes back to we're trying to find a an actual Turkey because he he knows the turkey there. So he's gonna wait till the like the time to find out turkey. Yeah. And and so
we transition to the nighttime,
and
we see a big fat rust bird, and Donald is really excited seeing that that there is his cherokee.
And and any reader who with a little bit of experience basically knows what's coming because at no point, this is all drawn silhouette like Barks likes to do Al night.
There there's some good fun drawings, but
Donald catches the bird
and he takes
him to a poultry cleaning plan which the sign notes conveniently is open all night. What all night.
There you go. And and Donald does that thing that suspend
suspend belief a little bit where
the suspension of disbelief where he
tells the
cleaner
to dress his bird without looking at it.
And and the the man looks in and he says just a minute. Do you want this bird cleans to eat?
And Donald doesn't bother. He says, of course, get busy on him and stop acting foolish.
Yeah.
Getting the point of the silhouette, and Barks, of course, has wonderful use of syllables. So that's sun brock
fantastic And and Jeffrey Bloom wrote. We're a whole article on that and one of the glad stuff traditions that stuff where he talks about that.
Mh And and here it's used not just statistically, but to further the story because you you see that that... What donald think is turkey as a silhouette and you're not really sure look... Has vaguely the shape cherokee and Right. And and, of course, that that's the whole point. I mean, you're seeing a so silhouette. You don't know what it is and donald does know it either. Just says, you know. It's definitely the right size too. Yeah. To... In mcdonald's defense. Yeah. So Donald serves this... What do he think is in Turkey.
To the kids. And it looks great. They're all excited about it, and then he takes his big knife
and it breaks
trying to cut the turkey and the Turkey and he said Al little too tough.
And then he tries another nice, and that life just starts to break apart and then you tries I saw and finally meet grinder and nothing than this turkey that what he thinks in turkey is too tough to. Nothing will touch. So
he calls the butcher and says, you know, what gives what's going on. He's really curious and the butcher is very much him used by it, and then
tells him, you know knows, exactly what's going on, because it it wasn't turkey. He says, he just wasn't a Turkey brother. He was in Eagle. And Donald is in belief about that, and he pretty he got thinking was mistaken about the the that you've kidnapped. And the final the final
panel is
scrolling into a yield old dining car to together a turkey dinner. Two dollars and fifty cents of plate dessert extra. And the kids seem quite excited about it and they're there with Al little little adorable little hats on it. Donald was kicked off, but resigned to what's happening. And he's guys his hands baldwin up and shifts, but he, you know,
resigned to what they're gonna have to
that's what they have for Thanksgiving.
Right. And I nice gag at the end and that he, you know, got an eagle not knowing what it was. Yeah. Yeah. This it is a nice closer. It's a good gag.
And and I believe
according to memory, that is about the way that
that that his first
thanksgiving
story concluded with them, you know, heading to to get a Turkey dinner at
at some restaurant.
And and I will note you and I were talking. I was texting with you earlier that I realized reading
my... Because you referred to this as the eagle story.
And and and reading this in my reprint I realized something that it always bothered me about this was that it's... It was actually
corrected
It it was actually edited
to something that seems to have been for, like, reader sensibilities.
I'm guessing.
But really steps on that punch line
and and the one that I read says he wasn't... He just wasn't a turkey bidder. He was a giant quail. And and like, well that's a weird thing to edit it to. First of all. This I'm cute... Yeah. Curious what edition was that when was that published the one that you was it just a reprint of a... Yeah. So this was the reprint that was done by Disney Comics
themselves Barks Disney themselves had the license. Okay. I think it was five seventy nine while disney comics and stories.
And and it's otherwise, like, very faithful.
Including... I forgot to mention. I... The... There were three pages
that had art drawn by,
like, replaced arts for this. One. If you check and in the
the guide book link
they know that pages is three, five and six were reg withdrawn, but that apparently, the original version was finally printed by the Dutch publisher or Over braun,
which which I think goes... I think that's who goes by Ag now.
Or maybe that's Food and burrows. But anyway, the Dutch
found, I guess, they found the original version.
So, yeah, if you look at some of those stories in some of the earlier printing or some of those pages they look they'll definitely look a little bit off.
Anyway with within this story, some of these pages they were they were
not drawn by Barks or... I I guess I don't understand what you're yeah
Yeah. Oh, emma and I'm not I'm not saying it with with total confidence. But if you look at... What which which one do you have Right right there. I I have the the glad. This is it's five stories and, you know, this is so yeah. They they call out. The all they say is that pages is three, five and six or reg withdrawn, and I think that it is referring to the original printing.
So I'll just note that there's there's is at least that comment that in some printing, of. Some of the pages were red withdrawn for whatever reason. Yeah. It's interesting what you're saying about the eagles versus Giant. You said Giant Pheasant? Is that what I quail.
Giant Whale. I mean,
the the eagle... It... I remember reading this as a kid and think that's a little bit far fetched to really eagles... Are they that much tougher than turkeys and but whatever, I mean, really gonna look past that that absurdity for the purposes of the story and and we kinda think the eagles is being, you know, tough and majestic and a way the Turkey are not. Well it's a bird of praise, so I've gotta imagine if
it makes sense at least. To me that it in a sense. Yeah. Yeah. So... But a giant quail actually was pretty appetizing.
Like it does
are our game Barks. So... Yeah. I mean it's interesting when they make it. It's like that. I I I would... If I were added there, I would probably restricted it to the things that I thought were, you know, just beyond the pale, if there was something in there that was just outrageous that that should be printed, you know, then maybe remove that. And even that I would personally hesitate on because I I know with my kids. I I... When I read something
older, and it's sometimes this happens in Barks stories whether there's something that is by our sensibilities.
Just
offensive. I'll point that out to my daughter and say, you know, this is a problem, and, you know, we need to understand, you know, Barks is writing in a different time with different types of
thinking, and this wasn't something he was, you know, people really thought about. Al much fact.
And and I would probably left it in. It... It's a weird thing to do because I'm who... There would... That many people find that offensive and even, you know, all I can think of, you know, I mentioned this to you and tax I I gotta assume that it's like a weird h
thing. Right? Like the eagle is is the national bird. Yep. Yes. To bald eagle. Sure. Maybe... I think it was even considered and endangered at that time. Right. So you know what? As I say it, that that that kinda of lines up in nineteen ninety one, I think it was considered endangered. So they might. They may have thought that that would
be a little more offensive for that But it's kinda funny because, like, famously, there was that original
this is one of those facts that people love to mention about the founding fathers.
Did you know that Ben Franklin... Yes.
For the for the turkey to be the next the national bird. So so it's kinda funny there that we have an instance the first instance I know of about the punch line being accidentally eating Al eagle. Right. Right. So so, David, this is a fun one. I don't really have too much to say about this because I think like you and like, the community
that this strikes me as a pretty average Barks story, you know, better than a story from your typical creator, but just just a fine example of a good enjoyable
Barks ten pager. Yeah. I agree. It's it's a fun one. It's not definitely one that I would, you know, wanna re reread, but it's it's a it's a decent Barks story.
It's it's it's one I remember from growing up reading the story. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I remember with some fond.
But I know you're excited to talk about one of your personal favorites
and I I think while I don't consider it, like a favorite, it is it is more interesting.
By far. And there's a lot more to talk about in a charitable
chore.
So I will mention
that. So as as you'd had mentioned, David, terrible C was published in walt disney disease Comments one forty seven.
This one
Oh and and that's five years later, in December of nineteen fifty two. Yep. Of course, that that would be the cover date. This would have come out, like properly in time for Thanksgiving because of the way that cover dates
the the release lags the cover dates. Sure.
This one has
basically
an identical
rating to the terrible turkey. It's it's also got a seven point two
and it is ranked eight hundred and eleven
out of those
forty two thousand stories. And just a reminder, that's three
better than terrible turkey. So this is basically a tie it's interesting that both thanksgiving stories are kinda groups there. But I think you're probably right
in in liking this one better,
and we can kinda go into why.
After the story. I will I will just know before we read it, that I read this in an interesting
publication
Disney comics put it out in a quarterly release that they call autumn Adventures.
Oh little title. Yeah. No. I I remember this one for growing up. I'll I'll just say that. This was definitely definitely one. There's there's a...
Is a is a a few memorable lines in it that I, you know, are burned into into my brain from having her many times
references to and my use
Yeah. It's it's a great. Great dialogue.
This does... It it stands out for for a few reasons. First off,
and and we we get this pretty early in the story. This is like Inducks family
one where we've got his girlfriend Daisy and we've got cousin Gladstone.
Is gonna join the mix. Very memo, I would say, also, as we launch into the story,
we we have kind of an atypical donald. We have like this
striving,
aspiring, Donald, who
is thinking to himself when when he sees daisy
club sign that says
give some poor hungry deserving person a thanksgiving dinner in your home.
Sign up inside,
You know, Donald is thinking himself what a noble idea. And and we get the impression that he really...
He he verbal is that he's got a little bit for Thanksgiving. Yep. Money this Thanksgiving, so he's eager to do a good deed. This is kind of Al a typical,
you know, donald.
Yeah. I'm curious if there are other stories in which he's genuinely trying to do something charitable for the right reason.
I mean, I guess there's certainly Christmas stories where that's that's sort of a theme yeah. Of the whole story. But this is interesting. It really focuses right from the beginning. It's all about donald trying to do this do something nice, you know?
Yeah. I think there must be a few, but it's definitely not typical. Barks needs Donald to be more
full of goodwill more than than normal for the inevitable, like, def fl. Yes. So... Absolutely.
So Donald,
Donald goes ahead and he follows Daisy directions
drawing a name from the box.
Oh, and and just like the previous story. He some of the the downfall comes because he doesn't
go to the trouble to look. Yeah. That way what it is.
And
Daisy
prepares to leave
as she directs him to the secretary to complete the arrangements.
And and he
he gives his details or he gets ready to give his details to the
kinda dump looking
secretary. Yeah.
Sometimes Barks does these, like dump looking women, but I don't get the impression he's like making fun of her in this one or anything. She's just... No. He's just a warm. Very majorly.
It's interesting to me David that we've got this, like, lady's club And and these exist still, but they were... I think I think this was such an important thing in in the fifties. This... I believe you're right. Yeah. A big part of civic involvement. Yeah. What do you think Scrooge opening? Yeah. It's great. And it it's... As we as, you know, having knowing what what comes nest next this is a great setup that he's, you know, flying high, you know, you know, feeling like an angel. And
doing the right thing and everyone daisy in this... And and the the secretary making it feel good about himself and that even spills on the next page as well.
And
it's it's all getting set up
for what what comes next. And you're right. I mean, this is a... That he doesn't look at the card, and that that seems to be in
the constant theme from in the comics that Donald gets some of trouble when he doesn't do something that you would think would be kind of obvious
and this is just he's full speed pulls team ahead and he doesn't... Even if people around them or especially the kids are saying, you know what? You may wanna look to the side and shut things out and see what you're doing and. He he's not gonna do that. He just... He's going forward. Yeah. And it it sets it sets it up very nicely.
So in the in the following page, he again, it continues.
He says I feel good all over, and he's gonna make Al extra big turkey. He's all excited about it. And then as he's running home to get ready, he that's when he gets the the the worst news of his lifetime when he realizes if the person he's going to prepare the dinner... The meal for is glad gander and of course,
know, anyone who's
with the Gladstone knows this is just the the worst
the worst news, the donald could have and, you know, almost... I mean, if you read enough comments, you can almost guess that that was what the name was gonna be.
Right. Beforehand. And that's a great panel when he's surprised, and there's there's no
there's no scenery behind him there at all. It's Barks wants to just focus on foul the, you know, is just Al gas and he wants to really capture that
and then. It's an awesome panel. I love I love the donald leap up into the air in in a gas
discussed panels. Yeah. That's that's gotta be one of my favorites and other of these.
Yeah. That's great. Yeah that's it. It's a it's a nice picture there. So he he says are I gotta get out of this so he goes back to the good neighbor's club, and of course, they're closed apparently they closed and they must lock the door and last immediately after he walked out. And then he decides he's gonna go to Daisy and
see if she can help him and, of course, she's left as well
very quickly.
And it's it's interesting that,
you know,
when I was re reread the story, and I know we were texting earlier, it's remarkable. We're gonna see more of this in the story where Barks uses, you know,
convenient things to keep the store moving forward, you know,
that, you know, they they left very Daisy left town. She he needs an older door and out of town back Friday. So leading donald with no other choice
and the and and you know, Barks uses that to move the story forward and
since it's so well done, we're we're
we're willing to forgive him that and and goodbye. Enjoy the ride.
Right. The timing is gonna be very convenient.
David, I I think as I've like, been doing this podcast and getting to talk to to people who have kind of been involved with some of the comics, which has been really neat.
I I think more about the things that Barks has to do to kind of
identify things for his readers and signal.
And,
you know, we know all about glad Gander Al long time Barks fans. But there's a good chance that a first time reader may have no idea. He's... He's only appeared in a couple of stories.
Before this. He's still a pretty new character at this point. I think it's just three years since he appeared in in his debut.
And and his luck doesn't really factor
in this one. You know, this is this is one of those stories where he's just gonna be kinda of the shift twists.
Version.
I think he at the very end, the whole thing but the something goes that we'll got to it and might factor in there. But yeah. Yeah.
But you're right. He's just sort of the foil in this
more so than they're not focusing on the locked part that, you know, that's not it. He's just basically you know, Donald introduces himself as you said, He says Right. He's no course person he's no good at professional.
So even someone who was not familiar with god's would kinda get the impression.
It's going odd here. So he does a quick, you know, job of introducing him, and and you're right. He is gonna specifically call out. Glad, I think he got his luck just a few issues
before this and and race to the south c's, I think was the first one. So, like, he calls it out in this one. But
much more of the story is really just devoted to to the fact that he's a shift moo. Right. In this one, And Barks hadn't really like, moved on from that aspect of his character.
I think at this point. So let's see. As you say, Al everything kind of coincidentally,
he he figures out the daisy is out of town. Barks
Friday because of a note that she's left on the door.
And we see him
just super determined to, like,
phone every member of the good neighbor's club, so you won't be stuck with that bum.
But of course, by the time he gets home Gladstone has clearly already been notified because he's waiting on his front snoop,
and and he's learned about you know, who who is gonna be feeding him on Thanksgiving.
And Donald,
he says that that's a big error they made.
And and now we get a pretty classic cousin
kind of put up your dupes
hose
And and, you know, David, I like the little bits of vocabulary that I probably learned
for the first time as a kid
because Gladstone says you're gonna rene.
You're gonna be a cheap well
And and I I I think I think I picked up really a lot of vocabularies yeah. Through contacts reading. Absolutely Al. That's.
And
Gladstone
implies that he'll report Donald to the newspapers as refusing to feed as starving there.
Yeah. He's this is just the beginning. This is like, the appetizer of,
you know, Glad. Not he's going to enjoy his Thanksgiving me all he's going to. You know, do everything can to torture your donald.
It right. That... That's half the enjoyment for him is the fact that he's able to towards your donald who with what who with the fact these forced to provide them a a free meal.
Alright. And and, of course, like, we feel a little bit for Donald
because he wanted to do something noble and pure. But on the other hand, he really could just suck it up and have his cousin over.
One one lousy meal.
Yeah. So I I get. I... You're right. I never really thought about it that way. I was I was... When I read this mark, I always think I'm a hundred percent donald. You know, I I can't stand Glad and Right. There's no way he deserves this and
by the end. You're definitely right because the the... What Gladstone is gonna inflict upon him. Right. Totally un recalled for. Donald could've have like, very easily
avoid all of this but.
Yeah. So yeah.
It he takes he... Yeah. Barks he digs himself and even deeper as well as we'll see.
It's an interesting a little little bit bit in the in the next page he...
He... He's Donald believes that he has something to hold over Glad. Glad.
Says, you know, I'm gonna, you know, report you to the papers that you're not falling through and what you promised and Donald says, I'm gonna expose you that you're a professional mood. And Gladstone says something interesting.
That the the the the good neighbors
investigated him and found him wanting those year old ladies actually we when I told them I'd never worked the day in my life, which is an interesting way to put it. I mean, you and I and the reader know it's that is the mood just basically takes priority and, you know, enjoys himself. But the the the the the nice ladies of the charity interpreted that is you can't find work and he's trying the best of hand and it's one of those statements that can be read. However you want based on your sensibilities.
It's a it's a very funny panel. Yeah. That that just the expressive
between the two of them Donald growing in response. Right. He's frustrated not only that Gladstone don't got away with it, but that, you know, nobody else sees him for what he is.
Right.
And then donald
brick that he's gonna attack Gladstone of course, the kids realized that that's the... You know, this is right when they finally intervene. They've been just watching until now, but here they're just like Okay. Donald. You know. Okay. I'll get Al he we can't do this. You know. Enough and enough. You know, you you can't you can't able to break and they explain to him what... You know, that that he has to do it
and we're seeing, you know, more of these these wonderful
expressions the Donald has of just
you know,
anger
humiliation, you know, frustration,
just every every
iteration of those emotions that you can imagine.
It's almost as if if you compare the expressions throughout
it's almost if Barks deliberately wanted to come up with a different way of
he didn't wanna use the same look in any panel. I mean, you know, he wants to say. I wanna do another look of humiliation, but different from the last one. Right you know, he'll come up with another way of doing it. So at the end of the page, he he's reconciled himself, and he's gonna have to do this and and Gladstone is now really trying to pour it on.
Explaining what he expects for the meal. I'll have Chrome dressing in the turkey with just a pinch of stage.
He's he's so specific about exactly how he wants in. Expect donald to performant, of course, donald and Al little bubble is he's thinking and carpet caps and the pie, you know, he's just, you know, he's he's a receiving ball of rage and he knows right what he's gonna do, but he knows this this can't this can happen. So... Yeah. I can see why you why you advocate for this one, because this this story is this page is about as strong as any that Barks is done. Like, There there are three
just individual panels here that kinda make me laugh out loud or at least check. You know, that one I mentioned. And then that one party just worthless
going to grab for the brick. That cracks me up
And and then and as you say that little
gag where Glad stone below, and he's just thinking to himself about putting carbon taxes yeah. It's very funny. I also see
why Barks is, like,
accessible
around the world because
kind of picture all of these exchanges without any die.
Yeah. You can you can follow along pretty fact you can. You can. Yeah. Absolutely.
So
we transition on the next page to Donald just doing. And
he gets this bright idea. He... He's struck with an idea, and he says He wants the Ducktales to pretend to leave town, so he's gonna call the newspapers
and make an announcement.
And David, this cracks me up right on this page and the last page.
It might be exaggerated a little bit how much the two docs wanna bring like the local paper into this. But I've gotta imagine not that much, right? Like the local paper figured much more prominently.
Kind of in the the day to day working of of the town.
To to the point that on the next panel, we see Gladstone literally in the free reading room. Of the library
reading, You know, he
everyone read the paper.
It's how you learned what was happening.
So I I like that. This this one feels like such a time capsule for this period
in America. Than me. Absolutely.
So Gladstone
sees the.
I guess it's not... I can't imagine it's a big headline. They sees the story donald Inducks called to Florida
and he goes on to read good or duck regret that you will not be home Thanksgiving. To host poor disturbing guests.
And and this is the first time we see glad stone Barks in the story as he runs out to
confront Donald and steaks out outside the house.
And the shade is drawn, but but he is able to hear some voices. Yes. So
he here's the voices,
as he said, Barks, and quickly discovers that they're they're hiding out there. They figure they're just gonna head out till
after thanksgiving, but he hears them and he now he really has them over the barrel.
And what she says, now I've really got you the barrel. And
not only
does, you know, donald now has in Thanksgiving
provide the thanksgiving meal to the glad, but
Gladstone can threaten to expose him. I guess what he... What did you say printing false? Yeah. Why don't you read that? I like... I really like the sequence of dialogue there. Yeah. Now I've really got you over a barrel printing false rumors as a crime. Do I expose you or do I and Al says, do you what? And then leaves us hanging to the next panel and the cloud says, do I eat Thanksgiving dinner with you in Florida?
So following goes oh as he realizes now, he's on the hook not only for a meal, but for flying
him his nephews and Gladstone is no good cousin to Floor. Right. And and now we're now we're off and running
in Florida.
It's... Yeah, Mark, That's a it's a great transition right there to... From things have gone for bad donald. Right.
And you know, in another story, I could see this almost being the lead up to some adventure in Florida. But but Barks isn't really interested in Florida except as just, you know, a little bit of antique
to
before the get get home. And and the next sequence
is
basically,
it's all about
Glad stone x distracting
whatever he can,
chi
like more luxurious
and more expensive.
Everything
out of Donald. And and it's a little bit of a stretch. Right? Because at some point, we know in the real world
maybe Donald would go along with the trip to Florida save face, but but there's nothing stopping him from just saying look I took you to Florida. We're staying at a decent hotel
so you can tell like that an adequate hotel. Right Right. But but it it definitely works in the vein of the story. Right? He what what the reader knows is that Gladstone has donald over a barrel and
and now he's just gonna take advantage of him. We do get some good, like, specific details
And any of them that you particularly liked as as to the sort of like things that hub angles goals are donald
I mean, everything. I mean, everything in this next sequence is just u great. I mean,
that that line... That's one of those lines burning in my brain when you breeze in the one Floor air, and he says,
Romantic, Florida who but lucky Glad Gander could come here free. Correct. It's it's He's just having... He's having the time of his life and and donald his, you know, just starting being beginning to see than, you know, he he decide using go to the most expensive
hotel in the area, the wander build and, you know, the the cab... The the the cab driver that, you know, conveniently says, can you afford it? Know, setting up the next line
even the name sq bills. Water just funny. Yeah. Right because because it's
It's gotta be a parity of the the ty name Van bill. Absolutely
the word sq for spend. Yep. I like the Or the alligator
skin vest
for ninety eight dollars that he has my
at
is
ninety dollars gotta be like eight hundred dollars an hour or something. It's Yeah. Yeah. That's pretty pricey. And boy. David look. Take a look at each one of Donald like win. I'm sure you have if you love the story. Yeah. But but each of his win reactions is like better than the last.
Right. He's Barks is clearly trying to come up with every possible way. He can draw you know,
disbelief Huey, humiliation,
you know, in the faces and then then when he's he's when they're in the hotel room and and the Gladstone says to the to the the Bell hop, tip yourself a five like charge it to my cousin bill. Right. You know, which is, like, whatever forty or fifty dollars now.
Is collapsed, you know, on the bed. Can't believe what's what's happening here.
Yeah. Every every look in his face is just... It's priceless.
And it and that's one of those stories too where glad stone being so rep apprehensive, where he he he like convince the nephews base sick lead to to, you know, he drives the nephews essentially
to
Donald level because you don't always see that. Yeah. Know. You're absolutely right. They seem if you look Al the looks on their faces,
Huey,. You know, some of the time they're they're angry Al Gladstone
but they're also happy to be in Florida. You know, they're not quite to the point where they're not angry. Like Donald is. And then you're right, they slowly as they see they're uncle, we'd be humiliated more and more. They they finally have just about had it. And they're they're right there with all Yeah. That night, so we have a silhouette of them.
The kids say that we... We've gotta figure out we've got to figure a way to get you out of this power. So now they're on they're on the mcdonald there there's a way of
they've gotta to figure this out together. So donald his usual way hasn't a bright idea. I guess, the second bright idea he's had to get out of
a problem with Gladstone, and
and then we go right into
the next morning where we see what their run is gonna be. So next morning, so they they they get a motor boat, and they're gonna go for a tour of the lagoon and and and
glad stone a little skeptical, but they managed they could been it. There'll be plenty of time to get back for Thanksgiving. Although Donald does have that kind evil looking his eye, then, I guess Gladstone wasn't seeing when he Barks and board. Well Know I'm sorry, David. Did you mention what the Nephews like bright idea was this morning? That that morning. Oh, I'm sorry.
You're right. They they said we could lose him in the swap Yeah.
Realizes that's the case. So I guess, yeah, this wasn't a surprise. So we're... This setup up is...
We know what's gonna happen or some some general outline of what's gonna happen in the next step. They're gonna lose him in the swamp. So they get out the motor boat and and they manage to to trick Gladstone to climb up on the bow to look for pearls. And once they find a nice little
tiny little island and they
dump him there,
they ran the island leaving and there and leaving them stranded. And
they speed away claiming that the boat gone wild and they can't stop it. And got some remarks that for both the running while that thing sure takes the curve beautifully as we see it worthiness and out of the goes perfectly
avoiding all the islands. So he he knows something's things up this is
just an accident that they they look to this tab. Yeah. It's a fun sequence. I don't know there's too much more to say about it. So so the next bit is basically Glad stone stew on the island and
it's interesting. He Barks has him thinking, I'll get out of here. My good luck has never failed me yet. But
but Huey, he's going to a little bit of actual effort, here, right, which is kind of typical for glass. But but you know, Barks needs to get him off the island and see kind creative way.
So you find some flaming
that seem to be pretty tame any fashions a sort of basket this sort of hammock out of
leaves. That looks like
what's that tree that is always, like, kind of looking like ripping in the south... The we can... Like, we.
Yeah. It does kinda look like a wee willow of that.
But so I guess I guess after that work, he Al least does get to kind of relax and his flaming ham and he says, a little more speed, you glorified crow I'm hungry.
And as we get to dinner time, you know, we transition back to the Ducktales,
nearly
assure
excited to go enjoy their Thanksgiving Turkey.
Yeah. It makes me wonder what their plan was for how a rescue Gladstone. Do they just figure you would somehow eventually make it back or they go one...
I don't know... I guess that's that's a a a bit of a plot hold there that we don't. We don't have to worry about because it's a common.
Right.
So they come assure
after Gladstone
because they had fun on their rented motor
exploring the the swamp. And they're greeting on
by a
looks like a police officer who says, if you're donald Doc, you're want at the hospital. Your cousins there in bad shape. So, you know, after enjoying the day and, you know, running around there. The motor going the scenery now they it back to reality and realize that something glad someone's got something more bad the store for them. They.
I love the
the interaction with the doctor, Dave. Do you mind just reading that exchange? Yeah. No. That's that's great. Yeah. He burst into the
into the the patient's room there and and the doctors he says Gladstone.
How did how did you get here? What happened and Gladstone is too sick to respond and that the doctor says nothing to be proud of. I assure you.
It's just a great line.
And then he goes on to explain the the the amount of money he spent eating a thirty pound turkey by itself. And the doctor has the bill from the from the water hotel, and then also the the the the the emergency room bill as well, which is expensive.
I
all of this. As as a physician, you're very familiar with thrust the bill
into the the face of the patient's fan. Yeah. That does that doesn't happen these days, but it's a it's a convenient,
like, maybe back in those days day. I imagine they they would have done that. And I don't know why the doctor would have the bill from the hotel, but for some random. If this is just Barks is being economical. But it's it's very very funny. Even if it it's funny. And, you know, and and and... That's definitely one of those points and what regarding the story and thinking about it where there's a lot of sort of hard to believe coincidence
that that he uses to propel the story forward. And... And you know what, as a reader, I don't mind it because it's a great story. The gag are fantastic. And we understand it's a comic book. So we're willing to
overlook that because we we just love the characters and the stories so much. Right. Yeah. He's got his punch line there and he's delivering. He's just delivering it very efficiently.
Yeah. And that sweating is running up the storm there can't believe that he's on... If not not not able to believe he's on the hook for all of this. That he never never imagine we you have to pay for. So... And then and then the final scene we see donald
home again, and he wander into the
the good neighbor club and ask daisy if, you know, how things are going and she says they're doing the the same thing for Christmas, and donald as always is the poor will put their names in this Barks before and and daisy he said, yes. And and so immediately donald has
cards filled out with...
His name, Donald, dewey Hue and Loop, and they are going to need a free dinner for giving.
Daisy can't believe it. And as Donald,
as she says you you're putting... You're putting in for a free dinner. He says, yes, and baby, how we're going to need it. It's Al nice little twist at the end that that he went from the beginning having a extra money to help out some poor to now being dead broke himself or not even able to afford to meal for the next holiday. So... Yeah, it's a really good,
like, book ended gag. Yeah. He he finishes right where he started. He's.
Boy, those four panels are really just really well structured the way he
sub converts the fact that, it's it's predictable to an adult reader, But it's it's a really good solid gag. A really good sub subversion of of what happened at the beginning. Yeah. No. You're right, Barks. It's it's nice how he does that I, you know, re reread and thinking about it it's, you know,
when when I just would read a story,
just to enjoy, I never really thought about how difficult it must have been for Barks to figure out what am I gonna put in each panel and how how much to put in a panel what to put the next panel and to keep it to keep it a moving story. And,
you know, it's it's a real are to be able to condense so much in a in a small space with limited room for dialogue
to express everything you know, and and a nice balance between the expressions and their faces and then the unlimited of dialogue and you'd be able to propel the action forward and so a few panels. It's it's great. I mean, that's this is a
no I'm master Al work. Yeah. Yeah. Both of these stories have been very tightly
constructed.
This last one is just a lot lot busier. Right? Like it it in a good way. It has... It has a lot going on, you know, he moves from Duff to Florida.
Very efficiently.
I...
Let's let's go ahead. Let's let's talk about, you know, how these stories
compare it's very convenient to compare these since the community has like, placed them basically in a tie yep. That and I've gotta say, like, I'm I'm convinced you. This is a favor of yours. I'm not gonna say that it's suddenly a favorite of mine.
But I do think this is a very
very strong Thanksgiving story. And and much stronger
than the the late forties one that we did on the terrible turkey, which which know, I I did find very enjoyable. Yep. But there's just... There's a lot more moving parts in this one. Really great expressive artwork
The the the ryan... I I do love to hate Glad. Yeah yeah. Yeah. He... Just about every story he's in his. Is fantastic. The the model room between the two of them. I also like how, you know, in a typical Gladstone story
there's a twist at the end where it doesn't actually end up the way, you know, you expect it to and off glad.
May win, but not really when right. If you think about it and, you know, we could list off any other
stories, but that's the case. And
there's always a twist at the end. And in this case, you know, technically one, but in Donald humiliated, but Gladstone. Certainly is is not a happy person at the end. He's having
pounds Huey,. He's he's pretty darn miserable. So he can't exactly cause
call Gladstone the winter in this one. But I...
Yeah... Yeah. This definitely as you said, this Barks this...
It's it's wonderful. To store the
the level of humiliation that has to undergo and it just drawn out. It just doesn't... It's not one panel or one or couple of panels. It's just, you know, Barks is enjoying just as like glad is enjoying torturing donald. You know, every step of the way, and it's it's it's fun. It's fun to refund a watch and see see the valve goes through.
Yeah. The expressions on his face are just... Or we're really priced They they really are. There there a couple of, like, very strong pages here. That one that I mentioned with the the near brick flop the throwing. Yeah. But but also the one
with Glad stone just lord it over. That that page is so
funny.
And it's got such a great progression of humiliate she Barks.
Bob's really likes to see Donald.
Yeah. No. It does. That that is. That is a great page. The the brick thing. He doesn't say anything already because it runs for the brick.
And that that just says all you need. You know, Barks is really brilliant without where he keeps the dialogue
to an absolute minimum.
And let's the... Let's the
the drawing speak for itself. I'm thinking other pages that I like. I mean,
maybe just know, we do like... I'd I do like to highlight favorite panels as well even though I I... I've been known forget that segment from time to time. But are there any any panels or pages that we didn't, like, highlight?
That you'd like to call specific attention to and either of these stories?
I do like what you said the that
you know, the panel where.
But, you know, Gladstone was demanding a a a pinch of sage.
Yeah.
And he has his fingers there. In that.
Yeah. That this is perfect.
Doubt.
I... You know, that that's great. I mean, any one of the ones
where they're at the hotel and and bottle realizes every extra expense that's going to it's gonna add. Yeah. We we skipped over that working
Gladstone says, he wants a sweet with gold door knobs and Al leopard leopard skin drape. Right. I I can't imagine imagine that any hotel would have such a thing. But, you know, maybe maybe glad read brochure that this water building isn't where that that they do provide such executives here. So
he's ready to enjoy himself. But... Yeah, I this is one of those hotels that'll
make it happen for... They will make it happen. Exactly. Exactly. Yeah. So, David, I I really appreciate you going to bat for this story, because I've gotta say I've got kind of a new appreciation.
I'd say it's... I'd say it's not really accurately
ranked
by how the community is has kinda got it. Situated. It's a it's a pretty strong one. I I think I I can't remember if I mentioned this, but I looked it up and I had kinda calculated
that
any story that was...
Oh, yeah. I I did mention the point. Right? That point is, like, seven point two too. So we these are basically both Al the fiftieth
percentile. This reads more like an upper
quartile.
Yeah. To me or sell. I I'll just mention kind of where it stacks up against the other Thanksgiving stories. They as it happens,
all of them
except for his first... The the the oldest
one where he does like a little shooting
competition
at the...
To try to win a turkey. Mh. That one gets to seven point four. All of the others are in the seven point two. Neighborhood.
But that does encompass quite a few. So, like, it ranges from eight hundred and eleven
rank to one thousand one hundred and for. Then in general, they're they're clustered together for the most yeah part. Yeah.
Is this your favorite of his five different thanksgiving stories. Yeah. I I would say this is.
The other one you mentioned,
it's the one where I think that the kids Win a turkey the raffle and then Donald wins the shooting contest and Yeah. That's all That's also it. You say can't
you you should you're on themselves that that was last. You did that. Yeah. Yeah. That's that's a that's a fun one too. They they can't themselves to do it. And that's a great and that's a great business that we're that with respect for the turkey because he he fought so hard, so another.
Yeah.
That's a pretty great sequence to
I think that one might be my favorite. I also remember quite enjoying the
the other one named turkey trouble, although admittedly, it's been a long time, so I'll have to check and on that next year. But, yeah. I I think I think we covered these stories really nicely.
And and David, I really appreciate you joining me for these.
Did did you have any other
thoughts about these or just anything else No. I think so so I I appreciate you're having me on your podcast mark. This is this is very enjoyable, and and it's it's nice to speak to another Barks fan or there a lot Of us out there. We're just scattered around.
Exactly.
Well, david
Thanks again. I I really appreciate you joining me and a very happy thanksgiving to you, because of
You as well like your family. And and, of course, we're very international so many
many listeners won't be celebrating, But, you know, happy equivalent holidays
to all of our Scan
and
European and wherever
you are listeners.
I like the idea that that the
readers around the world kinda get this taste of these, like, random American holidays, David. Yes. Yes. They do.
That through America culture, they they do get that. That's right.
Although, I'm sure I'm sure they get their fill of American culture. I'm sure to go.
But but thanks again, David. Take care. Alright. You use walmart. Take care.