Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of sc Mc Ducktales and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge con of all time
This episode is a ten page podcast all about one of his short stories, get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Hello, And welcome back to Mark's remarks.
I'm Mark Sever marino. I'm a grown man who still loves duck comics I've got a returning host who hopefully is growing a little more fond of them. Can you introduce yourself, reintroduce yourself Hi. I'm Sarah Santiago and this episode, I'm your resident lemonade expert. Awesome.
You're also kind of like my resident
glad stone end or go to at this point.
We're gonna be doing the most famous Gladstone
ten pager story today. And oh, I should mention that this is one of our ten page podcast
episodes. We're stepping out of adventure story mode and
we're gonna be covering one of Barks most famous ten pager, which is called winter time Wage.
And this one is notable for a couple of reasons, but but mainly because it is the introduction of glad gan that famous
lucky
cousin of Donald that en him so much and is such a good foil for the
almost always down on his luck Donald. And at this point, you know, he's very fresh. He's very new and shiny and he does not have his characteristic
good luck. But but he's still a good foil for Donald in this story I think. And Sarah, this also going to be serving as our Christmas
episode. Yay.
So I'm happy Christmas
marriott holidays,
etcetera, to you,
whatever
type of holiday you prefer. Over here they call it the festive season. There's no argument over, oh, but some people celebrate this and some people celebrate this. They just say, for the festive season.
Yeah. It's really nice. That was the nice inclusive way of doing it. Oh like that over there is Scotland as a little reminder, I'm I'm recording in the states
in Pittsburgh. I don't know if I've ever mentioned that. On this podcast.
But
this is a Christmas
episode in
passing reference only. Right? Because of the very the very beginning, they're gonna mention that it's Christmas morning and then pretty much nothing else about it is christmas eve. But technically,
this story gets to serve as our our Christmas episode on the podcast calendar. And
this this is such a fun one to talk about For the ten page,
these are I give myself permission to let them be a little bit less researched a little bit more free flowing
you, of course
always are
empowered to ignore that and research as much as you as much as you want.
I did look up a little bit about stuff like
what do they call? Polar bear clubs and and drinking
you know, water drinking and stuff, and I think you did too. But
but yeah, this is not gonna be Al detailed. Let's see. Comic details. We are stepping back in time from a regular schedule just a little bit. This one came out. I think I think we're at the beginning of the fifties right now in the podcast.
Schedule. And this one came out in January of nineteen forty eight,
and it was published in walt Disney's comics and stories number eighty eight, a very long running
title that had a lot of these great stories. And
this is I'll mention I usually mentioned at the end, but I'll mention at the beginning. This is one of the very highest ranked by the community for his ten page stories. I I think if you break them out between the adventure length and the ten pager, this is the second best rated because it gets a seven point eight on index out of ten. Good for
nine out of all forty one thousand some Disney comics.
And
you know, very it's it's one of the only two that I think hit in the top one hundred, Sierra.
I... I've gotta assume that some of it is just a little bit of brain inflation because it does have glad stones first to appearance, so it stands out to people. But But I do find this one like very funny, like, laugh out loud funny at times.
Before we go into it, what's your just overall impression of this story? Well, I'm me. So the kind of toxic masculinity
stands out. M. I I mean, that's fair because this one is this one is entirely premise on this sort of like macho blu
contest, right, competition between these two cousins.
And and you can certainly read it very off putting because it has these, like, ram ramifications and it is pretty toxic. But if you read this one, I think is kind of just a slaps stick commentary
on
blu and Brag show. I I find this one pretty funny. So I'm I'm looking forward to getting your overall impressions.
Hearing if there's anything individual about it that works for you.
And...
Yeah. Let's let's enjoy this seasonal story. Yeah. So I I'll mention too that, you know, these ten pager were almost universally un. They never called Al winter time wage or until decades later when, like, fans and and and
Barks
Devote kinda got together and assigned retroactively named so that they could talk about these stories. And I just... I love to to picture Sarah, some kind of like counsel of scholars sitting down
and mu them over and When our time wage is a great name for this one. It works. I think it works very well.
Because
on page one, we open and it just about the the winter
that you will ever see. Right? It is kind of that classic
winter
a suburban day. The the neighborhood is snow covered, and we've got the the nephews,
mentioning that this must be the coldest Christmas
ever.
And Donald is like sitting in his easy chair. He is the picture of c and warmth and he is
determined to enjoy his christmas day being worn by the fire and enjoying his bond bonds. The nephews user, do you mind telling us a little bit about how they're characterizing a cold. Well, the kids are reading the paper
while Donald max on his bond bones and They've read that the penguin club that swims every day of the year
even in the winter to be, you know,
is the assumption has called off today's swim for being too cold. Yeah. I like that little reference. You did you ever hear about those? I think Polar bear club is their real name Do you hear about those in the news growing up? Oh, yeah. They've... you know, they kind of just... They pop up in pop culture here and there. There was an episode of Brooklyn nine nine. I remember where
they all go swim
on a cold day and in various other
Tv. Shows or cartoons or even, you know, news stories, you know, the the feel good stories at the end of the hour. It's it's a go to human interest story. I don't know if this is something that is common around the world. But in the United States,
I I'm sure it's worldwide there's these groups of of devoted people who love to swim is especially in the wintertime and that's their sticks swimming every day of the year. And I I like that little. I think this works really nicely as foreshadowing. Right? And so the nephews are really fixed
on on how cold it is. And they wanna know and so they pest donald to go outside and check their outside thermometer. And and he does and he learns that the temperature
outside is thirty five
zero.
And so he runs back in
just desperate to get out of the cold. I do wanna point out that thirty five below zero, like about thirty two below zero is where the celsius and the fahrenheit
scales kind of match up. They sync up around there. So thirty five below zero
could be for us Americans, it could be fahrenheit and for absolutely literally everyone else in the whole world. It could be celsius. It basically is the same thing. So I think that's a very clever use I do wonder with it being that cold. Where are they are they like in Minnesota or something? Oh, yeah. That... That's a good question.
I I can't remember if Ph directly. I think he did reference it. So Duck berg is in the fictional
state. Of Al.
And Al soda is
so a lot of this the story geography of these
will
match up to
to what's considered Northern California
like the either the Northern Bay Area where the very north of California
or that sort of Minnesota for the for the winter wintertime stories.
So there's kind of this general I think there's been at least one reference to the actual state of Al, but someone might fact check me on that. But the fan kind of agreement is that they live in that there's a
That oc northern California. And Ducktales is in a sort of bay near the north of that. Because it can match both these winter and summer set stories. So, yeah. It's very convenient. Yeah. We're we're in Al
And.
And Dawn, Donald is...
He races back into the warmth of his living room and he's shiver and they get this unexpected did knock on the door because, you know, who's out when it's minus thirty five. I I should mention that's comic cold. Right? I don't think it... I think that... That's like generational. Once in a generation called for most areas of the United States. Oh, yeah. And so the the unexpected visitor is our very first apparent ever of Glad
Gander and
he looks a little bit different than what you've seen before, but he's definitely got his
characterization. Could you describe Gladstone for us a bit, Sarah.
He is wrapped up in the winter east of winter clothes. He's got a jacket
that has a fur line collar. He's got a cap with a with a bill that... And ear
and that bill as well as his own are just frozen over with frost. He's kind of a morph under all those layers. Right. But but he's interestingly, Huey, still got this kind of smoking
g even though he must be f
because he
is there for for a certain errand. And I like here how you can kinda see Donald reaction. Like he's either he either knows what's coming or he's processing
something half forgotten. And then that's just starting to creep either way. We know that he's not happy to see his cousin and that he's probably never happy to see his cousin. And and Glad announces his business
which is that he's there to take possession Donald house.
And Don is outraged and, you know, thinks that he's full of it. Of course. Until Glad
presents him with this note this contract of sorts that he has signed in the past And
Sarah, can you tell us just the contents of the note? I Donald Duck agreed to go swimming in frozen bear lake on Christmas day or forfeit my house to Gladstone Gander.
Donald Duck. In glad stone prompts, him, you know, do you remember writing this? And now Donald is admitting that yes, he remembers it, but but hey, it was a on a hot day in July. And and I I I tried I reread this a bunch of times. And I tried to decide if Donald was, like, already dread this instant, he saw Gladstone
or if now, he's kind of remembering it if it's kinda coming to him. On on the very next page, you know, Glad stone is talking about how he was bragging
Al that that summer picnic in question and Donald said, oh, he he'd I'd had too many lemonade.
So I'm wondering if the implication is that, you know, maybe they were spike lemonade or something,
but but either way, that's also a nice little. A nice little bit of foreshadowing what happen later. And Gladstone is gonna hold him to his
summer
dragging
you know, flight of fancy. He is gonna make him go outside to... I think their house has been re con into being right on this lake. Right? For the purpose of this story. There their home is on frozen barely.
I I think in some other countries, the story was actually touches titled frozen barrel lake or something for the purpose of that. We we kinda get the nephews checking in talking about how man mcdonald's
mouth is always getting him and trouble like this. And they're they're not as
they're not as distraught as I picture. They should be Sarah. So maybe this is they know they're gonna figure it out. Yeah. That probably some of it is that they they know that they can come to the rescue and they're probably used to him getting in kinda jam. What is that self efficacy?
They have a high sense of self efficacy?
Yeah. That's true. And so, you know, Donald is just utterly pleading with Glad, who is
stoic
and cruel demanding that he get out of the house. So
Donald realized, the ne user are telling him, you know, you're stuck. You've gotta to do this. So he's getting set to do the deed. He's gonna go swimming in frozen bear lake, the nephews user are stuck with the grunt work of
carving their way through the ice. So it's pretty... It's pretty thick. I I I wonder our sarah about how frozen that lake would be in minus thirty five. I mean, it depends on the weather the previous few weeks, of course. That's true. I like the little old tiny
semi old tiny big see that he puts on. Yeah. And the kids have
the the old fashioned ice block tongs with the points at the end. Yeah. That's right. You don't see... Those are pretty thick ice Barks. Other and they're very clearly equipped. For this kind of work. I guess, we should point out this is one of those rare times where Tunnel duck wears some form of pants.
For modest sake in the lake. Yep. And I just loved how they they introduced him, you know,
come forth, your loud mouth lords, Your boss is ready. It's a very funny panel to me a very funny image. I did wanna point out on this page.
Glad says, I'll not forget it. Is that kind of some formal way of speaking American English? Yeah. You're right. That's kind of an odd construction there. I think it's just meant to be in reference to, you know, Donald,
let's forget it. You saying I'll not forget it. But but you're right, it is a little bit. Yeah. It's a little bit formal. Glad kinda presents himself as a little bit formal. Right? He's got he's got... He looks a little more proper, a little more dapper
than his cousin and he's a little bit taller. I had another guest host
warren harmon and who had pointed to me the the Hollywood actor. That Gladstone is likely modeled after. And I can't remember remember his name. But when I when I followed it, I was like, oh, yeah. You're totally right. Dang Just bringing up Paul f Tom. He voiced him in the newest Ducktales. I love I love Paul Tom. Well if Tom kids is everywhere.
No, yeah. And and he's awesome. Oh, shoot. Who is that guy?
Unfortunately, I'd probably have to listen to the episode. But I'll I'll see if I can find it later because it's because it's pretty cool. He's very clearly modeled after this, like, thirties forties.
Heart t actor.
Yeah. No I think I think the actors definitely American Glad definitely meant to the American
Okay. I did also want to note that the kids are... you know, your boss is ready, b a w
t h and calling him your your loud mouse lords chip. You know, we we use British English to kind of denote. It's a shorthand for, like, oh, I'm being fancy,
or, you know, in this case, mocking lee fancy,
And I was wondering
if you had any idea how that was translated
in other languages because they might not have that reference where British English is considered
more posh or proper. Yeah. That's true. I I again, it's the ten page podcast, I give myself permission
research. But I know that, you know, different translators will have tackled this different and some of them will have probably done it with a pretty loving job. So, anyway, on the next page, the next page is all about his initial attempts to actually do the deed
to jump in the water and swim just enough to to cover the terms of the bed. Glad someone's not even gonna come out and watch. He's gonna
stay in the comfort of what he imagine to to almost be his house. I think that the illustrations here are all so funny of Donald doing his best to hop in and do this little swim. What do you think, Sarah? Could you
could you do this to save your house? I know you would never put yourself in this position, but
You know, I was thinking about this, and I...
Even in the summertime, I am someone who has to even in the summertime in arizona.
I'm someone who cannot jump in a pool. Right?
I need to stick my toe in. I need to go in slowly. I'm not impulsive. I'm not brave in that way about sensory things, especially water temperature.
But, you know, if if the situation where, all I need to jump in and
save an animal
or a person. Could I do it? I would like to hope I could. But if it were just to say that I've done it.
No.
Yeah. I would do it. Right? To save my house. I wouldn't love it, but but, you know, you going in gradually though, that's that's the death sentence. You can't you can't dip your toe like Donald gonna try initially there. Yeah. You can't do that.
So he fails as we know he's about to. He he has to rush back into his house
to warm himself up. And the Nephews
on the next page, they they convene to try and figure out what they're gonna do. I love how resourceful
and determined and just doing what they need do the nephews are in this little story.
What do they resolve? They're they're gonna try Sarah?
They've
acquired
somehow for children acquired Al track
and they're gonna pull him in. Yeah. Yeah. They're into tractor and tow rope. And
I I like the implied violence that it took for them to get the harness in the house.
We don't see them sub doing him. But but we see him being pulled out on the tow line. And and at this point, he's not like, rational at all. Right? He's all he's all hid his brain the like turned on that flight turned into flight mode. And so he's straining against the the snow tractor
refusing to be pulled in. That he he manages to stall out the tractor
and is just pulling desperately back to get to the house and the nephew that's driving the tractor
is like terrified because he's pulling it back towards the water and he he ends up on the next page having to cut the toe line loose. And and they're relieved that they manage to at least save the tractor. Right? So they're not on the hook for that. Donald is is just desperately trying to worm himself in the house. And the nephews are like out of options.
So we transition to Gladstone is confronting him. With the contract and demanding that he sign over the deed to his house. And he does so.
Any thoughts at this point on on the Ducktales plight. I'm thinking mostly of the nephews because, you know, Donald has clearly brought this on himself. You know, I'm a little bit curious about Donald just giving up. What does he think he's gonna do? He has these three nephews he needs to take care of and house.
Is he just gonna try to beg to
rent or be allowed to live there, like
what what is he gonna do?
Also,
home homeowners
something our art generation
and younger
are a little bit en of. We had no idea what donald does for work.
Right? Do we do we know what Donald does for work? I so it's a it's a long running thing that we're gonna see him take up just dozens and dozens of jobs and it gives us the idea that he's he's one of these like, jack of all trades master of none and and that's, you know, the comedy is that he he doesn't have a long running job. But he is always
he is always down on his lock and he is usually
looking for something that he can do. And and yet he owns a home that he can sign over to his cousin.
That's the dream. It must have been nice to live in the nineteen forties and fifties.
Yeah. Home homeowners was there weren't quite as many roadblocks.
To it. That's for sure. And and obviously, everything is really heightened for comic purpose. Right? Like, it's yeah list that these two cousins are I have this kind of relationship. This is a terrible family relationship.
Gladstone,
you know, he he's putting these young Ducktales out and street on the coldest day and in maybe twenty years. So it doesn't work if you think too much about it. But if you view it as kind of slaps stick, almost like the Disney cartoons,
you know, it it it works better. Yeah. And so
I think it's interesting that we get that worst case outcome. There's nothing that saves the day before Donald signs. Right? Like, he does sign his house over.
But at this point, we do get the little turning point on the story where Daisy shows up. And I I love Daisy appearance when she comes in.
I think she just... I think she looks kinda notably fashionable.
Or for this story, you know, that's generally geared towards boys. You know what I mean?
Mh. You mind describe distracted. It looks adorable
She looks so adorable. Her little her bright eyes her cute jacket with the... It's very santa like wait. It's red with the fur trim. Oh yeah. Just it's adorable. You just gotta love Daisy right there. Yeah. And and and I think that this story is is the best that Daisy is ever gonna come out in these comics. I... She's great in this one, you know, she's witty. She's clever.
She
You ever talking earlier and you pointed out that she's definitely enabling
Donald
situation.
And that's true, but in in the context of this sort of slaps
situation. She's the smartest one in the room, and she...
I feel like she is allowed to be
represented the way a male character usually would be in these stories.
And unfortunately, this is one of those very rare times because most of the time Barks is gonna have her Al like a foil for Donald, either like someone who's very s or Al as like, a prize and a competition sort of between Donald and Glad don't here and there, she gets, you know, better depictions, but this is like the high of Daisy. I I really like Daisy in this story. Yeah. So Daisy comes in and she has
her this contract of her own. Right? So she saw what was happening
with the bet on the
swimming in the cold the lake on the coldest day of the year, and she has a contract
of her own that she signed with Glad stone at the same picnic, and it says
I glad stone gander
agreed to drink two gallons of lemonade in one hour or give Donald Ducktales house back to him. She was banking on Donald Duck not being able
to swim and giving up his home and
support
forfeit fitting his home
where he was raising it his siblings kids, and
she she's the one that figured out and out for him. That I think she... The fact that she knew that this was gonna happen that she predicted it, but she still obviously loves him
I I feel like that's kind of a mix of
unconditional love. Right? I love you even though you are this person, but I predict
will be homeless with the three children. But it's it's also
when you look at it from a relationship
point of view, it's kind of the epitome of code.
Right? Donald is pretty fantastic at making his problems.
Everyone else's problem. Yeah. He he... The kids usually have to solve his problems in this case. Daisy is solving his problems
And what I thought was kind of especially interesting is that the at this point, c dependency wasn't a thing that they really had studied or or talked about.
But it it basically
came out of relationships
with
alcoholic
and kind of their rescuers, you know, the people who would clean up after
the missus
you know, we... With the lemonade,
oh, I had too much lemonade. You know, maybe we were thinking that was an illusion
to alcohol, maybe it was spiked or something like that. Like, this fits perfectly
Yeah. That's interesting. I wonder if there's a little bit of a parable for alcoholism in in here.
But I I love how this the the comedic timing in this one is so good. Right? Like her arrival parallels, glad stones arrival so nicely. Where you just see Donald is just happy to see her. Right? He's lost his house. But even though he's lost his house, he's still very happy to see her. He doesn't know that she's there to save the day. And then Glad has this his own dawning and real realization. And we're not meant to think about this too much. Obviously, this is gag. This is a gag story. This is comedic. But I love... I love the thought process. Us that Daisy wrote it in. She wrote her contract, not proactively,
but reactive. Right? For the common fact. I'm I'm gonna swoop in after the fact maybe it'll help Donald learn his lesson,
but I'm gonna let him go through this pain in torture
before because she put a road written at preventative Right? Like, I Gladstone gander will not take his house.
I will not subject Donald to this.
Unless I can first
demonstrate that I can do do that. So so... Yeah. You set it up. He's got he's gotta a drink but is it two gallons of lemonade in one hour give back his house. And the Nephews u's are ecstatic, they go into the kitchen to make the lemonade I like that element of it where they have to make the lemonade and they conveniently have as many lemons as they would need.
You have to do a little bit of hand waving. But but I don't mind at all. The them running in and saying bring on the lemonade
is just adorable. It is very cute. I did wanna talk about lemonade.
I went down Al laminate hole. I even ordered a bunch of lemons. Out after this, I will probably go into my kitchen and make a bunch of lemonade.
Pink lemonade is what they seemed to be illustrating in this comic And that's generally
made by adding other fruits to give it a red color like raspberries,
cherries, maybe
and then we go on to the alcoholic side and we have
s,
which is a mix of beer and lemonade.
So if if Donald had claimed oh, I had drank too many lemonade. You know, Maybe he was drinking a sham. Yeah. That I I kinda wondered, you know, as an adult if that was what it was referencing.
And so they're they're kinda debating
whether they should make it more sour, so he has to drink it slowly or a thick and sweet, so it'll fill them up faster. I'm guessing that the sweet one is probably the right one. And gosh. Yeah.
And I I love Gladstone
expression as he's pacing just in the same way that Donald was agonizing over what he's gotten himself into
Donald ridiculous panel where he... He cha Gladstone for being such a brat.
And daisy cha. Says him, Look who's talking?
Right. And so the Nephews have made
just ridiculous amounts of lemonade and they bring it in and Gladstone gets ready to drink up and it's very appealing. The color chose to to represent it as pink lemonade. I've gotta imagine that it's it's so that it doesn't look like urine or something. Oh, that's good idea. But it it looks very appealing to me and glad don't starts gu it down in a way that makes Donald
uneasy because he's he's making it look easy. And and just for a moment as a kid, I remember, I was like, always Gladstone actually gonna do this. Oh, yeah. I I was in one of those states where I wasn't sure whether or not I was rooting for him. Right? Like, he's getting so close to this almost una goal that you start wondering if he's gonna make it and despite the consequences, you're kind of rooting for him. Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. He's exactly right And and this is a really it's such a weird thing to be so compelling. But I feel like this ridiculous lemonade pint
is surprisingly compelling. Yeah.
Mcdonald's is too. And they but they both have that great element. And they both make the reader feel uncomfortable.
In different ways, you know, because Donald feels so acutely cold. And on this next page, Glad is gonna start to feel just deeply uncomfortable and and loaded and nauseous as he's drinking
more and more. And Daisy gets in this great little dig that, you know, that you're doing
swell, Gladstone. That's one chord down only seven more courts to go. And I'm gonna commit the cardinal podcast
sin. Sarah of of referencing, how great the visuals look here on this
the auditory medium, but but listeners really do need to be reading this as we're talking about it because Glad stone expressions are so funny and so great. Oh, his little tongue sticking out in three of the panels and and the extra worry lines that have appeared above his eyes
and then he goes cross eyed as he's dipping his cup in for another go.
Pretty master.
I I laugh every time I read this and donald feeling better and better as Glad is gonna be sicker and sicker and at about three courts I'm thinking. He he gives in he way... I think it's his come button. He holds up as his white flag of surrender and you know, there's there's this celebratory
atmosphere on the last page, which is really devoted to Daisy
and the nephews,
you wanna tell us about how you wanna take it home, sarah? Daisy
starts putting on her adorable coat and her snow boots. And she says, well, my job is done. I'll run long home.
Donald is very thankful
and
then the kids walk her out and they talk about how they're sure. They'll learn their lesson, they're going to never break again. They're never gonna make
ridiculous contracts with each other. And we hear
Donald voice from inside the house and the kids are looking worried kind of comic looking up at the speech bubble. Yeah. You hear Donald Say, oh, so I'm not a man because I wouldn't go swimming and so his man not just you know, his his ability to go swimming has been challenged, but his man and we all know how factual.
Donald Duck is about his manhood head. Yep. And
he starts bragging again saying that
next July, he'll climb in a barrel of ice, water and sit for an hour and
glad stone not to be out done. He also says, well, i'll you do that. I'll drink five gallons of lemonade. And I'll do it in half an hour they've have learned nothing.
Absolutely
nothing. We've we've we've sketched it back to the beginning, which is which is what you I guess what you have to do when you're doing five hundred of these stories, you can't have characters
learn long lasting lessons.
Which can be
infuriating, but it's also it's a very funny cap or to the story. I think you know, the the nephews user are like did you say anything about those blow being cured? She's like, forget. And and this is this is very, like unhealthy behavior for real humans. But but I think in the context of this story, that is about Donald, who is this fragile
brag,
you know, character.
It's hilarious. I I love this story. It cracks me up it cracks me up every time. The the artwork and this one, right? Because it's one of the ten pager. It's not about, like these
adventures and these
sweeping vista or or anything like that. It's about these, like, intimate expressions and emotions and the the funny character responses. And I think it's wonderful.
This one just cracks me up, and I love this story. What what are your overall thoughts on it? Since I didn't grow up with anything like this. Right, Like, my Eye was raised by my mom. It was my mom and me and my sister.
When my dad was around it he was never this kind of masculine,
he was never fragile about his masculinity
And and so that it was never normalized. To me. And so from a young age, I've always thought what? What the that doesn't make any sense. And and so it's hard for me to
see it as funny. I I understand how it is funny in in in abstract sense. Right? But
I myself I can't see it as funny. I think because I've seen
how harmful
that kind of f
is in the real world, as always,
with these comics, I am just... They're it's vastly
fascinating to me to see that this is what that generation grew up with and of course, they're the ones having such a hard time as the rest of us are saying, your man is not being challenged. You know, what what's going on with this
fragile masculinity.
And so I I'm not saying I have the answers or are blaming this kind of humor on that mentality, but I gotta wonder about the connection. Obviously,
you grew up with it because you were exposed to these from a young age. Mh. And you're not somebody
who subscribe to
that version of masculinity
and you can still see it as funny. So I'm not saying that there's a path from a to b, but it it's something that I do wonder about. Yeah. I think that's very fair. Right? Because, like, it's you're not saying that this that that this kind of humor or appreciating this kind of humor
causes that kind of behavior, but it's it's kind of a symptom. Right? It's like a side effect, and and you're right. Like, I grew... I certainly grew up with these as though I was in the nineteen fifties. However, I grew up with culture, other culture that was moving on and advanced. Yeah. If someone if someone threatens my masculinity
my response is gonna be to laugh at them. Right. But
but yeah, it's it's fascinating from a cultural person effective
that you you can tell, you know, this is a car, obviously, but you can tell. You can tell that there's some truth in donald response. And and you can tell that Barks is poking some degree of fun Al it too. Right? Like, Daisy and the Nephews are the ones who are in the right. Barks in this case and and very rarely
has Daisy point of view and the nephew point of view too, but he agrees with them. Right? That this kind of Brag show is ridiculous.
But but he doesn't see it as that unusual and he does see it as something to be made light of. To to mine this... To me very funny, like hilarious... A comedic comedic situation out of. And You know how can you do otherwise? There's so many great classic movies
that, I guess you have to make a decision at some point that you're either going to not
enjoy anything from the past at all or you're going to completely ignore what you've learned that you can enjoy it or you're going to just
enjoy it the best that you can. But, yeah, like I can still... I can still enjoy this while
understanding
that it is toxic like you've been talking about. And and I'm sure there are people who are like, I can't believe you'd get all analytical with something so slaps
to be that's meant to just be enjoyed. Because because people probably hear me and enjoying it, and they hear you having reservations, but I totally understand your reservation and I'm I'm very comfortable
with enjoying it while acknowledging
those reservations. I think is I think is where I am. I'm reminded of a quote from Lindy West in her book
sc notes from a loud woman.
That says, in a certain light feminism
is just the long slow realization that the stuff you love hates you.
Yeah. And I feel that to my bones in when I revisit stuff from the past, you know, even, you know, fifteen years ago, There's stuff where I'm just like, oh, we know better now. Yeah. And if you've read Lindy West, then you kind of understand the mentality of still going back and and trying to balance your nostalgia with this
understanding.
Right. And she really informs my approach to this podcast. Right? I think a previous version of Sarah
would have just complained and oh, this is terrible. Oh, I can't believe that you would like this, but I think after reading Lin West, I can
balance
that right. But I can still, you know, come on here and and look at it from a almost a detached perspective, you know and that allows you your love of it and nostalgia and enjoyment, but still can be like,
you know, Daisy was a huge enabler.
You know what's been really
crystal specializing, I think for me per smelly. But there are definitely people that I I think must be
upset when I
recognize some of the things just problematic in some ways. And and in some ways, I've I've come to terms that part of my mission with this podcast is actually to, like grapple with some of this stuff in a way that I I wanna preserve Carl Barks legacy. And I think it's really important to actually approach them and contextualize
them, I think as like a a community of fans. We actually do ourselves a big disservice
by just plowing forward and pretending that there's... There's nothing wrong with that. That's just the way it was at the time and and you need to just enjoy it like you did back then. Because that's not gonna ever build an audience and it's just gonna fall. He's just gonna fall down the memory hole because
because unfortunately, those those things they do stand out. And they make it really una
and so stories like stories like Volcano Valley, and Voodoo Hut do and
land of the tote poles they they really have to be reckon with. Right? You have to, like, recognize them as both great art, but also deeply flawed and and something that doesn't work going forward. Communities that don't accept
that, you know, legends can have flaws. They their work is not going to endure. So like, I I really view it as part of my mission is to help these great works and endure by
neutralizing them. Mh. So so we got pretty deep there for...
This very silly Christmas story. But
this is my podcast
and I'm all for it. I make my rules. And and I'm I'm really grateful to you, Sarah for
processing
that part of the story. I I definitely
love this one. Love revisiting this one.
Recognize, know, the part of society that did allow this to be funny and
different contexts
it doesn't always work, but but this is a whole hilarious story that's great. And I think oh we're well worth revisiting. Any any other thoughts?
It seems to be pretty
irresponsible
to for Glad stone. And and for everybody to have enabled this drinking of to gallons worth. I because that is that is gonna kill you... Yeah. Because
I can't remember I did look it up and you can't drink that much of any liquid. Right? Like, if we understand the Ducktales to be basically human size, I don't think the human stomach can take two gallons of even water. Right. Yeah. I don't think it's big enough Yeah. So so glad stone part of the wage is technically impossible Right? That would technically kill him. Mcdonald's only might kill him. Well, I looked that up too and and Ducktales can swim in in any temperature.
Their biology prevents them from
freezing.
They swim in in all letters.
Start... And that's a fascinating bit of Ducktales biology, but we do have to keep in mind that Donald is he's a human Right? Like, he's he's not... He's not an ape descendant human, but he is a he is a Ducktales descended human. So we gotta understand that when he jumps in, or he dips his toe in. He's freezing because he's freezing. So I wonder about a few I think humans can could probably
swim like that for just a very brief moment. Right? And then you probably need to take some hypothermia
protocols like right away. Yeah. Oh, yeah. Barks.
Barb position is that these characters are are humans.
Everyone now fudge it because, you know, you can't do, like, five hundred some of these without without referencing it, but we are meant to think of them as humans.
Yeah. I know. It's... I learned a lot about Ducktales Anatomy anyway.
Yeah... This this is a fascinating
story. Just there's it says so much about society and it's also so fun in the specific wage
that they paid against each other. Anything else you wanted to cover?
Nope. Awesome. Thank you very much.
Let's see. I will just wish you. What what did you say it was? The the festive season. Festive of seasons.
Now so a very happy festive season, a festive season to all of our listeners. Anything you wanted to say?
All holidays matter. I haven't figured out a good way to, like, throw it to the end. Yes. I need some... I think podcast podcasts have some dick. I need some s. So i'll I'll reflect on that. Yeah. Drop us line if we annoyed you with our commentary
Al Barks remarks at g dot com or on the Facebook page
and
join us again for another adventure length one soon and more of the ten page pods cast. Bye bye.