Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of sc Mc Ducktales and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge con of all time
This episode is a ten page podcast all about one of his short stories, get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Welcome back to Barks remarks. We have another episode of the ten page podcast.
We're gonna be talking about a great ten pager from nineteen forty nine,
and I've i've got my returning guest here. Can you introduce yourself? This is Ryan Bailey. I'm the newcomer two duck comics.
Actually so less so with each passing episode. Yeah. That's right.
I'm I'm glad you've gotten to read couple of these ten pager now, a few of the ten pager as well as a good chunk of adventure stories. And I I don't know if it's enough to compare, but do you have kind of a feel for, you know, the difference between those two different
creatures.
Probably just the first hints of it.
Yeah. I think we've gotten to read super snoop. This one, which I'll mention is the sunken yacht.
And then, you know, you read Donald Ducktales At.
Yeah. Yeah. The fire was kinda spiritually a ten pager it was a few pages longer. So... Okay.
Yeah. That... That's some... That's a little bit of grounding.
So We'll have to have you back for a couple more of them.
This this is really fun one. Right? Because this is one of a very
small number of Carl Barks stories that's gonna have some pop culture
connections. This one is is
actually fairly well known
outside of Disney comics fandom.
Ryan are you a a fan of Myth busters? I am a fan lu. I used to watch them all the time
back in the day. Excellent. Yeah. So we'll we'll get into it, but this
this story was actually featured in an episode of myth busters.
And, you know, it just... It comes up here and there. It's it's appeared in in other reference.
I'm gonna I'm gonna talk just a little bit about the background of this one. And and as usual for the ten page podcast podcasts these are a little bit less researched. Feel free to point out my mistakes.
And
I will
politely listen and then move on.
There's the least you could do after after we spend all this time pointing out any of karl Barks mistakes.
Right.
So again, the sun yacht is a ten pager that was first published in walt Disney's comics and stories, so probably at that time Walt Disney's comics, number one hundred and four. This one is in
nineteen Published nineteen forty nine, so it's pretty conte with the adventure length stories that I've been doing right now. And...
So was he... Was he starting off with
shorter ones and then expand it to the longer ones later. So he was pretty much doing them side by side. You got to be
on for the first
story that he did that was an adventure length on all on his own, which was the mummy
ring. But as soon as he was brought on, like, to work on the these full time. He would pretty much do an adventure story two to three times a year. And then in between, he would be doing a bunch of ten pager. And that was pretty consistent. Throughout his career. So he... He's really... He's cranking these stories out.
I don't remember the exact count, but you know, it's it's in the neighborhood of five hundred, you know, these ten pager and maybe a hundred or so.
Of of the event showing story. So he these are really kind of his bread and butter. Yeah. And and this one stands out because it's a little bit more adventurous, maybe than the average one, you know, there's there's never any real mortal danger, but it's it's a pretty exciting story. Yeah. And so
let's get into it. The the sunken yacht,
oh and, you know, I shouldn't note too that these titles for the ten pager. They were generally un.
So this is kind of like a
an after the fact
tit that was
kind of agreed generally agreed upon by fans who wanted to track the stories. So, you know, some of them, some of them have these really great
clever titles and some of them are just kind of... This is what the story is about.
But I assume I assume once they're, you know, in collections and stuff later, they they get kind of officially
named.
Right? Yeah. Exactly. Like, the the official names,
you know, it's kind of what the fans landed on. And And here and there, you'll see a little bit of variation even in the publications.
And this is all for the English, of course. And
and then at some point, it gets cod. So so this one's been the the sun yacht. I don't know how for how long. This is... Oh, you know the the notable thing about this too is that this is one of the earliest...
We're still in that new character mode for uncle Scrooge Mc. Right?
You you were here for his introduction in Christmas on Bear mountain. This is not
that long after that took place. And and then it's he's had, like, three or four appearances in the adventure length stories right now. So Scrooge is very much a work in progress.
So Ryan, why don't we... Why don't we kinda save some of the
like myth busters and other pop culture stuff or after we talk about the actual
story. Yep. Alright. So the sun yacht,
it opens very similarly, I would say to the way that goes to the g story that you and I uncovered
opens up the docs just in progress with
some some work that they're doing on the c. Barks really enjoyed showing these characters working at sea. They're there basically Scrooge salvage, you know, recovering anchors and
stuff from sunken ships.
And at the seabed bed. And you know, they're talking about how it's it's dependable work it's not that lucrative, but they seem to be doing right. And as they're heading back to shore,
they spy a
rack a ship rack down at the bottom of the seabed bed, and the Ducktales peer over. And, you know, they they see that it's a small yacht that has a hole in the side that must have sunk recently and they kinda speculate that they could be equipped to tackle a job of that size. Yeah. I noticed
I feel like we're getting, like, capable donald in this one. Because once the kids speculate on it,
he pulls out a pencil and starts running some figures on the on the side of the the main
cockpit or whatever you would call that, the main cabin of the of the boat.
And he seems like a a sensible business owner. Yeah. That's right. You know, he he and the nephews user are very, like, collaborative and very sharp.
He's very much, like, figured out. Thank you for talking and I like to talk about what version of the sort of every man donald we get. So on the next page, you know, as you said, they kinda... He kinda does some figuring.
He decides
He seems to be doing really some business planning, you know, figuring out what it would cost to raise it and what kind of profit that would leave them. And so they decide they're gonna go for it. And you know, I really like this little part of the story. It may be a small thing, but it's neat seeing some of the sort of, like business ends of how you would go about doing this. Right? And it feels very authentic. The Ducktales leave a small boo over the rack to signal that, you know, they're intending
to to raise it. They go to the Harbor masters office, they look up the registry for the ship to figure out who owns it.
It just... It feels very
like he really took the time to understand how this would work. Where or at least did a good job of loving it.
And and they discover the the registry says that it belongs to their own uncle, the ty Scrooge Mc And so Donald is like, oh, wow. The price has
has just jumped and, you know, this being a new version of Scrooge, he he clearly doesn't know Scrooge that well yet.
Yeah. Also, the book is roughly the same size as Donald. I think in scale and scale size, it would be like a five foot tall book. And once again, I can't tell if this is cartoon ish exaggeration. Or if this is an accurate
representation of the nineteen forties. If you could go to look at a registry of ships and it would be some gigantic book listing the names and contact information of everybody who owns all the different boats.
Right. And I guess it's worth noting that the the yacht is named the Last ceo o.
And I there may be a reference in there, but I did not look it up. Because again, ten page podcast. I'm I'm cutting myself a little research break. So listener wants to let us know what what it means to be the Gladstone
dune. Usually, Barks would probably throw in some some funny clever name. But that sounds like it could be a real ship. I took it as a
reinforcement that
hey,
Readers, Uncle Sc very scottish. Yes.
I show Scottish. Yes. Yes.
And the the nephews referred to him as the richest man in the world. Was he already that in
Christmas on Bear Mountain or was that added here? So I don't think he was referred...
Yeah. Yeah that's that's a little bit of fact checking there for the ten p box.
Sorry. That's alright. And now
hit me with it. I... I'm gonna say he wasn't yet, but I think
by his, like, third adventure story erased to the south sees, he might have been, you know, correct me everyone. Alright. So, you know, we transitioned to Donald going to
propose raising the yacht. To his uncle Scrooge and he reads him very familiar.
High
gunk.
And,
you know, he proposes to he's gonna raise it for the sum of fifty thousand dollars.
And, you know, Scrooge is insulted. This is clearly a high vol offer
It is way too much.
And
by the next page, he he's given him the low ball offer of two thousand dollars. Right? So this this tells me that Sc already knows he's very sharp. Right? He knows what it's gonna take
to raise the ship and he's not even baking any profit into that. And and, you know,
they come
to that their cow at each other. They're they're immediately upset Al each other.
Scrooge tells him he didn't become the world's richest man by being dumb, and he tells them to take it or leave it. Donald decides to leave it. And, you know, this leaves Scrooge just
stew and he wants to show up Donald And so he
approaches his clerk
and he kinda has a list of tasks for the clerk, and he's clearly putting plan into place, he put some money into a lock Barks, and and we'll see what happens with that in a moment. Any any comments about this sequence or this, you know, version of Scrooge? At this point, it does seem consistent with even the like Mickey east Christmas carol kind of just grumpy a guy. He's literally sitting at a desk counting his money. When
Don locks in with his high An donkey. Yeah. But... Yeah. And and then also, I mean, fifty thousand dollars even in twenty first century dollars.
You could buy a a pretty decent boat.
Right. Fifty grand,
that's that's a pretty crazy amount of money. I mean, that's gotta be more than a million dollars in in present present day money just to like bring up someone's boat. He just figures Uncle Scrooge is made of money, i'll just give him a number. He doesn't know what's what anyway. He is no, you know,
it's just a banana mark. What could it cost ten dollars?
Exactly.
Yeah. And and this is... You, it's it's obviously some cartoon logic, but if if you wanted to over analyze it, and this is a podcast so we do.
I'd point out that, you know, Donald made a big mistake here by if he... I'm guessing if he'd had a reasonable
proposal,
sp might have been amenable to it, and, you know, then Scrooge just
could off enough that he
isn't even willing to bake in any profit. So they they just got off on the wrong foot, basically.
And, you know, it it leads us to to some classic hi. So
the next sequence has Donald receiving a a delivery
Before we move on to Donald, I want to show
sc walking out to his secretary.
His secretary is sitting at a desk in front of a chart. There's nothing on the chart except just Al line rocket upwards.
Yeah.
Presumably representing uncle Sc
rapidly recognizing fortunes. And then there are figures written on the front of the desk. U. Similar to the way Donald was writing figures on the cabin of his ship, and it has... That would be
two trillion plus seven point six trillion equals nine point six trillion, and then a different problem says seventeen trillion plus eighteen billion equals thirty five what.
Yeah. Thank you for pointing that out. So that it's there can be no question that Uncle Scrooge certainly the richest man, that's probably more than the value of the entire planet
is
Jeff Bezos in two hundred years. That's right. And and even even the non made up figures there are like, more than the G of the Us at that time. Right. So I... You know, you were with me for super snoop. We recorded that one now. That might come out after this one actually, but I like that we have another of these
quote messenger boys
that is like an old man.
I I think this is kind of a running gag that he does in a lot of these that that today's audience might not pick up on. But he just loves to use old man as telegram.
Yeah. And so Donald getting a
delivery package from the law firm of squeeze fleece some skin skip. This is an old joke, but I... I'm I'm guessing it wasn't quite as old at this time.
The Ducktales open it to find that it is a... It's the lock box that we saw Scrooge
getting ready to send, and it's got a note that says the box contains a thousand dollars left to you by your late uncle Mar
Mall.
And, you know, Donald mentioned, he's never heard of him just to he previously never heard of the law firm. And
he he learns that, you know, he can only earn this money if he earns this similar thousand dollars within five days. And so, you know, the this is kinda one of those classic setups where a character has a chance to make a windfall, but they have to they have to make a similar amount, you know a, limited period of time. And I think a lot of
creators, Ryan have used this trope to to
get characters
moving
and give that sense of urgency
to, you know, put them in positions that they otherwise wouldn't. Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. This exchange reminded me of
when I got Al listed email that someone has a banker check for me in the amount of twelve million dollars. And all I need to do is
write them a check for the processing fee,
and
they'll send me the money. It's completely... The legitimate make, obviously,
as as Donald Can tell. Yeah. I... I mean, what are you doing on this podcast? It sounds like you've got...
I am extremely rich out. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I'm very glad I better get to it.
So the Ducktales are, you know, agonizing over, you know, how are they gonna make this kind of money. And so Donald heads up town to see if he can figure it out. And we've got uncle Scrooge stalking in the background basically telegraph to the readers that he's determined to sabotage him. And and we're about to get this sequence where
these these money making
opportunities just
throw themselves donald for for comic effect. It's it's super unrealistic, but it's it's quite funny.
And so Ryan, would you like to describe his his first
money making opportunity that just leaps out at him.
So a
stereotype of a French artist
with a
Mustache of who's the melting clock guy? Oh, yeah. Dolly. Right? Yes. So he looks like Salvador Dolly
with Al little on and I realized i'll it was not french. And then he has a Al in one hand and a little a little bow Bow tie and the asthma mach. And he he's going to pay Donald
fifty dollars an hour to pose
for his painting,
man of Z sub order.
Right. Because
because Donald is a pinnacle of humanity.
And, of course, Uncle Scrooge
the...
Whatever
has nothing better to do than to be following him around and trying to foil his
money making out of just sheer spite.
Yeah. So he's he's gonna sabotage Donald need to stand still in this
caveman Man pose
with a box of each powder.
And so he just... I don't know if you're familiar with it powder. Ryan like sold as a novelty at joke shops and stuff you really only need a pinch true too for it to do it stuff.
Keep. I did see... I did see some warner brothers cartoons growing up, but i saw some some bugs bunny and all of that. And this was along with the Al
know, is one of many chemicals that I'm only familiar with in in its cartoon to form.
Yeah. Yeah. I'm pretty sure I actually ordered this. One time from the, like, novelty company, Johnson and Johnson. And
but... yeah. He just... He just dumps the whole box of each powder on him and, you know, predictably
donald sq and itch and and loses his pushy posing
gig
and just puzzles over
what what suddenly came into him to make him so itchy.
And so we transition
to the next sequence.
Do you mind describe that one for us. Ryan?
So he happens to walk by sign at Joe's Jim that says boxer wanted to spa with the champ, fifty dollars a minute.
And that's some decent money. So he responds with
what All ducks say when they get excited. Black? Mh.
Yep. And, you know, these opportunities are getting better and better. So he
he jumps into the ring and and this guy, this guy absolutely
what Without
him because it's just this big hulk
gorilla of a man.
But is, like ne phase two to add to his...
Right. Persona. This guy would have been great to pose for that french.
Yes.
I didn't even think of that. That's perfect.
So so the champ sizes up Donald, you like. Alright. I'll I'll I'll do what I can. And,
you know, uncle sc just gonna sabotage this in in a manner that should definitely get him put in jail.
He sneaks a horseshoe
into the man's boxing glove
and it's it's just lights out with a single hay or upper cut.
And of course
Donald is instantly killed. And and
the nephew more his loss and
then their orphan out on the streets right.
No. Also,
You know, when you're putting on a boxing glove, you can't have it just like, it's not like putting on a a writing glove or like, an oven mitt or something like that. You actually have to, like, tie it on you have to have someone probably tie on the other one. It's tight against your wrist so that it's not just flying off as you're swinging your arms around. You can't just
walk up and slide a gigantic into to iron horse you into it, much less without the person noticing.
Right. Yeah. The the champs probably use to his crooked manager
slipping stuff in, you know, some problem it's probably true. Oh, I guess
Guess have do something to get out of paying a thousand dollars to some jump for lasting twenty minutes. You gotta be like, here's your here's your five bucks for your six seconds that you last.
Right.
So so Donald is not in fact in a coffin. He he wake up. He comes to four days later,
He's been unconscious
since
since he was knocked out. Honestly, his first stop should definitely be to the doctor's office.
But, you know, he's focused on the fact that he's...
The the time period is almost up.
And he only has a single day left to earn the thousand bucks.
So, you know, he's he's feeling desperate at this point.
He runs out of his house looking for anything.
He he immediately sees uncle sc who smiles knowing lee. What do we think Ryan
just been pacing out there for the last
anything thing for Donald to come to.
His spike truly knows no limits.
That's right.
Yeah. And I I didn't really mention we've thought.
Pretty much the version of Sp were used to minus his top hat. Right?
He's not wearing his his like red
broad cloth I think is is the term for the the garment he usually wears. He's got his spat. He's got his cane. He's got his pension as
Spectacle
and his...
His whisk are a little bit bush here, but... But we're we're pretty close to the version of Sp. We've got definitely and i I think of them as like mutton chops. It seems like what an old Scottish guy in the forties would have yeah. Yeah. That... That's that's what they look like here.
So anyway, he he knows at least he's got this opportunity to raise the yacht
pretty much Al cost. So
as sc intended, he takes some up on the offer.
And
we transitioned to the ducks
getting ready to raise the yacht,
sc just kinda
with light. And
and
we have this fun sequence now where they're gonna go around to rent the necessary equipment to do the the salvage operation.
But
everyone they talked to tells them that the price has been set at three thousand dollars a day
per
her instructions of the owner, Ty Scrooge Mc.
And the Ducktales, you know, they immediately su out what sc is doing. He's trying to kinda put the screws on them.
And have them do it for his cost. They they come up cold because
Scrooge has his tentacles and everything. Right? Yeah. Yeah.
So they have a sequence of a few places they go.
The first the first guy that they were going to go to.
The pontoon and pump boat
is owned by sc, and then a big Derrick barge is owned by sc,
watching someone play Ping pong they get the next idea.
Yeah. And this is this is where the story kinda takes its memorable turn. Right? This is what everyone remembers about this. And nephews,
see this little ping pong match,
and they get the great idea that they can float the barge that they can float the yacht with ping pong balls.
And Donald got the the natural response. No.
But, you know, he's he's desperate and and he thinks about it. Seems like a great idea. So they're gonna...
They're gonna give it a try.
And we transition to the ducks hard at work.
Ryan do you mind describing kind of the process
So
Donald get the diving suit and he's down at the bottom with the tube.
While the nephews are up top with, like, like a funnel and, like, a Ram rod,
and they're just dumping box after box of ping pong balls.
Bigger than they are.
The boxes are bigger than they are. And they're just ram them into the chute well Donald kind of points the shoot into the
the open hull of the ship and it kind of rises up out of the mud and pulls up and floats on top of the water. Yeah.
Yeah. So it's worked. It's worked fantastically,
really beautiful panel, I think of the ship emerging,
the water cascading off, and they celebrate. They sing y and a bottle of ping pong balls.
And, you know, Donald
approaches sp who's at the dots and tells them he's gotta pay up.
And, you know, Uncle Scrooge signs the check for two thousand dollars.
For the job done without any fuss, he comments that it's the first time in his life, he ever paid a bill without being sued.
So you know, this version of Scrooge is is definitely a little bit s than the kind of default that Barks is gonna land on.
And so they they race home to get that lock box. There's a little bit of hand waving about not bothering to wait for the lawyers, because, you know, they know that they've they know that they've met the terms Do you mind Ryan telling us about what they what they find upon opening it?
So they crack it open, and there's actually a thousand dollars in there, which is Al slightly surprise. Yeah.
And it says, here's
one thousand dollars. Thanks for raising my yacht. Uncle Dumb Scrooge
Yeah. And and so they they puzzle this over because, you know, Scrooge just
done what he's said. Even though they didn't know it was him
He's paid up. They've got their three thousand dollars. They don't really know
what the other shoe dropping is gonna be.
But then we get another of those
suspiciously old
telegram boys
delivering
delivering a bill for you bob, He says
for three thousand dollars
from the bouncy ball company, for a fantastic number of ping pong balls.
I love that. I love that Al little bit of dialogue.
It's great.
The ducks process.
Okay. That's you know, this this this is awful. This is everything we just made is is already taken
and
one of the Nephews has a hunch and he he asks the delivery boy to confirm who who owns the bouncy ball company
And who who is it Ryan?
It's Sc mc duck, Banker, Industrial, Magna and Ty.
So,
yeah. So resourceful donald and his ind nephews,
they they come out on the bottom uncle Scrooge
wins out and we leave them
hauling old boots over the side of their of their boat having transitioned
to to another day.
And... Also on this page, I only noticed on the second read
this
Portrait on the wall, it looks like Donald face.
Just
just sc and fury and zoom so far into his face that you can't anything else in the picture. It's just one eye and about half his week. And and just just his sn angry eyebrows and
I have no idea, like, what the context is for that.
What that's supposed to represent.
It's such a weird random piece of artwork for him to insert into the background.
It is. And the only the only comment I can add is that Parks has a lot of these, like randomly
sc
pieces of feel artwork work.
Maybe maybe at the bark household, there's just portraits of his sc eyes on the walls. So his kids could be like, should I do something that I'm not allowed to do and they kind of glance up and go oh, dad. Oh, sorry. No. I'm not gonna...
There you go. You know, this is a brisk story. It's
it's just one of those stories that Barks does about one character
trying to come out ahead.
And
sometimes Donald wins out, but more often than not, Barks likes to see him as the underdog. So, you know, we're kinda... We we revert to the status quo as so often happens
by the end of these stories. We we'll we'll talk about that myth best stuff in a moment. Just first Ryan, What's your impression of this story? How'd you like it? I I thought it was pretty funny.
I thought
Uncle Scrooge was a pretty despicable villain in this one Yeah.
Where he just feels like... And and once you kinda framed it as, you know, Donald Way Donald Way overs stepped at the beginning asking for fifty thousand, and that was an insulting high number. That is true.
But
but still just kind of
using his omni over the entire world economy
to force his own family to do lots of hard labor for him for free. Yeah.
Not to mention even if it was just that, that would be one thing, but now you say we're back to the status quo, and I wanted to add We're back to the status quo plus some traumatic brain injury for Donald Duck, who was in a coma for four days after being.
Punched by a gigantic
Who had a an iron
horseshoe and his glove.
So I mean, you know, if Sc had not interfered, you know, Donald could have made some decent money being a painting model and then some decent money.
Being a boxing
competitor. Hopefully, in that order, you can't really reverse that order.
Because once you've been all punched up, you not not a good model anymore. But
it seems so bad. He seems so mean in this one Yeah. Yeah. Sc is really a sc
in many of his first few stories. You know? He's...
I guess, he's he's he's mischievous and that one we did Christmas on Bear Mountain.
The old castle secret which was his very his second appearance yeah. That soften him up quite a bit, but... And then he kinda reverts and race to the south seas to being more of a sc draw not to mention, I feel like, you know, in the in the Ducktales cartoon or something when he's going up against Al gold or whatever,
these are these are rivals, you know, and they're on equal footing and he's trying to show his superiority or whatever. And this comic is just... It's just ten pages of him punching down as often in as hard as he can too. Yeah.
You know, this Scrooge eye and his... The little kids he tried to take care of.
Like and
it's just not not in.
Yeah. Yeah. I agree. Barks clearly hadn't decided what to do with him. He he knew he liked using him. Obviously because he's already bringing him back
in in pretty pretty quick
succession.
This this is like conte with the Voodoo Hut. Which I recorded a little while ago and and recently released and that that is
probably the height of sc as a villain where he's like outright
colonial who like, laughs about having cheated some natives out of their land. So
he's he's gonna course correct
with Sc
pretty quickly here and and
within just about a year from this, he's gonna be presenting him as you know, definitely still greedy,
but but with much more of a moral compass
as part of his, like, default characterization, Yeah. I I like this one a lot. This this one is, I think very memorable, the idea that they come up with is fun. It's got a fun sequence. I wouldn't call it one of his best ten pager,
especially when you consider, like, in in the index, you know, this one is ranked very, very high this one has a seven point six
out of ten and it's good for two hundred and thirty two out of the forty one thousand some Disney comics.
So that that places it very high especially relative to the ten pager, which are not usually Al
remembered as well as the adventure stories.
This is probably within the top fifteen
to twenty
of his ten page stories in in that fan ranking.
Man, Ryan, I've got... I've got to think that some of that is a little bit of inflation just due to the fact that this one like,
you know, it kind of en into the the news a little bit. People remember it for these other reasons.
Because, yeah, Myth busters had actually featured this one. This maybe one of the more famous Barks
stories
Do you mind kinda telling us in some terms what what the heck myth busters is?
It's show where they it was established to take like, urban myths
and test to see if that is, you know, a real thing that could happen or probably did happen. So they they'll declare... They'll do a bunch of tests and see if, you know, doing it the way the story goes
makes that thing happen.
And if not, then what would it take to make that thing happen?
That's how they usually go about it. I think the first episode was a one I had heard as a kid of a man who equipped her a rocket to his car
and
Had an accident at the end.
So, yeah, this one, this one, they were actually...
In one episode, i I didn't remembered... I thought of it the episode as I was reading this up this issue.
And I probably saw it fifteen years ago, but
it actually is based on this this comic. Nineteen forty nine Donald story, the sunken yacht by Karl Barks,
So... And I could not remember how it turned out because it's been too long, but I looked it up.
The myth was, you know, the ping pong Barks can be used to raise a sunken ship. And I I do remember they made their own
ship where they or they bought one or sunk one or something but they had one that they named the panic too. Yeah. That had had a hole in the side similar to uncle Sc
yacht here and then
and then I do remember them rigging up some kind of system to fire ping pong balls into the side, the open side of the ship underwater.
And
they expected that it would take probably sixty thousand
ping pong balls,
and
they actually did get the boat to rise to the surface with twenty seven thousand ping pong balls. They noted that if
if the containment of the balls were to fail, they would probably
be in violation of the clean water act, which is true. You're know, allowed to just put junk in the water in the United States. And
so they they labeled it plausible. I would have labeled it confirmed. They say, you know, it's an imp large number
of ping pong balls, twenty seven thousand, but
Here we are on the last page of this comic. They describe it as a fantastic number of bing pong calls.
And then if you look on the barge, if you... The one the one frame we have of the kids, on the deck with just box after box after box that could fit one of the nephews inside the box. And they're just dumping him down this giant funnel and jamming and down. That could very well be twenty seven thousand ping pong balls. Very easily. So I think I think
I think Barks has stumbled upon
some
verifiable
techniques here.
Yeah. Absolutely. What what a fun episode it was. I remember it. You know, I I was all primed when I saw it the episode was about to be like, that's that's they're testing the myth from the Carl Barks. So I was so excited and they actually do show a couple of brief
frames. I'm I'm pretty confident of of the comic itself
in the episode. I don't think they actually named chat Carl Barks in the episode. Although if you look up like the,
you know, the the media that supports it, they do mention the because they credit this story. But,
you know, Carl Marx is not really a household name in the United States. It would be more natural to just
name check the donald dot com. But...
But... Yeah, this one's pretty familiar to audiences. It's it's it's made appearances
in others. You know, I I say I won't research these, but this one is a pretty notable one.
When when this was reprinted in
the eighties and I read it, they they had a neat feature on a couple of the stories that they paired called the science behind the stories.
And, you know, they mentioned that someone
that there was a scientist
or a researcher
in Denmark in nineteen sixty four, an inventor named Carl K,
remembered and adapted the idea from this story.
And so there was some reporting in in a nineteen sixty five issue of popular mechanics
about this attempt to raise a
freighter that had caps sized with five thousand sheep in the Kuwait harbor
and it threatened to contaminate a water purification
plant. So he he didn't actually use
ping pong balls. He used poly
foam, but he was inspired by the story, and and supposedly when he attempted to patent his idea, it was declined because a preliminary description of the invention had already been published,
referring to this comic.
And yeah, there's been a couple of other
reports on on this over the years. So I think it might be giving it too much credits to this, you know, cartoon physics idea, but it it obviously
stood out enough that very invent people
and and then very people who who love to feature
catastrophic explosions in their entertaining show
you know, they took the idea and ran with it. So this one
really fun story very memorable.
I'm I'm glad to glad to get to cover it. Any other thoughts on this one, Ryan? No. I think I think we've squeezed it dry.
Yeah. Awesome.
Alright. Well, thanks for joining me and talking about
creative uses for Ping Pong balls.
I would encourage listeners to reach out if they have any comments.
For for these ten page podcast stories, I'm not going in any particular order.
So if if you have one that you'd really like to see feature, you know, give us a suggestion. I'm definitely not gonna cover them all.
So you can reach out on the Facebook page, box Barks or bar Barks at g mail dot com.
And
hope to have you join us again. Thanks.