We have
Hello, and welcome to Barks Remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comic of all time. This episode is a ten page podcast, all about one of his short stories. Get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Welcome back to Barks remarks. I'm Mark Sever.
And my guest Sarah Santiago and I are going to resume
part two of our episode on screw genomics,
and we're gonna be talking about spending money.
Alright. So
Sarah for this second part of our screw Genomics
episode, I want to read a quote
that I found of Barks from way back when
when I was looking up the story stat
spend f. He's talking about this other famous ten page where he's in this
like ridiculously
expensive statue building contest with the mah raja of how do use stand and he said that the statue building contest between Uncle Scrooge and Mah
became ridiculous Al time went on. I don't blame one woman for writing a letter saying that she thought it was a gross misuse of money. I wrote back to the office, telling them that the woman had missed the point entirely, all the money that had been spent on those statue have gone into
circulation. Much better than if it had continued lying in the Mah raja money bin or sp just money. That money had created a tremendous amount of work for jeweler and gold smith's and concrete men and hydraulics
experts.
Everybody had a job out of that so the money hadn't been wasted. And so that that right, there is a big,
like,
philosophical
idea.
Right? We we talked about kind of the
inherent
propaganda or editorial
that lay at the heart of a financial table. And the next story that we're gonna be talking about spending money is really like that quote written large. That quote turned into a story. And again, just like financial,
he's got these, like big ideas that are being
a founded it upon in this funny animal comic book and and they're... He's writing them as though, they're an iron cloud law as the universe. When there... There's a lot of for debate there.
So
Sarah,
that quotes to me, like,
really sums up how Barks feels
about, you know, kind of the, like,
stimulus power of money
some of the good aspects of essentially concentrating
wealth. And it it really strikes me as like a a a very ahead of the time
advocating for the policy of supply side
economics.
Which I would argue
is is a big part of
how the Reagan
administration ruined America.
Not to get too political for this up episode. But
but I think these are very political stories.
So Do you do you know about the Laugh four curve Sarah?
I don't.
What is that? So just in brief, the Last curve is this like idea sketched up by an Economist named Arthur
la firm. Literally on a cocktail napkin can,
And and he became very influential
in the reagan
administration. And it's basically what gave the American right the idea
that
what justify the idea of supply side economics. Right? It was impossible
to cut taxes too much because
money that
stayed in the hands of the rich
was
extremely product Ducktales give money, and it would stimulate the economy and you would actually get more revenue.
Because
money in the hands of Rich people is so incredibly productive.
Like a financial.
This is a story that to me is like
incredibly tightly plotted
very very funny and and works in and of itself with the rules that Barks has given it, that really falls apart.
When you try to apply
examine it as an economics experiment.
Very much like supply side economics.
Yes.
So
this one is is also very highly rated. It was originally published
and walt disney comments and stories number one hundred and forty four in September of nineteen fifty two. So just a few months after a financial table.
And a reminder that that one was rated seven point seven good for one hundred and twenty nine on index.
This one is also a seven point seven. Just a little bit below of one hundred and fifty nine.
And
like a financial,
it's generally hangs out in the top ten rankings.
Of all of his ten pager
if you just break them apart. So this is a very well remembered very well regarded
ten page story by Barks among fans.
So what do you say? You ready to talk about this one?
Ready.
Alright. So
spending money
is one of those stories that opens on Scrooge is money bin
And it's a very recurring theme where he's having problems storing all of his money.
He's pondering about this is the trouble with being rich what do you do with all the money?
And he
he barely manages to close his vault when his clerk.
Brings up this like, cart load of money bags
explaining that it's a sack of last month's receipts
from things like his movie theaters
and
and his dress shops
and Scrooge is pondering how he didn't even know he owned these businesses.
And and this is like a very
sort of
This is a very accurate picture of the idea of a Ty
having his fingers in so many businesses that you don't even know.
All the things that you want.
And so eventually,
all of these new profits add up to this massive pile of at least thirty tons of money with no place to keep it and Scrooge is left to ponder. What is he gonna do with this windfall? You did mention that it's a recurring theme that he can't store all his money and that was one of the questions that I had was how often
are we
starting a the story out with him
not being
able to
find storage? I I'm
in just the few that the I've read for the podcast,
it's quite a theme.
Yeah. Yeah. That's a good thing to point out. This comes up a lot, you know, we saw it in Christmas for Sc town.
I can think of it in...
Well, I can't think of it under under pressure, but but I think it's safe to to assume that there's
probably a dozen or two stories with some
variation on this.
It... It's it's a great theme for bark to go back to. Right? Screws is the super rich guy. He's got this great concept of a man with, like,
all this physical money, what are the problems with physical money? How to store it, how to keep it safe.
And what to do with it. So we get a couple of those things here. Right? And it answers a question that I've always had. With these stories
Why does it he put it in a bank? But he's saying that the things have refused
the banks they've refused him because he's already
taking up too much of their space with his money already.
Right. Exactly. Barks does some pretty good setup here. Because as you mentioned on the next page, you know, he's Donald comes over, and he's complaining to Donald about this awful
problem.
And and Donald is making the suggest, you know, build a bigger bin,
but Scrooge complains that that would cost billions, what's the point of spending billions to storm millions.
I don't think the logic works there, but at least at least Barks is addressing it. Right? Mh. And then he suggests putting in the bank and as you say Scrooge
is like every... Banks refuse me at this point and and that that kinda of rings true.
And so we land at the only
real solution as Donald sees it, which is to
spend this
cash.
And I I really like sp and Donald
expressions here as they're pondering this problem and sp is a gas Al the idea of spending it. What I I like
even better.
Is that he's
unwilling to pay donald
for his help. Right He negotiate
down from Donald request of fifty cents to that
to
thirty cents.
Right. Right. Like the very obvious solution to this problem that he, you know, doesn't even entertain and Donald probably knows not too. Is the Donald could take some of it off of his hands.
But but I kinda like how it's just so under...
It under underpins Scrooge characters so much. That
we... He doesn't even ask to be given the money. He just
proposes that Scrooge hire him to spend it.
Right. Because, you know, that work ethic that he's always trying to flip drill into Donald. Use a good way to
to
earn the money.
Right. And and I like Donald
excitement at the idea. And And honestly, this is a great bit of wish fulfillment. Right? Because, like, who wouldn't
This is a great exercise. Who wouldn't love the task?
Of getting to spend a massive pile of money. It it's
almost to me,
like, It's almost a blessing to be told that you can't keep it and that you have to spend it. Right? Because you don't have to stress about being responsible
quote with it. I I like that term wish they'll fulfillment. So much.
Because
you know, as a a formerly
very poor person,
I
have fantasize size
so much about what I would do with any amount of money, let alone
screwed just money. Right. And
and I, you know, I'm still... I still think about that. Right? Like, I could help so many people,
and it also brings up
the episode of the good place
when
ta Huey, and Jason just walk around
Sydney
and just give away money. Just for the sake of giving it away. That was the fun one? It... And it...
It was just... It just
illustrated. It in that in that episode it was illustrating what beautiful selfless
finally?
People
they had grown into...
Oh god
in this episode. In this comic
It's just in line more with
Scrooge pink screwed.
Right. And Donald being donald.
And Donald being donna. Yeah And it's very much played for Gladstone. And I and I think very successfully.
But But, yeah, I think I think that's this is gonna be a big part of why this story works. Right? Because this is a fun thought
exercise in if you had to spend a bunch of...
Someone else's money,
how would you do it? And and donald goes about it in this pretty ridiculous way.
And and that's gonna be most of the rest of this story.
Right? It's it's very light. It's very fluffy
we get to watch Donald Scrooge and the Nephews
go on this really
extravagant
road trip around the country
spending money, and and we don't need to think about the fact that Scrooge is joining in. Right? Like, we need him there for the comedy of it, even if you shouldn't
logically, he shouldn't be along.
But but it's it's just a very fun funny
size.
And so Donald sets out with a literal wheel wheelbarrow full of cash.
I I just love screws is agonizing look. As Donald
pushes the wheel wheelbarrow through the town with... With all these go.
So staring at as you would expect, you know? And and we're gonna get this pattern where Scrooge points out a very frugal little cherry Al a very reasonably
priced
little car, and Donald ignores them and says, I'm spending this money. And he points to this
chemically
overpriced the luxury surety vehicle, a road v twenty four.
Do you wanna tell when what is the sn salesman say is the cost?
Fifty thousand dollars as is.
But if you wanna upgrade to Urban
Seat covers.
It's a hundred of dollars.
Right.
And so Donald dumps the bearer and tells him to to count it from this heat.
And they perceived to buy a fancy trailer to haul the rest of the money and for their their big extravagant road trip.
And they pick up the nephews.
And, again, we see this
exchange for their their first meal.
Where Scrooge points out a very frugal little bean
with
burgers that cost only twenty cents
and Donald pulls up to a very fancy restaurant
saying, it would take you forever to spend that trailer load of money on until Through. Willie here.
And Sarah beforehand you and I were pointing out that
the restaurant there a name that would be
considered offensive nowadays
with the the word gi
which was just, like in common
use at this time.
It's called the old chip in again, that's not something. That's that's something that we've just collectively
most people have moved on from using that term. Right.
And and I really like all the interactions
where Donald is a extravagant
ordering things, like from the restaurant. Do you wanna tell us what the order is what he orders?
Five double orders of
bro
of Al.
Including everything
from soup to nuts.
And the waiter asked if you wants whipped cream on the nuts, and he says
Yes. Topped off with a cherry.
And and went told that the cherries will be five dollars x tells them to to put on a handful.
And And and this is how the stories gonna go. You know, They invite a bunch of the junior wood checks in for this fancy meal when they see them
Scrooge is just as hard as breaking. Right? After they leave, he says I admit you're spending that money nephew. But do you have to be quite so extravagant
and he just, you know, he has to accept this, basically.
And and I love... I love what Donald says about the card. Do you wanna tell us about the car on the next page? There's a bug spot.
On the win windshield.
So they're going to
buy another car.
Just like that one,
but with rabbit
died to look like
herman, which is much much better. Right. Because it's another hundred thousand tall unisex.
And and they passed this character picture of a very poor person who's kind of in like a a
he's supposed to look like a hi billy, I think.
And Donald notices he doesn't have any shoes, and he toss him some money for a dozen pairs,
and the man just pla keeps listing all these extended family members.
And and it's it's a funny Al little bit, but it's based the guys at at the expense of people who
are stereotypes
to be like hi abilities with with very large families.
Right? So the punch line is is that this year would be a some country
to sell birthday cards. See, that one didn't make sense to me, but now now that you explain it, okay. Yeah. I get it now.
Right. No That's that's a cute joke. Yeah. Yeah. It's it's a it's a silly joke Al at poor folks with large families.
And and then there's another kind of joke on their road trip where they passed, like a a tourist,
a tourist stop where they're a native American selling quote Indian silver tri.
And,
you know, it's it's a very stereotype
representation of a couple of native Americans
who've priced their tri at ten cents each. But when they see these rich tourists coming, they raised the price.
They jacked the price up to ten dollars per tri. You know, Donald doesn't care. This is all the better for donald. Right? Oh, yeah. I mean, if you can't give him their land, then
might as well just give them a shit ton of money.
Right. And and, you know, Barb does this frequently. He definitely has these, like kara
versions
of native Americans, but he also
I've noticed that he really likes to show them getting one over on quote like people. Right? Because, you know, we know that the docs code is being, like, white
Space. They're the default, which is white.
Right.
And and I love it when they transition to the blue mountains and tunnel to size up. Gotta get a new car to match the landscape.
I think I think the story is very successful,
and it he keeps hammering this this comic be home. Right, these ridiculous over the top extravagant ways to spend money. And the Ducktales finally finished their road trip six days and seven
automobiles later.
And they're all just exhausted. And I like Donald asking them about kinda of their last meal before they wrap it up. Do you wanna tell me what he asks them? Can you eat anymore? Bro
of Al and chick.
And they're all just outraged. No.
No.
They finally do visit. Very down home bean or they can get thirty cent piece burgers.
Donald kind of be moons, can't you wrap them in gold leaf to make them expensive. And and they do it. You know, they've finally managed to spend all the money and they head home a job well done and Scrooge has
Donald come up to his office to pay him Al wages, and he's just thinking himself and I was never through worst torture my life. Thank goodness it's over. And do you wanna tell us Sarah how the story wraps up? Well, it turns out there are several more bags of money waiting for him. Yeah because and Scrooge
protests, but I just finished
spending
a big pot a pile like that. And then the Clerk says but some spent thrifty billion has been touring the country
staying in your expensive hotels.
Eating chick in your expensive restaurant restaurants, buying road hog Barks which are made in your factory buying your urban sea covers
from your urban farms,
your few factories have been working over overtime. And here comes another sack full of money
from your silver minds down in the Indian country. And we get one of those great Barks like reaction drawings where it kind of don's on Scrooge. What has happened? You know? He spent all this money only for it to circulate
through the economy
right back up
to him because the box stops with him, basically.
And we get this funny comic
copper gag at the end. Where he asked the clerk of his cane came from one of his chain factories,
and when told that... No, you don't own Al
fact. He he chases donald off intending to cal him with it saying Good. I just got a hunch. I'll be needing a new one in about ten seconds.
So
that story is very well constructed. Just like the financial favor. Right?
It has this. It's a very
story.
We we end up exactly where we start out. He he has this very consistent theme that he is maintaining throughout the story. It's it's less moral.
In this one that it is in a financial favor. But he keeps up with that comic through line, and this very consistent and to me very funny way.
Just like a financial favor, it it only falls apart for me when you actually think about like the economics of what he's implying And like, I'm sure that there are people listening Sarah who are ticked off that, like I'm getting
I'm getting political with this. So what I would argue, this is a very political story. Right? This this story is taking the position
that
spending
by the rich
drives the economy. And and that like... That's what Ronald Reagan
basically
steak to presidency on. Right? And and that is is a huge part of
what I would argue is what's wrong with with the American
economy. Right. Are you in a huge a huge
portion of what's going on right now is the wage stag nation basically since the Reagan
administration.
And in order for... In order for Scrooge to have gotten
so much of his money back, he would have needed to not be paying his workers very much. And that's, of course, not addressed at all. By you know, for for comedy sake, you know? We overs simplify these things. But it...
I can only make noises. That's how frustrating. I I.
It's It's just frustrating
how
this story is one of the kind of
pro
wealth
accumulation stories
that we get starting uncle Scrooge. Yeah. Because, like, Both of these stories, you know, the the previous one that we did, financial,
and this one, they both like are taking the top that At the end, it is reverting to the status quo to the default. The rich
supposed to be rich, his money just
naturally
flows back to them. And and for this one, I do have a real problem with the idea that, like everything that he spent comes back to him. Right? Like that that
buried in there is the assumption
that his money
compounded.
In a way that economically, it really wouldn't. Right? And and I accept that this is done to simplify the story and and to make it funny. Right? And and I actually think it works. Like, very well.
It is structured. Barks gets to make his own watch. For these stories. Right? Like, I I accept that. And I I think this is very successful
story. I think it's very funny. Like financial.
I love this story. I think it's great. It just... It does have that part of it. That that rings
a little bit false for me
that I that I just find
philosophically
I'm sure that there are a lot of people who would say, well, you know, that this is just how this is how
the world works and and economics works. But but I would say no. That's wrong. You know, the these stories do have it wrong. He is presenting
these
concepts as though there like laws of economics and that's not actually how it works. And and this is just part of, like, this is part of why why I'm doing this podcast. You know?
That because I I I love these stories and I want to celebrate them. I wanna recognize their genius, and there are street, but they were so foundational for me. I also wanna be really thoughtful
about some of the, like, messed up ideas
around the culture,
including the... Some of the old racist ideas and the
economically
un sound
ideas that he presents.
So... Right. That's that's a lot to just kind of
stuff. Well, I I know that your listeners
tend to skew canned.
And so I think you'll find a lot of agreement there. Yeah. That's that's true. Right? Because
it's weird. Right? Barks fans are either. People who are reading these in in the forties fifties and sixty. So a lot of them are are older and a little bit more politically and economically conservative. I've definitely heard from some people
who
disagree with me on, you know, kind of focusing
on some of these problematic elements. But I I really appreciate
that they're willing to listen
and engage with the podcast even if we don't like. Even if we disagree on the utility of thinking about these things. So I definitely have that kind of listener. Then there are definitely
more
younger listeners who have discovered these stories
like, during the time frame I had. And and you're right. A lot of the listeners
from Europe is especially scanned
probably
grew up in economies
that are like mixed that, you know, they're there's still capitalist
economies, but they definitely have this, like, democratic socialism
that that is more focused on kind of societal well.
And and it... That's another thing that really fa me is that there are all these, like huge fans of Carl Barks. From Norway and Sweden and Denmark and in Finland and and so on Netherlands
and in Germany
West and Northern Europe,
especially,
love Barks
and yet so many of the ideas of Barks, are really
hypothetical to, like those societies. And that just fascinated me. Well, it fa me that
for the same reason, right of your
love of these, your devotion of to these. Right? Because I know how you believe politically and you showed none of the signs of taking in a lot of these
political messages or these economic messages.
And and the fact that you've started this to kind of re examine and Those ideas while being while consuming them at such a form age. Right? Like, you're kind of emblem mba of those
listeners who are Bark fans, but still, you know, politically
fiscal
blessed. Yeah. And I think there are many of us, and I I like to think that there are people who are willing to enjoy it on on multiple levels and and kinda be able to separate out aspects of it.
And and I mean, all I can say is that I just I find his his art and his riding and the universities created
so appealing. And so clever and and Intriguing
it really does
override those, like,
reservations
that I have about some of these aspects. And honestly,
I I think that low
people do not appreciate what an incredible
mirror for, like American
history
between the the late forties through the mid sixties. If you like think about Barks,
kind of his his overall work. Right? He had hundreds of these stories.
They talked about pop culture. They talked about venturing around the world.
They've talked about just all these American ideas. I think it's one of the best
representations. If you wanted to give, like, an alien
an idea of what American culture was like between nineteen forty four and nineteen, like sixty whenever he kind of went into his pseudo retirement. You could do a lot worse
than, like, having him sit down and read all the Barks stories. Well, also explaining that yes, most people are not three and a half foot tall talking dumps.
But, yeah. Those are those are kind of the reasons why I'm just endlessly fascinated by these stories. And and I I love them so much. I'd I really do. Then and it should be said that they're not all, you know, he he was a complex man. Right? I think I told you. He's not like purely
a a retro grade reactionary. He has some fascinating
politics. Like, the man was Al isolation.
Even even into World war two, you know, he was a a big non intervention.
So I think there was a little bit of a manifest element to that too.
He
certainly
believed in supply side economics.
But he also...
Like, you can see in the later part of his career, he was up big time and environment.
Mh.
And like, those two things don't really go to kevin. Fool, they they don't now
but they
very well could have back then. The the political
platforms
of the respective parties were so much different and as as America
got pulled more and more to the right,
despite the evidence of how supply side economics
effects wages and the country. You know, he... I feel like he was more in that, like, starry, hey, this is a good idea where we're in this boom time
and, you know, maybe this will be a good thing.
Whereas,
you know,
later on, it just turned out to be
fitting, the wealthy,
and then we started getting propaganda to defend the wealthy
and more and more people who
were not prosper
in the way that they were in the post war, but we're still able to be convinced to vote against their interests. Right? Whereas
they
they were so early in the supply side experiment that they didn't even know that it was in their interest. I think at that time. And so they could be a lot more
progressive on
some issues because they didn't see
how it would threaten
the
ideology
of the of their economic
desires. I guess. Yeah. I mean, I think that's right. Like, things have gotten so polarized that people like naturally
assume this belief has to go with this belief and so forth and and and and that's a good way of really dividing and conquering people. And and I don't know. Maybe
maybe the creation of Scrooge is is a good like money laundering
for
for Ty goo and the acceptance of Ty goo except that he's not always
he's not always the hero. But. I don't know. So let let's see. I I wanna talk a a little bit about how
both of these stories do this really neat thing that Barks does memorable a few times. Right?
And this is likely gonna be a two partners. So I'm I'm talking about our previous
episode about Scrooge Genomics
where we talked about a financial table as well as spending money.
What they both do, they're they have... There's a lot of similar threats. But what I really like is that they're both these, like closed experiments. Right? He creates
his own little economic experiments and watches them play out in a way that's very like,
to me and
It kinda reveals how he thinks the world works. And it's also a really
invent and interesting story. And he kinda does this as well in that famous trouble with Dimes,
you know, where he like has Scrooge
manufacture,
scarcity.
That Al is just an incredible
I don't think there's any of these, like, problematic elements
with that one either. It's just an incredible
exploration of scarcity and kind of as early discussed with collectors.
Mh. I mentioned at the time I recorded that episode that it would... It would be fascinated to see what he thought of the prices that his paintings and original comics fetch now.
Oh... That's exactly where my brain went. Yeah.
Because he was... It it already blew his mind when he was able to sell some paintings into the hundreds. But now, you know, of course, those, like, they they can go into the
scores of thousands.
And and we have a few more examples. You know, I recently got to do an example. I I got to do an episode for T a famous bottle cap story. They attempted that one into a duck
episode. I'm not sure if you ever got to see that one. But... No. I don't think so. Yeah it's just, you know, there's that lost value of people who
I think it's interesting that as these there is that it's the metal and the money that corrupt the people that they're they're actually pure without it. So it's it's just another example of one of these kind of closed experiments.
He does. And then the last one, we're not gonna go into big detail on this that he did do this really cool five pager. Did you notice how risk this story called
there's something fishy here was Sarah. It was so small that you could just email me pages just straight in the email. Right.
And this one is cool because, like, it is one of the examples of a five page story that really left a Barks people. If you look it up on Inducks,
it is very well regarded. It was published
alongside the very famous
one shot story back to the lawn and floor cover four hundred and fifty six January of nineteen
fifty
four, and
it's got a rank of seven point five. Good for number two hundred and fifty five out of all the stories.
It's by far the highest ranked story of that very short length. So I I think it's a notable little accomplishment
that he was able to construct something so memorable. And and again, it's this very funny
experiment where donald.
Wants to play this prank. On Scrooge.
What do you wanna tell us what the prank is Sarah? Donald convince is Scrooge
that congress has decided that currency
will switch from dollars
to fishy.
It's so over the top and and again, cartoon logic, this one falls apart. But, you know, I'm willing to go along for the ride with this one just because of how outrageous it is. And and the whole
of this story is that Scrooge is so
he is such a good ty.
He's such a good industrial
that
starting from nothing within just a couple of days, he is able to, like, Barks up from a couple of fish into his whole
mountain
of of fishy money again. Mh.
And and again, it's like that myth of the protestant work ethic. Right? Scrooge is able to do this in the course of of a day, I believe. And it has this very funny ending
where, you know, he... He's realizing that you are talking about the joy, right, that he gets from diving and his money. But pretty easy to sympathize sarah with why he wouldn't wanna dive through his new fishy fortune. Right. And I found it so interesting again with the stereotype that I'd had had carried over from watching Ducktales and now reading a few of these fruit comics
where
sp was greedy for the sake of having money. When he's decided like, you know, this fish currency is not my bag. I don't wanna be rich anymore. I'm gonna give it all donald,
you know, you know, for ob reasons because nobody wants to forward fish, let them alone like it's not as fun to swim around and like, clovis.
Right.
Yeah. And again, it's all very broad over the top and ridiculous. But it makes for a great ending.
As Donald comes back to find that his house is like, in engulfed in this pile of fish that sp has like sold to a trucker
partially in exchange for
dropping them off to Donald and the Nephews are able to to say...
And and with the fish came a note from An Scrooge. It says well, never mind what it says. Your dad
fired.
It it's again. Just a very well
constructed gag story
that's very breezy very funny.
And again,
underlying it is this like, interesting
assumption
that he makes about about Scrooge being such an exceptional man that he can do the rag to riches things thing.
Again at the age of, you know, seventy five or eighty or or whatever he is in the span of the day. Right. Because it's you know, like, it's not necessarily the hard work. It's the
the the good decisions you can make. Right? I remember there's an episode of thirty rock where
the Ceo of
Got fired because somebody else took over the network of the ceo but the jack Don whatever I don't know what he what his position was. So he just... But he decided he didn't wanna leave and be so he started Barks back in the mail room, and he's like, last time it took me this many years to get up to my position as an executive But this time, I think I'll I can
I can whittle it down to, like, nine,
You know, learning
using what he learned? Right. Along the way the first time, and it's it's this myth that America Loves to tell itself over and over. Right. And and and self made men
and women definitely
exist, but but much more common are the people who, like band themselves as self made. And then if you look into their backstory, you realize, oh, while I was working in in the garage on my start up. I got a seed loan from my Ceo father of five hundred thousand dollars
that that I had to pay back under Sweetheart terms. And...
But but people love this stuff. I love this stuff. Right? Like.
This... I loved reading these. Stories. And I still do. It's such a it's such a weird dynamic. Yeah. I think it's... I think it's a skill to be able to
know what right and what is more beneficial, but still, you know, see that see the fun in this kind of thing without internal the message. Yeah. One thing I wanted to go back to was my thoughts about when Scrooge was giving donald the fish.
Mh. I thought it was interesting
that he didn't trade the fish
for anything that he wanted. And he didn't just give the fish to, you know, whoever.
He gave it to Donald, you know, as his heir, and it it was kind of a sweet moment in the midst of all of the
other times when he's been created. He doesn't want Donald to have any of his money right? That he's like, okay. Well, here's this thing that I've decided is now worthless.
I'm am going to give it to donald and not expect anything of. I'm not gonna give it to somebody else. I'm not gonna trade it for something better. I'm just gonna give it to Donald. Out of the warmth of my heart.
Because he wasn't in on the gag. Yeah. I know I totally agree. It's it's a little bit It's a little bit touching,
but of course, it also
benefits
our setup up because Oh, yeah.
Because it's got a backfire on Don. He... He loves it. He likes to have prank. Backfire.
That's very satisfying to read. Yes. So I I really have been looking forward to recording this
series
for a while. This these are a couple of big stories to consider even if they're Al little ten pager. And I really appreciate you joining me for them. I think I think that they're among the most fascinating
and
revealing.
Of the stories the Barks ever did about kind of like his worldview and what what he thought about wealth and and money and finance.
It's also an excellent snapshot
of
the kind of prevailing thought of, you know, the middle class of the time.
About wealth. Yeah. For sure.
So so thanks again, Sarah. I
I will
hold my hopes out that it someday as you walk throughout the side and hold out your hat that, you know, maybe a couple million bucks.
Will we'll fall into it. And you can go to the world. And I hope that someday, you have a rich great uncle or uncle
who needs you to help spend his his millions.
Oh, yeah. Yeah. I'll take it. Awesome. Well, listeners, thank you very much. For joining us
for these episodes
for our concluding part of our Scrooge Genomics
episode. I had a great time talking about these stories. Feel free to reach out on our socials Al Barks remarks,
Facebook,
Instagram, if you wanna yell Al us about
why we're wrong.
You know, maybe even agree with us. And and our pi
commentary.
But, yeah, thanks again, Sarah. Thank you for having me more. Awesome.