We have
Hello, and welcome to Barks Remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comic of all time. This episode is a ten page podcast, all about one of his short stories. Get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Welcome, come back to Barks remarks. I'm Mark Sever a Grown man who enjoys Inducks comic books, and I have a returning guest with me to... For this
episode of the ten page
podcast which is basically our our back to school
episode and we're we're gonna talk about a pretty cool package.
Of t and c or true and officers stories. But first, I would like to... I'm I'm delighted to welcome back to the show Patrick
block a fantastic Disney artist. Patrick. Can you
tell us
Were you were you one of the kids like the nephews, Did you play?
Sadly, really not only one so I can remember whole Scrooge career. Was like the last day of being senior. It was almost compulsory that everyone didn't show up. Sure. And cape Al is still going to school last day. That doesn't really count because everybody also going it too. So I was one of the ones that didn't didn't play.
Right. The the... What's usually called the senior skip day. Right? Yeah. Yeah Yeah. Like you, I'm not a big cookie. I didn't do a lot of h keep playing. I I did I did skip school a couple of memorable times, my senior year with previous guest host Ryan Bailey,
And I guess them magically this is appropriate because weirdly one of the things that we high school senior boys did was to go check out the newest Disney movie
at the time, it was move on. Yeah. So that was my big... I didn't ride the rails or or go fishing or anything like that, but I watched the Disney animated movie. Yeah. So Patrick's remind us. You are Inducks artist.
You you had a lot of work done in the, like, mid
late nineties they're thereabouts. Yeah. Well, from the... Yeah. From ninety three ish to early two thousand
storage.
For Gladstone,
Johnston
here in the states and then put months in Europe and then occasionally for boone and maybe that'll reason what's the come. Yeah. They they had a lot a lot of publishing turnover in that couple of decades man. Mh So did you ever... Did you ever do any stories that kind of have this sort of theme the the Nephews
skipping Scrooge,
That's a good question. I can't remember anything
playing
specifically play stories. I.
Yeah. I couldn't couldn't remember one of yours. I think I know most of them. But it was there was one story, the happy H, I think. We're they're not actually skipping school, but they decide to leave home and ride away. That's sort of counts is well is to they society like. I guess there was what forgotten about the Yeah. I that page for... That does kinda qualify. That's cool. Check that one out. Sounds fun. So I I really like this story. Right? That we're recording this in the dog days summer here. My own kid is getting excited about back to school shopping. And
this is where I'm gonna be releasing this. Back to school. It's it's always
an exciting time and it's a great way to connect with kids. Right? The idea of skipping school, even if you're a good student like you and I apparently were.
It's a fun little kind of way to to live like curious sleep through the nephews.
Sure
even if they don't do it. Right. And so the Nephews
in and donald in this story. It's that very classical
idea too of playing.
Right? It's it's running off to to go fishing
or something very, like, it's very all america I Yes. And
I am... I am fascinated
Patrick by just the idea of the true office.
Right? Because that's like a very specific thing, and I feel like it's not very
salient
anymore. In in America, I don't think you really hear about true and officers first. Yeah. I don't really remember they're being a true officer, but I was a kid. Can't recall any the of the person like that. Can you you were??
No. Like I I always I heard about the idea. I think I might learned it from these stories literally.
But just always felt like sort of an old Hollywood
trope like little ras
or or something you know watch out for the truman office.
Yeah. There were other clinics too that use true officers and stories like little Aluminum and Nav was the name of the true officer
Lots of stories about him. It must
common period. Yeah. Exactly. It's it's an old and I think I looked... I was looking into it. There there are still true and officers around that they're they're much less
of the track and catch them variety now. It's more it's more about having conversations with parents and business threatening legal action and and stuff like that. You know, I've worked Al schools, and I've I've been present with some conversations about how oh we're gonna have to have a conversation with this parents about possibly,
you know, having having some unfortunate interactions, legal interactions shall we say. But... Yeah. There's this is a this is a really
interesting, like, pro were plot device that was used as you said in and a lot of old comics, a lot of cartoons.
And
beef four he...
Before Barks would do the first of these true and office for stories, which is called True Al officer Donald. He actually did a a pretty famous Disney short cartoon
by the same name. And this was
this this was... The story was created by him and Scanner. Right? Is that the guy's name? Jack checking? It was creative by him and Jack Hannah who was, you know, his partner on donald Inducks finds pirate and a long time collaborator during that span where he was involved with the cartoons.
It was directed by Jack King.
And, you know, it's it's pretty good. Did you have you checked it out, Patrick? I thought it was quite funny. Yeah. There were some really really great gag and it's hard to compare Barks written story to one of those features because you they're a lot lighter tone and fast paced to more about the gangs and
animated shorts. And I thought there was some hilarious guys like the thing that ten eyes when you're trapped in the true track. And maybe giant and pen penalized they're nearly big as them. They flicked them open and
Severino the whole truck away. When done you see the whole truck spot the home with trucks completely all the woods going on. None that was hilarious. And then later when they're in their little club house thing don't tries to smoke them out. And they're... They have chickens like on the fire and they put the chickens in the bed with their hats on like, Don cooked them. Never get away with that. That was really funny moment too. Yeah. I I think you're right. That's probably the stand gag. Right? One of those like, fake those fake. I've killed my own nephews.
Yeah. They to get away with today anything think. Right. It also just makes you on comfortably think about, like, these characters are Inducks. Right? Even the chickens.
Like, it it just... It brings that to mind. It's also one of the rare cartoons where Donald kinda talks for a long
lot. Yeah. He does. And you really hear you really hear Clarence smash voicing him, and it's I I find it a little disconcerting. You know those those cartoons.
Barks was involved in them and he's not remembered for the. Right? Like, it's kind of a foot in his career.
It really set him up very well for
doing the kind of stories
that he was gonna do for years, because he... Because his mine kind of my understanding is that he kinda thought in story board. Sure. There a story artist, and that's basically the same kind of a job as where do for comic books. It's not that much difference. So it's like the perfect learning experience for him going into ko weeks. Right. I and I'm just so glad that he got to make that transition. Right? Because the the Disney
cartoons. Like, I I enjoyed them a lot as a kid. But they don't hold up as well for me as, like, a lot of others of the era. As much as I love the characters, like, I would rather watch Lu tunes from the same era or like a Al cartoon
There's something about, like, just donald
versus his nephews. They're always at longer heads.
It's it's very... It's a lot of slaps take a lot of mayhem
they're they're fine. They're funny, but there's know slab sticky is the other
is. More cleaned up and awesome feeling. Cartoons and safe felicia. Places be much darker and much gritty.
So this what difference. Yeah. That's about right. So I I didn't want to talk about true and officer Donald without mentioning that short that it's based on you know, that Barks worked on it. Don't wanna say it would have been five years before he did this first true story. So let's let's get into it. We are gonna open up with that first story that you did. Which is called True and off sir Donald. This one came out in January of forty nine
and it was kind of a milestone issue because it came out in walt Disney comments and number one hundred and and this is rated quite highly by the community. I'm just...
Since we're talking about multiple stories here, I'm gonna talk about Inducks Al the outset.
So if you look at it on the
fan, like voting site Inducks,
This one has a rating of seven point six out of ten, which is good for rank number two hundred and thirty two. And so that's quite high for a ten pager. At at some point, I kinda broke all of the
ten pages out into their own list. And
that... This would be the twentieth
highest rated.
Ten pager of his on.
Yeah. So very well remembered,
you know, especially being that first true and office for story. And I think it's a lot of fun.
So the the thing about all of these stories, right, is that they're they're all gonna be about the same similar concept this
classic concept of kids wanting to play hockey from school. And so they're all really gonna center the Nephews. Huey, doing, Louie gonna be the stars of these for the most part.
Because there are students,
and they're also
going to be that kind of miss mischievous this version. Over the nephews. Right? Because Barks is gonna he changes his characters around as he needs doing. Sometimes the nephews are very like, Goody goody. Sometimes they're a little bit more on the of this side. I like
that. That's one of the things about his colleagues I really like is the way the one story to next is willing to adopt to see different facets that we personally. I agree. I think it's
definitely... It... It's something that made his stories work very well. Can how many hundreds of them he could produce. Yep. It made made it, so they're not all cookie cutter. So this one opens up is very clearly a winter time
story. I like that, you know, this one. What what did I say it came out in? I said came amount. January forty nine. January of forty nine right? That was the cover date. So we are in the thick of winter. He he has a chance to be seasonal here. So the Nephews are basically ad the snow. They're on their way to school. And they're talking about wanting to play in the snow
and they're they're chatting about the idea of playing hook
and whether they should
and they decide that they'd like to if they can get some other kids to join. And so they they passed this kid called Butch. And Bark has used kids named butch before and think he's meant to be, like, recurring here or anything but and they propose that join that maids haven't you heard about the new true officer and they haven't.
So, you know, Butch is kind of standing in as like, informing the reader. But but he sets him up as very mis mysterious
wearing
disguise,
no one knows who he really is. But Barks has a really good job of setting him up as like this kind of fear the force of nature. It it does have a very very
mysterious sort beginning couple of pages. Whole tone this story a whim
field compared to together other two stories. And I think the snow helps that the so nature of the story. Yeah. Yeah. That's a good point. So, you know, this first kid brushes them off Butch is... He says thirty kids played hook from Bug School last week And he caught every one of them. That's enough for me. And they approach another kid named finn again, and he's afraid to even utter the word Huey,.
He sets up the some paranoia
by saying, he may be behind that tree listening. He may be that old lady over there. He may even be boring along under this snow drift like a mole but which is a nice little setup for a a pretty like something that's going to occur and that makes it I think seem a little more realistic.
And so Finn is so
count cloud by the
new true and officer that he's got a shiny red Apple to take to the school house. Man, this this just feels so classic.
So like, old School.
And so the Nephews, you know, they they're kinda seeing this now as a challenge.
Because they'd like to try and out smart that flat foot as they say. And they they... Where do they go, Patrick? Did she notice that? To a hill, Cookie hill, they're gonna slide down the hills. So really flying in the face of the po they can't... Huey, call the Al from this point instead right
Yeah. I I like that, you know, they use the word a lot. That's definitely an American slang term. One of the things I saw when looking up that true and officers is that every
every country has, like their own very
specific
slang for that idea of of ditching
school. And it it was a a very, very fun to read through.
So, you know, the kids
set up to sled
They have a great first run, and then they immediately get caught in a long net by
By the nature officer, you wanted about the the T address looks suspiciously, like the true officer and the cartoon.
Innovative criteria. It's Al done the skies. I don't think anyone really fell full for or is this disguise it's really complicated nice. Right. It's definitely that cartoon
disguise logic. He's got like a mustache and he's got the classic
true Al officer
outfit and badge. Because I guess true officer basically is a sheriff. He looks as much like a spies. It does a true an officer to me. Yeah. Yeah. That you're kinda sneaky looking.
So, you know, the the Nephews kinda talking with him as as he's hauling them away and the the true and see wagon
asking how they knew he was at H Hill, but he doesn't give away as professional secrets.
Thing on top of this vehicle then too can't and true.
Yeah. That's right. I didn't... I didn't even catch that. That's another good little fore shadow. So we transitioned pretty quickly here to the evening
and the nephews decide to slide down the roof of an old garage that has a keep sign. And
one of them
just break right through the roof. And do you wanna tell us about what
they discover in this building. They discover the hidden to officers a vehicle in this oh garage. And then they go down and take a look at it. Patty wagon and all. Right? The t papers and the seat. That's when they discovered that the children's officers is
done. And something something I noticed
Al long time ago that really this way, at least of my Barks library company the front in the back and of the tune off vehicle says you two. Does your copy have that? Yeah. It does. And this was written in nineteen forty nine. And the actual Youtube spine playing which uses Al
kinda of gear, like, radar
detecting sounds and periscope,
started into production nineteen fifty three. So I wonder someone in the Cia
liked Carl Comic books didn't actually read the story. And the name of the Youtube spine is so famous. It's expired on the Soviet union took the photo first, like long distance photographs sync. Surveillance? Change the idea came from this store. So least possible. Other things have come from Barks workspace. Yeah.
Goes the way in the bottom bottom panel, this story of this this this page there's a radar track Scrooge a gadget of detecting zones and the Powers in the surveillance Youtube vehicle. Yeah amazing. It it is. It's it aligns like, perfectly. If not for the fact that the timeline doesn't doesn't match, I would think that Barks was doing an homage to it. Well, nineteen fifty three is when they started
research. So forty nine, the story comes out. Someone reads the store in by a time in fifty three fifty four, and he named the project. They just, you know, have to come from somewhere,
Know. You may be on to something.
And and I think that this stuff is is a real part of the appeal of the story
for me, like, when I was a kid that this just seemed...
You know, it's it's all very old fashioned now. But it still seems a technical
tech at the tone. Yeah. It's very cool stuff. So they they established that obviously, this is how they he was able to track them. And so they just side that, you know, they're gonna take another crack at it. Now that they know his deal, they can be one step ahead of Donald. Yes. And so
morning
Right.
Exactly. They're gonna have some fun with him. So the next morning, they ham it up They talked very loudly about playing hook again and out smart that true and officer
back at Hill, and this does
This makes donald due what Donald gonna do. He he runs off
half half cox, you know, putting his teeth annually,
and
He tries the same stunt. Right? The reader is probably... I know I was like, come on. There's no there's no good reason. That they should fall for this again. This is donald being kinda will for. Mh. So this time, I I do like this Patch account we see the same sequence, but now we get it from his perspective. Right? It's almost like this.
Yeah. And so he's watching them approaching the nets. He's saying they're even dumb than I expected. But the three slides rip right through. You wanna tell us about why it's because they have rocks and the slides this time instead and so. They love the panel where he's coming out of the door house in this page. Is really angry. You got the stop kind of run kind thing going on. It's really beautiful you. Yeah. That is a neat pose. So, you know, Donald
inspect the
slides
and realized what's going on. And and again, there's a really cool panel when he is
all frustrated and he's looking around, and he's like, racing around all the trees. I really like that one. It's nice. And and it turns out that the Nephews have hidden in some false bottoms of the sled. And so Donald resolved he's gonna head back to his truck and use his radar beam. And And at this point, we just get to see in this next sequence.
How the kids have sabotage
all of his gear. Do you wanna tell us about what he encounters?
Use his radar and Al again out of this as a blur and he puts on his ear phones and Al yours is like Grass and like raspberry.
You know. Still at my periscope
Uses is the Barks
can see is himself looking back in. So they really valve things up sabotage.
My whole outfit has been blessed. Al
little bit of World war two Jargon there. Right? Very we're not very far for we're to at this point Right. Isn't it amazing to think about how much that just perm permitted pop culture that, like, you're getting this cut kind of
that kind of language and Inducks kid's comment.
So, you know, the the Nephews
clearly have figure... The jig is up they know who he is. They're having a fun with him, and he is just getting angry or angry.
He tells him you kids are gonna get the works. We had some really great donald
tamper
panels, I think in this story. It Andrew.
And and they can easily out run him in this snow. So they're just really ras him. They make a... They make a snowman
with a fake Barks style i's like. I think that's a pretty famous image. Right? Because I think Barks had a cover like this. Didn't. Yeah. They've used that image. I think Jim Gladstone
used their image for a couple of different things. I think my copy of this
I think it originally had it, but it sadly lost the cover
at one point. So Yeah.
Hello zoomed and panel in the panel before donald looking booking at at them with the snowman. The walls never like don't think of something music. It's another beautiful for job on. Yeah.
The way he's draped and snow partially
very nice.
And so he he gets Al idea and tells them, you know, I'll be back in ten minutes. Take you law break or single handed. And this really free them out. Right? Because you they can tell. He does
have an idea and they start to reflect on what they have been doing and worry that they've gone like, too far, you know, because
he... He is an officer of law. He does have that badge
So
do they they go ahead and fix his equipment, basically.
I like that it turns out that they just put wasp and the phones. Yeah. I like the fact that they say that it's Al wasp, but looks just like a cricket coming out hip
legs.
Yeah. You're right. I noticed that too. It doesn't match. You you wonder if
Mark's just changed his mind or there that carl was up to it Al moment. Not sure. Right.
And so you know, Donald drives the out he makes them weight and
they start to get nervous and they kinda... This is one of those situations where they talk themselves into a mistake. Right?
Because one of the nephews realizes is oh, he he can probably get us for making that snowman. That's that's contempt of court or something.
So they they resolved that they're gonna knock it down and then spam. And I love this panel here. Patrick where they approach the snowman, tell us what's neat about it. Defective that it has a little trail behind it of the snow reading up to it, and we've been have warned about earlier the story from a had Al little kid telling me that you could burrow through the smooth. Right. Exactly. And and the nephews can't see it from their perspective So the reader knows just a moment ahead of time. And that Donald has like into the snow man it's definitely a cartoon logic. If you keep you can't really do that, but it works in this context and it's it's pretty
funny and exciting when he pops out snowman.
Kid guam them. And he says,
the law returns to Cookie Hill. And the story wraps up very nicely
on the last page here. You wanna tell us about how it concludes? Well, Huey,. He's outs more than the back in the truck they're like, Oh like, how they say, you bored, like, the into that snowman, like a termite, that wasn't fair. It's kind of be his capture, but still have none of
well now. What do you say that and you walked to school? And they say, wait. It's a good joke on you.
Saturday. There is the Scrooge the school locked. Name has a big padlock. I think that's hilarious.
Goodbye smart. Yeah. Hell all that trouble for nothing. You be the donald is just a minute by the authority vested in the vantage of true officer and carrier a key to his school and his uncle donald dot authority of this poker he has a stick I can you to write one hundred times on the board the words prime does not pay. By the way, Huey, Prime has spelled with a need can't spell it Crm I Right is they need they need the school. Yeah. He he needs to dumb them down a little bit too, because in most of the adventure stories, they're they're very bright junior wood checks. Yeah It's it's a it's a pretty classic ending. The
the cartoon
itself ends
in largely the same way
except that the Nephews really do get one on over on Donald. And I think I know it's in Thomas Andres, book where he speculate that may be because the cartoon,
you know, you you'd see it in theaters and you'd really only watch at once and it would happen so brisk you wouldn't reflect on it that it was okay to let the nephews win,
but that maybe it was felt that, you know, in a comic book that kids might read over and over, they can't fly authority like that and and Donald has to come down on them at the end. And though didn't actually cook this one. Yeah. Exactly. What... Yeah. Even though it's nominally an adaptation of the cartoon,
they really have very, very little common. That's right It's really mcdonald's
Donald look
and the ending set up, and and that's really just about it. Yep. So I I like true Al officer Donald a lot. I think this is just a really good example of Barks work from the nineteen late nineteen forties period
It's a nice like donald versus the nephews.
Yep. It's it's a very fun story. It's... I think it's well positioned as far as where the community thinks. You know, that number twenty ranking that seems pretty, like, on target to me. It's not like an all time great, but it's a very good story. This is very sold So we are...
We're gonna go ahead now and transition the to the next the next of these three stories. And we're jumping forward in time three years. To the story called the true Nephews.
And this one is
in Walt Disney comments and stories number one hundred and thirty three. And this one is kind of, like,
regard as being an average
Barks story by the community because the the rating is quite a bit lower.
This one is
a seven point two out of ten, which is good for number seven hundred and nine t. So, you know, when you consider that there are, like, forty one thousand
stories, that's not like a bad ranking. But that tells us that it's not really anything
special as far as
as far as these stories go. Okay. Perhaps perhaps the reason for ranking Al those it is is because it's just an nephew for the most part to the whole story where there's no donald, you know, feature debt, and I think the Al lot of people base their like on donald stories because it don't die. I click count for some so because it's actually beautiful drone the store It's like absolute Barks is absolutely peak as far as drawing. It doesn't really do any better than the months right around the Right. Because this is definitely like nestled and right in his golden age. Yeah. I really like this one. I think that this one I think that this doesn't really do it justice
the the low rating.
Where or the the fine rating. There is done donald in the store. Don't yeah. It's it's the only story I can think of
entirely the kids. It's it's notable for its lack of anyone else in. Right. Yeah. That's true. And and then even the title itself really refers to centers than nephews.
So
at the true and nephews, it also has the nephews kind of Al their brat
and and that might rub people the wrong way. A little bit. Right? That's like... On this one particular when they can't wait everything that they do is they keep running into schools. So it's like know they're brand. It seems like the... I guess they sort off kind of. Yeah. They've definitely got a very, like, un dewey or or it's more of the cartoon
Huey, dewey Louis attitude and the com Q Dewey Louis Attitude I'd say. Alright. So let's go through this one. We we basically have we have Donald
chasing them with a switch. So, you know, we've got a couple of these stories that report... Referred to some corporate punishment. Definitely something that hasn't aged very well.
But he's chasing them with a switch
to to get to their first day of school. This is a very common place gag. It's not like it's unique to Barks to depict this kind of punishment. And they're just soaking on their way to school.
And I really like this Patrick how they're talking about what they really wish they could do. Tell tell me about what they wanna do But, first of all, I don't I don't think there's ever been a time when they're more beautiful drug those page with their attitude we know it they look at their heads, a wonderful door they're like they're like perfect nephews. It's like it may never look better before after this they're exactly something very exact about the joy. The wonderful for a wonderful line. Yeah. Yeah. I don't want to go to back to school I went to sleep late in the mornings and fish in the afternoons. We too They said they're already smart, and I only to it us good just because I'm old focused made up a lot of saying we have to. That's why all creepy cranks that think books are more important and swimming and. There's love them for they're out
like that It's just like wonderful
yeah. They're so angry about school. I don't think that they're bragging so much if they're just, like, fed up with fed with
And I I don't I don't feel like... I'm I'm against them at this point. I think that like, you know, I kind of like their attitude in this particular so it's different. Know They're not like goody two are kind of like
revolt against the system the. Yeah. It's definitely a change of pace based on what they're kinda typical.
Characterization is. I'm noticing too that, like, Barks really does some signaling with their hats
in this one. He draws them, like, very,
you know, cock a little bit
yeah kind feels to have Yeah He you puts a lot of details like attention to details and nephews in the store. I think he have a lot of thunder on this person. You can always tell is enjoying it, you know, you can just tell because he puts he lab lavish, like attention not attention as in details, but the details that are there is so clear. And and the layout of is page, just the way they're slowing and down the street. Each panel is different and interesting. And it's not something it's particularly exciting going on we're just walking to school. They just express wonderfully. Right. And we're in that golden Jira where he he really did a lot of detail just in his backgrounds too. Like you said, I'll just a lot more attention, than he honestly needed to. Yeah. Absolutely. How about that panel, the the second the last one on this opening page where they're t up the stairs and single file, I think. Looking at that one, it's really calling out to me. It's a really neat one. It's just a beautiful page. And and then basically, the whole setup for this story is where they say, I'd take off in a minute if it weren't for Donald eagles I.
And it's and...
Yeah. That's
that's how that's how this is gonna go. Once
Once Donald learns the next morning from mister Bum,
that he's landed a steady job at Bum
bucket Barks.
And and he won't be home till late tonight and that it's basically up to the nephews to get themselves to school. You know? They know they're they're in the clear. They dickens, like, name mister Bum It doesn't like it great Yeah. So Donald then manages them, but that's really all he can do. And we have our setup. They resolved that they're gonna play hook Severino everyday, and they set off holding...
They're each holding a Inducks, Right? Like a h, from this Sarah wood or or an adventure kid would.
I love parents Al he's going out the door. See that you do that as and they're best dog Yes. Oh, yes. They're so happy gone. That's right. And so as they walk off, they're talking about all the fun that they're gonna have. But very quickly very brisk. They encounter Donald delivering a load of buckets.
And so they're forced to turn into a building. You wanna tell us about what they experienced. And, of course, it's the bus Barks for school buses that they were forced into just horrible because sweden them to Scrooge, so speak out and here comes a teacher down the street is the country express truck here kurt five minutes. We've been playing hook and already was surrounded. They got buses on one side, Donald on it side teach you on the other side. So there's no way to go to pretty country express. Right. And this is gonna set up the dynamic for for this whole story. Right? They keep getting
railroad
into these
situations that bring them to school. It's kinda like reverse Gladstone gander
left or something it is. Mh. This bad luck for them Al around for their crummy
on page?
It's a really good bit. It makes for, I think, a very effective story.
And I feel like Barks has done this a few times. Right? He likes this kind of, like, series of circumstances that does
has a sense Huey,. Yeah. Basically. So, you know, they do what they have to, they
themselves away in this country destin
truck. And after a span of time, they find out where it's gonna deliver them. Do you wanna tell us Yes. Course, they're hoping know, cattle branch or something like that. They're gonna go to the suffering sour tomatoes. This truck was bringing Al load of school Barks to a beat up old country store. There it is full district point zero zero three. Right. Al the dismal
eating lock, Severino nevermind the grape, save your win for running. So they're still running at the end the end of this page. Right. And and so, you know, they they have to transition to to keep getting away and they end up going away on a train and of course, that ends up having a school car that the little school arm explains is stationed here for the section games. Children. Mh. And
so again, they narrowly
escape the worst situation going to Google. Is wait, you can't leave that. You must check in. That's where you're wrong, Way. We're checking out. And you jump off the train. It's at this point this what I remember first time I thinking what no like how are they going get school situations they jump on the train? Right.
Right. And and Barks does a neat thing in this story. He has like this verbal running gag that I'm just noticing.
Because you you had highlighted the dialogue where they said of all the dismal moth and luck as they leave that rural school house and this time, as they jump out of this one, the Nephew is saying of all the low downs leave didn't luck. And and so they they follow the rails now at this point, which leads them to an airport. And this this is pretty cool for some board kids in the nineteenth of these going to school. Yeah. Exactly. They can watch the planes take off and land.
And they they go and watch one plane being loaded up, and they they're good they decide to go look inside but one says, but make sure it's not a school playing or some such movie. They realize the chances against them at this point I think.
It's being loaded pick and shovel and buckets and the owner says buckets and may Al and the distance going bucket they've got hide in like coaches. Right? Yeah. It's really neat how the story just keeps n them into this situation. So again, the story logic has them tracked into this chest.
The plane ends up dropping it out of the cargo hold with a pair, of course. So you know, they're they're a little bit messed up, but but they're safe, but they're in suspense. As they land. There's a really neat drawing of aircraft and stuff in the place are gonna jump to go out and it's just really nicely drunk. Al lot drawing this, like, very nice with serve. Right And and Al first, you know, they're a little bit, like, stressed out about this situation. But then they realized this is actually pretty perfect. Because they're finally
somewhere where they won't find any schools, true and officers,
or even they're uncle with his buckets.
And Barks sets up this this gag very nicely. One of the Nephew says, you wanna read... Yeah. It's really funny. There must be forty miles from the nearest school. Perfect place sweet booking. Should be Al awake where we can go fishing. Yeah. Maybe wake up this new road their building. They're building this road to go someplace. That's for sure. And that's whole hilarious panel. I think this is very fun Rock Hill School District, the only school for forty miles says off the building. And teachers ringing the bell is happy little kids with apple going in stuff sour tomatoes, and they realize that it's like, hopeless. It's a one wonderful. I love that kind of gag wear like it's set up with the dialogue
and then the payoff is in, like, the narrator text or in this case and just the signage. It's it's. It's the perfect integration of both pictures and words. And collin colleagues can do that. Yeah. Oh. That's that's a great thing to point out. Right? This is Barks like really using the medium in a way that makes it work. This is why people like comment, but yeah Sure. And it's like the perfect example of that happening. And he does the timing this wonderful. Right. So so the nephews, of course have to continue fleeing
And they kinda tumble down a hill, you know, they there needs to be some poetic justice. So Barks wants them to get a little bit rough up in the process for the for the payoff. And they Al interesting thing when you're telling the story, you know, you expect in this first top half of the schools paying, they're gonna gotta end up for the school. You know it's gonna have
sure. Right. Inevitable. And the thing is that the guy is so smart about plan his stories out He doesn't do that. You know the climax wouldn't be as good as the Scrooge no matter how wonderful big the school was. The fact that something else related the school makes a hundred times better Yeah. This this
That he takes at the end is is This is an excellent
payoff and I... It's the stand moment in this story. It makes for a great Al. Do you wanna tell us about where the road leads them. But they can see it's a big resort, so they think they're safe. We could buy a hamburger and then once like, wait either there look this place over, before we go in. They're like, why? We know this isn't the Scrooge, they be full fishermen hunters. People like us, they think he themselves as fishermen
still Scrooge pound. The the one still just the same, I don't feel safe any place anymore. It says dining room so know you must be safe go in and there it is. True and officers
send off luncheon and for all true officers in Webb foot County. And all the true offices is attorney and looking at the kids and most of them have, like, an expression like
funny especially They're gonna eat them up, you know and they'll have true officer badges on and it's wonderful And the one on the right right hand side, it looks exactly like that what I first started working with in the Barks business. Was working when I got out of college, and before I do my first story, And a district manager and the shoe store I worked Al he looked exactly like this guy. I was thought mister G has been just like this guy. Like he looks exactly like him even though he's a dog face. It's nice. That kinda lee guys and the
very right. Mh.
I like how he he goes out of his way Barks does to, like, shrink the nephews down a little bit here. Yeah. They're they look like pray, basically
these big. And the true officers.
Right. And then So the last page of the story, it finally
transitions to Donald, and we get sort of his inner interim monologue. He's He's been worrying about the kids.
So he decides he's gonna go into the school house and check up on them in between his bucket deliveries, and
he turns around to find them just a couple pieces behind him marching to school and and he says so you did play hook today, and they they admit yes, on Donald and I suppose you'll play hope again tomorrow. You wanna tell us how it ends. And they say no. Could be. And then behind the marching up going twelve pump pump the ground on the ground or all these true up so we found out it's too hard to do they. And it's a wonderful and It's it's amazing. It's silly, you know, but it's just so funny. Right. It's obviously over the top. There's no need for more than one or two of them to accompany them. But it's such a great image. It's something that I've never I've never seen before. It's just unusual.
And it's it's very over the top. It's it's very funny. The too. So I really like this story I would say that this one is
an example of an underrated story because I actually think it's quite a bit stronger
than our last story. Which I I find to be a very good Barks story. Mh. Yeah. But I I think this one has a has a nice impact. It's got that great punch at the end. And it's kinda of fun to see the nephews who are usually kind of like, they have what you might call plot armor usually,
well bad things typically don't happen to them. Right. So it's kinda fun to see them putting that. Position. They get that they get their just desserts in this particular
Right. And they do actually, like, deserve it. And so is very very neutral and this one doesn't like. Whole lot happens to Just Al a five standard or even the background tools Right. So our last story is the traveling t.
And this one is from almost exactly three years later, it has a cover date of October of fifty four. So let's see. We've got three stories
five years apart, basically.
Mh. Right? So, like, that doesn't sound like a huge span of time, but Boy, you think about how much Carl Barks did? How many stories in that brief window?
This one was in Walt Disney disease Conference and Stories number one hundred and sixty nine is quite well rated. It's got a seven point four out of ten. Which is good for number four hundred and eighteen.
So, like, not an all time classic, but but definitely,
remembered fond.
By place sweet opener with the house boat situation in making a boat everybody can, like, enjoy thinking about doing that sort the thing is a kid. It's not Inducks opening background the background always amazing how car will jump around to doctor the various locations. You sometimes the snowing and duck they look Al, you know, the bottom of this page in the background. It's like, lush like like a very wet looking kind of like kind of an area like California ish, I guess, maybe Right.
Marsh. Yeah. Really interesting. And
I think you're right too. The this this opening here where they're making their boat. It's a nice bit of wish fulfillment. It feels very like, feels Tom's Sawyer, again very classic American.
And again, just like that previous story open up, there really just be moaning the fact that they have to go to school that they're facing down the first day tomorrow
nine months of stuffy classrooms
And he really doubles down on them, you know, Think they out and need school. Because in this one they're saying what a waste of time and we already know more than most one you're were something go lesson for last.
Right.
But in fact they have resolved that they're not gonna go to school. Yep they they want to set off
on a life of adventure
and and we transition at the end of the page over to Donald who does not know about their specific plans. The narrator box tells us. But was young ones himself? And so he's reading this book, it's got a a good little gag title. It's called child raising
by who can do it? Mh. The author.
And he's in a section called forty ways to catch true Scrooge
children. So this is one of those battle of width.
Stories, Patrick. Yep And I like the next couple of pages. Why why do you tell us about they set up this escalating, you know, Donald attempts to keep them at and obviously, they're both on the ball. The kids are on the ball donuts own Al. They know it's but this is all about dogs tomorrow and the speak. Up early sharpen wet keen Bye. Fact, I'd better be on... Alert even sooner than that. Barks the door, so they can't get out... They think that's funny who do something old fashioned trying take out work. They had extra key. They loosen the glass in the window, and they've got like the rope going down into the attic case those two methods don't Barks they can escape. Al has got a chance of stopping us. They're just two up to date all the latest charges. I like Al the last panel the look how he stuff cotton the alarm clock. He wouldn't waking us up time to sneak away so child like shore uncle donald do it. I think they've got things going here. Right. I I like how the the setup almost feels like they're preparing to go into bad all the next day both sides.
So the next morning, you know, we switched to Donald
perspective, and he finds their doors unlocked, and he says that he kinda expected that
And and they've left a note, which again, he kind of expected that they'd be gone and and he'd expected that they run away from home but he
says that he had sprinkled ji some powder around the house to make their traps easy to follow. Kinda many little touch. Yeah. As a kid, I was wondering what G was. This like some. What is this stuff? Where is this? Like some sort of plaster?
I didn't I have a clue it's the and news kind construction material in the little Right. Isn't it something that goes into isn't the dusty stuff that goes into plaster or something that's related plastic. Yeah I think it's yeah. People use the word. No. This says,
it is the main cons stitching in many forms of class
black or sidewalk chop in drywall. It one.
Barks mysteries as a kid for me. He uses that work quite bit. Yeah. So
he is able to follow them. We get we get like the visual of the footprints, but it's actually convincing because Barks says, you know, created
justification for it. And he tracks them to where they launch their boat,
calling them mighty Clever boys. They've been building the boat for days so they could sneak away without leaving a trail. I like Patrick, how he's like almost proud of them, you know, he's kinda smiling to himself. My likes this challenge.
Yeah. These doesn't seem to be worried. No it doesn't. You wanna tell us about how he track him down? Well, know that the the boats can have so they're not gonna go up wherever where. They're gonna go down. So he's been look down river it takes his car, and there's a nice shot of him on a bridge. If you could see them heading towards the bridge and little but it. I always enjoy these stories that have something like that that carry through from different angles and like sydney. The most be business it's drawing to the story like this. It's fun thing to carry that through the different angles and you kind of wanted to think of whatever is you're doing. It's three d ninety
inside.
So he says he could go and grab them, but it'll be welcome on to teach them lesson. And he's got a whole, like a whole diving outfit there with and he's going out even more than they and he as a drill with the old fashioned hand with the z, I can put a damp into to the rash.
Typically wonderful Barks expired day benz or the rash power right and width for. So we see them under the water, and they're fishing They don't know what's gonna happen. Until all of a sudden
They're both springs holes and received it vote his developed guise. It's sinking Grandma more duff in abandoned ship but he's still down their drilling holes. So and ends less and number one. Right. He's sc their beautiful little boat, what does shit take long.
So they're forced to seek refuge on this little san Barks Island, and and they've gotta try and light a fire to warm up and while they're doing this. Donald is gonna take his time to, like, keep his
lesson
going.
He ends up, he ends up getting a stuffed lion
and he's contracted with a pilot
to seed the clouds, you know, shades of Rain maker, Donald. Our master rain maker,
which I guess would still be...
Oh, he's done it by at this point, hi. He's already had that for. Well anyway, this is the second time that he's gonna do some rain making here and and full... And basically,
leave the boys getting rained on cold and wet. And finally, they resolved that they can and that the lion will also have taken refuge so so they consider themselves beat and they head home. And as they approach their front door, donald has gone a little bit too far. Al us that. There is a note on the door when you get home, and the note says, I have gone to Afghanistan to forget my
by my friend's donald dot They're like, very upset to crying,
dogs and mcdonald's gone away. And we haven't got a home anymore. It's all our fault. And he's like it's very funny it's hiding behind edge of the house. Right into wow jesus.
Yeah. Because he's broken their Spirit pretty quickly in this story. This is how Barks Joke a little bit in this one.
Where he's gonna... He's gonna give them a little bit of a scare. He's not gonna reveal himself. And when he finally finishes
his
soda at the fountain and returns. He finds a note from them on top of his.
Selling like they're but Yeah. It's very comic
misspelled
dear people,
we have gone to Al Gladstone stand two, we want to be with our uncle donald good by Kiwi Louis and Dewey dot, and he's got this, like, shocked expression on his face realizing that he's He's just set himself up for another
chase, but with much of higher steaks now.
And so For the second time that day, he has to charter a flight this time from a helicopter to help him look This is gonna be an expensive series of lessons room. Certain news.
So he has the pilot circle to keep an eye out for him.
But a storm comes up, so he has him touched set them down on a farm, and Donald gets himself
caught up the top of a well corner by what he thinks to be a bowl
And he just... He's
pretty pathetic here. All he can do is, like, call for help. To be done with him going to help help
it's got that sketchy kind of thing. Not exactly. So
wet it's not black. It's like going and sweet. Really pretty. Yeah. This really pretty has really nice sense depth too.
And and so we transition back to the nephews you wanna tell us about that. So they're in the truck And wonder of this truck is going. I don't know. I even lost track and where it's been quiet. The driver will hear us And they hear a faith voice
yelling from inside the truck and they have to investigate themselves and it jump out because it's going slow west coming from our field. The wall has somebody tree. That's no ball getaway away by.
Going like
well. And that's how we know. Right? Because they call it boss, which is good nickname for cow. And so, you know, the docks have to, like, t off together, but it turns out that Donald is lost
two. Because he didn't keep track. He can keep good track of where he was going.
When the Nephews pointed out, the name of the county,
the the county name is pretty... It's it's it's two things. Right? It's got... It's not a term that we don't use anymore for a native American woman,
which would have been in common use of the time, but then it's also bun
which is pretty funny implying but it's like, really far out there.
So when he's talking about the name of the county.
Donald is revealing that he
himself played h
so often and he doesn't know his local geography. Huey, a little geography. Yeah. Right. And
finally, in the morning, you know, they have a wet and miserable night the mary box tells us, and they they eventually find an emergency
phone
where Donald is able to make a call and ask where he's calling from, and he's told that it's from a public phone on Lonely lee Lane. And how does the story close out, Patrick? Donald in the phone both he's fine. And know one tell you the Duck True officer to come out here and get some ducks that need to go to school awfully way back and the closing gag is includes himself in school with them because of his bad job. Don't look so surprised. When I said some ducks that need to go to school, and that need to. That's little thing at the end little surprise.
Then look Al sound of these Scrooge also set. You all the fees subject? That's it's a nice little
as you say a surprise gap. Right? Where we... It converts our expectations
One of the one of the reasons this stuff is great. See with never... Like, a lot of people, if I was wearing the story, I probably have the Scrooge don't put them in school. But he the car will always take an extra bit. Do want people to know beforehand, what was gonna go, try surprise you always at the end something special some little thing that need to make sense, but you wouldn't think it does hear in the little ways. To small. Yeah. And it kinda sets up this nice cam
between domino's nephews that's nice. It's a very satisfying yeah. And
balances out the beginning thing where they're both thinking the on top world knowledge and they both
hiv.
Probably And at the end, they're equal their.
Yeah, You're right because like both sides have been full of blu. And and that's usually who Bark will deflate at the end. Whichever side is like full of themselves. Yep. And and it it was both of them at the beginning. And and Patrick look at this, we've had... We've had three stories in this relatively
brief span from Barb, you know, he he went back to this well a couple of times because it was a good topic. But these stories are very unique. They they all end in very different ways. Yeah. I don't feel that one steps on the other in any way. All three of them but and they're Al different enough that they don't feel like the same topic at Al. Yeah. Exactly. And know like, Barks could be forgiven for having... You know, he he did hundreds of these stories. We know that every once in a while he would repurpose one of his stories. You have to imagine some of the very late ones, you know, it doesn't get away with it quite as well. Right. In the sixties, but at this point, he could really do me wrong. He can revisit things and they're still fresh. Somehow. I feel like even when he revisit, he he does It does a nice job of, like, doing a different take on it. And there's really honestly not that many of those. I don't think But this is just a neat. I I think A neat opportunity to see these three different takes on this same subject in in in the ten page
I am struck by how how incredibly old fashioned
all of these feel. Yep You know, how very, like, classic
American.
I mean, kids still play hockey.
Right? But it's it's definitely... No... No kids or generally gonna sneak off unless you're in a very rural area, I guess to to go fish.
Well, yeah you know, back here at this point in time. You know, the I guess the Scrooge was worried about kids not going to school. Today they have on the guardians.
So it's changed but it's there's still a security thing going on it's different
looking at a different problem. Right. Yeah. You've gotta imagine too, like, just the the whole idea of compulsory
education it didn't happen all at once. Right? Like a lot earlier in American history, you were not required to go to school. So, I guess it's natural that but eventually, they would figure out. We need... We need a system in place to, like, get kids to school.
And then nowadays, no one really... We don't need true officers is at least in the same way that that they used to... There's a lot of less of definition being school that doesn't require build. So much of scores online now. They come home and be work and you don't have a box they do. It's like right. The lines board between school and much more than. Yeah. So that... I I I definitely recommend
people checking out these stories. They're all...
They're all very worth while. I would say, I think that the the first of them probably is my favorite by just a little bit. Mh. I really like the setup with that, you know, and how it's really about the kind of the spy element of it feels very cool. Plus it is the youtube and yes.
Yeah. The that they're all very strong stories
I should mention... I guess, before we wrap it up, I should mention that Barks had a pretty cool oil painting
right, of
Did you do a couple of whale paintings for more... I think that there might have been more than one version. One was very early thing. Pleased tomatoes a really super early. One of this, like, nineteen seventy something one early.
Right.
I'm thinking I... I'm I'm looking... I brought it up right now. I like the one where they're they're fishing
casually just across the state line. Mh. That's... That's one of his great gag things, I think. So
let's see. And do that... Do you have any other thoughts about these three cool stories? It's... They're all within, like, the best period,
generally, the best curls best years. And it's interesting to see him like from stories of when you look at all three stories back to back I can wait, especially, we really get a sense of how cold calls
style slowly changed.
We're almost weird here, you could see, like, in getting like, more and more confidence than the first sorry to the second story in the drawing physical job. And the third story is doing it's it's like carrying on and still is dexter stove look really good and he's more didn't like lighter, you know, lighter handed about composing panels and their loser again. More like they were earlier again. So
it's a nice three stories Are really nice to look at from artist perspective the same.
Well said, I I love hearing your perspective, you know, Al a doc card is because you always point out. These things that I... I'm not, like is keyed into. But I I really appreciate you joining me for this one. Was fun. There more fun that I thought it would be. You I. The three ten pages Scrooge like would like you can be okay? I really enjoyed it just looking at the true back to Barks like this I really like
looking at the Barks stories them. I think this is a fun opportunity to really consider that this good three fix Excellent. Alright. Well, listeners,
we'll we'll be back with another episode at some point of the ten page
podcast.
You can check out
Patrick's work, I'm sure you can find some of his great, ten pages and other stories. And
thanks for listening. Thank you, Patrick. I really appreciate it. Thanks for having me.