We have
Hello, and welcome to Barks Remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comics of all time. This episode is a ten page podcast, all about one of his short stories. Get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Welcome back to Barks remarks. I'm Mark Sever a grown man who enjoys talking about stuck comics.
And I am joined by another grown man today, a new guest host that I'm very excited to have So I'm gonna let him introduce himself. Hi. My name is Y kim Y.
I work as an editor. At Eggplant in Sweden, and most work with local brands of economics like ban and
That most of you never heard of, but
I also edit a comic book called Ka Sc. That's roughly da Ducktales classics
six times a year, we try to fill it with obscure and fun, great classic dune stories, and we also have one classic Barks store and every issue. So that... That's very exciting. What a what a treat, it must be to get to work with local es
the Barks stories
I... I'm just so excited to get to meet people who are involved with the creation and the curation of these comments you joaquin. So So thank you very much for joining me. Thank you also for... You know, you you run the Carl Barks, I think you're one of the moderator of the Carl Barks group on Facebook and you've been very patient with my
my promoting the podcast. So I'm very grateful for that. But I'm having so much fun with this this
series
and
we agreed that a good story for you to join me for would be what we hear in the states. It's
titled the think box ball.
What is it called
over there in E mont land. And and why are you excited about this one? Well, it's called the pro
when it was
published in the seventies,
back in the fifties it tell, of course, no title. Right? But in the seventies, it was called roughly. Wonderful language would boxes, which has since been changed into
wonderful think boxes, which makes more sense. Yeah. I think so. It's interesting how these, like, titles will kind of evolve until they get, like, cod. You know, If you look this one up, I guess, in English, it was at some point it was called the Brain wolf.
I am excited to talk about this one, but I but I'd love to know a little bit more about how you came to be into Carl Barks. You know, have you've been a Carl Barks fan for a long time, Y? Oh, since it was a small kid. I mean, this is the story of my wife, loving called Barks comics, my father bought all the comics from the late fifties Mid fifty up until nineteen sixty nine. Is save them whole so our grandparents have them stacked in their attic and then in the closet sets, and don't there. Just heaven for for kid like me reading them over and over and over again. Then of course, I I did not know about call, but I noticed
those stories, the best uncle Scrooge adventures they were drawn a certain way. So yeah let's it discovered it the Barks stores. Yeah. That sounds really familiar. Right? Like, I remember being a kid and enjoying the Disney comics that were coming out in the mid and late eighties of that time and and it took me a little while to kind of figure out that there there were a couple of artists that just stood out, you know, they had a certain style I loved a lot of the comics by other ones, but they're there was really something about the Barks stories where they they felt like the the right version of the characters.
And the Old got, the More of the other stuff was not that interesting and more, but the Barks store still work and could still read them and reread them. Not the case, which with so many of the other stores. Yeah. I I think that's a good point. Right? These do have, like that timeless feel And when I've been going back now because it it's been probably a decades since I red. Most of them like you as a kid. I I read them over and over some of them, you know, maybe a hundred times literally, and and then I had a pretty long break where I wasn't reading them, and I'm I'm really finding that going back and reading them is a has a grown man now, I'm finding a lot of new things to appreciate.
So so it's a lot of fun. I think you mentioned that you've got some kind of a project coming up that's related to a certain mister Ji Gear. Is that right? Could be could be? Because I've been think Al lot about this story in particular, lately and
how the relationship
between Donald, the nephews and ji evolves through these first stories about Barks. And I think we will get into that more after. We talk about the story.
Yeah. So I sense that your your decided to get into the the meat of the story itself. Let's cover a little bit of the background.
The the think box alex,
was released
in nineteen
fifty
two. It's got a cover date of June for for the American public communication in walt Disney comics and stories number one hundred and forty one. This is of course, one of his ten pager
So I don't research these ten page podcast episodes as much but you know, this is a pretty significant one so so I had to do a bit reese church. Right? We are dealing here with Ji Girl
first full length appearance, but he was a background care her in... What what was the original story joaquin?
The previous issue, actually, he came onto the scene hopping around for an hour on august he
is trying to turn better. But it's better. Yeah. It it's so interesting how, you know, Barks will sometimes turn these incidental characters
into someone who will like be the star of dozens of stories. Yes. One of the if you for first name a guy in a published. They had no clue news. Barks is no clue, but you remember him and tries
to open and next month. He's Barks. That's right. So a very
a very modest
beginning there. Oh, I do like to mention how how often stories have been
reprinted. So this one has had
you know, a pretty good number of reprint in the Us I I count on index that there at least eleven. Counting
the main one. And, you know, that's not surprise. And since it's such a important character
introduction. And it didn't take long for to reach Sweden
in early nineteen fifty three. So only eight months. Yeah. And that's not too common. Right? Sometimes there's a pretty big delay. Yes. Yes. Sometimes you you wait ten or twenty twenty years. Or so but this one came first. Excellent.
Alright. So y kim I am going to
go into the story itself. And then, you know, as something strikes us is interesting or notable,
We're gonna go ahead and talk about it. Sounds fine. So this one starts out from from Donald
perspective of. And the reader is drawn in with this really
loud sound the Donald is listening to, and he He's wondering what's going on. He here's some explosions from over fence. And so he runs to see what it is. And when he rounds the corner,
key and the reader, see Ji Gear we're about to learn who it is. Rolling down the street in this really unusual vehicle that he's gonna call a buggy
and Donald, Donald identifies him as being ji Gear the quote dizzy
invent her And Donald Wonders what this crazy buggy is, and he asks Ji about it, and he he tells him that it's his jet powered baggage buggy, and he tells them that it runs two blocks on a quart of fire crackers.
And and so at the end of the page, he loads it up and cautions
anyone in range to to get out of the way. So that's our introduction. Yes. A what a great introduction page because Barks also master this. You know how it says it's giant Girls the dis vendor. He explains to the readers
exactly who they see because they no clue and the nephew says hi Donald as if the reader is don't know who donald doc but every story someone's first stories of course, they need to know who that doll doc is. That's a good point that's like an editors
point of view. Right? That... What what he's doing in the introduction. Al as a long time reader, I'm not noticing on that little, like, catch up that a good creator is doing at the beginning of every
for you're right. It's incredibly important and he does it at the same time that he really gets you interested because we see donald
and and he kind of keeps it out of sight for just a couple.
You know, I I just recorded an episode about the tear of the beagle boys where he'd stretched it out much longer, but It was the same thing. He was all about the
anticipation of always to come. So with the first page would know who all the characters are and
this serves has a set up for the setup of the story. Yeah. Some great shorthand setup.
And then on the second page, you know, we see the vehicle take off, and it's just an incredible bit of character art because The vehicle le forward.
It's... Knocks donald off his feet. Gyro looks just ecstatic Al how it's working.
And Donald has this kind of surprising reaction, I think. Right? Where he, he's like delighted at looking at how
strange
gyro is at at this point, the
characterization is not really... It's not settled at all. And I love how in this setup, John
really, really mean. This law in the general
behaving
but Barks has to do this. He does because this is the... This is the story that he wants to tell. Right? Like, he wants he wants gyro
to, like,
overcome
that... This mock
this division, but it's technically a donald Inducks story. So he needs to be the avatar for...
Yes.
I love the bit where where gyro just like stops the vehicle by crashing it into a tree and ten
and he's totally... He's totally nonchalant Al lot about it.
Because that's how he wanted to stop. Yeah. Of course. Do you so... It doesn't bother you then how mean Donald is in this one. No. Because it's part of the setup. So that he will get what he just deserves like wrong. And the readers will...
How how do you say it? They will feel that it's.
Yes. Yeah. Yeah.
Because because of the way it don't behaves in the beginning. And and this is again, me as an editor. I think about these things all the time.
Sometimes I might think too much about this stuff. I love to hear. I I love to hear this, Y joaquin. This is this is great to me. Hearing the editorial process is is so interesting. So I appreciate you telling me
because I know as a kid reading this one. I I loved this one I think this one stands out for a good reason. But I do remember thinking like, why is Donald so mean in this one? And and, yeah, you know, sometimes Barks just needs him to do this. Because because that's what it means when you have that like, every man character. And so at the end of this page, you know, we we learned that really, this story is not even about this crazy contraption this this buggy. He's just used it to take himself to to test the other invention.
That he has now perfect
with which are his think boxes.
And show the readers what kind of work inventor
and is such a visual way to do it by showing this this driving around thing. Right. And and we immediately get two examples. Right? So we know he's not like a one off. Me know, he really is inventor. He has more than one. Onto to the next page, you know, the the characters are transitioning into the woods as we're getting the explanation for what the think Barks
are. And
I really like the explanation. Would did do you wanna tell us about what the think boxes are supposed to do you joaquin? Well, the ray bean learned the animals how to think when they pass these two boxes. And here's the thing of course animals do think why shouldn't they.
But but then the nephews
explains the animals will be able to talk and do things like human beings, and now it gets interesting. The nephews,
they see themselves not Al Ducktales, but it's human beings. Isn't that room? Yeah. This is one of those times where, like, I guess he never he doesn't usually talk about it overt. But, of course, Carl Barks always thinks of his characters as human. Yes. He doesn't usually talk about it. No. But that's a key point. To realize what made Barks so good. He always fault about miss humans. Right? A not cute little docs
exactly.
They're they're being Inducks is just it's incidental. And so we've got this very nice quick setup up. You know, they they are leaving the think boxes
on an animal trail, and they're gonna check back tomorrow and see what the results are and Donald
is
he's kind of had time to digest what's going on and and
he's still getting a kick out of it, but then he's He's realized that his nephews are mixed up with Gi and so he is dig, and he's like why are you involved with this crack
and the nephews are very proud to to be able to count themselves as his assistance.
Yes. Sir. I think this was to be bugs original plan
and that it was going to stick to it, that they were going to be his assistance. Pairing the nephews with gyroscope to lead situations and stuff. But as we will see, this didn't work very. That's true. Yeah. He's got
guess he's just got too many different scenarios for the docks. But but we transitioned to the Ducktales house and the next page, the the entirety of that page is basically about donald her rang his nephews that...
They're gonna bring shame to the name of Duck by being involved with a crack. And then If do a really nice job of standing up for for ji and pointing out that, you know, people called the great inventors of their time like Edison.
Crack as well. And
this is the conflict page of the story. Donald is calling
screw ball Barks,
Wacky brains, I mean it's just inserting all the time here. Any and is install the nephews. That's right. He's he's insulting them by extension.
Those terms are pretty fun, you know, Barks
English terms. Right? Crack, Scrooge, I imagine that it's hard
sometimes to localize terms like that. Yeah. I wish I have the switch this coming right here
the came I'm always interested when when people translate, you know, whether they decide to do, like, a literal
translation or if they which I think is much better if they try to get something that's really within the the character of what's being said. Yeah. That's the tradition
we have here kevin Sweden. Just to make it as good as possible, not to stick to every sentence making just exactly as the English version. But
to make as good as possible and fun as possible. And I just
this also something else that's struck me. I'm gonna re reread it. But is referring to edison
Al only, which today's kids know who they were. I bet they did in fifties,
You're you're totally right. Right? Like, during this time, they would have been shorthand
for a great inventor.
And I think maybe Edison would still be known that people would probably go to like Tesla these days.
Right, Addison rival. And Marco,
of course, famously invented the telegraph.
Right? The wireless typically Yeah. Yeah. The wireless telegraph. So so, yeah, not not as relevant. But still important, but, yeah, it's inter... It's it's fascinating the the re the references
that resonated
back in in the men early fifties. Yeah. So this page closes out with Donald
getting an idea. And and this is a great trope. Y kim where Donald wants to teach the Nephews lesson and and he gets some kind of wicked idea to send them up. And the second does we know how this is going to. Badly for Donald. Absolutely. It's so reliable.
So and he's of desperate
about this that he goes straight to week's must coast in store.
And on the door. We got them there. I want to read now to it, and of course, the store owner is living in a store because
that works for the story. It's wool costume. And now with that in hand, the plot thickens.
Yeah. Indeed. So
just as he's set up. Right? We we return to that trail, Jay and the kids.
The next morning, and and they're very happy to see a number of sets of traps,
including a set of wolf tracks.
And
immediately on the next panel,
we see a by pedal wolf that we the reader know to be donald in a wolf class
introducing himself with really
formal
airy language,
yes. That gentleman, that was me. Good morning a couple of couple of musical notes meant to den denote that he's being very airy about it. And they're they're stunned by what they see. Yeah. And and we, of course, get the little trope where we we the reader can see the buttons in the wolf class team, but of course, the the other Inducks can't. And also nice touch that in the final panel, ji even seems to price... That it works it says my invention works Yeah. Absolutely.
He he maybe was not confident. Yeah. Because latest stories, he mentioned anything and he
mentioned those fabulous things, but here, he's might just starting out. That's right. Yeah. He calls himself inventor of anything.
So
On the next page, we get Donald trying to
fulfill his, like, devious plan. Right? He's explaining what happened that he was a dun wolfe walking through he passed through the boxes
until he started acting like a human being and Donald
transitions into, like, acting creep beer and creep beer until he, he tells them that he no longer Al likes raw food, key wanted cooked food,
specifically roast Ducktales
and Y kim, I was really struck as a small child.
Like, one of the reasons this one stands out to me and my memory is how scary. Parts of this story look Yes. I mean, Donald wolf, Huey, pretends that they really want to eat the kids. And of course, that is scared for a kid this is someone coming up do you want to eat you? And again, and here here, here's us a switch because now Bark is not referring to the humans anymore. Yeah Ducktales.
Yeah. Need to do that to make it work in this story because it comes roast humans. Right. Kits. Because the sensors would not have liked and roast.
That's true. I I think in this era of Western Publishing, he was still getting away with a little but but he was starting to get a lot of push Barks and we're about to get into a a pretty
sensible
period in in a couple of years. And and so
as Donald is chasing them in the guise of the wolf Gyro doesn't really react proportionately. He's just kinda standing there wondering what what went wrong, did I have a dial set to Let me and and the nephews user, like crying out in interior, and as they passed by a tree, we see a figure just the hint of a figure hiding behind the tree. And as Donald as a wolf passes, a a man trips him and to basically saves the nephews Ducktales
tells the the wolf the supposed wolf hold on there, you know, you can't harm those boys while I'm around. Donald pretty quickly revealed to that man that it's all a frank,
and he he pulls off the head of his costume and tells him Not a wolf. I'm Inducks. And y, do you mind telling us about how this man responds. Well, he's just laughing. And is this bedding half of it buddy I'm not a dog. I'm a wolf. And this is just the beginning of the exact same dialogue. As Done spoke before, is now the dual saying, and he's reacting this same way. It says that it passed between two funny boxes that was sitting beside the train, and he wants cooked food, rose jack, and he established chased out, exactly the same way that Donald chased and nephews So we got this the same sequence.
Yeah to from another the perspective. Yeah... Yeah. You said it perfectly. It's it's
it's a really confident thing to do. Right? Because as you say, he's it's almost verbatim. Right? It's almost word for word that he's saying Donald lines. Barks
and so Donald is like, I I know where this is going. His hair is growing.
That
image of the the real wolf. I'm masking
himself. Again, I read this one probably at age eight, and that's stuck with me because as scary as Donald looked this is a really upsetting
idea. Right? A wolf that can talk like a human, I mean... I mean, it's it's the old trope of like, a werewolf basically. Yes Yes. And I consider this one of the scariest things that Barks put in his ten pager and honestly, I I think it's up there with the regular economic to meet maybe it's... Maybe it just lands like that to me, but I I thought that that was a very disturbing image. Yes. I can only breathe. And and I mean, it's in a good way. Right? Because it it gets you like really invested in this story and now you're worried for Donald. And and the nephews have just run off. Right? And when they realized that they're not being pursued, they backtrack,
and they are able to see
the the tracks that that indicate Donald sc with this real wolf. And we get another great story be here that that tells us what that updates the nephews on what happened. What is It Y? Yeah. It's a rabbit a total rabbit but, of course, also past those boxes.
Much to the nephew surprise and Ducktales
and nephews, which way Donald and the wolf were heading so know they are trying to find him before it's late. And when they see...
Go ahead he's all tied up. Ready to be
roasted by the world. The and the wolf is trying to make a fire. So now they have to move fast think quick. And back to ge, who still only thinking about his think Barks He doesn't care if it kids and oh chase by is only thing about his inventions. Yeah. It's very single mind in this one. Yeah. Yeah. And then,
the kids asked first for a solution, and course, because it's a jeans and inventor, it comes up with Al solution in the Jiffy. And
then the nephews takes the pink boxes with the beams And and, yeah, they set it up, you know? And and, you know, before we hit that last page, I just wanted to note, what a neat way it was to, like, introduce that rabbit? It's a great little story element. We needed the nephews to be updated. With where Donald gone, and this was a nice way to do it, I think because Barks casually gets to throw in you you never show one.
If if you have a a high concept element in a story like this, you know, you don't show one animal that's able to talk. Usually, Barks follows the rule of three is what I've noticed, but there's a lot going on on this one. So he at least had to get one other talking animal in there.
I guess, I guess arguably Donald was the the third one. But anyway, the Ducktales will set it set it up and in the nick of time, as as the wolf is garnish donald, he's become so human.
He has a a favorite garnish he likes to use a little bit of sage.
They are able to transform him back into a regular thinking wall and the wolf runs off and an animal
fight, and and they save they saved donald old. And
Y kim, do you wanna take us home on on the ending or do you have any comments beforehand? In the end here, we see the docks and ji won't away, and it turns out that an nephews will write all along, Jared is the genius. The think Barks worked and it even saved donald. From death, and
they say that you can never tell what wonderful things are going to be invented by crack as you call them. And during this sequence,
Donald doesn't say word. But I think I know what he is thinking. Because I've been thinking a lot about Jai the the relationship
between the drugs lately. Huey, might just be thinking that gyro might actually be genius. And maybe Jeremy's betty for the kids than I am. Am I a good parent? Maybe I better. And this yes gets too much for him. Then see the rabbit again. He acts a beg and say mister,
spare time for a bunch of carrots? It just snaps for donald. And it says, oh, shut up. And it's such a wonderful handing seen thinking
this final off page. It is
go
within just shouting at in innocent as rabbit
is is nothing
I wonder if that could be done today, and same thing with the beg, the rabbit because Al is, quite a sensitive thing here and canon eighties at least. How will you portray if the tray figures Al adult in comments? Just economics. Yeah. You were mentioning that to me before we started recording, and I thought that was fascinating because I don't think that would be a controversial
element
in the states. Some someone might correct me. I think if if they were dressed
like like, coded as homeless,
than than it might be. But I know that at this time in the states, you know, the idea of the tram the bag wasn't was a pretty common
comic trope. Barks has all kinds of comic burgers in the backgrounds of stories. As you said before, also, this story is a second store with the jira and Barks of course developed the character later on. So
instead of being this scribble w brand crack? Al stomach puts it? Later on, in comics and storage one hundred and fifty three the fishing story, Donald meeting in by and calls
fabulous and then day. Something must have changed here. Because
in the stores between
counts stores one hundred forty one and one and fifty three, other artist also trade ji and the Net use Al sort of the
assistant, etcetera. I didn't know that there were other
non Barks gyro stories that quickly. I I knew that, you know, he immediately he became a popular character. But didn't realize that it happened that fast. Yeah. We did. It did. The interesting. And they kicked Barks original concept because I guess, either
they saw themselves on the comments or the address who say, hey, we'll gonna a new character here here's how it works, and please do a story with him. Yeah.
It comes to stores one hundred and Severino one is again refer to a fabulous event
and I'll actually seek him out when he sell. So he no longer he's no longer the guy that you do who thinks he's cool, but he's not a friend of Donald. So what happened there? I I think that could it be that Barks for a Donald need friend? Because actually, he didn't tell any friends before. That's true. Yeah. Donald doesn't have a lot of people characters to just bounce off of. Right? It's it's interesting to me. He he must have just thought that he would work better not to be
antagonist
against him. I mean, sometimes he even gets lumped in, like, with the, like, donald duck family kinda of representations. You know, he's not a family member, but he's like just outside the family almost. Yeah. So, yeah. So I love the story. I think that this... As you said, it's a really neat ending.
I love how the rabbit is set up just beforehand to give it that little comic sting at the end, I I love Donald walk of shame where he just pee is soul came because he knows he was proven wrong. And
and and maybe he was proven wrong enough. That you know, that's where he ended up going with the ji and and and maybe for one Donald duck actually learned than something. Yeah.
But Have you seen the other version of this story? Are you thinking of the, like, the follow? To or in nineteen sixty,
there was four color one shot called. This is your wife, Downtown. Oh, yeah. The the one red
red, almost entire number. Yeah. That's right. I forgot about that. I'm sorry. I spoke over you. Tell me again, Tony Str. Tone str did Am so red withdraw redo version. Of this store. I have seen that. It's been... It's been many years. I wonder if I have the original because I I remember vividly reading it and being very puzzled.
But obviously, this is a story that really stood out if they used it for that element that that celebration of Donald Inducks. But if I if I remember right, when the laptop still rep that this is your live dot they substituted
the struggle version with the Barks version. Right.
Kind odd because the styles doesn't match but
I can see why they did it, but I might not agree that it was a good choice. Sure. I know that str bowl is is a bit divisive to many Barks fans. Which which is fine.
But but yeah,
So highly productive
and had so many different ink. So from time to time, you got a bad ink. I know that this is the lifetime doc. It's
swapping
my opinion.
But
sometimes when had the it could be real good. I... That's my opinion. Yeah. I I think I'd agree with that. I think he you know, he got to do a couple of of
collaborations or or, I guess, finish
with Bar, so barb, obviously,
I guess I won't say too much about struggle.
There are probably some some people really like him. Do you want to be to really hard no territory about this story. That's...
I'm a man with a podcast all about all about Carl Barks. So that that hits my sweet spot. If you look at the first page of this story, the very first page, you will notice this if you compare it with with the first printing on the fifties. The pages does not look the same. Because what you're looking at, if you're looking at the glass or reprint, for example, Right? Pages cut. And
it is...
So very
scan open from index. They've had a scan of
Walt disney con one forty one. Huey, will notice especially in the panel where the whole says
earth.
The docs have been red drawn and why am might ask. You have theory?
What which panel is it? First page panel five
man, I think that I read something about this.
Researching another episode and now it completely
escaped my memory. So so please tell us. Well, it was actually another doc fan pointed this out to me is some two years ago because I hadn't noticed before. And obviously, not the person's
doing their complete Barks collection here in Scandinavia,
but the thing is that back in the late sixties, when it was reprinted, they had cut the first page make room for the information about the publisher etcetera.
And then they remove Donald and the voice from,
they moved things to round the page, I'm on Gladstone. We're about to reprint this or another rainbow
for the car box library in the Us. The original proves we're not.
So they have had to sort of recreate
missing parts and try to make a look as close to the return as possible. But
the missed if few things did notice just a few things, So it has never been published again, I think since the Severino zero scandinavia eighty, the sixties in the Us wow. Is
originally drawn. That is a great detail. I appreciate that. But I recently made a
restoration picks for Pixel that a hope can be used in the future. Wow, that's awesome really cool detail. Nice. Thank you for sharing that.
I tell that it was know territory but I mean, I love.
And
if I can just with the one page, it's just just. Oh, yeah. What it what it thrilled to be able to have, you know, this this this is me trying to kinda have whatever involvement I can. In
in the Disney comics and in the in the Earl Barks realm. So I I appreciate getting to learn about that. So, you know, why don't we talk about Ji your a little bit. Right? He... This is pretty humble beginnings, but it obviously,
like stuck with people if if their commissioning stories
redoing this one, you know, fans remember this story and Barks obviously like the character enough to
to use him a lot. Yes. Of course. And even of the scandinavian Ducktales,
the the beginning in the sixties. We'd used a lot over here too. And it's still pop is in the new Ducktales.
Mh. Tv series for example. But, of course, it hasn't look the way it did in the beginning. Yeah. Know it was a bit chu,
and now it's so super slim and thin. It's true, he went through a pretty big meta or pretty pretty quick on, you know, he had a a pretty chu, like almost sloppy look to him. Yeah. But this is common for characters in their first appearance, you know, Scrooge Mcdowell and Gladstone Gander or other secondary care that got expanded and their look got refined
You mentioned that duck version of him. I I found that one really off putting.
I did not. That design, I I think it's I just basically been ninety to seventy to one model sheets or working can looks like that, and it is in the video to meet Al. I I just found his
characterization. He his his gyro has always been, like a very genuine
warm character like scatter range, but this one is is
outright mean, and that's fine. If you wanna have that kind of character great, but I... You know, I think the original Ducktales probably was was much more in in keeping with the characterization is as much as Mark's fans will will criticize the duck. I I think they got Gyro is pretty right. But but, yeah, the character Barks would go on to use him as as, like his own
main care and a lot of stories. Yeah. And,
I mean, he got his coming but for a while. A couple of one shots. I mean were there three or... Yeah. I don't remember. I don't I don't know that one off the top of my head. But most of those stores were written by a Big clock one of my others. Oh s.
Just through them. But
quite okay. Yeah. And I find it interesting that, like, there's this weird fact. Right? I might be getting this wrong. But my understanding is that sometimes he featured ji
because of this weird rule with the Us postal service. Oh yeah. Where they weren't allowed to... They wouldn't permit comic books to be sent through the mail that featured more than one story with the same character
as the lead. And so Yeah. Am I getting that right as far as you know? Yeah. Sure. Because used must backup stores in on Scrooge. Yeah. But a weird... What a weird convention that that that kind of Us postal service regulation would dictate comics. How about if we talk about... I I do like to mention
how this story is regarded by fans, I use Inducks as as a a representative for that. It's not perfect, but it's a pretty good way.
And according Inducks where fans can vote on the stories, this one is is a very highly regarded story. It has a seven point seven out of ten, which makes it rank one hundred and fifty four out of all the forty one thousand some Disney comic.
That are on the site. Yeah. And
they're really really good stories. Story. That tell so so much about the characters and it's also so Al introduction to to giant. So... Yeah. Deserves. I agree. I think it does deserve it think it may be a little bit inflated just because it's his, like, first appearance, but it's it's a memorable story. It stands out to me. And you kim, I'm enough of a nerd that I
made my own list,
like a little spreadsheet where I I pulled out the ten pager from that ranking.
Just so that I could see how they compared to each other. And and so I can tell you that this is the fifth most popular
okay. Of of Bark is ten pager. So pretty pretty highly relayed rated. The only the only ones that rank above it would be trouble with dimes,
Glad stone first appearance wintertime, wage,
stat,
spend f and and the tear of the vehicle boys. So a lot of first appearances there. But but I understand it because it's Al not only a scary story. It's also
story that triggers your imagination as a kid. I mean, that if you had a think box, if you to make your own animals think act like humans.
It's triggers the imagination. Absolutely.
Yeah. You're totally right. You know, some of Barks best
ten pages are like wish fulfillment ones, right? Where kids get to imagine themselves
in in the place of Hue dewey in Louis,
maybe being Gyroscope assistance and and helping them out and and having these pool adventures. Yeah. Awesome.
Have you seen the
the other store where the think Barks disappear? So I know that Don Rosa featured them in a story. Are you talking about that one or are you talking about Al? Bush. I wrote the store back in the nineties.
Or barrel politics. Awesome. Thrown by the car. I think it was published in the Us. It's see on shaking index. Yes. Back in ninety eight. No to six hundred and twenty two.
So he's obviously a fan. He remembered this the story and wanted to use that elements again. That's awesome. So that's that's a few creators. Right? Because because Rosa of course, was commissions
like specifically, Was that by you guys? Oh, I don't know. I'm know I think it might... I think it might have been E mod who commissioned, but I but I don't know. But, anyway, one of the European Publishers Commission Rosa to do
a sequel tying together a bunch of the nineteen
fifty
one...
Excuse me, Nineteen fifty two era stories,
including statues
spin drift.
This one, the think box ball, Christmas for Shack down. And was there another one in that story? I'm looking it up right now. It it sure is an story from two thousand and one. And I I just reread it.
It's it's a really fun sequel.
And and it it uses Bark pink boxes to kind of
retroactively
explain the origin of Gyro rose helper. Oh, it's been while it's already. So maybe I should read it again. Yeah. It's it's an awesome one. I I thought it was a great follow, I really liked it. It's a neat sc and Donald story that's really all about ji. So I I do like to mention when when there have been sql or follow ups, and I'm glad you mentioned I didn't remember
the ge one. I will have to take a look and see if I have that. I own most of the early number six hundred while Disney comics and stories. And then the... You said it was drawn by... Is... I always imagine his name was pronounced to v carr. Is that How do you say his name? You know, I don't have a clue.
Okay. I I just said the card, but that is probably a swedish
pronunciation?
That's that's neat. It's good... Yeah. It's been to... This one is obviously
really
held up very well because fans remember it very fondly. Any other thoughts? Oh, I don't wanna forget that I do like to ask people and I didn't I didn't remind you ahead of time. I'm sorry. I like to ask people if they have any favorite panels that really stand out to them from a story. A good question.
Let's split back through the Barks. Library and see if I can find it again. While you're looking, I I will just point out that
most of the pant panels that I consider my favorites and this one. They're pretty predictable.
It's the kind of payoff shots of the the
unveiling of the wolf and how frightening that wolf looks. Because that's just really I will say that it it scared me a little bit as a kid. I think this one is pretty scary. And then maybe especially the one of the wolf trying to create a fire as he prepares to rose stumbled over a spit because that that is both funny and frightening a same time. Yeah. If you ask me, the first power that would probably come to mind
would have been the dog revealing himself to be able Yeah I'm not even that it that is the best withdrawal or the most effective panel, but I sure remember it. Yeah. It's jarring.
But my my favorite Al must be the last time on page three. Oh, that's the name of Inducks. Should ever sync slow. Yeah.
You you see how devastated
doll is
when the nephew says that there his assistance.
Yeah. That's a great bit of
Mel drama.
The other one that comes to my mind oh a couple more. So the one... The one on the first one on the second page where the buggy just launches.
There's a great sense of motion to that one, I think. Yeah. And and I love the one with the rabbit with his hands hand out in that begging pasta. I think that's very funny. Yeah. And look Al panel one here.
Dull thinking Well it here this spam pump speech. Other the places, is it the fourth of July and that makes no sense whatsoever,
press and scandinavia
Right. So if I remember right, I think it was fireworks Barks
because it was published I think in January nine to fifty three, So it makes more sense. Oh, for, like, New Year's celebration?
Yeah. Nice. Yeah. That's a fun detail. Excellent.
Well, y king, do you have any any other inside or anything else you wanted to point out?
No. Just it was fun talking with you about this story, and
I hope we do it again. Soon
Absolutely. I'm I'm so grateful to you for joining me. I really appreciate. I had a lot of fun.
It is always great to get to talk to Duck fans and and people are welcome to reach out to us on the Barks remarks Facebook page. And I look forward
to look forward to our next episode. And
thanks again. Thank you.