Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of sc Mc Ducktales and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge con of all time
This episode is a ten page podcast all about one of his short stories, get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Hello. Welcome back to Barks remarks. This is Barks Sever, longtime Carl Barks and Disney comics fan,
I've got a returning guest here, who I think would characterize
himself as a longtime
superhero comics fan. Please
introduce yourself. I'm Ryan Bailey. I've been on before.
I
have had a subscription to
Marvel online for a long time. So I can read all I want. And
I I tally my totals of what I've read, the end of November of year, so it's not exactly on, but I'm comfortably over
five thousand issues by now of
mostly twenty first century marvel superhero comics.
Nice. So, yeah, you you're definitely a super superhero comic fan. And and the reason that I'm bringing it up is
because today we get to cover one of my favorite Carl Barks ten pager. Yeah. This is a new thing I'm doing Ryan. I'm calling Al the ten page podcast.
We're gonna be talking about
super snoop. Carl Barks, won and only real foray into a superhero story. You know, this this should be a lot of fun. We can talk about it from those different perspectives.
But first, just a little bit of background
detail about this story. Alright. So super snoop
is
as a ten page. This is one that did not appear in the four colors, which is mostly what we've been covering. This is in the the very long running
series Walt Disney's comics and stories, number one hundred and seven. Ryan, the notable thing about walt Disney's comics and stories is that for a long time, it was the
third longest running
comic book series in the United States.
Do you know what the
the two ahead of it would have been?
Probably
action comics and detective comics or something like that. Is that right? We nailed it in one. That's exactly. Right. So
unfortunately, that's no longer the case, you know, the comments not published. In North America anymore. There are very long running versions of it in places in Europe, I believe. But while Disney's comics and stories got got well into seven hundred issues. I don't I don't know where action comics
and detective comics are. Do you wanna remind us who is featured in those two titles?
Action comics number one,
famously is the first appearance of
superman.
I've got a stack of them and mint condition right here next to me. That the listeners can't see that, but they'll just have to take my word for it. Yeah.
So... Alright. So that's that's action comics.
And then detective comics
features the world's greatest detective that.
And
his his ward and small shorts.
Yes.
Was that was his first two parents like number twenty one or twenty two or something like that, I think that sounds right. Yeah. Yeah. No. No fact checking. No fact checking aloud.
Unless it's Disney and Ducktales.
And and listeners, if you know the answer, please shout it Al your phone right now. We will wait. Yes. Okay. Yeah. Okay. That's right. I do remember that now. Yeah. You're right. Yeah. Yeah. Clearly.
So,
you know, super snoop, just the title to me. It's it's obviously the perfect
ama
of those two heroes. Right? You've got you got soups in
in Sup. You got superman represented and and batman man. He's the detective. He's snoop. So I I think Barks did a great job of kind of announcing himself. Right? So the the fictional comic that the kids are gonna be reading in this is is basically meant to serve
as a stand in for
the the superhero comics
that annoyed Barks marx so much.
So
so that this is almost his response
to these comics.
Let's see. I'm I'm digress a little bit because I had mentioned which issue it was in. I should mention that it it came out in nineteen forty nine. Brian, can can you... I know you're more of a modern age twenty first century, but you you've read enough of them. You can probably give us some idea of what the superhero comics were like in nineteen forty nine. Right? In nineteen forty nine. Yeah. They would have been...
What's the right word?
Kind of kind of uniform
where all the heroes are boy scouts,
and they all mostly look the same.
With their square chin and
many of them have the same powers. They all have kind the same values
and
most... They they don't really do Barks yet by this point. So they're gonna be, you know, probably a new villain every issue or, you know, maybe a turning bill and if we're lucky.
And then
they'll,
you know, foil the villain by the end of the issue and then and then move on. Right. And and pretty wholesome. Right? Most of them weren't, like, doing kind of the edgy like, Ec comics stuff. Although they were they were violent, but Right. Yeah. It's gonna be
very old tiny,
you know, like, dip Tracy cartoons kind of style of you know, they'll suck it to the bad guys, but there's there's not going to be any unpleasant language or blood or probably even any, like,
witchcraft or anything like that. It's gonna be pretty
square, you know,
the the faces punching the heels
wrestling style, and
and that's that's what we get. Yeah. No. That sounds like a good description to me.
And I and I guess Al this point in super superhero comics, we we do have those two heroes
introduced, but like a lot of the most famous superheroes are not not even around as of nineteen forty nine. Right? Correct. Yeah. Yeah.
Spider man was was a glimmer and and his
soon to be to deceased parents eye. And
so, you know, at this point and lee's, right? Who who who is entirely responsible for his creation?
No. I
I don't know if the listeners are familiar, but Mark is being facet.
There are a number of other people who are more responsible
for his creation. Stanley famously would would be like what if we had a guy and he had wings or something Make that a thing. And
and then the artist would create the thing and then the person running that issue would, you know, kind of make a background for them and and make a whole story and so... So yeah, at this point, yeah, we have we have Superman we have batman.
I don't know if we haven't even have wonder woman by this point.
There's gonna be some captain America in what will eventually become marvel comics
name or is it kind of a modern character that would be around
human torch,
but not the fantastic
four version Correct. Correct. Yeah. The human torch at this point is an Android.
Who punches Nazis along with Captain America. So different torch, not to be confused with the other the other flaming person toro, who is also punching Nazis with Captain America, the two two flaming people on the same team. But yeah. So it it's it was a really good time to punch nazis.
It was a great time. There's...
There's really never a bad time. No. That's that's right.
Great time to be punching not.
So there... There's also a lot of comic book companies at this point, a lot of really minor ones and they're just kind of throwing out heroes left and right And so, you know, being like, here's, you know, toe man or whatever. They'll just throw that out and just kinda see what sticks. And, like, if the people. And they're like, we love Tony man or whatever then they'll get some more of that later. But in the meantime, they're just kind of being like, here's. Here's a new guy. He doesn't put up with evil and,
you know, he's got a cape and a mask. And
and otherwise, wears a suit and time which is also very common back then. So... But we you know, we would we would have the phantom and the shadow and, you know, a few other kind of full time sort of guys that you'll see in other forms later. Right. And those are usually serial.
Sure. Yeah. Those are the ones that I guess did get some real continuity.
Yeah. And that
that would keep billing for a long time. I mean, superman was in the newspaper.
Star Wars was in the newspaper.
Al lot of comics
kind of ran that way. Awesome.
Yeah. There there's not too much background trivia about this one just because of its nature as as one of his shorter
ten pager. Just
I would note that this one is very fondly remembered by fans. It is
much less of a gag story. I think it stands out because it really is like this little mini adventure. And and I mean, it's certainly funny and it's got some funny parts.
But yeah, this one is has definitely gotta be one of his most popular
ten pager.
So the the reason that Barks created this as I kind of alluded was that he he had a bit of an irritation with super superhero comics. Right? And I I think it was an issue of attention.
Because he is famously...
It's written that he never encountered a kid
reading one of his story. And that was very,
you know, that that that annoyed him. And I understand that.
Because these were definitely
Right? They were hugely popular, they sold very well. Obviously, if it... If walt Disney's comments and stories ran for more than seven hundred issues, you know, someone was buying them But when he was out in the quote wild, Carl marx only encountered these superhero stories.
So this is I would say a gentle
criticism
of these stories.
And
Yeah. Any any other comments Ryan before we cover the the story itself? No. I'm I'm sure I'm sure Carl marx is comforted knowing that
as our listeners know his fan base was much more attractive and smarter than everybody else. Wow.
That that pretty much goes without saying.
And and I mean, who even talks about
superheroes these days. Right? And completely they've completely slid out of the public consciousness
These these stories are are pretty much all anyone can talk about. Certainly in the United States.
Exactly.
Alright. So let's do this. Super snoop. Opens up with donald and counter his nephews,
reading a comic together on the couch and in the way that triplets do where they're they're always holding the same comic, all three of them.
And and it is a superhero comic. It's it's called super snoop and Donald is just
So annoyed. He he's enraged to see them doing this.
He he's basically
describing super snoop
as
superman. Right? Is what he sounds like to me. And, you know, he tells them...
I'm not I'm not too sure about the reason he gives for this like super snoop, but he says you know that no man could be that strong. Why don't you waste your time doing something useful? And so he he tells the F used to get out of the house, he needs them to do an errands to the drugstore
and get him some a bottle of d pepsi medicine.
Because this stomach is very acid, which sounded a little bit archaic to me, but You know. But, yeah. He tells them to spray out of the house. And and by the end of the first page the f user are dismissing him as an old funny daddy. That that's a great term. I think that we need to bring back
and and they can't believe that he doesn't think super snoop.
Isn't isn't the Bee needs. Yeah. I remember when I read this page,
it's struck me. And reminded me of
the nineteen eighty Ducktales. I remember there being
recurring conflicts in various episodes where the kids think that Uncle Sc is an old funny daddy or he thinks that they think he's an old funny daddy. And at the end, they assure him that he's not and they love him and they Al love each other and they're happy family. And I I don't think I've ever heard Donald referred to as an Old body Daddy. He doesn't seem that old in the comics. I mean, it's hard for me to tell any ducks age versus any other duck. Other than their size. But
but he seems like a young guy, you know, he's always doing like, manual labor and stuff like that. Right. Got like some... He's not a retiree Yeah. It's kinda weird to see him characterize
Al as out of step. But...
But but on the next page, you know, the nephews do that thing that kids do.
They wait till they're just out of sight and
and they stopped doing their chore, their errand or whatever, and they they sit down. And and you know, this this memory hits home for me. I I remember vividly having a pile of comics and waiting till I was just out of cider until so my mother left the room and and went right back to reading comments. But they they finish reading their their super snoop comic Ryan, do you mind describing how the the very complex plot involves itself in in Yes. Just.
And
Barks is parity here is is
probably not that far off the mark.
But
super Sn is buried under seven trillion tons of rock in a dynamite coal mine, which is probably a pretty good percentage of the earth itself.
Right.
They've gotta see how he gets out of that jam. And then he flexes his mighty muscles and lifts the whole mountain range like a cellar door.
Al one does and walks out. Yeah. This that part really cracks me up right? Because this this feels like Barks
basically
criticizing the the superhero comics for for all having the same sort of paper thin
plot that is essentially always resolved by by the superhero flexing their mighty muscles
and doing the the basic thing. I'm sure some of them
did avoid these tropes but
but probably a lot of those golden age superhero comics were a little bit same same. Yeah. Yeah. It was it was a developing medium.
And
I love this second half of the second page where they encounter when they characterized as a messenger boy.
It's this
incredibly aged man with a beard that that literally drags on the ground.
And they just with a straight face. They're like, it's a messenger boy. And and he tells them, you know, his Barks killing them, he just can't complete the delivery of the package that he's got. And, you know, the Nephews want to offer to finish the delivery for them, but he cautions them. No. You can't do it. It's a it's a very dangerous
package. Also his cap
is entitled wi union. That's who he works for.
Yeah. That's great. Instead of Western Union, that's a nice little site guy. Thanks for putting that out.
So can I say I... This guy, you know, they're they're reading the comics, and and I'm sure something is going to come in in real life to parallel what the comics are. And this this thousand year old plan.
This thousand year old man shows up with a mysterious package, and he's like, Hey.
Oh, I guess he I guess he isn't offering to let them deliver.
But it's it's still this point. Yeah. And so I'm like, I'm like, there's something weird have here. This is secretly zeus or or something else is going on. You know, he... There's... This guy's an alien. There's some kind of deal going on with this guy
because
There's no real... He's on a bicycle. He's not driving a delivery truck. He's a bicycle messenger delivering a package and he is one past so So
this was a red herring for me. This threw me completely off.
Not that way you expected from a an air sat superhero origin.
Right. Excellent. So
the the nephew the the messenger her boy.
Feels that he has no choice, but to trust them because this his ninety seven year old back is just hurting him too much. And he tells them to check the slip of paper.
And they read it, and you mind telling us about the the address they have to deliver to Ryan. They have to take it to cosmic energy testing laboratory
at thirty three secret Drive,
which is is classic. I mean, that's probably one digit off from from... I'm gonna say the Hulk's origin story. Right.
Right. Right. I I smell gamma rays or Yes. Yeah. Alright. So so they had...
They had to do the delivery
and they decide to leave the comic book that their at their house since it's on the way. And and when they get to their house, they realize they forgotten
mcdonald's medicine
And I guess they fear his wrath, so they decide that they've gotta... They've gotta go take care of that immediately
and they faithfully leave that package
on their table,
which is convenient for Donald, he thinks because he's feeling worse and worse
as he's working in the backyard, and then he notices the package and he he very reasonably
assumes that they must have gotten back and left the package there. Yeah. We also have on one frame here. We have a
bird bath as the kids are walking past their house outside, and there's a bird just totally kicking back in there the way the way
anyone... Any human would after a long, hard day of work, And now the kids are in bed and they're they put their favorite chill on, and they just get in the bath, lean back and close their eyes and put their feet up and and that bert... That bird knows how to relax.
Yeah. Like as in many comics, I appreciate
the the
detailed touches in the background.
Yeah. I love Barks site gag. They're they're great and
a very a very memorable one.
So, you know, the this next page is great. This is where it kinda kicks into gear. Donald
grabs the bottle
and he he doesn't see any directions.
So so instead of bothering to dos, he just kinda kinda gold it down with a nice sense find
Al.
And and we pan to the the wrapping paper
did have some directions.
That he overlook.
And, you know, it's it's in cursive. It's a little bit tricky to read on the panels. Do you mind telling us what it but it conveys Ryan. Two scientists in charge of cosmic testing,
caution, these liquid isotopes are or to be given only rats.
In theory, they'll make a rat as strong as a horse. You of very sparingly
professor,
ion Cosmic is the name of the person who has written this letter,
which, you know, that's a good... That's a good name for a boy or girl really, You know, if if any of your listeners have a kid,
you're going to be having a kids soon, put this one on the list. Yeah. You can't go wrong.
So, you know, a great setup here and and Donald
finds the flavor of it revolt. He wraps it back up. He intends to send it back. And by the second half of this page, we we do see that he he's feeling
great. You know, he's radiating with
little squiggly lines that suggest how good he's feeling. He he decides he's gonna head back out to the garden
and and get back to weeding. And he grabs that doorknob to open the door and he just rips it right out of the door. He's very puzzled at this. So he he's very annoyed. He takes it to me that the house is just shot construct and he throws it to the floor
where it crashes right through into the basement.
Yeah. Yeah. Although
I thought the cosmic energy testing laboratory was kind of a silly name, but now that I see that it's probably named after
the head scientist professor Ion Cosmic.
It makes sense. It's just like, you know, Mcdonald's or whatever. You just named it after whoever who owns the place. The miss no. It's actually a peninsula.
Exactly.
Alright. So, you know, Donald, by the next page, Donald still hasn't figured out that something is up. And so he goes to push the door open. He knocks it right down and he he he is donald duck, so he's getting pretty mad at this point and he goes to kick the door and anger.
And the door goes flying half a mile as he says. And at this point, he he's starting to puzzle things out and he kind of flexes looks Al himself. And I I love how this page ends
you know, this this is very... This feels very golden age superhero to me, Ryan you to tell us about about the situation on the end of the page.
A little girl's doll is caught to under a steam roller that appears to be
unattended
mh.
And she's just crying that her dolly is trapped under the steam roller. I also Also wanna add
this frame here where Donald is looking at his muscles and going. What is this? Am I imbued with some kind of incredible power that I didn't have before, you know? The look in his eyes that communicates
this wonder at his new found abilities or whatever. This is timeless.
This is a staple of the medium from the very first... Probably from Gil
to
to...
I'm gonna guess Venom one the movie.
But there's there's even even modern superhero fans make fun of the point in every superhero movie where you have the origin and someone has to stop and they do something incredible, and then they have to stop and look at their hands as the their hands are about to explain to them what is going on? But
Nope. They're still just hands. They look like hands it's just the same hands you had earlier except stronger now or they shoot things or whatever.
There's no reason for anyone to do that and yet every single person knows does. Yeah. Barks may he may not have liked the superhero tropes, but but he certainly
he got them in this instance. You have to follow him. You know, he didn't write the rules. You just have to follow the rules.
Right. Right.
So so this is great. You know, by by the next page, Donald explaining that, you know, I can't get your little dolly out from this steam roller. You need a derrick for that. He goes to demonstrate. And un.
He he lifts the steam roller with a single finger.
And
he thankfully, he doesn't freak out too much because the little girl is right underneath the steam roll.
Why would you call that part of the steam role or it's not a wheel. Right? It's not tread.
Whatever Don't know. The big the big press on the steam roller is And, you know, at this point, he's figured it out. He's he knows what's funny. He's strong. He is super strong. And and I love his first
deliberate act, Ryan, Do you mind telling us what he does to to kind of, you know, wear in his powers
he he, like, rework the steam roller in some way.
It's hard for me to tell what all is going on, but he he takes the kind of cylindrical tank on the top and makes it round,
and then he takes the the round kind of press on the front and on the rear and makes them square so that they're not wheels anymore.
He plants a pot of flowers.
And then
he adds
like a seat right there. That was not there before. Yeah. Yeah. I think so. There's Al there's like, Al seat with a steering wheel in the back now with with new handles and everything up in the back. He's completely reconfigured the entire thing. And I I can't tell what the brown kind of twisty thing is that's going around from underneath and around we. Right. It's, like braid or something. And it's... And it's totally pointless and tokyo. It looks like maybe tree branches or something twisted together. I'm not sure what that is. But my favorite part is his thought to himself. That steam roller operator is going to be mildly surprised at my first job he thinks.
Actually I laughed out loud at that one because that was pretty good. I imagine the Steam roller operator coming out like
It's interesting.
Getting on and resuming his steam rolling with his
square steam.
And and then the best part is on the next page, He just thinks better of it. He reconsider,
and and he reverts it back as though nothing happened.
And, you know, he's he can fly at this point. We got the slam bam
introduction
to his superpower
And and I've been having a lot of fun with this story and and chuck at it, but I love this page. This page as
just a presentation of his powers,
you know, where we must be halfway through it
at this point. So this story is happening at a break neck pace, but the art on this page as a a showcase
for what these
isotopes can let him do is is just stunning.
You know, he flies leaving the steam role in the distance.
You wanna tell us about the next panel?
So he just smash us through Brick wall
I guess just to show that he can. Yeah.
Then he takes a bite out of a steel gi
from, I guess, some kind of skyscraper that's under construction.
I have to say if I had those powers that would not have occurred to me to attempt.
Right.
He zooms under the ground, like a jet propelled gop, which seems very... Bugs bunny is certainly already doing that by this point in history. Right? Oh, yeah. He must have been taking a a wrong turn at Albuquerque at this at this point. Exactly.
And then blow down whole forest with his breath just as Super super was doing with armies at the beginning. That's been the actual issue. Yeah.
Some cow is
displeased at this development. Yeah. But And then he runs he runs faster than the speed of light, and and we're made to believe that he's he's probably gone somewhere in the American Southwest because he passes a cactus
with a a very funny on
in in English, It's at least written as z And and, you know, by the end of the page, he's noted that no one has been able to see his great feat here. And he wants to keep it, you know, private. While he kind figures out what he can do. And and, Ryan, I just... I love this page in the next couple of pages that follows because this is like, so
I think accurate to what a real person
would do. I mean, maybe not maybe not biting the skyscraper or like, it's sponge cake, but, like,
so many of the comics
depict them as, like, figuring out how to immediately harness their powers for good. I feel like at least a lot of the older ones. But you know, a real person would probably just mess around for a long time seen what the heck they could do. Yeah.
I feel like
there's an example on on my mind, but I can't think of it now before they just mess around
I mean, in the in the, like, Spider movies, you know, I do think they do a job of showing him
like, having
fun. But but I I feel like so many of these origin stories don't kind of play around with that.
Let's see if I can do this. Let's see what happens when I do this.
Yeah. Yeah. The that first that first page. Again, I love that first page where he's purposefully
exploring his powers. And then the page that follows the the stakes really get upped into, like, the cosmic scale And again, it's super over the top and and the art, I I think is just beautiful.
You know, this is some of some of the best of his art during his his golden age period because he he leaps higher than the moon He ties two comet tails together.
He he lifts a sunken ship from its ocean grave and he turns a mountain
inside out
exploring the the hidden vein of gold inside. And can you take us home on this page?
And then give the right of way to nothing that swims runs our flies. He seems to be head butting and eagle. Yeah.
Who is coming the opposite direction,
the eagle know now to just get out of the way of any Ducktales wearing caps.
Coming coming us opposite way. And
so... Yeah. He decides to float home and surprise the kids and then suddenly loses his powers
falls helpless to the ground and and plop onto the ground. Right. And and on the next page, there any other comments for this one?
Of course,
anyone who
knows about astronomy, you know, comet tails are just kind of a collection of dust particles and
and gases
and they cannot physically be tied together.
So
I think this comic is not very plausible in real life Barks. I I think that just makes it even more impressive trick.
Okay.
Oh.
So on the next page, you know, he's he's puzzling. He's landed in his own yard, and he's puzzling over what's gone wrong. And he's kinda,
you know, searching his memory, and he realizes oh, it's that medicine. It's that funny tasting stuff in the bottle. So he he races back for it. He gu it down again. And then we transition to the Nephews who are just getting home and they're kind of
kinda rehash the day and and how how silly it was that Un donald seems to have believed that they believe in the superhero stories.
And and they're, you know, acknowledging that they know it's possible.
No kid is that dumb to think it's real.
It's a nice setup for what's about to happen. And and I think it's also maybe an acknowledgment Barks that, you know, these aren't my favorite medium, but but they're harmless.
These are just kids having fun reading. And the nephews when they get home, they're greeted with Donald. And do you mind just reading verbatim what he how he greet them. High kids. Meet super snoop. The mightiest mortal that ever tried the assad. This is how he's speaking. Certainly. Sn sn. Wait. Tell me the biggest thing super snoop ever did, and I allowed do it. Yeah. And and nephews are are immediately like, u, what's what's wrong with donald. They they assume he's feeling poorly and
So so Donald,
you know, he he gets them to say, one of the feat that Super Snoop could do is that he could they tell him he could bust through walls like their tissue paper, and he says that's that's sis stuff, you know, kind of an outdated a little insult there, but he he runs straight for the wall and he collide
with a great artistic
sp. And he's not days. He's asking, he he he doesn't know what day it is. He doesn't know where he is. And we we just transitioned to the nephews letting him recoup brad on the couch. She telling each other that, you know, he's not silly. He doesn't remember a thing since last Tuesday. And so they're kind of figuring out that they must have they must have been a bad influence he must have seen their super snoop comics and they decide that, you know, they can't trust him with the comics around, and kids should know better than to leave fantastic stories
lying around with our parents can read that. And the last panel, the stain is that he chuck the comic right into the trash. So I mean, I think that's just a great a great little etch sketch ending to explain how Tunnel not gonna remember this, how the story is gonna end. I I love this. This is one of my favorite ten pager
Thoughts on the last page thoughts on the story overall Ryan? Yeah. I think it was interesting after all of the super cosmic things that he did,
The feet that the demand of him is, like something that real life For Could probably do, you know? Just.
And I thought oh, that's kind of a small ask, you know, from from someone who who just jumped over the moon or whatever he did. So
ironically, if they had said, leave earth's atmosphere by jumping, you know, he he probably would not have been hurt. He would have just jumped to another sidewalk.
And they're like, oh, that's odd. You know? Would've have told them I swear. I was doing all these crazy things earlier. You should find the little girl who saw me lift up the steam with one finger.
She's the only witness to anything in this whole story and I like that she was really at that little age that that age that no one would even believe her. Right? Because she like about three or four, maybe five Yeah.
So
I I like this story a lot. I laughed out loud at multiple points, including the
the twist ending where comics are bad influence on adults and Yeah we need to throw them away so they don't do stupid things. I thought, you know, a lot of people try to do parodies of kind of classic superhero stories and
most of them are terrible.
Because they don't really get it. Or or there they just know, like, one thing about superman or something, and
this was actually a really good kind of send up of the of the genre at least at this time period. Yeah. I I feel like I feel like for someone who is very annoyed by the Superhero comics that Carl Barks actually really got them. Yes. Yeah. I think so. Yeah. Know and when and he even got, you know, you even have the nephew saying, you know, we know that there are not are not really people like this. We just like reading about these married suit types who can do anything and conquering evil and everything. Right. Yeah. I think it would have been interesting to see
maybe to see his take on one who knows.
But, yeah. I I think in the end, it feels like kind of a gentle send up. Right? Because, like, it it really just is he's annoyed by them. You know, he doesn't like that they out his comics,
but I don't think he actually beg grudges kids reading them at all.
Yeah. Yeah. What do you how do you think this stands up compared to other superhero origin stories? Did this remind you of any on
reminded me of almost all of them.
The the like the like, here's some liquid isotopes.
Okay.
But this is actually more realistic than whatever vita arrays are, which is what they shot captain America with that's right.
And the Hulk coup is just
beamed with the kind of
raise that would instantly kill a man. Yes. Yeah. The kind of thing that that are shot out by black holes in space and if any of them struck earth,
Earth would be completely sterile forever.
But... Yeah, all of these kinds of stories of, you know, I was hit by a meteor or I found some ancient artifacts or I you know, I got a an alien
ring or I find out that I am an alien.
The the idea of
kind of the modern day where someone's gotten some
surgery or there's some kind of anything that's a little more scientifically plausible is very very new. Know in the old days in the old days they just kind of used long words, and they're like, these long words gave these people powers.
Yeah. They don't they didn't really bother
going too deep into the origins back then. Because because as you said, they were really throwing these superheroes
against the wall just to see what would stick. Yeah. And and, you know what? If you're if you're forty years old and and it's nineteen forty nine,
and you want talk about atomic science, you didn't learn anything about that in earth science or high school chemistry like we did. Nobody knew that except Albert einstein back then.
Yeah. So Very you. It's it's it's kind of... I mean, it's basically magic. You know, if you're if you're an adult at this period, Yeah. Absolutely.
So so I love this one. This is definitely like if if you ask me to to recall one of his ten pager,
This is definitely one of my favorites.
And the the community as a whole definitely agrees because this one is for for one of the ten pages very well regarded. You know, this one has...
This one has a seven point six out of ten on index, which is good for two and thirty ninth out of all forty one thousand some
Disney comics. That are that are ranked. And and, you know, that doesn't sound too high, but really, there's some inflation with the the adventure stories compared to the ten pager like the they just they stand out more in people's memories. There are a fewer of them. So they're overall rated a lot higher.
But if you look at his ten pager,
I I haven't, like, tallied them all up, but this this is roughly his tenth or or fifteenth or so.
Best regarded of his ten page short stories. So very well remembered, this one was well remembered enough that Don Rosa
later on,
we'll make an adventure length sequel
to this story.
Where he he goes through basically the same experience.
They they he kinda replace the story beat for beat. It's
it's a pretty good one. It's a solid sequel. It's not one of my favorite rosa stories, but he
he plays around a little bit more. You you can tell that Don Rosa is also
very annoyed at the...
At the popularity of superhero comics. And I mean, I I think rightly so in a way because he was, like publishing in the very early nineties, which was kind of the dark ages for superhero comics.
Yeah. So I think to be to be routinely out sold at least in the United States by by some of the direct and junk that was hung out. And I say this is someone who read and enjoyed superhero comics in addition to these at that at that point. But... Well, if if if Don Rosa wanted to sell some comics in the early nineties, his ducks needed to have more pouches and more belts with buckles on them. Just around their thighs and just all over their bodies for no discernible reason. That's that's what is awesome, Mark. Yeah. What what's that guy's name? Who is that dude? Is that I'm I'm thinking of like rob Life elves probably. Oh. Yeah. Yeah. Oh yeah. Thank goodness, missy he didn't. So, yeah. This one this one's well remembered, Rosa made the Sequel.
I think it holds up great. I think there's a lot of fun. If so...
Any final thoughts? Any anything else you wouldn't say about this fun ten page or ryan? Think it makes sense that the
twenty five or thirty page ones
get higher ratings because you get more space to kind of raise the stakes and kind of develop what's going on and maybe some more peril for the heroes
and more kind of conflicts for them to have to figure out how to solve.
And so, you know, this one you pretty much
introduced the the weird thing that's going on kind of soaking it for a couple pages and then and then resolve it quickly with the the gag at the end and and just kind of gotta get in and out. And I think for the amount of space, it's it's very good. Yeah. I I totally agree. Thanks. Thanks for saying that. Because that that's worth worth highlighting for this one. You know, it's it's such a tight story, and it just... It just gets in and it gets out. Doesn't overstate it's welcome. He he could certainly have punched this one up into an adventure length story, but
it's so tight and it Barks so well. I'm I'm glad.
I think this this is pretty close to a perfect ten pager to me. Awesome. Well, thanks again. As always for joining. I I really appreciate it. I'm having fun doing a handful of these ten pager and
we'll We'll hope to see you again soon.
Give us drop us the line. If you have any comments about super snoop Barks remarks at g dot com. We're on the Facebook page. Awesome. Thank you. Yeah. Thank you.