When
Thanks for joining us for our Halloween themed episode to the ten page podcast.
After getting the trigger treat ear where stuck in your head. I just wanted to make a quick note that this episode has just about five minutes of a little bit of echoing
dialogue
before we figured out how to address it. So, you know, yeah, hopefully, you won't notice it. But
it shouldn't last too long. So enjoy the episode. Welcome, back to Barks remarks. I'm Mark Sever, a Grown man who enjoys dot com,
and I really love Halloween.
As well and talking about Halloween,
and I'm very excited today to have a couple of guests on who can talk about halloween and dot comics as we
discuss a couple of
ten pages or at least close enough to ten pager. For this
episode of the ten page
podcast,
we're gonna be talking about the stories H Goblins
and With Willie, but before we do that, my guests today, one one is new and one is returning. I've got Tim Arts and Henri
Who
who are Dutch comic artist.
And I am just always so thrilled to have duck artists on to talk comics so you guys thank you very much for joining me. Why don't you introduce yourselves and and let us know about what you do with the comics and maybe a little bit of your relationship to to Halloween.
Tim, since since you're joining us for the first time, can can you talk about your work? Yeah. So I'm
disney artist from Netherlands. I do other comments, but mostly this. I've been drawing since
I've been drawing them since
two thousand and nine. And on and off again during my studies I kept kept trying the docs. And at the end, I thought that when I just make my job of it because... Yeah. It's it's what I do anyway. So I just kept on drawing and finally got accepted to draw comics for the touch done quickly. And
a few years ago, I actually got asked to do some digital findings for the new Ducktales,
Shell. So in some episodes, you'll see my work during flash.
So that was really cool. I... Can I let me interrupt? Are those the the ones that are kinda
stabilized to look like the the Barks, spot style paintings? Yeah. They
they're still in... The the characters look like the the those from the show. Right.
But the the colors and the
atmosphere supposed to be Barks like as as good as I could get it. So, yeah, That was are mine. And as really proud those. So... Yeah you should be proud of those. Those are those are really good. I I watch through the whole series which I felt was like pretty uneven but but that part was, like, some of the stand out. Yeah. That's awesome. Again, I I've I really enjoyed the, like, throwback that was in that series. And and you had some really
really neat art. I saw the the digital paintings that you mentioned online. You also did this really cool stamp series
for the for a Netherlands, like it sounds like a social welfare program, but it was really cool. Yeah. Thanks. Yeah. Those are our
indeed a good cause,
thing here and Netherlands.
Condition,
dating back to the ninety. Twenty something. But it's like
school children they go and sell these stamps
door by door the door.
And the money goes through a good cause and the good cause is different every year. But mostly it's in the the life of children, and they can trying to make them better. Right They they tried to partner up with a different
Ips. So this year was donald doc and I did draw them last year for another Ip, which is Tom,
but that's not known
of right. Yeah. I think I know my name. But I'm not really familiar with it. So you've been... You've been a Barks a long time Barks fan. Right? Yeah. I I have.
When was it kid, I
I had to do... I had to go into surgery for
little tubes in my ears or something.
But my parents stopped like oh this is my parents they felt sorry for me and they they said like, oh, let's just give them a subscription to donald doc extra. It's like the dollar weekly, but another monthly
publication. And
with that subscription, I got a... I've always got a a gift. This was like an and Al I full of Barks
stories. And I immediately fell in love with those.
Nice. And and with Willie was actually one of those stories in that album. Excellent. And then
excited to to join join for that one. So... Yeah. I love it when people are really animated about specific story. Well well, thanks again for joining. And then how about over to your colleague? Right? You guys get to work together occasionally? And and?
Yeah. So this year, on the back of the the touch menu, there's every week there's a one pager. And for of twenty twenty two, we got asked to to draw them, but we don't collaborate on them with we withdraw them separately. But I also have another job month demo ten.
How does it He's been drawing like, two three quarters of them, and that's been drawing a quarter of them. But we also
we also we both draw,
and we've also collaborated actually on a book and the bo where already split the drawing So where where I do the characters and into enjoy the background. So we also actually work together, but our these comments have been separate so far. So we always... Every time we have sketches we sent them to each other and give share feedback. I think there's even there's even one word... But I couldn't figure out some Barks so do like
yeah Imagine that. But that's awesome.
That's something we haven't mentioned, but we... We've now chatted for quite well already, I think. Maybe since I was fourteen or something like that, we were on a very dirty tall doc Disney covid four. So that's where we where we got to go each other and so we go back a long time we're both wanted two. Become economic artist
to schools that we about to do it. Otherwise, then we feel really bit.
Yeah. That is great that you guys got to come up together. And now now I gather that they don't... They don't give you guys creative creator credit in the Netherlands. Right? Yeah. There's a tiny tiny thing taking in the front of the magazine or if you use magnifying glass, you can see a list of names.
The people then who got hired locally, so I think for example, stay have
economic and there those art aren't listed at all. And it also doesn't say who did what. So... Yeah. So you think it's alphabetically also. So it's.
Does that is that a source of friction I mean, think it depends on the art...
I think most people would refer to good cards, and I think
third I don't think it's really a source of friction though. There's even within the magazine, I think, they're still reconsider whether should put credit. I don't know if it's just... It's it's always been like this and it just never started doing it And you know reason. It's way certain
and right or to change it. But then I do notice when when it does get we published in different country and our name is there. I would like
Yeah. Do you feel a little exposed?
Yeah. Yeah. I mean I'm clearly yeah a rock story.
The Us
of Publish one.
Well... It's... I think it's important to give creators their credit. But but I I understand feeling conflicted about it. Yeah what... It's it's it's mainly when... When I was reading as a kid, I wanted to know who what Because, of course, if you're a fan, you can tell the sales a apart with many it took me... Well basically to to funds
index which is also when I was fifteen or something but I whole childhood That definitely had favorite art and there was just no way of knowing who they were. So right person always did prefer. The one exception is called Barks because for Barks, they... Not when it's in the weekly magazine, but
nurses this whole that album that Tim talked about, then he got as a gift. That's this series which is the title is the best stories of the.
They're pretty clear about it and it's it's only Barks And with this Al series, I personally went I was little I had two or three of those albums, and I that the exact same one that didn't it. So I also...
West is also one of the first going I I read must have been five years old or something. Nice
Good. I'm I'm glad this is one that has some some deep meaning to you guys.
But but what about Halloween it's self. Does that have any real meaning for you guys? Nope.
For me,
only recently, I think, it's it's starting to to come up here. And
I've been following some...
I don't know if you know the angry video game or. Yeah. It's James Rolls. And
is Mike Met, and he's also a Barks fan. So Oh neat. What have Anyway, he he had this series where he he talked about
sp movies
from the thirties and then I Al all of stuff. And that kind of got me into the mood of of Halloween during this season. So Yeah. Recently
last five, six years, I've been getting into a bit more. Yeah. I mean, I also... I... Of course, halloween is because I have a lot of friends from the Us and I'm online a lot. Of course, it's impossible to miss Halloween regardless.
Right. But... But it's been big boy which American movies and American Tv shows. So they're going to know Al lean at some point. And I think I would send the process ten years or so. It's really become... It's very much become thing over here as well. But
still I've never been triggered treating or I don't... Still in my town at least and also I moved to amsterdam with there also never really saw that people decorating their houses. Is not a fitting is actually fine and I think about ten years ago. One single time
in our neighborhood to try to do an event and they might check or treating and kids came at the door and my mom opens and she didn't know what it want.
So I like entered it covered and found too Gan, because I knew what this one right. Literally didn't know what Halloween was ten years ago, so that kind of says a lot about how how big debt is culture. But Right. Well, As far as cultural
exchanges, I think it's one of our better ones because it's it's a great holiday. So It'll be fun to hear your thoughts as the folks who don't, you know, observe the holiday directly, but but are very close aware of it. I looked up before before we started, I I was curious how Took or treat Barks come like was translate in the netherlands.
Yeah It's they call it for years fist, which means
spring festival,
which is not even a fitting
time.
They just came up with something random. So you guys as mentioned, we're we're covering a couple of
a couple of Halloween ten pages today. It part of the podcast is that I really like to do the big, like adventure stories chronological.
And so I just I can't really time things like trick treat to Halloween.
But that's why it's nice to cover the ten pages because I just felt. Free to kinda throw them in wherever and group them them dramatically. And and these are a couple of bark like better spooky stories. But but if you're looking for a real halloween
story, you know, you should check out Trick treat. It's it's not one of our best just because it was adapted from the cartoon
kind of hand adapted but it's it's still Al lot of fun. And and it's not without its like controversy
because apparently, it was, like too scary when barb initially turned it in.
So So they required him to, like, remove a lot of the original stuff that he'd added for its first printing. And And that left him needing to kinda make up this shortfall in pages.
And and so they asked him to do this additional
short story, which is the first one that we're gonna talk about called H goblins.
Apparently, Barks was not very pleased about today because I think they didn't even pay him for the pages
That that that he was required to leave out. But
to me, this one kind of... You can kinda tell that it's a little bit it feels a little bit half baked. Just a little bit weirder than your average Barks story.
But that it is fun. So a little bit of the background
because it was that replacement,
story. It was published in the same issue in the United States and donald dot twenty six.
Technically, it's a nine pager, not one of our ten page podcast stories but close enough. And it is this came out in November of nineteen fifty two was the cover date for it. And
I you mentioned Inducks
earlier, Henri Eureka.
I use that site. Heavily, of course, it's where users can find information about the comics.
And then review stories as well. So we'll we'll check in on the reviews. It is kind of a middle of the road ranked story on index it gets a seven point two out of ten, which is ranked one thousand two hundred and twenty out of all, like, forty two thousand stories on induction. And
there there are a few notable things
about this story. You guys... I'm Sure you guys noticed that it's one of Gyro very first appearances. Right? Yeah. When he didn't let me just weight.
He a little this first experience in the second.
But right or or he's wearing a fat suit or something. It's... Yeah. That's a very p
But
disclosure this is... So the other comment I'm very familiar with, but this was my first time reading this one. I actually didn't know there was another story where jo was still
I used. So that was also very jarring to read It is a little jarring to see pug like first character design version of Ji. This is his third appearance.
After...
Oh, well, Henri, you you and I talked about his first. Which was just a quick little cameo
in
Glad stone terrible secret. You can tell that he got rid of his Ticked after afterwards.
Right.
Yeah. That would have that would have helped him keep keep the weight off. Well, for whatever reason, Barks decided to make him more spelled And it's obviously been a very popular character design. And only other notable thing I noticed about this is that this is like it's a it's build Al a Donald Ducktales story, but it says feature Hue doing Louie, and really, they're they're the stars of this one. Yeah. And the version that the title doesn't even... The title is just the the title characters and here we do we all this mentioned.
Right. But what I what I wonder about this come again we'll will go through it
other than than the effect that he had to replace it It really felt to me this this story felt to me in a similar way, like, the the golden and Christmas tree, for example, it felt like somebody else gave him a promise that it that it had to involve goblins
because it feels a bit unrelated to the rest of the story. It could have been told without the government's in it probably.
Exactly. But I mean I for that attention Severino. And Go has kind of a a weird
connotation in in in American English know that I could exactly define what Goblin means, but like, it doesn't feel like an invisible
presence. To me. Yeah So this this feels more like it would match the description of, like, fairies or
or something. Or the greenland things.
Yeah. Yeah. I I know this this god by kelly, I think, where there's
on a plane and they do same but... Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. It definitely matches Kelly's ground ones. Those are fun little. Again.
Characters.
Yeah. So... But... That's also...
Because we we're... I think tim missed dutch one as well. So I'm I'm reading both the English introduction at the same time with the thing of go is that there's actually no direct translation for the word. So if you were translate to Dutch, they they use the word that you would use for ghost or genie in English? They're put them. It would... Then you would want to describe an actual goblin, like the the criteria would think of which just a different word than that. So like, it would maybe be like an an over or cobalt or something, but those would definitely not be invisible. So it's already right strange that the from the get goes so in dutch
Jar is basically talking about ghosts.
So yeah. That makes more sense. Wanted to add to henry like, like, Eagle spirits is is sort of the... Yeah. Yeah. I think any of those terms, like spirits or imp or even ghosts would have worked.
So so how about are you guys ready to go into the the kind meat of the story. Sure. Excellent. So I'm gonna
describe the action
on each page and give you guys a a break in between to kinda chime in with your thoughts. So this one, H Go
opens
with
the boys, the nephews and encountering
ji, and he's in the midst of kind of a a mini panic. He's telling them to get back
away from his... What's gonna turn out to be his workshop.
And he he has them duck behind the bank to to avoid any danger.
And he goes through this sequence
of, like, things to be careful of First, it's in English. It's flying hex rays,
and then
his electronic Adams sw
There there's some very neat are showing the effects of whatever this, like, weird experiment that's going on at his workshop
is... I I like the opening. I think it's pretty strong. It's very intriguing
And and by the end of the first page, He tells them it's safe to come out and see his new invention.
And he
describes it as his greatest aid to mankind's to date a goblin
foil. Tim. Yeah. It's it's it's fun he,
like he he he doesn't show what he's inventing. It's like
already in the unseen
world or something. So kinda sets it up for.
So that's that's really cool.
What do you think Enrique? Yeah. It's it's a great setup up for it could even be the opening of a big adventure comic. But I like how he gets just right into the action. And right. And also also found interesting with Barks always does especially since Drivers you that he
driver comes running in and the nephew say, it's shi the fabulous and inventor. I just noticed in dutch version. They don't bother to say that and all they're just like, oh, it's dry.
He's already so established at that point that they didn't feel the need to translate the that sentence. Right. But... It's it's definitely because it's a new character, but I feel Barks always tries to set up the characters in way, so you can
understand who they are without knowing the character. Right. He does some really... He does some quick signaling which I guess, was necessary since it's his like, second real story. Right. Onto to the to the next page,
we go into
Gyro workshop
and he's showing off the invention, which is kind of it's a really great panel, that first one
where where shows us the go foil. It's in the midst of this
really wonderfully.
Illustrated range of gadget
that's that's labeled with some nice little site gag It's just suspended from a pole
in in in the midst of all these raised blasting Al it. And, boy, Barks gives us some very quick x exposition
about what this is. He Chi
explains that it is the first ever device. Made to out Goblins,
and we get this very brief moment. This should be like a world view shattering moments. Right for for the Nephews.
This should call everything
about their existence and their theology and everything
into question, but but we got this goofy nine page gag story, so it's not what it's about. The Nephews take a quick moment to bog over the fact that there are really goblins
and ji explains... Yeah, they're just invisible
a cause Al all trouble. We get reminded that this is for Halloween by saying that that's when they work over overtime.
And
and and he shows off the invention to them and explains how it works. Henry, do you wanna tell us about the invention and how it works? Yeah. So it it looks like a little horseshoe,
but it basically is a almost like a magic ape ball for sure.
A horseshoe on a on a string with a little knob on it, and it shows a little... It has a little window in it that shows
text at the top.
And the device is going to
give you advice of what to do when any trouble comes up. Yeah. I like I like the simplicity of the invention. What do you think tim about this page? Yeah. It it it also kinda reminds me of the the device itself, like
if a toilet is occupied or not
Really.
But it's it's fun. Yeah. The the expectation is really quick. And I really like the the panel with in the at the top, the first panel. The nephew looking really impressed.
Yeah. Right dumb expressions on their faces is yeah. You you see them making like,
like,
Yeah.
That's that's what it's supposed to be.
So it this it was my first time reading this call. The second page baffled me indeed is worldview view shutter just
drops the knowledge that all troubles are can't I.
I guess
we have everything that's better the world to blame on garland. And Jared just fixed it apparently.
Right. This is definitely Barks doesn't care about Canon, but this story is about as non canonical as they come. It's funny guess it's also this is still when general mainly is about making useless inventions, I guess, but this seems it seems a very, like a very useful invention, but then in a very un unpredictable way solving your.
And and, of course, the fact that we never see the goblins or anything,
you know, it could very well just be this crack thing that's not doing anything.
Yeah. This is also why I was wondering when it was translated to Dutch if they even bother to mention the goblins because she could just... It could just be anything
you you don't see any
at least... Not yet. Right. It could be predict the future
itself. So On onto the third page, you know, the nephews are excited, they're bringing at home
And and, you know, they're talking about how they can avoid anything
unpleasant
hand.
And and as they approach home very conveniently,
Donald and Daisy are having a conversation And
Barks is gonna set this up by meeting
the Nephew needing to avoid their worst nightmare.
And and what is a little boy's worst nightmare in the nine... In the nineteen fifties, it's it's being around little girls. This is the part of the story where we get some some pretty weird gender politics
thrown in here.
Because Daisy is telling
Donald,
she wants the boys available to dance with the little girls at her afternoon
already.
And and they describe it as the most horrible torture
boy can endure. Mh I'm gonna disagree, honestly.
I I I would have been right there with them at that time. It's just... I I never
experienced
anyone basically
you know, telling me. Oh, your job this this afternoon is kinda dance with little girls It's... Yeah. That's a weird shoe horn setup. Yeah. It's it's it's basically adults worst nightmare all over again only the setup is even stranger air. Yeah.
But I'm thinking fifties people were this cruel two points.
Right.
You're a girl's part to do this? Right.
And and then this the page closes out with one of the nephews making a pretty cool expression
saying that it's lucky for them, They've got this goblin foil. Any other thoughts on this one, Tim. Mh.
Yeah. I'm also right there with them in nineteen nineties.
Yeah. I wonder how it is...
No. It's it's really great that that that's the most horrible thing they can enjoy
super funny. They could take for time. They could fix world hunger with this
right.
So
the next the next sequence
it gets pretty invent here. Right? It if you ignore the fact that this is all being caused by invisible goblins.
I like this this sequence here where they they take the
advice of the foil, which says to go far away.
I'm we're gonna say, it's not the most innovative advice ever.
Stupid
but they decide they opt to go to Grandma Inducks farm and
and very predictably the this feels you guys like kind of the Gladstone donald mh sequences.
Right? Where where his lock is kind of the foil. But
Donald that turns out is gonna head to grandma's laws as well to harvest some comp.
And by the time they've walked five miles to get out there. Donald is meeting in them. And. I guess Donald went by com.
Right. Probably. I like how the advice is just go far away and then nephew you say sounds like good sensible device.
Which.
Which is pretty
self aware, but Yeah. This again, this this page, like you said, it it it sounds almost like a glad slow story and I don't know if if if Barks ever said anything about this
specifically, but it still feels to me like, he maybe had this idea for a different comic and that he maybe she wanted in to work with goldman. It it it feels like it could been an interesting glad comic but then
he he ended up using it with a with the kind of tacked on halloween halloween fee. Right. But I'm not sure, of course, maybe I'm I'm doing it with this service thinking this but.
Yeah. I remember reading a little bit about it
when I was doing the background for trip treat. I didn't really review that. I I think as I recall, he just kinda slapped it together. Mh. Which which it feels like
And the bills need to be paid
Yes
I can understand businesses is this.
For a
the story that slept together, it's still good reading. I mean, Yeah. It's very yesterday.
Absolutely.
And this
Go ahead.
I of the tech the textbook.
That says if goblins could be that easily, there'd be no fun in everything around. Right. Yeah. It feels like Bark sometimes has the most fun. In his text boxes.
So
it proceeds in this sequence where they're gonna go through and and do their best to stay one step ahead. So the next time they spin the dial, the foil tells them to climb a tree. Mh It's really appealing looking Apple tree that they climb.
And and start picking an apple
from. And
while
while they're doing this, Donald is complaining about the dr of Harvey and and piling some pun.
And he decides that he's gonna take a
rest under under that Apple tree and join apple. And so he just absolutely
weighs on the Apple tree
with a with a club or a branch. And as he says,
well quite a harvest as a bunch of apples, but also the nephews
fall right on out.
Yeah. And what way to to pick an up just
where want.
Right. I guess is too sure to to but one.
And and we get... We get next a brisk little sequence that's basically the Nephews
consulting
the
foil
And they also comment that only a goblin could give him such speed. So they've just totally bought into this whole universe now. Yeah. They basically became hyper religious
on this.
Right. Everything. Everything
is caused by goblins ones.
It it is pretty weird you guys, they're usually so national. So Barks really has to... It's it's it's pretty strange. Right? They're they're usually such rational.
Characters.
But but we know that we've talked about this Al lot on the podcast. Barks is very elastic
and he makes his characters
be what they need to be in a given story...
Well not like totally diver,
I think, from their their true nature.
So the goblins ones, the goblin foil tells them to plead from mercy egg.
And he puts them... He draws them in a pretty great pose of application and they beg
for for it. And and Donald,
Donald Ac is
Henry good you wanna tell us about the bargain, he makes with them. So he says, I'll make you a deal. You follow the pumpkin. But if you carve so much Al one face and one pumpkin, you go right that today's and Of course, this is also one of those states that if you don't know what Halloween, this makes zero sense.
I'm not he would even... Why he would even assume they would do that. Actually in no dutch version, he just does if you make a game out of this, I'll send you right back. So they didn't translate that directly. But yeah. The next the net look adorable as he Barks down.
He he apparently does... He doesn't identify expectations of the nephews that he already expects to carve the pumpkin
they were told to stick. Right. I like the idea that they're just gonna be so overcome with the urge
to car pumpkin. Have you guys several car of the pumpkin? No. I I want to do it for years already. But
I so hard to buy pumpkin
to like that. So I'm here to tell you as as a parent of young kids, and I've been through this now. I'm going on my my third kid it's actually really super unpleasant
to carnival pumpkin
because like, you have to clean it out and it's it takes a long time
And it's it's it's like the sw vegetable, I guess they're technically a fruit.
It's the slim
inside So, like, it really does fall apart. But but... Yeah. You you're not gonna just sit there and carve it randomly.
Yeah. And of course, if... If you're Al artist, you have to make really good focus.
Right. You can't get him away
yeah. Hey, Tim. Do you wanna tell us about this next sequence. I I think this is one of the highlights of the story. I always I always like the best as a kid. Yeah. So so the nephews
are gru like they have to get out of this gem.
This this deal that they made with An macdonald. And
it kind of feels like
their own fault, all of this stuff, but
that's just me. Right.
So the they spin the dial and it says just speak away.
And
Al the kids sneak away, donald throws another pumpkin on the pile based been different been building. And
three of the pumpkins
fall on top of
three space or three tools. Mh. And and also on top of the fence, And
somehow those
those
land on the nephew heads. And
being encouraged by those tools in this.
And
nobody but a government could have cleaned up this catastrophe.
And immediately Donald is there, of course. Right. Yeah. And he catches them red handed so he believes I don't know why they would have smashed the pumpkins
onto their own heads.
Yeah But of course, there's no other
explanation. They can't blame it on Goblins.
It's
It's a very goofy sequence, but... But it's fine. It's one of those chains of events that bart me sometimes. That's that's neat. Yeah. It feels like a
it feels like it went back to his story boarding days for the sequence would've
creating Inducks correct yeah. But I I love how how how it just
They barely sneak away of quickly, which is better terrible advice.
This takeaways are quickly, you just froze donald first pumpkin Al an empty bowel. And the the this very first part is they went to car pumpkins inside that.
Right. So it's like a as though it's like a drug habit of theirs or something.
Yeah. I could just hear Car and Donald saying in his voice like, so I So Yeah. Yeah. So yeah I wouldn't be... Yeah. We don't get a lot of that. So from the comics, but it's ever present go to.
So you know, the sequence goes into the nephews fleeing again.
And
while while their uncle is tangled up, in what seems to be.
They get their last piece of advice spinning the dial they're told to hide
and they come across a very large pumpkin,
which is the only place and they need to get inside. And again, you guys this It's cartoon logic so that's fine. But even even as a silly eight or nine year old, I was like, wait a minute. I've carved a pumpkin before
I know that it would take hours to get the guts out of that to make room to actually hide in there. And and the predictable thing happens,
in that
Donald has to give up chasing them, and we get our our brief appearance from grandma dot. I don't get to talk about her that often you guys.
Who says
that Daisy phone requesting a pumpkin for her party and wouldn't you know it, Donald is gonna get that big
show pumpkin.
I'm gonna see this becomes more ridiculous of.
Right.
I I wonder if the if the government folder is actually just reading the Nephew spots because all the advice is it gives basically the most basic first thought you would have a job.
I
way, hide yeah.
Exactly. And it feels like
definitely feels like none of this would have happened if they hadn't, like that they were... That they called the attention of the Goblins something who usually wouldn't have like, honed in on this.
And and the next sequence, the the last page or so of the story
is...
It's very goofy.
Daisy at at Daisy party, she has hired
a
a swords man named
Lab blade who's gonna show... Demonstrate how to carve a face with a saver.
I do love his, like, ridiculous
french. I don't know how they
if they convey that
in the Dutch one or anything. But but he's ridiculously act accent here. He says voila
with z
category
trust
of the eye to share.
Christmas.
U. I say near nearly die.
Right.
This is honestly as one most dangerous situations than nephews have ever been in.
How about you guys did do either of you have the Dutch to see what
how that was translated.
He he doesn't doesn't just an accent.
Okay. No.
He does... He does say unnecessary
French words. Because he's called muscular
lam.
Okay. And he says
in
I'm
I.
Yeah. But
and yeah, he's just
slicing through the pump and and as he's about to finish it up, the Nephews
are forced to use their... Their handy nineteen fifties era pocket knives that every child, every boy at least has to carve their way out.
And they're... They keep them in their invisible pens
Right. And and he
sa blue. Z pumpkin was populated.
And
Henri
tell us about the, like, closing of the story with the little girls and everything.
Yeah. So the girls shot. Oh, good goody.
The nephew look absolutely petri wine just get I don't know how many girls had Barks, seven or eight. They've just run that So there's more girls and boys, so that's already
can only imagine what Barks they have to.
And it follows with one of the greatest panels I've everything seen after the nephew.
It says Al evening chad fall. Oh, woah, woah, what a great gala afternoon is donald. And the nephews has walk in front of him. Just looking...
I've never seen in any
Right.
Expressions of murder.
In their eyes.
I'm I'm at least happy that I would be worried for them that they would be covered in in lipstick or something. That's right. Thankfully. I they seem to have survived okay. It's just their dignity me that's got shutters.
Right.
And and we get one of those classic
violence.
Gag endings
where
where he asked them,
are you tired, aren't you gonna go home Donald says and they say not yet on donald.
Right now, we're gonna see a man about an invention and they they've gotten some large plugs from a wood pile.
And there's a very convenient sign gyro gear and
that way. As they strive off to to whale upon him. So pretty large clips do. It's Yeah. Yeah. It's gonna be brutal. Maybe
that's how he lost that way.
During his recovery peter
yeah. He had he wife he ended up in hospital for seven months cent.
Right.
Just so So you guys that's H Goblins.
I guess it should really be H gear loose by the end there. But it We haven't been two kinds to the story, but it does have some really fun sequences,
some nice expressive character art do you think, Tim? Yeah. As a whole, I I still like it a lot. It I I remember it for reading it from when I was a kid. So it it stuck with me.
There's a lot of Barks stories do, but I think the fact that that Al kid, I really didn't want to dance with those.
Anyone from that You found available?
Yeah.
I still don't like the bones. But
So...
Yeah. I really stuck stuck chord with me as a kid and
I think it it might have done with lots of kids Barks then. So it is really these these ridiculous situations
that make a fun story. Otherwise, probably would have been a bit boring. Yeah. What do you... What do you think, En? Yeah. So, I mean, the story in in most part, it doesn't really make sense, and it aged forty, but it's very fun.
So I like it because if I laugh what I'm reading a callback like, I usually, like it so
yeah. It's it just... Definitely, like I said, it feels you can you can kind of... It's not
bell structured that it's now as well structured just most of but what you would expect from from Barks, but nonetheless, it's has a lot of really funny moments and then the expressions are great. So I would still consider it a very enjoyable call. Yeah. You're totally right about those expressions, it's it's one of the things that I love doing about the podcast is that it forces me to like pay such careful attention
to each panel that I find all these great expressions like those murder faces that, you know, I I may not have fully appreciated it. Just stewart during a regular read through. So that there's some really fun sequences here. It's just the whole... I do find it off putting how we're just supposed to accept the invisible god ones for it. It's it's a ridiculous story. Yeah. And gyro doesn't doesn't daryl a lot if it things in here that if I would look at the story very critically, I would consider not very good stories I think, but I guess he had a good experience for it. Right. Yeah. That... It's weird how gerald basically doesn't return and the goblins are... I wonder if they're even real one when I was reading it kept expecting to either see something or that it gets acknowledged that that the invention doesn't work or that they're not real, but it just... It's it just feels like a sequence of events. That is enjoyable. So
I wouldn't consider it a great story, but it's it's it's already fun reads. It is. That's very entertaining. And what you said about the the presence in the panels. So well I hadn't read this comment before a lot of these Barks panels are they've been reused out of contact so often in the Dutch magazine that several of these panels are drawings I've seen tons of times already. So it's funny to find see them in the context of the comment you're from. Yeah. Bet. That would be cool.
Yeah. How how about you guys any any favorite panels that you'd like to really highlight? That that one from that los page that we just mentioned with the Nephew looking
Right. Mh Angry. Yeah. I agree. I I think that's gotta be the winner as far as the expressive
I really did like Gyro rose workshop and the and the just crazy elaborate equipment. Yeah. And I wonder if this is the it's is the first time you see his workshop on the inside? I think so because
he's never in it in the
think box story. He's they're they're outside and out about.
Yeah. So I think it's actually the first the first time you see da workshop.
Yeah. Way, it's it's funny. I just I just thought about this actually that there's no door or wall.
His not. Just one realize. Yeah. So so I assume for safety. Yeah. So the panel... I mean, I think it's just the storytelling so he wants to have them running towards his workshop. So he's he's showing them entering the workshop. But because it's difficult to show them entering
all these characters entering through a door, I think he just didn't her, but he just saves it away. You don't but lightning
that is lightning
had to be outside. So it's sort of... Yeah true. Right. I wonder right. Mh
But this
that you don't think about until you draw yourself or when you start paying this,
ten many other panels you wanted to highlight
Yeah For me the one Donald
striking the three with the with the club is is like
it's really funny to me.
Oh, yeah. Now that the threes the
sp.
Yeah.
Right. So it's really yeah yeah. And the one with the Nephews
and they after dance with the girls when they're I was pumpkin
I really love those expressions like... Yeah. Yep red red on their faces.
Just rev.
Yeah. Alright. Well, you guys that that was really good that that's a fun story at least to have talked about. But why don't we transition to the the kind of the Show story?
And, you know, this one is, like, not really technically a Halloween
story.
It's just it's just spooky. Right? I mean, the the the creature is meant to be like a jack Gladstone.
So
we're we're shoe horn this in a little bit. Yeah. And well well
Hell hello too well, Hello isn't really... Wasn't really a comics, of course.
They they would make themed negatives with spooky stuff. So in that regard, in a Dutch magazine this would fit right in with the other ones. Right. It fits very nicely within our October theme.
And then, you know, it just feels very seasonal.
Two. So you guys were gonna
proceed to talk about our kinda main feature story with steve Willie. This one is published in Walt Disney comments and Number one hundred and fifty nine.
About a year later, the cover date was December of nineteen fifty three, This is a true ten pager, and this one's rated quite a bit better on Inducks.
It's not like a super highly rated one but as well regarding It's it's ranked four hundred and eleven right now,
which is good for a seven point four. And if you kinda break out all of the ten pages as I've done
and put them on a spreadsheet, you can tell that it's in the eighteenth
percentile.
Of ten pager. So so pretty pretty well regarded, you guys I I have to think that most of that is is because people remember the cr sure.
Whiskey Willie himself. Even though he's not like a really big part of this story, he's just so darn like, creepy
and goofy feet and memorable
altogether.
Cute.
Yeah. But guess this is one of those...
I have to say so like I mentioned, this is one of the first Barks comments I read, and I hadn't read it in years, and I forgot what the story was even about, but I definitely remember I remember this all these panels with really in it and
so you can definitely
say that he's very... Yeah. This this panel defend at Al. See that they're very memorable and all the stuff that's happening to Donald does memorable both and I forgot that it was Scrooge to this too.
Yeah. He's kind of... Tim, he's kinda incidental to the story itself. Right? Yeah. That's that's true.
It's it's like the final
things groups does to to to his cause. But the story is isn't titled with the Willy or anything. As far as I can tell in the original
application. So so maybe the fan just named it doctor him because it's such a striking character. Yeah. Because in the dutch one that it actually has a title and the title is
where, although
dutch is done the bowel list.
Which us a great name. Right.
Most of these have been, you know, un titled originally. And at some point, they just
them I know that this one was originally also called...
Oh, I can't remember. Had some other name to Iowa.
But, yeah. It's
he he's what stands out. He's what people remember.
So
and this is technically a donald versus Scrooge story, which is easy to forget. It it also means that this one sometimes gets printed and while disney comics and stories,
sometimes in an uncle Scrooge in the Us,
it it fits in a couple of places. Yeah. And this is definitely one of those stories where when I saw Ducktales is kid in the nineteenth I always... Even when I was very young, I thought screw
strange because it was so nice and the soft.
But after when you read... If this is one of the first Scrooge stories you ever read that
you you get to see the worst of scrubs, basically.
Yeah. He's just... Huey, just her. Yeah. He's he's a real jerk. And that's fine. Huey, he's an outright villain in this one. Which which I enjoy. So...
Yeah. Thank. It can be fun.
You you have to read the stories as though every issue that, you know, they don't relate to each other. Yeah. I... Did you still do you still do the sequence where you reach different titles from different countries? Or... I do. But sometimes I just plain forget.
So is is there a title that you noticed
that you were animated by Henri? I see that the German, the German one is it's slight like. Which just means... Inducks should we transfer to Camp, but, like, two... It's two brewster that are fighting so you can imagine what what it means And let's say. And the this the spanish title seems to be specific. But you speak some Spanish. Right? Yeah. I alright. So, yeah, the Spanish title, it says... Yeah. I see that the Spanish one and
And the Fuego
means the game is between fools.
So when I when I see the Danish one, one title,
I can absolutely not pronounce this thin lit month, which I guess means something like the the wheel of the wrist. But then the other one another side was moses
motion.
So I'm gonna guess that most of this is main it's really name. And almost and probably means from this one. Nice.
Tim, do you wanna mention any of them? Yeah either?
The belgian one is really
really on the nose, I think is is just Donald sells house. That's.
But yeah. It's also the the Belgian french one is also mcdonald self house in Australia it was one called moving days.
Yeah. That's the original title. The the the title that it used to have in, you know, in the Us. It's pretty pretty bland. Yeah. And it's sweden. It's her still Al, probably house for sale or something. That's what it sounds like. Yeah. I do like his his Dutch name Al lot doing deck val lift. It's a nice alteration. But derek is just derek, basically. And so it's like thin derek willow.
It's into keeping with Barks
for Yeah. Or whiskey Willy.
So,
yeah, let's get let's get on into the story and again, break in where appropriate.
We get a really good setup This is one of those kind of classic
ty
against the little guy stories that you see in a lot of media
where someone wants to buy
a piece of property. In this case, Uncle Scrooge wants to buy Donald house
for
his new... For his new widget factory, I think he's gonna say at some point in the story. But but initially, as he's handling with Donald, he's
he doesn't want to
admit. He's saying the the city is gonna develop this part into a model district
And and he's given Donald this
pretty insulting low offer. But when I looked at up two thousand bucks is what he offers him, which That that was like the price of a medium home in the Us about a decade and the half
before. Is what I found looking up inflation.
I Barks the worst corner of Inducks burger.
Right
And and the page closes out by
saying,
by one of the nephew wondering why Scrooge On ridge wants this place. And Donald stubborn saying it doesn't matter. He isn't gonna get it at his price. What, you guys think it's a it's a pretty strong setup. Yeah. It is. And I I really like the the the way Scrooge like, tries to
say he wants to donate.
It's the development
great expression. Yeah. Yeah. But it
does a really poor job of it the
starts out by lying he just tries to buy our Nephew House lying to right.
Yeah. It's horrible. And and s state doc... I love how they on the first panel, they're kind of bent over two our etcetera and and the second battle, you see a a long shot where you see the whole house and you can just see that if you look pretty closely the Nephew sitting on the fence, so they're just watching
Al domino's
discussing this. But Barks str great arguments.
Yeah. I love... I love seeing two people at odds. They're just... It's so amusing when Barks draws them.
So on the next page, we get a little bit of Scrooge
motivations. We learned that in fact, it is that this will
hold up plans for his new Gizmo factory
because he can't buy the land and he emails over Al he's looking at a map of the area. He says that he's bought up all the other places around donald
for half what they worth, but that Donald insists on more than a fair price.
And so far fair.
Right. Yeah.
I I do love this part of you guys. He he uses an old style intercom to tell his clerk jeans.
He asks them to bring in his book of dia volatile
strat.
And Tim, do you wanna tell us
about...
Did just talk about that panel where he's reading through the book.
Scrooge is like reading a book and he says ways to make people sell homes, which is a apparently a chapter and dialogue
lakes, thurman.
About.
So
you tell us about the first scheme, please.
So the next day,
one of the nephews comes up to Donald and says, if he noticed the... We have rats in the house.
There's this, like I think when or something red Inducks
and donald is like.
Outcome come we have so many suddenly. And then there's somebody at the door not And it's the city red inspector.
This rats, it will have to be torn down. And it's it's like this really goofy guy with the the str Barks, and
I think some pillow is in his
his jacket, and
it's pretty clear it's it's on group. Is a classic Barks disguise. Yeah.
Yeah. I just tied them up to a face or something Yeah. And I wonder if if Donald
can't tell if it's him or not. I don't think so. My read of it is that he's completely fooled. Okay But the reader still gets to see the the specs and the the glasses and so it's right. Pretty clear obviously obvious. Very obviously.
And donald this reading, walt disney stuff.
Oh, yeah. That's a a fun catch. What is reading in the the dutch version... And then that one he's reading a job the,
which is the name. It's the name of the... There's dutch Disney magazine. And there's a page with sent jokes and kids. Oh, nice. Apparently what three. See. That's fun. Pretty same jokes for. Oh, the the fake inspector,
you know, says I... I'm also an
and he
khan donald into offering to spread some
repel
around to drive away the rats. And screws thinks to himself that it's actually
sku oil,
which is something I've never encountered in real life, but I hear about these comments all the time. Yeah. I wonder if that's... I don't think that's actually something you can buy but is the worst imagine snow. Right. And I I love
Al pages already just so silly.
Screen looks silly, and he says I do wonder if Donald I wonder if they'll know soon it who it is because he's smiling it in the whole. Yeah. He's smiling, but it's not in that like, Barks is really good at drawing like rye
recognition.
I think. So I... I'm pretty comfortable
in in the read that
he doesn't
realize.
He... I think he's really amused when when the Nephew used capped. Chases the mice out and knocks the stun oil into the stranger. But that's just because Donald kind of appreciates mayhem him.
Yeah I guess donald was happy to let them in to get a free sample. And Right. So so Scrooge. I mean, the salesman is...
I mean, It's.
Right. It's the inspector who happens to be a sales.
Right.
I you you can you can save yourself a lot more. A lot of trouble by selling the house. I will... When I get my price and then exclusive little.
Right. This Al pages is very silly. It is. It's deep silly. Any other thoughts you guys on this one before going on? Well, the Nephew also say as so Scrooge gets bumped over by the cats and the two thousand threats or house And as he gets bumped over, he gets the the stun all over himself. And the one of the nephews point to them and says, what's the matter of the inspector, he reads to say the least
right. Once again,
not really to share whether they know or not. I mean, I think they don't know, but you're not really sure. Well,
because on the next page,
Donald is kinda of pondering.
Right? And he says, I'm surprised that Uncle screwed has been
me. So like, he's not registering this even though it's screaming obvious to the reader. That's right. So our next
our next attempt we're gonna see screws next try is that they're gonna hear a loud Scrooge
at their door, their Barks.
And when Donald opens the door, he's gonna see a a wicked witch. There's no other word for it. She basically looks like the witch in snow white,
I think.
Right? Yeah. Which would and everything?
Right. Would have been really still culturally just a huge force at this time.
She announces herself Al a witch who's moved in next door and says, I don't like you.
And for a lot of the story, Donald just gonna be this really bla Al, like,
really
stoic.
Person
saying,
I'm sorry to hear that you don't like me what sort of spell when she threatens to cast a spell on him.
And and when when she leaves,
you know, he's laughing about it with the Nephews calling her some poor diluted woman.
Who thinks she's a witch. What do you guys think? Yeah. I really liked the the the panel with the, like this the second panel it, this the word Scrooge just.
Panel. It's it's swedish. Yeah. It's it's a great setup that Donald just refuses to be intimidated.
Yeah.
Yeah. Barks is just trying to draw the away keeps snow wife from memory here.
Yeah. Problem. So looks like, Yeah. Just like she opens for I'm a which that has moved in next door, and I don't like.
I
Yeah. The the switch is not good at making friends clearly.
And Scrooge keeps upping the stakes. Do you wanna tell us about the next attempt, Henri Rica? Yeah. So... Alright. So Donald says have you haven't heard of anything so corny, and he hasn't even finished the stent and here Al this crushing and smashing in the kitchen and
Gorilla walks into the living room.
And once again, Donald is not faced at all by Gorilla, and he thinks it's an actual gorilla and he said oh, it's just the pet that escaped from a multi lot, which is apparently. Makes this real not in intimidating.
Right. But then one of the Nephew points. So what about this dragon that this coming for the other door? The drag just says, it's
but donald is again not thing they you know things there they must be from some Tv show. So I'll just ask, how's everything snow and show business these days boys?
Then you can see that the gorilla whispering to the dragon...
Which makes it clear that they're actors like, Huey, won't get out. What do we do now? Let's go the office.
For whatever reason, I really like that panel of them just cats these like fantastic creatures just talking to each other casually. It's also the dragon even as actual fire coming.
Pretty impressive cost.
They are. Yeah. Those
actually looks pretty scary for... I'll tell you would have cost a lot more probably than
the the difference
in price to it to hire these.
Those are you like
when the when the two creatures, like, confer... Confer with each other and their heads are together, but the next bundle you see that the head of the the dragon is, like,
really.
Where the dragon inside is. So
Right. Yeah. Because that next final is is them
on the phone with Scrooge. We see those two actors
and then a woman who is clearly the witch You guys noticed that she's a human woman. Yeah. She's a human and that that's too active are a Barks host human, but she's an actual
She looks like a Huey, Barks. So he totally hired, like, the most famous Hollywood exit.
Sure.
And and so you know, they report to screws that Donald just doesn't scare.
And he just gets off a pit. Consider yourselves fired. I'll try another stun. And and this takes us to good old Willie. You guys were gonna get see Willy his setup up here. I really like the lead up to Scrooge like, pondering.
He's kinda running out of ideas. So he goes back to the book of tie
strategist. I love that title so much.
Any elbows through ghost,
and cheese, wear,
willow the twists,
and he stops there because he says, Willow of the west, there is a form of hideous horror that hasn't been used too often.
And that's kind of like breaking the
right in the fourth wall. Right? Because, like, that's
true. It's literally really what bug Barks was thinking. When he was right discover.
Right. It's it's like a monster that we don't see featured very much.
And and who wants to tell us, what is the will of the west? I don't know, actually. It's it's like there's
swamp
thing
made of gas or something.
Well that's that's what it's gonna end up, like, being logically in the story. But, like Yeah. The.
Yeah. It's yeah an actual phenomenon of the... When
guess on marsh and swamps.
Can symptoms sometimes sketch on fire, I think? And so sometimes you'll see, like,
I'm not sure what what's the exact cost by but this gas and sometimes light up and a lot of legends concern
or
she just...
On this. I know? Right. That's right. I mean,
it's it's what people it's why people joke about, like,
Sighting being swamp gas. Right. Yeah So... And and the the the dutch name for the of the also Al is also what you would call this this guest that you see at as swamp. So
I find it interesting that
Al well see the of the
described as a J lantern. And that's something I didn't know because I I know a Jack and is what you call a Halloween pumpkin if can it. But apparently
j lantern is originally a assigned for of the west. Yeah. Yeah. That's right. It's supposed to be like the captured wi Because... And it's... And it's kinda like it's a creature that has been used and pop culture more. You see him in, like, brave
and
twists and like warcraft are kind of the same
Same deal. But then definitely,
oh, yeah. It's definitely something that's not like his common place. And Barks is gonna create his own version
of this here.
So so he hires
a scientist.
He's not gonna use ji for this one. Right? He needs some anonymous scientist is the guy named doctor Super think.
And he orders up. He orders up a willow the list, which the guy
explains hopefully for the reader is a jack lantern. And Scrooge
makes these like,
B fingers, which is great and says I want more than the lantern. I want the horrible slit something that carries the lantern. And that's all Barks is gonna give us to go off with basically. That's that's his little
mythology here. But what a commission to get doctor.
Tim, do you wanna tell us about the Inducks and encountering doctor super think in the
swamp later? Yeah. So the docs are apparently
going out fishing in the evening
nearest sw mir March. And
doctor Super think
is on the water with his little boat and he asked the that if it'll help them help catch her... Some of the Barks gas and adults are sure. And and the next page,
they've proceed to to capture some of it
Donald has to stir at the bottom and then the the loose comes up and but that's the way they they capture the gas, and he also sends the Inducks into an old mine.
Ask them to bring some mold from its must year's depth.
And
the end they they've collected all the things.
And doctor
was he doctor? Yeah. The doctor asked them
if they want to help him some more. And
next thing we were in the...
I think it's laboratory and Mh.
Docs asks
ask, what are you gonna make?
A one of the,
a clear old chap wants me to make him one complete with gas growth arms on lu eyes. I like that reference to huge.
Yeah. Yeah.
So.
Yeah.
So in the in the final panel, the gas fuse into burst white sparks
and
doc asks the donald... That's the lights and watch when it's the guest strikes the mold. So so, yeah, we're we're into the process of creating the the of the on this page. Right.
I
I love this, like, pseudo scientific
nonsense.
That bar is pretty pretty elaborate creating for this this very silly
process, but but it feels kinda believable. But at at the same time, it's quite funny. Yeah. I think we're within these economics as long as you sound...
If as long as the character stops convinced or convincing, you can basically
right whatever logic he wants as long as it's convincing within the economic. And right. Something I I found very funny with these pages that's is not there and the that's translation is that this this doctor just keeps asking them to help with increasingly weird things and to absolutely everything he says, Donald just says, share.
Help me with this Smart guest. Sure. Don't you go into the mind with me. Sure.
Did just... I mean, I would also be intrigued. So it's understandable that they that they going along.
Right. And and is like, just just profoundly ridiculous too. Yeah. And this is in between
in the dutch version,
the panel the the gas bubbles up. It's unintentionally hilarious. Oh, yeah. This this him... They missed the same coffee so he was also laughing. Oh, yeah. Because the the the gas rice is up
But the gas clouds should be white, but in the touch version, they did something wrong, and instead of them being white, it says the word white
Oh, So like the... They just have to work wise written in them so they... Terms like Al bites and it
No. They just intended to call and white they forgot there's something does... So it just says white
instead us... Yeah. Being the actual caller right. We'll send you a Screen transcription here. Nice. Yeah.
You guys the this whole sequence is also it's very
atmospheric.
It's very moody.
It's not like actually creepy
I mean, up until we get the the kind of the the creature taking shape
on on that net page.
But the docks never look scared. So we're not we're not scared. But like we see... We we hear the doctor
talk about a wi shape forming and asking for help if it breaks... Yeah. If they need to control it if it breaks out, and the Inducks get to see it, and Donald describes Al a bunch of Marsh gas and mold scores, but it looks like it's alive. So I feel like we never really like... Even though they say it is alive, I don't think it's ever really clear if he's what he's created here. But but who cares. It looks cool. It looks cool. It it has great character design. Is this what what you guys found memorable
about the story? You know, like like I did these these panels
we only get a handful of them of of Willie himself here. Yeah. Absolutely absolutely. I mean, it's also one of those this sparks characters that only appears but you just really remember the character design and it's actually... It's a ten but to eat one of the do last year, he actually gave really a cameo in it... Oh how cool.
I can I can say that it's memorable to him at least? Yeah.
Yeah. Sure was. Well, please do share that. I'd love to see that.
What what do you find so memorable
about him, Tim? Well, it's it's also the build
until the finally centimeters
these these... Especially in the dutch
application, the the coloring is also very hyper.
And
this real mysterious thing that's growing and
just... What essentially comes out of it it's just this really other world we
thing and
educated and really made an pressing on me.
And during the time when when I was reading the these comments,
I also was reading
from who comments or another common. Mh. There also so all these days.
And there was kind of the same theme with these these
one of the guys and then yeah spear was just the same. So those two stories were in my life at the same time. So kind of
fantastic
yeah.
Yeah. Because if if I don't know exactly what Aj was when when I read this, but probably five or six, and I probably couldn't even really read that shit, but that must have been one of the serious things I had seen up until that point right now.
Strangest... It stands out. It's it's so visually cool. He's got these ten arms and these eyes on stocks.
I love it. I love the care.
You can hear the experiment music playing in the background.
Right.
Right And then love is that that he's serious he's,
but he's very cute. He looks to the silly, but also cute. And the left... Like, the the docks clearly
like him right away. And the moment... They see him, they're all smiling at him, and the doctor says they can feed him. So like, like he's said a little cute course c or something.
Right. And and that that's really the last kind of memorable bit of the story is that we get this cool build up to
to Scrooge doing what he's gonna do, which is like Launch him Donald to scared of them.
It's... Fucking nephew also.
Right.
Yeah. It's a great we get some great villainous
expressions here from sp, and and maybe the best panel of Lily
is
as he is kinda creeping up to Donald House
in, like, a full with
full page with panel.
I I love this page you guys watching
watching Scrooge
sm and scheming as he absorbs Willie going to scare them and seeing the Ducktales just excited greet him
high, willie
and
talking about getting him some tool roots as though they've got them lying around.
Oh, and and Willie delight full little smacking of his lips or looking his chops.
Is it...
It's it's really adorable.
And I love our Scrooge
described as this horrific monster. Like nobody could stand.
They see him. I can hear them yelling inside of he's so excited to for him to be verified
and he thinks apparently that the are fine. Right. It's Yeah. And I I I don't know maybe it's just me, but I think maybe looks the adorable.
Yeah. Oh, yeah. What what do you think in? Yeah. Barks this way with with regular animals to make them look really acute something in the eyes I think I also to say tim that this looks that that panel was really looking to cute. It really reminds me if your drawing style, so you're really must've have internally.
Probably did. Yeah. Do think. That's so cool. Yeah I also really like the face
the Willie makes when he's still in the the bucket thing. Yeah. Yeah. Alright
it looks like he's scared by his own Ja and and that his holding. Yeah. That they called two monster meet where they had, like, a female looking version of Willy
meeting
warm meeting
sm, the bad, the og from Yeah. Trick treat. But other than that, I didn't actually run across Yeah. I mean I wonder.
I wonder if that's because I I used them as in as an ice sculpture.
So it's not
yours is listed as a cameo. I think, but Okay. With a lot of these cameo, it's... I mean, somebody has to write to them index? Right. It's not always Inducks fully. I don't remember for sure, but I'm pretty sure that He has said cameo and some touch comic like there a one by I added, and has a lot of monster to seen it. And I'm sure there there's some Barks monster Daniel...
I wouldn't be surprised if he was in there, and I wouldn't be surprised if My high used them on on one of his posters maybe, but I would have to sure. They dig through my old call to... Those type of things are not always listed online. So...
Great. This this I I love the sequence.
I will say that nothing else in the rest of the story
really quite, like, stands up. To how cool
this part is. Right? Yeah. It's... People remember it for the sequence, not not the story itself. Although, there's a lot to be said for the rest. Of that. Yeah. I mean, that counts for a lot of stories I would say. Yeah. Right. But I mean the only one page left, I think so.
Right. Right. I I will know before going on that I really like what they did
on... At least the reprint that I was going off of the coloring
on these few pages
and the kinda glow that he cast, I think, is just really nice. This is one where it the character needs to be colored.
Very like thoughtfully. Stands out Because, of course, really is supposed to be a glow and a dark translucent
we feature holding on lights or. So that will be great. Al to to yeah. You can only... He could only get it give it and hope that we would color a way that would work with this, but Yeah. That's a great thing to point out about how the king is so suggestive of the the the evening.
So So, Tim, what do you think about the closing of the story? I I feel I feel like it's a little weak. Yeah. It it kind of is, but it to be, it's it's also so ridiculous
setup that that it it pays it off
well decently.
So
so Uncle Scrooge, apparently,
several weeks later,
has bill a factory
clear around Donald house.
And
Donald is still holding out for his price. That diet work and make me sell. And then all of a sudden, there's this blazing of trumpets
str bones.
And
Donald looks out of his window and the apparently Al it checked, what what but was what they were building near house
john bone, so that's what he's making perspective.
Things out of the window and says, yes, and we'll be testing thousands of them in this courtyard. Now are you going to sell at my price and then
Donald says, okay. You win I'll sell price. And the net ask,
donald how much what's your price on.
That that's thousand them... The same as Scrooge
except that I wanted twenty five cents more to pay for my for sales sign. And then we see the
the nephews
saying, tens of millions of Inducks in the world and we get those two for relatives.
The funny thing is you see donald and Scrooge arguing in the background again,
so it's it's it's this hopeless situation. Right enough just look all this there.
Just like sing sink against each other one is holding the artist filter.
But I I I personally
like how the story is because it's it's almost like such... The build up is so big the faith pays off. It's almost such a let down that it's funny. Because so petty. And
that's right. So the the toronto factory is just
ridiculous
It's literally really a a giant factory haul and all the trumpets are pointing out out of the window exactly at donald house of course of course. Purchased betty. Huey,.
The way he sticks his head out of the wind... This is so fancy and I I I love that all of this stuff was to the whole belt exclusion being pet and the and the build was
overkill from his part but the whole at the whole argument from Mcdonald's part also very petty and stupid. So
to be, it's actually very funny ending because it's... Because the build is so big and it leads to basically twenty five cents that makes it buddy?
Right. Exactly. All all of the humor of the ending is in how
just
How much overkill there was
for this ridiculously
patty ending. And and it's like it's a super old joke. Right? I've seen... I've seen this exact bit at least the building a factory all the way around someone when they're not willing to sell, and then them regretting it be because, you know, it's gonna be something
that that would drive them away. But like, the humor in it is is really elevated, I think by Barks
expressions.
And there's a... I do think it was still in the time and Barks was Al the studio working on the dot com. There's a call cartoon so animated short called t trouble, which has a similar theme being completely overkill. I seen you in a few years, but in that one, Donald neighbor is playing a t bone, and it's so annoying that it noise the gods
and can give donald powers just so he can
Remember that one.
Probably I'm probably telling the story Al wrong, but I feel it's somehow feels sparks in way too. It's so over the top. And it's like so involves strong bones. And it it literally... It's it anger the gods and becomes Al funny to get rid of the terminal.
I would have to to look this car tune up again. And I'm probably telling the story completely wrong but I'm I'm curious if this is a common cartoon that Barks worked on because these
reused themes from some of the old sorts and economics too? Right. So... Or even even just individual gag that he really liked. Either eight's cartoon watching. So... Yeah. That's cool. I'll I'll check it out as I add it. Yeah. So, you know, what what what additional or closing thoughts do you guys have about
Willie here
slash, are there any panels that you really wanna highlight or mention?
Outside it that to me it's it's not per s, one of the best from expiry. But to me, this is very
quintessential Scrooge donald comic and I think a lot of them a lot of the Dutch stomach still were inspired by these type of stories. So to me this really feels like the Scrooge I grew up with and it... Yeah. Just like classic. You like that means spirited. Scrooge. I mean, when it's funny, I don't I... It depends on how it's used, of course. But
so over the top that it's... Yeah it's just... Yeah. I don't know the relations between this family very unhealthy.
Yeah. Because
a wide ben see screws wondering
thinking
fires and slots are against the laws if that's the only thing that keeps right. I see when I was reading... It's true
reading the comment I sent Al penalty to
thought it was about. Yeah
Glad you mentioned that. He's implying that he would use it if he if he could find
It's a far. You would just sets the howard how this that fields on fire, I guess. But...
Yeah, in terms of benefits they're there's a lot of very great expressions. The last then was very funny. And that, of course, this the second to last page when of course, really climbing our great, but also, it's one of the most
taking so much delight into
doing this.
Right. Very very.
Yeah. That that quote that you mentioned the the little sequence where he's pondering what to do. Those four panels
are really awesome.
Him pacing
going into the book and then the silhouette him continuing to look in the book. It's all like, very... I don't know. Barb keeps it very interest even though it's just a sequence of him thinking about it. Yeah. He's just sitting and thinking, but he's facing around and sitting down They always has these ways to just make the characters
do something interesting while there's something for... Would not really be boring Inducks ground. Right. And the same with the donald and the net pennsylvania. Just look at when in the house.
Sometimes this sitting on the floor, then Donald is playing in the chair and they keep changing process. He just keeps his visually interesting.
Right. I mean, the whole sequence were we're really is being created, but when they go to the to the lab, and there's a the huge mysterious looking tank and the the the Ducktales just look on with their hats and their hands. The duck will look very cute in stomach for.
Say. They just observing all this stuff going on. And I like their very warm interactions
with the doctor super think. Is it? Yeah. It's just very
contrast with screws quite a bit. Yeah. And I wonder
if parts didn't use ji here because it would be too obvious if he would just... I mean, he would Scrooge sc obviously. So Al spelled He's doing it for screws. Right. Yeah. So super is funny name. Yeah. And and I don't know if Ji would infants... Well, I just stayed in this previous story, but... Yeah.
We didn't invent something like a bit
or something.
Right. Yeah. The doctor doesn't ask questions. He just... Huey, still... He he just took the money.
What's gonna happen with before really, though? I don't like how screw is freaking this I know. It's too bad that Willie just kind of... It would have been nice if
maybe we saw the kids fondly playing with with Willie at the end. It probably lives on grandpa's firm now as a scare or something. That's just... Has
Okay.
Yeah. There you go. Yeah... Well, thank you guys so much
for
joining me. Really appreciate it. It's it's so fun to get to hear your perspectives.
And and even if you guys don't celebrate Halloween and I'll wish you a happy one because this will come out in in the week or so of Halloween.
Before we close it out, though, do you guys wanna, like, point anyone to any any art pages of yours or or mention anything that you have going on or coming out soon? So in in any case, I think with when you post... May you make it post, maybe you could we could include like a little screenshot of very intense comment. When you when you look... I looked when you look and Inducks the character, you do get page as well. Could
I will definitely be sure to do that. Yeah. And then I can link your your pages
you guys but you guys don't need my
my traffic. You guys have some some well traffic ones, but it's nice to share. Share with people what you guys do. But yeah. I would honestly.
It's also... I I recently traded original pages with them, and I got this it's great hilarious page, but they are just reminds me of this stomach in general it's so it's in in our Dna.
Yeah.
This silly to send that also all the the shading. So I would definitely show show that one off as well. Yeah. For sure. Yeah. Press me on I post art on both my personal twitter and my Instagram, but I would have to spell my name, I think.
Probably. So it's it's it's Henri enrique draws on Twitter and henri enrique could g on for the first of the the letter of my last name on on Instagram. I think and x I occasionally post work and progress of economics and things too there. So it's it's irrelevant.
For. Yeah. For me,
I I mostly post on Instagram, which gets forwarded to my Facebook, but the Instagram handle is
dim dot r with a z and the,
dot design. So that's where you'll find me. Nice. Yeah. People should check, check you guys out. You guys have definitely your own style, but like, I I can tell that you're both, you know, huge Barks fans, and it's
it's it's great Barks see Disney, you know, comics. So
check check them out and and thank you guys again. We we have our own Instagram and Facebook presence. Sparks remarks is our socials.
And
hopefully, listeners can check this out next time around. We'll have more ten page podcasts
episodes
here and there and the happy halloween to you guys.
You're scary. Al a week.