We have
Hello, and welcome to Barks Remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comics of all time. This episode is a ten page podcast, all about one of his short stories. Get ready to enjoy our remarks. Welcome back to Barks remarks,
and a happy Christmas
to my guest hosts for this episode and to all of you listeners.
I guess, you know, what whatever holiday you celebrate, a happy a holiday season to everyone. I am Barks Sever,
a grown man who enjoys Inducks comics and talking about them with other grown men, and I'm very fortunate it to be joined by a couple of other Bark fans. I've got Patrick Block and warren Herman. With me this time. And
again, Merry Christmas, Patrick, are you are you into the holiday? Yes. Very much I was forward to the hold thanks. Thanksgiving... Halloween Thanksgiving Christmas New Year's, things like one big thing for me like, leads up to Christmas.
Computers. Can get carries on little bit longer? And and you know, I'm I'm recalling that you... One of your one of my favorite stories that you wrote and and did the art for. Right I can't remember if if Shelly, if your wife collaborated with this one, it is a Christmas story, and it follows up Carl Barks Christmas for Sc down. Are you're talking about this. Am I remember right the one... The one with which hazel? Yeah Don't for Christmas. There was one for Fernandez for down. Oh, okay a little bit but the most of its roles work and he was right and line to collector friend of mine. Who's in west Virginia. I. We did a wonderful job on that story. It's like doing nicely done as well hard, you know, which we talked a long time about bo and Christmas stores when we constructed that story. Tried the base on his trying to follow something that really felt like a kinder to Barks is well. Yeah. That one's a lot of fun. I really like that one. It's got it's got a couple of nice bark like references with which hazel and wrong thought which hazel it was much under use by business. You like to see a lot more Three two stores with Which hazel Nice. Yeah. I haven't seen the other opt that on a Halloween wings story. Excellent.
The poorest Ducktales Duck nice. So as I said, you know, you you are also a comic book artist and writer in your own right. Do you...
Do you like doing the holiday ones? Yeah. There are lots of fun I always
enjoyed them the most. I think reading that those giant size issues were clear. There a wonderful box. Oh, Christmas
parade. I love love
christmas parade. Looking to those. And warren,
happy holidays, Merry Christmas to you. You into the holidays?
Yeah. You know. Thanks, Mark. And Merry Christmas to both you and Patrick, and I Al
everyone. Yeah. It's great. Especially when you have two little granddaughter. And makes it even more special. And I know you've got your your children there to Barks and and it's just this is very it it's it's great. But I will say what I love about the story what we're gonna talk about is I feel like Donald did in the first eleven panels of this story.
That's that's kinda how it is,
and it feels like that. So it was great to visit this and and review this story today. Yeah. Absolutely. And and the story in question, we're gonna be talking about turkey with all the scheming.
Is the kind of awkward title that it was given after the fact. If you guys from the title, I I kind of even forgot that this one was a Christmas story. You know? It it sounds almost more of a thing giving story, but it... But it is a Christmas story. And
I I landed on covering this one for Christmas this year, because it might be the best Karl Barks
Christmas story, but I haven't already covered.
The the duct man had a lot of great Christmas stories.
We've already gotten to talk about, like, I've covered letter to Santa. I've covered Christmas on Bear Mountain, Christmas for Shack.
Yeah. Warren you were who were part of that one. Yeah
tons of great, a lot a lot of nice Christmas ten pages as well, but, you know, this is probably the strongest one
that is left. And it's fun. I wouldn't I wouldn't say it's like one of his all time best. But there's a lot of lot of really fun elements and a lot to like about this one. That's a wonderful Scrooge moment. Oh yeah. I I... I'm I'm looking forward to that. Yeah.
So let's see a little bit of background on this story. This is a
walt Disney comics and stories
featured ten pager.
It was in... Well, an issue number one hundred and forty eight released in January of nineteen fifty three or that was the cover date at least. And
I read this one in
Glad stones
publication Gladstone
two's public
two hundred and eighty four. And I think notably, this is like the last issue
before they started doing don roses
life and times of Scrooge mick duct like epic mini, you know, series or whatever you'd call that. Sure. But
let's see.
Was this nineteen fifty three? Did you say? Yeah. Yeah. Fifty three. Yeah. Yeah. It's just great. Again, Al classic early fifty story and and
everything in it kinda reflects that time. Yeah. And I think it's a pretty strong time in in Barks kind of like swing. Right? His his Barks is really at the top. What do you think Patrick? Yeah. You got almost story and flowers story. And flip as story after up before. It's super good period. Yeah. This one is is kind of bunched in with a bunch of other really great stories.
And so you guys why don't we go ahead and and launch into it. This is the ten page podcast it's a little bit less researched a little more lucy goose. I really like that... I think the opening is probably the strongest part of this one for me, to be honest because what it is showing is Donald Duck, you mentioned this warren. This is how you feel sometimes a Christmas, and I think this is how a lot of grown ups feel about Christmas
because Christmas is for kids, Al adult have to run around and be frantic and
be paying for everything and getting everything ready. And we get this really imaginative of page of Donald Duck being really busy
on Christmas day.
Well it seems a lot older here and more disciplines of organized usually. Yeah. It's a very, like, suburban parental Donald at the beginning. And he's also more on top of it than he usually is. He really is organized here in these panels mean it's organized confusion because he's really tackling so many these multitasking like I've never seen him do without getting angry.
Right. So so here rapid fire he answers the door to find the the mailman with the kids presence,
He puts some under the tree. He
he wakes the kids for their Christmas dinner with the junior shot. He sends a a donation to the messenger boy for a charity club. Any ask the kids to stop off and pay for the Christmas tree. And that, like, that rapid fire rec
of of all these panels does not do justice to the, like, manic energy and amazing posing that is in each of them. It's beautifully composed. And it's got two funny gag or, like, the site
messenger voice, like, seventy sixty years old.
And the guide is delivering the packages is like like, a hundred packages little just stacked up came to see the guy. It's, like, so many packages
cute little gigs throwing. Mh. I I like those two, patrick out. So I also really love the fact that he's testing to strength here by to the metals.
And and the the net users are spilling out because they're their loafers. I mean, is just he just doesn't have time. So he's gonna
with boys. Let's yeah. There so much great energy
on this. And it's it's this controlled chaos and and Donald doing a great job here, you know. It's it's part too ish. And it continues on to the next page. Where, you know, he takes the call for daisy and he rapid fire. Thanks her for present confirm that she got his.
He he wishes
I I love this. He's asking the operator to connect him to another call in the midst of wishing the kids well. It's really rapid fire. It's great. And this airport in that second battle airborne still talking as if nothing is happening, and he's almost upside down well, we see the boys for the last time here. Yeah. This this panel patrick, what do you think of that third panel on page two or you possibly like that's a they panel in the stores, I think it's so cute I love that panel looks like I think it is my favorite panel from the store. Weighs upside down all wrapped up and the wire... The telephone where. It says beautiful. Beautiful to drive.
It is. It's very funny.
And then he takes another call at the door from
from the printer with the bill for Christmas cards, and so a lot of these little
exchanges, a lot of these chores involve him. We see him spending money, you know. But also being really responsible.
It's it's a neat version of Donald
ten... And finally,
he has a moment to kinda collapse into his easy chair Barks did a really good job. I I shouldn't gloss over the fact that Bark did a great job of chewing the nephews
out of the story for this one by explaining their wood chips dinner. Right? Because Barks is not interested in having the kids around for this
from the beginning that this was the plot. Yeah. Yeah. And we see the Mcdonald's problems like mcdonald's and commands until his black broke right where I finished on Christmas day flat that's broke without a dime. And that's always like one of these big issues and. I think a lot of people can relate to Yeah. They're like control of events as long as they have money once they're out the money and you're mcdonald's phones don't it's like. Alright as you know. I love the Al usual because it happens Severino
Every year. Yeah. What what is more relatable than trying to make your your wallet stretched through Christmas.
He thinks he's got covered, but maybe he's missing exactly. He's also proud of this list. This long list that he has mass and he's checked off every item. Right. And and we've seen him do a genuinely good job of it. So on the next page when we see him get ready to cook his Christmas turkey and not find it. We we feel a little bit bad for him. Right? Because he's been doing such a great job and he's actually been like thoughtful with... With... This is not one of those. Oh, I forgot to get Daisy a gift. We see him. Confirming that she got his gift, same thing with Grandma Inducks, but he doesn't see his turkey, and is very funny to me that he has to, like, check the list. To make sure that somehow
something didn't go right, and he confirms. Yay Cats, I forgot to buy a turkey. I didn't even make a memo. And what is he what is the only thing he's got in the house warren? He's got a of beans.
Sitting there on the shelf, but I love the little dotted and eye target there and and just flooding like crazy.
What surprising is he doesn't have any other side dishes. I mean it's just a can of beans Al a turkey. That refrigerator is empty?
Right. He wasn't gonna prepare it with some carrots and the onions. I I.
Yeah. Yeah. Have some mashed potatoes. And fine. Yeah. We get that
because I love the of beans is always a great fall Barks again talk about eggs. Mean Al classic. Right?
Yep. Yep. It's... The the kansas and Diligence Island. You how you open is, you know, that's this is a tragedy worse than the burning of room. The Al. Yeah. Right. Right. And again, all of Donald like Manic moving around and and now he's like plop on the floor. It's very funny. And he has a choice here you guys. Right? And he tells himself Am I gonna eat those beans for dinner like a starving monitor? Or will I just start? The resolves? No. And and I mean, technically,
he could just he could be fine with the beans, and there wouldn't be a story here. Right? Like, beans... The funny thing about beans is they they'll keep you they'll keep you going.
That's right. I like the writing on these two panels, these last two panels. It's like, typically only Barks would write those lines. No one else more. Oh yeah.
Running the rome and the late the things like a monitor or low started it's like where does he come up with this sun? You know I know it it digs into the classic literature and pulls out these wonderful words that a love boy isn't gonna really understand. Yeah. It's great flo
dialogue.
So super. So, you know, we see him resolved that he is gonna get a turkey dinner and he very quickly snaps his fingers and comes up to the right idea, which is that he's going to trick his uncle Scrooge into buying his dinner. So
This seems like a pretty high
some high hopes. Right, Gentlemen? Yes. Very imaginative.
Very manageable and maybe a little bit too Far fit. But he did
anyway. He'll be the very first person to trick Scrooge Dot into buying him some dinner. That's for sure.
But but the way he's gonna do it, Patrick, do you wanna tell us how he's gonna go about it? Really out of across you from the creaking Barks actors guild with apparently he was a part of at point. Yeah.
Dressed himself. Like, he's a big business man there make a deal. He's gonna go with this self on and the bag of a pair coins to talk to school.
Beautifully drawing in this story. I think that this is like perfectly drawn Scrooge at the in time
great. So wonderful and every panel on the story. I've used the story in fact model like I start out looking a pictures of Scrooge. This is a one of the stores that I looked in a lot because I really love Scrooge screws looks here. What a great thing to point out. Yeah. I I think you're right. This is like Al
of Scrooge. He's he's definitely passed that, like, early
stage, but he's he's a little shorter now and more compact know than he was we was for created and used more this.
There a point mickey. Mickey mouse really great, like, nineteen thirty eight. Like this.
And Scrooge screws is the six perfect. Yeah. Yeah. I think you're right.
So Scrooge is in the middle of doing what Scrooge always does. Counting his money and he's He's at ninety billion trillion
when he is
interrupted by as he says some dim wit coming to the door interrupting him counting his thousand dollar bills, and and he talks through a very animated
intercom to a clearly disguised Donald who introduces himself as San.
San,
The.
And Donald is gonna adopt a very accented
very accented English saying that he is the big oil type from South America. Yes. The signed signed sign on the door suggests that Scrooge is celebrating Christmas. This is Merry Christmas beat. Yeah.
Yeah, it says one one soc to Christmas is a seasonal
sign.
You guys that you know, you you probably both know I'm not a big fan of the like goofy accents. This one is not like it's not that much of a thing. I guess it's
it's I I think the joke is almost more on Donald, because he just looks ridiculous doing it. Right. He's desperate. Right.
And and he's putting on his ru here saying that he's come to make big deal And and I like you mentioned you wanna tell us about the wash Patrick? Yes. You know, Donald just doesn't have any money at all. So so uses what he has to work with, which are probably washers out of his garage click into a bag and make Scrooge think over the intercom with this money. Yeah. Pretty clever. He probably knows that screws has an intercom. And It's not gonna let him in to begin with. So... Yeah. Pretty well. Right.
And and it ends up being pretty good bait for Scrooge who does let him in. Guys. Do either of you have
a a Barks worth of washers in your garage. I do okay like that.
That'd be pretty pretty poor the closest I was a bag full of pennies I collect all your then I take them to the bank and nice. Yeah. Should didn't for... I know Christmas dinner or something or dessert, you know, whatever mean? So it's a little cartoon convenience. But
the... I think the panels of Scrooge
really thinking about getting a hold of that bag of money for himself usher assuring
San Vas
and... I think they're very funny. Yeah. I love it especially when they walk in waste deep into the coins. I don't think we've seen that a lot where the action is taking place literally waiting through the the the mountain of of coins. I love you recall that either. I know.
More panels. Yeah. Yeah. And usually if he's walking,
coins, it's on the surface of the my end of likely. Yeah. He's right inside. Yeah. Right. And it's usually just just Scrooge
himself.
So
and a nice touch on the next page is that Donald
says that he'd better leave this money here or it will be safe and and sc is just lee at it with the g
expression Severino saying sure petroleum, It belongs here.
And and so Donald gets what he wanted. Scrooge is taking him he will. Key and Scrooge are going to dinner and Scrooge
suggests the writ which is just the generic classy restaurant that every every city seems to have. And I was donald.
Dwayne, I love them walking to the that's donald had already dreamed of going. So he got his wish and and I know they're sitting in this lavish restaurant full... Which which I just like is the greatest little gag. The an entire turkey for two people you know, right. Essentially, one person
because Scrooge is absolutely not hungry. He is absolutely hungry for money and and can't get those that bag of what he thinks her coins out of his... Out of his head while donald just doing everything to eat and not talk about the business, the business and this deal that he has going. So far, it's working out. So far so good but for donald. Yeah. The dynamic here is gonna be screws trying, constantly trying to get back to the discussion of business and Donald trying to delay it and and Scrooge gets more and more annoyed. As Donald chow down and finally
during dessert, do you wanna tell us Patrick about the dessert incident
Donald is eating some pie, and he says pardon me his pie tastes fully. You phone don't you petroleum that she must status chewing lost his mustache, so we think he's immediately think he's dude he's gonna be recognized done. Right. But it but it turns out to be a little bit of mis direct. You wanna tell us about it. Yeah it's probably one of the more clever things in this story instead of being revealed it turns out don't with the just his big looks
tremendously like the world's second rich Duffy is in town at balloon, and en happen to save a pick sure of the duke from the right table this morning. Shows in malone here. And it does look just like donald and and donald is blurry b. That mode looks just like me. I'm Severino
it's a very, like, unlikely high concept
Yeah. The changes.
But it is very funny. And
let's see nineteen fifty
three. I'm trying to remember is the actual
story we we just covered it in the podcast. The actual second rich stock is in nineteen fifty six. Would hurt.
Right. It it came out in fifty six. Right? The first time we seen with the ball of urine, that story? Yeah. Yeah. It's great story. So it's it's interesting. Right? We've... Because we've got... We we have the story the second richest duck. And and you gotta wonder if, like, one of these stories kinda led into the other that it's just something he seems to have been kicking around at this time. Yeah. Because we just covered the podcast just a couple weeks ago covered the actual story, the second.
And we had the
One the ten page with Raja. The according Gladstone.
Wasn't he also, like buying to be richest that time. I don't think Huey, Severino actually... Yeah. I don't think they ever measure the Yeah. Right competing the statue she making bigger ones. So the my was thought he was just rich Scrooge.
Fifty one. Yeah. Yeah. And that that's an all time favorite mind. That's usually
that's the first comic book that I ever read. It was a great first story for Yeah. It definitely... It definitely hooked me.
So after that little bit of mis action, they're kinda talking up how big their deals are
they're they're talking up how big their deals are gonna run. And And you guys, I have to just kinda read the sequence because very funny as.
He he says Donald says let's discuss that deal because he still has stall until sp pays the bill. And screws says I'm sure it will run into trillions of dollars due. And Donald toss is off quad trillions of dollars my dear Mick duck. Perhaps even sep trillions of dollars, and then the waiter she officially comes up and says You gentlemen make me almost ashamed to present this pew bill for nine dollars and seventy three.
And and both of them
look in horror
at the bill, but but for different reasons.
That's right. Yeah. This is but we know Donald in trouble. He was fine until this point. Right. Because screwed
Scrooge isn't gonna be willing to cover the bill, especially given that he thinks he's with another rich man. That's right.
That that that one had been going for a little while while. I love the the first panel on the next page. They're both just... Now they've resolved just look out the window and just ignore the the the the waiter. But yes. Donald doesn't have a dime and Scrooge isn't got a spend a dime. And now the fund begins. Right. And on trapped Inducks a competition and who's the cheapest, you know? He's not gonna win against Scrooge. It's like even with no money. So still be.
Exactly. I love... And you gotta give props to this very determined waiter as well. Right? Yes. Yes. Yeah. The this this next sequence you guys is very funny.
It's it's a riot as they both just kind of... As you say, they compete to ignore the waiter and and hold out as long as they can.
Donald tries whatever he can. He he says he remembers he needs to to phone his banker and Scrooge goes with him, and the and the waiter weights right outside the phone booth as well.
It's worth noting Al a bill of restaurant bill of, like, nine dollars and seventy three cents in the early fifties, probably a little more than a hundred dollars.
Today. Okay. Usually. Usually times ten before before inflation stuck about times ten was a good
rough guess for a lot of.
Were Nickel... Yeah. Yeah. Which as the candy board today. Yeah. Yeah. Not not everything
appreciates Al the same rate, obviously.
But but it's very funny. They stretch it out and stretch it out. Warren you wanna tell us about later much later.
So they're they're both now back at the table after trying every or dialed. Trying everything,
and they both think grown and sci nine dollars and seventy three cents And then the closing time, I love the shot of the waiter again. These he is absolutely
not giving up the bill gentleman. He's beautifully drawing ink U. He's beautifully dry. He it that it reminds me of of some of the waiter actors character actors of the fifties and I can't remember who he looks like, but there's this... There's this recognition in him but he's tough but he's also very elegant and so I I really like what the way he's drawn. But he he will not let that get out of their booth his place
go away. Can't you see we're talking business Al a great line. That's good. It's a great line.
It's funny to see that weight getting more severe and stern Al the night goes on. It is. It is. Patrick, do you wanna tell us about after closing time? Yeah. So donald thinks the Scrooge the sleeve now this chance to sneak away, but when he tries, suffering so that old fox tied my leg to the chair and falls crashed. For the ground. Got beautiful silhouette panels those two pounds. And then the story wraps up pretty quickly at this point. We're we're at page ten,
and
this kind of farce
has to end the only way that it can end with the the real case of mistaken and identity walking in the door, the the waiter
kind of triumphant
points out gentlemen,
the duke of baloney, and
Donald tries to play it off as him being right. Him being an imp, but Scrooge just realized who is is really the Imp.
I I... I'm... I am cracking up at this closing gag here.
I love what screwed does so much, Patrick. Do you wanna tell us about about?
Who isn't willing to spend nine dollars and change nine dollars and change for dinner. For this immediately
willing to pull out a million bucks and buy the restaurant just so we can go mcdonald's and control things
slammed a million dollars So the whole time we had all this money in this pocket. It shows how it impossible it is to try out box Scrooge when it comes to money.
First thing I thought of two Patrick. Oh my gosh. That was great, great gig. Yes. And and this way, Scrooge
force him to, you know, wash the dishes
for that debt. And I and I guess, you know, in Scrooge Dot mind too, like, he's not gonna lose money because now at the restaurant is an asset technically yeah. It's gonna make a model. But but that's that's more thinking than you need to do for this gag because it's just... It's it's funny, how spite he is about it. And then, Warren, how does it wrap up? Yeah, you can see
he's in the kitchen watching dishes again, which is great. And
asked the chef, the... Can I use the phone sure calls Huey, Dewey and Louie back home? Have you eaten that canada of beans and the cupboard? You don't want them? Well, save them for me because I'm sure going to enjoy them when I get out of here next Friday.
Right Look the look on his face is is very It's brilliant. He's he's bad he's exhausted. Yeah.
Onions or potatoes. Yeah. He's just on the floor. And it's a wonderful... Again, Al classic ring Barks the
Which you introduced earlier Al sort of that final impact on it's always gonna eat anyway. And he's now well after Christmas. Right. It it is a fun gag, but it's not nearly as strong as the one that preceded it, you know, that's that to me is kind of the real Scrooge
they're ripping out that lot of money and slapping on table. Totally agree. All he had to do is... I don't know how many bills he's got. They're bright thousand dollar bills. Right? Or whatever. But...
Yeah. He was just counting them. And interestingly, we don't ever see, like, he... Barks doesn't close the circle of of Scrooge
discovering what was really in that bag. Not that it's like that sentence for anything. But, you know, usually, you'd wanna see the character reaction, I think. I love how Scrooge lourdes over donald with the the note the bill and then I
petroleum.
He completes the the name Gag in Donald
right face there. Yeah. So I I think this one is is really funny. I don't think it's like an all time class. But I do think it's a very strong Chris the story.
There's some great manic energy
and this one. Yeah. It feels like it's like a
slaps stick movie comes
feeling. Like you said, like a fifties,
yeah. Great description almost like on an early stu short. I mean, it's really
that yeah very well well paced and and funny the visual gigs. Yeah And it's fun to see Donald kind of starting out as hyper competent and.
And then things kind of just spiral out of control for him
through his own fault. Right?
I really like this one. I I didn't remember this one all that well. And and I had a lot of fun revisiting this. Yeah. Yeah. Really Barks could do it alone this period time this story right So let let me take a look at
what the community thinks to this one. This a pretty well regarded one. It's not like an all timer or anything. But on on index, the site where fans can rate the stories. It gets a rank of seven point four and a three hundred and ninety two out of all, like, forty two thousand
some stories. And if you just break out the Barks ten pages,
that puts it... It it does creep right into the top fifty of of his ten pager or in the top twenty percent of them basically.
Me, that's that's pretty good ranking. I don't think this is one that anyone mis.
It's a very strong story. Not an all time, great, but but very funny very entertaining and and very worth reading when when you're stressing about your christmas
this. So Barks, this was fifty three. Did he write any more long form stories after this about Christmas? Or or were those in the... Before this? Yeah. There yeah.
We've got a we've got a few. I don't think we have any of his that are like his all time class, You know, there's the black pearls of Tab.
There's that logging story or the do after a Christmas tree for the... Oh, yeah. Yeah. Christmas and Inducks, I think, is that one
Yeah. Kayla
lifted and legal boy still the middle of it. That's.
Yes. Yeah. It's a great pedro though. Yeah. That's a it's a fun one is it more No. That that is a full length one. That's Al full like. But this was the one we just did was a great pager. I mean, he got a lot in there and
and I agree with Patrick, you know, your your your description of Scrooge and the artwork there.
And just the scenes and the money been were we're really memorable for me. Is very good beautiful.
Yeah. Any other thoughts about this one, Patrick? Just a Al around enjoyable story. This
like donald is different than you usually seem at the beginning of the story. And then he sort of forced into his regular regular way of doing things just by financial reasons later in the story. Yeah So it's kinda a it's a little bit different because of that, I think. It's not Al entirely his fault just and have enough money to cover,
like, Al lot. So I'm I'm curious before before we wrap up this episode, what would you guys say are your favorite
Christmas Barks stories? My favorite by four is you can't do.
We did that one. Yeah. Yeah. It's a beautiful beautiful story. It's it's it's sort of like a ten pager and the personal nature of it. You know, like home story. But it's got to know that whole great thing with the them trying to guess with donald ones and taken and the have the test to
that was crazy mind leader. Yeah. Yeah. And all the cars at the end too. I mean, Yeah. All those Barks. Outside grandma's house. Yeah. The car is in the building set. Yeah. I remember doing that one with Sarah. I think Barks you and Sarah and I, but I I think my my favorite for a lot of other reasons too just maybe the humanity of it too was Christmas for She I. That's everyone's. You almost know that to me just that that was Barks
editorial a little bit on on this... The the the state of the world and sending a message, and I thought he did it very well. And the artwork in there. So... Yeah. Those are fine. Yeah. It's hard to go wrong with Shack down. I I do love you can't guess and point. I sure do love the first half of letter to Santa.
I don't think it ends as Scrooge. But that is that with the still steam the same shovel? Steam troubles? Yeah. It's beautifully drone. This like, a purely strong great.
Those claus. Green deer. Yeah. Yeah. It's in incredible.
And then, you know, it's barely a Christmas story, but, of course, the first one with Gladstone gander is just
one of the very the the winter time wage, the title they've given it. The the one where they go swimming and and half to drink lemonade. Donald has swim glad drink lemonade... Very funny story. Is his hysterical. So Excellent. Any any closing thoughts gentlemen? Not really. It's just a... It's a great period for Barks and tremendously drunk. Great character Barks for Donald two. The generous
thoughtful full donald turns into the I donald
all because he forgot to buy a turkey. I mean, it's just, you know, when he knows. Yeah. That was it. And I can't you can't beat screws when it comes to money. Right because it gonna happen. No one can. Not even even doing his weaknesses. And get the donald goes into the thing knowing that Scrooge is a soft spot for many, but know hang on for so long. Huey, that it was the league. Right. Well,
gentlemen, I really appreciate you joining me, and I hope that you all
have gotten your Christmas,
and I really appreciate
everyone listening over the course of this year to the podcast.
People can check us out on, you know, various socials with Bart remarks can be found on Facebook
and on Instagram and...
Yeah happy Christmas to to both of you and to all of our readers, happy all of the holidays.
Thank you please thank you Barks.
Three years. Yeah. We have a lot of fun doing this a really good time. I'm really... I'm glad to hear. I I've I enjoy this so much. We're happy for you congrats on a great year, and thank you.