We have
Hello, and welcome to Barks Remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge Comic of all time. This episode is a ten page podcast, all about one of his short stories. Get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Welcome back to Barks remarks. I'm mark Sever a Grown man who loves Inducks Comics,
and I'm joined by a couple of other grown men.
One of whom, both of whom love dot com. One of whom does great dot com.
So
I am gonna introduce both guests but
but I I wanted to first wish them a happy New year because, of course, this is our big New Year's Eve
episode, our big New Year's day episode and and we're gonna be covering a couple of new years
related ten pager.
So happy New Year two Warren Harmon and Patrick Block. It's great to to hear and see you guys again. It's they'd to be back for New year. We new year Barks. Yeah. It's going to be back to with two fellow duck fans and and this is gonna be fun. Yeah. Looking forward to it. Right on. So you guys are you
first off? Let's see Patrick. Are you are you like a new Year's resolution kind guy? Do you make resolution
absolutely not. You know, at the end of the year, I'll like clean up my my art room and three rearrange my books and put my old mail away, and that's about of it. The resolution. Very nice. And in patrick, you are, of course Al extremely well regarded Inducks artist who does
paintings
as well and and a long time Barks fan. Is is there anything
interesting that you've been up to recently that you'd like to mention? We were just in Copenhagen Denmark for a big book event book
signing and
signing
Plus or or gallery and neil treated us great. With this family. We had a good time. It's got to the point where they're like they're very much, like family there. We enjoy the trip so much. Get to walk around Cup copenhagen and take a few extra days, you know, walk Al beautiful city. It's like the previous one of the prettiest
big cities in the world. That's awesome. It's isn't it nice that the cons are, like, getting back into this kind of things? It is. It's very neat. It was kinda there for a while. Yeah. Oh, I know. I I got to go to Baltimore
recently for the first time because my my previous con base was Phoenix. Fan fest. But but I got to see a few a few people in the doc community. I got Don Rose there. And I got see Kim Weston.
Yeah. Alright. Awesome
Again, welcome back patrick. How about you warren
are you... Are you a New Year's
resolution kinda guy? Well, the older I get certainly, I... I'm wiser now, and I know that the more resolutions I make the moral break. So I I have decided to maybe make one or two
but here's my rule for it. I have to start practicing that resolve behavior at the least two months in the previous year in order for me to have a really great confidence, you know, that I'm gonna make it. So yes. I do. I I have in the past as a family we used to do it. But in inadvertently, it would okay would... They would fail after three months. So, you know, Sure. Leading Pat method here.
Well, and I'm guessing, I'm guessing that neither of you do the advisable thing of
challenging other people
to a penalty if you break your resolution because... Because that seems like a recipe
for
disaster
but but maybe funny disaster. And learned for Uncle. Carl to do that. That's right. That's right. No. I the whole idea of a forfeit was new to me and I... I I will never never ever give that the ability to my family. Yeah. That that makes sense. For for my own part, I'm not a huge resolutions guy. I'll
kicking around the idea of one, but I did make one last year that I have actually
stuck with. I'm so proud of myself. I... My my wife is always offering to make me salad. And I resolved to say yes to salad it. So now anytime she offers to make me a salad, I say yes, and I eat the salad, and and it's been great.
Sounds vaguely familiar like a story where we talk about. Yeah. Little food theme going. Little a little food seemed a little bit healthier though. So you guys...
This is an the ten page podcast, which are a little bit more relaxed and a little bit less reese search, but we are gonna do a little bit of background on the two stories that we'll be talking about today. We are covering the only two new Year's themes stories that Barks did, which are
new Year's
revolutions
that was published in Walt disney disease comments and stories number one hundred and seventy three. And if the cover date was February of nineteen fifty five, but of course, it it was released in time for to to be, you know, New year's relevant.
And then we're gonna do Karl follow ups from one year later, which was secret
resolutions
in the same title
number one hundred and eighty five
exactly a year later in feb cover date of February nineteen fifty six. And,
you know, Patrick you pointed out that well, the user the only two
New Year's themed stories. He has done some other, like, resolution stories. Yes. You know, it sounds like a noble idea for donald to resolve to do so many things, and it's just a recipe for disaster that you know, is gonna follow. So Carl gotta have that in his index cards
things. I feel there's always a couple of, like, earlier stories
Oh, is it, like, three dirty docks or something at date time? It's it three yeah
Yeah. That... That's a... That's a really fun classic one too. Maybe maybe I we can cover that next year around this time. But
but you know, I think it's really appropriate to stick with the holiday themed stories.
You guys these are... We'll mention the rankings at the end, but it is note
that like, some of the holiday themed stories they're not
necessarily his strongest ones. But these are actually pretty well plot of by the community. So we'll we'll talk at the end about what
how they're regarded by fans on Inducks and then maybe we can check in and and see which one, the three of us.
Things is the more successful
of these two stories.
Like a plan. Yeah. So gentlemen, I think that it makes the most sense to go chronological.
Right? Start with the earlier story...
Excuse me, New year's
revolution first Alright. So starting off, I'm gonna point out to you guys really quick that I'm... This is kinda of rare. My only copy of this one is a Wit po.
Like I guess that would have been on nineteen seventies. They're hard to find some of those.
Yeah. It it wasn't small. I It wasn't the the, like best of times for Disney comics I would say the Lit era. No. So pretty.
So this one opens up this is a Carl Barks winter story. I really love to see the winter art that he does. And we've got Donald and the kids basically talking about the quote solemn resolutions
that the kids have made, and and it's starts out very up upbeat very like, noble before it's gonna inevitably
send. The the kids are talking about how they are allowed to never be late for school again, you know, to to just go straight to school without any fuss around
And
Donald is, like,
unusually
pride of them. I would say, and this one he's talking about how... You know, what a great Oh, I like the quote the
Lincoln and washington and simplicity.
Patrick. Do you wanna... Do you wanna tell us Patrick the little quote that he gives them about how proud is. Yes. They they tell donald that they're never going be late for school again. He's that is a noble resolve. That is the kind of rugged hero that makes Lincoln and Washington's growing boys. I think that's like the best line in the story Yeah. Great. And pretty cute. Considering the time too it was such perfect timing for the popularity of those two presidents and in the in America, and they were frame pictures on my first grade classroom, and that was Al little bit later, but still
I remember calling out Lincoln and Washington. Al beautiful yes you can feel like Carl... Curtains Carl Barks and a a level of sarcasm so you can question of that as well.
Yeah. Right. Right. Yeah. He even he even gives them this nice warm pad on the head. This is about this is about the kind and most respectful he's gonna be in this whole story before it just ends.
Kids have those cute hats on. Oh, is that great? I love their winter outfits.
Again, have like that. And and then here's where it takes a very donald turn. He makes an
advisable
value to never again lose his temper and Any you know, the kids warren they they respond exactly as you would expect. They do to this. You gonna tell us about it. Well, first of all, they they say what we're all thinking that that's impossible. Number two, they're literally concerned for his health. Because his blood pressure will go up the deal. He won't or survive if he doesn't blow his stack once in a while, so I love this part because you know right away. We're setting up for the story. Yeah those.
Yeah. This is the perfect setup for a character
Donald Duck, who is like best known for plumbing his top.
So on on the next page, the kids they
introduce the idea of the fourth fit. In case they break their promise.
And for whatever reason, they say that they'll pick... It's established the they'll pick mcdonald's for fit later. So so they agree that their penalty can be washing dishes for a whole month if they break their valve Donald again is very proud of them for this you know, noble
pledge.
What do you guys think of how how quickly
Donald
resolves to... Help them break their resolution.
Well, what what direct me first what struck me was that he's the good uncle at the beginning. And then he's suddenly on this incredibly what would you see him doing a lot of the stories.
One up shipping he's gonna be challenging them so that he that he wins and they lose and it it's so uncle like, you know, it's it's
It's it's now their pure in a way. So it happens pretty quickly. It's very abrupt. It is a little abrupt. It's it's it's a abrupt enough to me that I find it just a little bit jarring.
Okay. But, you know, I'll give it these ten pages, they he needs to get the action going pretty quickly. And and we do transition pretty quickly
to the Nephews
heading to school the next day. This is a really fun sequence. Do you do you wanna tell us about this one Patrick?
Really huge shot of them in snow escape, you know. That kinda scam bring along and doing results. Kinds of fun stuff and walking across the fence, and they see as giant bird tracks with apparently of Giant bird tracks on Creek bank and of course they're interested immediately. How could any kid not see tracks as big as them and not month to Al of them? One of them says, I wonder if to over must be ten feet tall a picture of the picture
the acute picture of a big gigantic birds snip boot wires, phone wires, busy. I love it when... I love it when Barks kind of imagine these, like, fantastic creatures.
Those are great illustrations. Yeah. He tends to, like, make the images like, crown out the characters Al we'll always really a does that. Yeah. Way the image of the bird is so big that it's, like, pushing against the if pieces it's right. Well, as they imagine this feature that that is so well
described visually
immediately
Bark does the right thing he takes us to the orphanage income. You know, the well the children are and that's where the nephews
absolutely now must be the heroes of the story. And forget the New year's resolution, we better save Inducks. That that's what I str is instruct me as the as a perfect way to move the story along. Right. He introduces a little bit of steaks for them
to to let them get sucker into what is gonna be an obvious ploy. Right. And and the orphanage makes donald look worse. Oh, if it makes it look horrible. Oh my god. Goodness. Right. And and it is worth noting here that, you know, Donald is is gonna make them late deliberately. They're completely within
their right
You know, like, it's it is if you saw bird tracks like this, anyone would have done, especially anyone craigslist enough not to think that they're being
sn by a mean call. Right.
So, you know, they they continue to follow these tracks, they
they kind of
reconcile that, you know, the ten minute warning bell that, you know, they can ignore it because this is a matter of life and death
And they kinda follow the tracks into what seems to be a little box canyon. And I like the touch guys that they don't seem to notice that they pass right under Donald fake bird legs.
And when they see them and are confused, he explains
Warren why don't you read
the the panel here when they ask what he's doing here Well, all donna is doing is perched high upon those bird legs that they're standing under
and and he's just looking off smiling saying, just listening to the school bell as it's ringing, and that's the moment where the resolution was broken. Right. Because he has he has tricked to them.
And and and it... I think he's a reader here you really feel a sense
outrage for the new.
Oh, this is how dare you donald. You just scared these boys after them. With this monster that they imagined. And and now you're you're you're just glowing in your your t.
Is And again, the kids have even cute had on this time. Oh, they got the stock Gladstone. Yeah. I little.
Yeah. I feel like Barks probably showed them extra cute just just for that little sympathy play here. Yeah. I think too. And does things like that. Yeah. So we transition pretty quickly to the Nephews taking their punishment,
you know, gru about Donald
trick. And
one of the nephews
gets an idea when it's mentioned
that they haven't dreamed up the four fit yet. And and so they do approach him later and they say that they're... The fourth is that I'll have to buy more dishes but specifically paper ones that they wouldn't have to wash.
It's a nice... It's a nice little clever comeback. I love Donald reaction though two to the fact that that what he just did. Now he's claiming that they're per him you know that. The they're cheating. They're don't. Come on. What that's persecution.
Right. So it's just typical donald to just make themselves And I also like the r where Donald is is like talking to himself and reassuring himself that he's gonna keep a good grip on his.
Yeah. You is I'll do it And And so we transitioned to the Nephews getting ready. They're kind of brainstorming
how they can make him mad the way we expect that he would. And and they describe the thing that's gonna be the hook for the rest of this story that Donald thinks he is the best ski jumper in Duck.
And and we have... And that's gonna be their angle for getting them. And we've got this kind of interesting moment, guys where the nephews set apart a little bit, Barks doesn't usually kinda like, distinguish them. Right? They usually act as a unit. He immediately one though the reason is there is he needs that for the surprise ending sort of situation he likes me Barks always always tried to make the audience so that they didn't know how it was gonna no matter what I was like, a really important thing the decline is not... You couldn't figure it out on page one. And he doesn't introduce this it's well into the story, this the thing. There's no way you could guess what kids gonna do. Right exactly. Because because one of the Nephews says that's an idea. You too Youtube too man make him spill all over the hill, and I'll do the rest and it's really intriguing for the reader, isn't it. We find out it's Louie who who has this grander plan as as Patrick just mentioned and and now, yeah, Al a vehicle to move the story not only along and see how the skiing adventure turns out. We know something else is happening behind the scenes and we kinda forget about it during this than the next few panels would you like. Is that oh, yeah. We're is. Yeah. Yeah. I I like that too warren. I think you're right Barks has a real really neat way sometimes of introducing something and then taking the reader along, a different path enough so that it's kind of gone to the back of your mind, and it's all the are satisfying when he goes back to it. Yeah.
So, you know, the next few sequences
are are basically gonna be the ways that the Nephews
mess with donald and is skiing and and the whole way that that he's doing it that they're doing it, Donald is is
successfully
maintaining his cool. Even though you can tell it's really trying to him.
Wet these coming off and... Yeah. I love the hash Barks head too. I mean, it's just and grading the petite then and it's just really wonderful art here. Yeah. What do you guys think about?
Anyone wanna call out kinda of their favorite moment in in the little sa skiing, sabotage
sequence... Well Barks is clover enough to use his uses giant feet with the leg phone legs were used earlier by dollar kids get to use them to sabotage
Donald he they stick them on the end of the skis so he's gonna lift to Inducks having try to walk down the hill on and doesn't work out a little. It's like a clever reference back to donald bad thing we. I really like that. Yeah.
I think that's my favorite too because of the return to the joke that sent them to wash dishes
Retribution retribution right there, and there's so much back and forth revenge happening now, and it's just wonderful.
And and Mark, we pointed this out before. There's the classic rule of three here again. Yeah. You know where where there's the the tar, the birds in the bird legs and then the third one. Yeah. Right. And you chooses... Like them it tried tries to make it the funny one last. The bigger one last yeah it's the brand.
Do it. Right. I really like... You're you're totally right about. It's it's nice poetic
retribution. You know, that they bring those legs back and it's so funny to see him, like w about on those. It's really great panel.
And and Donald throughout this, you know, he he keeps up this facade. Of not being angry.
And and eventually,
the boys... Do you guys wanna mention anything else, I I don't know that I need to go too detailed into interesting how they can't break it, you know like with the regular the three gag, they eat Ducktales like because he seems like kinda crazy and the last with a pig, but he just not broke. He's not mad. And he's like hanging in there. And new disappointed about it. Well I got We got to the end of the last egg with the pig and and donald just joyful just laughing.
While, he's doing this silly skiing down the hill with the pig dragging and we're carrying him. So I went back and I looked at the facial expressions from Huey, and Dewey, and I and I just love it... You're right, how they just built toward this incredible frustration if there's that... And and the panel I'm looking at is where
after the bird legs went into the snow and here weight underneath you... You don't see Donald, but the Joke on me again. I love the country of the fifth of one of the Nephews
shot. Yeah. Sensitive
I'd be a wonderful to run down and little run and then there's two nephew standing the expressions are wonderful. Did you guys notice the panel where they they're talking about the props being set up for trick number two, One of the nephews says to the other, you know they are compare. Oh, yeah. Yeah. I had to look up That's like it's like a comp comp. Right? It's it's just it's not a very commonly used word. I find I found it interesting that Barks he he does such a nice job of trusting that his young readers are gonna, like, understand. In the second story, he does the same thing with the name of a dessert Right. Yes.
Yes. I I like that too. And I'm glad you called that out because I went... That's not com. It's here. It's not pure. I haven't looked it up and, yeah, there you go. I mean, it's a word I had not used. Yeah. I was on the boat. Definitely. So, you know, the other two nephews, they they're they walk home and defeated.
They've got these great expressions with their tongues hanging out. Yeah. And and they're kind of pondering what Louis was doing Al afternoon. As you mentioned warren, it's gonna turn out to be louis.
And and they're
initially,
outraged when they see him coming home with Donald acting all chu. And he accused.
Yeah.
Again, Bark is like
probably not a lot of kids know that that's a snake. Right? And they're calling him, like, a snake in the grass,
right.
Someone who's of the tray. But
so, you know, they said we've been working for hours to make him mad and he says, yeah, but I've been working
too
and he explains
You wanna tell us warren what he explains why it was important that he do what he's gonna reveal. Sure. You know, he he acknowledged to his his brothers that you made him look like a monkey on skis, but no one else saw him. So
so he just left it off. Now I'll show you what I meant. When I told you not to worry about the dishes anymore. And he... And again, the reader is like, what did he do? You know, he wasn't there? Apparently. Right? And this is just I love this. I I absolutely love this twist. So... Yeah. He off and and has uncle donald does. Sit his favorite chair, and this got me. He turns on the Tv he's is your favorite Tv program so specific
were on skis.
And the last panel is great because the reader knows what's happened. The tone it does... Right. Preview the next page. It's like the bottom of that last panel it's wonderful because the fact that... I wonder who he is really ridiculous is. We know.
Yeah. Do you wanna tell us Patrick what the Tv announcer
announces
Today, we have a surprise funny feature a movie real of the antics of Ducktales worst skier. And then even when he sees it's him, why that looks like me, he still doesn't I that.
He himself on the on the bird.
Garden bird monster
lakes. It is
disgrace for life this absolutely terrible. At this point, those reactions are all over the place when this last page. Because from, like, know outrage,
shop he sees the camera that does a louie really has. And then then then like a slow burn it gets very and bernie is it design done spirals. It's like quite wonderful.
Inducks injury. It it it wasn't justine seen Inducks
he's holding up the cache. Yeah That's right. He's fully up the cash that says I sold it, like, the phone rights
for worldwide broadcast and that's just... If that's another deal donald. I love it. Yeah. This is really fun. It's a it's a fun ending and and it really stands out to me too because of how our archaic it is.
Right? Because this is something that anyone could have done easily
today with the cell phone. That's.
Right But like, Louis holds up this room he had to rent a full on movie camera
you know, we we know that it would take a lot longer than this to, like, sell the broadcast. Right? It's been in the context to this comic it works pretty well. Sure.
And and I like, that this is about the mattis we've seen Donald get in in some of these comments
He's pretty. Yeah. He he chases them with, like, murder and his eyes.
And and it closes out with one and the after... The other and nephews saying you shouldn't have ported on so thick, Louis. Something tells me we'd have been better off washing the dishes. Yep Yeah. So it's a it's a classic
threat of corporate punishment
ending, which obviously isn't something you can do it today, but but it's pretty funny in the context of the time. Yeah Yep. So that that is our
first of these new Year's stories.
That I think this a lot of fun. I really enjoy this one. I do too. I I love the twists and I love the
expressions. And the artwork, I think, you know, Mark when when you and I were talking about the the last one I did with Sarah, something was wrong with the artwork there. It he's back informed now. I think. And and and and this is really nice. Yeah. Just one has some some great expressions.
It's a very domestic, you know, little little story and it works very well for it. It's fun seeing the docks in their winter gear and everything, you know, mixing it up a about. Yeah. It's a white fast story. I think the... I don't think that it's a money. Personally, I don't think it's these best stories. It's like very medium for Karl. Okay. What puts this is a meeting but carl stuff because medium stuff is better than anyone else is best stuff generally. So it's not relating so it's just... They can't all be. Number one. Right. Tier. Exactly.
I mean,
fifty percent, fifty percent of your stories are gonna be better than average and fifty percent are gonna be worse than your on average...
Yeah. And it's, you know and Carl, I think Carl peak was like because the absolute peak and combination of the riding we are just like
somewhere between fifty fifty one. And then for me, he like sides a bit and then about fifty six fifty seven fifty eight is another peak for me. Story wise. And it's a really great one. This is kind of meeting between period for me. And the next story is just before it gets back into, like, a little gear. Thought I think that just in general, I prefer the second store and talk about that why that is shortly.
Yeah. Yeah. We'll we'll get into it because I I think there are things I like about this story, but just not everything for me is as good as some of the other stuff. End strong. Mean, I I love help like that big panel he end the second the last panel mcdonald's really mad. Because buttons are huge. Looks like he gonna have, like, a stroke, you know. It's just like he's like really mad,
Right. Yeah. And they've mentioned is blood pressure before.
Yeah. Yeah. It's it's some pretty nice anger art.
Excellent. So
let's go on to to the next story that it sounds like you're pretty excited to talk about. Yeah. I know this next I'm I'm pretty excited to talk about this one as well. I'm gonna be reading from my issue of Disney,
Disney comics
publication of this and Okay. While Disney Comments and stories five sixty nine just before I actually started doing stories that that particular comic but cannot just be just about just before I broke into the market.
Yeah. Gladstone started re picked up after this after after Disney. Try kind of kind of went or his comments in general. Took a drop then, Gladstone picked up the comment again and I brought with my first. Yeah. I was gonna say to To my memory, you didn't you didn't have any stories during the Disney goose stuff. We tried to break into Disney through Disney through the mail. On the phone through the mail and got nowhere. We didn't get rejected. Again they get accepted. It was like it was passed around some the studio and knowing one we're make a decision And then disney... Glad picked it up back up and as the last ditch effort. We actually flew san diego Comic on, talked to John Clerk for ten minutes and he both the store it was are really weird. You know it it's like wasted a year, my life going to get published to disney. Wow. That's that's really interesting to hear. Yeah. So it was it was Glad stone two oh the. The second iteration of Gladstone, I think. Did did they publish all of the Disney comics that you did? No No Glad
Johnston did stories of linux. Okay. So you had some come out during the Gems era. And then, of course, E, is only
overseas.
Yeah. They well... But but only being like, probably fifty times the comments are published here. So much much bigger Right. Right. I say only, but what I means
they're not a domestic publisher that if if you were published... Yeah. Was like, publishing like be two hundred thousand Barks something that. So Europe like noise. Right. Just I think, know the point that we were doing month's stories that
make much the disposal tiny country and just denmark. Denmark, looks were weekly, and they were publishing.
I think in a month, they were publishing more than Al the stuff was sold here. Right. Amazing.
Which is why you still find yourself going to Denmark. Right? Yeah because it talked just to they're still compared to her. Right. Yeah. That's awesome. Thanks for relating that. I appreciate it Yeah. I'm I'm really interested in the, like, behind the scenes of how it came out. It's amazing to me I it blows my mind that Disney comics
who, you know, was like, they didn't only publish Barks stuff. You know, they were clearly interested
other publishers, or is it it it blows my mind that they could like let you get lost in the shuffle as like
section matter what we did, we couldn't get a rejection.
We we sent like, really nice letters, you know, cover letters with the story ideas and stories and try different things we tried shorts after wrong stuff. Tried the same stuff we sent to ads and john clerk took ten minutes. You wants to start. A year. You're trying to sell through doesn't. At incredible sense was really strange.
Alright. So
we're gonna we're gonna get into then secret
which is a fun title. It's it's nice and intrigued. And it was un I guess, when It was originally published, but we were talking a little bit about this originally, this is a a pretty rare case of where Barks seems to have referred to a previous story in this case he referred to the story that we just talked about. We have a pretty spa opening that we're not outside this time. The Ducktales just inside the house in front of the calendar
You guys
The calendar
itself is such a funny little background site gag that I'm just picking up on. It's really.
The rapid facing the hunter. It seems to have a rabbit chasing a hunter who's just dropped his gun. Right. But but Donald is mentioning that it's January again, time to make our resolutions and the nephews are referencing the last story that he made a resolution last year and broke it within a week and and both sets of docs are talking about have the each of them
knew the others
resolution So clearly, that was the problem
because it they made it hard for each other. And Donald has a solution to this, warren you wanna tell us what the solution is? While the solution is that this year, we won't tell each other what we've resolved. And then, of course, the nephews is immediately
don't find any fund in that.
And then they sort of challenge donald by saying, you know, how will we know whether or not we're keeping our valve or in, and.
Yeah. Good question.
Yeah. Exactly. I will we know And it it gets donald to kind of scratch head and say, I... Yeah. We can haven't figured that one out. Yet. It's still a deep sink. No. Not at all. No. No. I like I like the Barks is kinda
he's obviously taking the time to think about the ins and outs of how this would actually play out. Yeah. This is a rare story and then it almost entirely takes place in
yeah. I was that too. I noticed that. Yeah. Barks
is really setting self up for with a problem because it's hard to carry something with one setting. Just like a movie the same way if you just put in your house. There's just like two panels with the nephews outside walking. And one was donald looking into the house, but the rest of its fall in the house.
Yeah. I'm really glad you mentioned that because it's gonna be interesting to kind of think about the ways that Barks is gonna keep this one interesting, the little sign,
the ways that he's gonna kind of change
the perspective
to break the pace
up a little bit. It it's it's really interesting. The because of toys farming toys, which is kinda cool too. Ones got track one's got cow one's gonna pick on Scrooge. Because that was kinda fun. It's a great thing though pointed out. Gentlemen because
I I'm just kinda looking ahead and we're gonna see them change from room to room. Yeah. We're gonna we're gonna see a lot of different examples of of Carl Barks
funny background Barks
or his overly full
goldfish fish bowls. Yes. And donald the those very much into black black velvet with painting apparently.
I was wondering but
Right. So
so Donald does figure out a good solution to this. And and again, it it it's a great setup for a story. He says we'll write our resolutions on pieces of paper and seal them in an
envelope. And then in a week, they can open and kinda have a big reveal.
And this you guys this is very intriguing to me As a reader, I can see immediately how this works. This is a great setup. So
we get a little panel or a little sequence
We get a couple of very
funny. I imagine that they're simultaneous
sequences
where we're gonna get the the master stroke of this story. The two docks are going to independently
come up with new year's revolutions that that are entirely in conflict
with each other. Yeah. What well what else would you expect? Yeah. The one thing that I love about this story, the thing that puts it over for me, first of all, Donald what he's thinking about, like, what he's gonna do, I love those panels have in thinking. Those two panels on this page were he says his him his his hand resting on his chin if he had a chance. He he's like, you know, how their longer heads about food and how he's gonna know down that it was to do something good for the family. And the kids are doing that too. And it reminded me, I read this first when I was in high school. I know it was at that time because I just because I immediately
recognize probably ricardo source. First of them, you know than doing good trying to do good for each other. They end up doing bad for themselves. Both of them, and it's just like the o story, the Christmas story where the man going to buy his wife comes for a long hair and I both really broke the poorly young couple. Have no money. So he sells his watch to buy the tongue for his wife's hair. His wife sells her hair to get a watch chain for the gun.
They're really young. But but it's not a bad thing. You know, Both it is a bad. Thing but when they get together. You know, they realized how much they loved each other and like got emotional kind... You know, like, they both gave sold their was surprised thing to for the other one. And this is the same thing but kind of in reverse. You know, it's like... It's like a humorous, like a but it's the same idea. You know?
You know,
instead of... They're both trying to do a good thing, the food business. The back. Just like black first with the Christmas henry. So I bet, he had he with red that, he love the story and wanted to include that tricky business. That's great. You know, and I I'd love the the... I love the way that they wanted to do good for each other. I I just picked out that. I wasn't aware
the.
Very. There. But I I really I really do like the noble gestures that both want to do, the thing that makes it feels good. You know, it feels good. Yeah. I like that Take Patrick. I think I think you're probably right because I myself have not read the o henry story. But I'm familiar with it. It's like one of those things that's embedded in the pop culture. Yes. Nineteen o five. It was really one Right. I I think I can remember some like Simpson references where they make jokes about it.
That's that's sort of a thing that comes up a lot. So.
Yeah. I think that's probably influenced a lot of people a sweet story. This is a very sweet story. That's all the desserts going.
Right. Hey. So, Patrick, why don't you tell us what specifically what does Donald resolve and then warren I'll have you tell the other? Yeah. Donald resolves that the kids love desserts. He's always forcing other stuff on him. So he's going to go along and give them nothing go what they want food wise. And he's gonna partake too. It's just gonna be desserts constantly. Right?
Basic, simple thing. It's gonna try and make happy with providing them the food they will. And and warren, what what do the kids resolve? So as it nephews are talking and they resolved to bring peace to the Ducktales family, which I really like that. But their solution was to
resolve eat only the kind of food that I donald as always wanted them to eat, and that's potatoes, corn breaded and turn of greens. Healthy food. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Right. So total conflict with two resolutions.
And and you know, we we should acknowledge, of course that, like, these are not realistic
and donald certainly should know better than
than making this. It's actually...
I mean, technically, it's it's it's abusive to only feed the kids
sweet.
But but it definitely works in the, like, comic book world for the cartoon lo. And the fact that there's secrets which makes sense of hilarious
right know.
Right. So we've got this awesome
dynamic that is set up.
Both both of them are determined to keep their resolutions We transition to where they
they put them in the envelope. And
then as Donald hides it behind the clock, one of the nephews he asked, what happens.
And they bring up a four fit again.
And,
you know, if they're gonna... Barks is gonna go with that old standby washing dishes
for a month. And the nephew... An nephew even calls it out, you always think of that same forfeit fit, but that's fine.
So, we're gonna transition to the very immediately we transition to the first
instance where the resolutions are gonna be put to the test
Warren, do you wanna tell us about this sequence? Well, sure.
Donald launching right into it now. And he he knows what he wants to give the voice. We they'll make them happy he thinks However, the boys have this sort of... The the the thought bubble is this menu of of of healthy foods. And I think it's the resolution that they route. They're they're.
That's right. We resolved the heat carrots. That's right. That's what it is. I I can read it now. Care turn up and greens. And so they say,
a carrot salad boiled beats, we suppose mcdonald. Yes. That'll be just dandy.
Look at that as great expression they're they're innocent, you know, is what makes this funny. It's like it does only and the kids. They're in the about. Are trying to do something good. And it's gonna turn out disastrous and the Hub and the whole story revolves around all these thing con collections the Barks comes up with the the types of desserts and things the name.
I know this is the story, but what troubled me is if if Donald had asked them the day before, they would have said Gui treats and donuts and thighs. And they... It just it was a wonderful twist on the writing and the the story gateway way it's moving. I I really like you guys for for whatever reason, just the artwork of donald baking is really really nice in this. Yeah. So I I think that the order is the story is particularly
decorative
strong. It's like because it doesn't have Al outside thing to show other things and trying and hard to decorate the duct house and make it interesting. And I think that's one of the things I like about is the composition of the panels and things that was... You're not they're not fancy. It there's nothing really exciting going on. But he's trying really hard with the and things. Placement blocks. And I'll know that all of Donald baked goods they look very enticing. They do.
Tasty. So Patrick, do wanna tell us what he brings out? Well, he brings out on the trade holding with his hand probably like he's waiter. I here you are boys choco claire butter scotch putting banana cream Pine, and instead of being happy now. They can't do the go for of or
ever do to deserve this, since I right in front of them
because of their resolution. Right.
And and so here's where the resolutions do come into to play as you say, and the Nephews is like nervous
asked for just potatoes
instead. And and Donald annoyed because, like baking is hard work. Right? And and we get to see as he leaves to make something else
the Nephews are like I find the art of them just straining themselves very funny.
One of the nephews like holding himself
very mother mother like
where he's reacting to them about the potatoes. He's like, Al the nerve. Like, he's, like, mother donald and gets a feeling is like he's like this him now. Know. He's like right
consulting is wonderful banking skills. Yeah. Because Donald is he's he's a caregiver too as much as we're used to seeing him like as Angry Donald. He is also their caregiver, and so he's gotta do a lot of domestic stuff. I like what he brings out. He brings out hate
potatoes baked with special caramel custard filling,
and drenched with Marshmallow
Say. Yeah. That was that reference back to the last story remember I said there was a there was something in here it was similar
a kid might not guess. You know. Yeah I
say is he is he
the word moose is
Okay Yeah. Yeah. And so... But the way he says it is just funny and and and I can imagine in the kitchen while the boys are friday. He's saying, how can I not break my solution by giving them a potato stuff with all these sweet gooey things? I think that's just brilliant. Yeah. Right. And and so it's gonna go on this way for the next page,
you know, and and the key thing for poor donald is that part of his resolution says that he's gonna eat this stuff too. So he.
He has to choke it down. What do you guys think of the panels he does that. I think they're very funny. Yeah. It's there some of the funny or stuff in the story. Yeah. His facial expressions the shape of his head changing
his body shaking his throat. I mean, everything is throat.
And and Barks really zoom in. Right? Totally those Yeah. That eating sequence. It's it's all very funny. And and the poor nephews are just
subs on raw turn on lettuce leaves or broccoli stems, chopped with beeps tops.
Yeah. So So
everyone in the story is really suffering
right now. And on the next page, he just made it through one day. I mean, they're just they're just now going to bed. Yeah. Right.
Exactly.
Do you wanna tell us warren about the the exchanges at night that first night? Well, they they can't go on like this. They they realize that eating raw vegetables while go down loads up on the Gluten treats were starving in the mid of plenty. I love that line. So for breakfast snuggle donald, served pepper, you know, peppermint on cake and lunch fudge pie. So this is all happening over the days, you know, of the the next day.
And for dinner, I they going
that are that are happening. One of
about calls work yeah.
They some stand out for me. It's a chronic book a genius comic Al opposed to a writing work with withdrawing. Is the way because store is a good example the way he integrates visual gag like food the like in the last page eating, but even food up with the written stuff without it is the same thing with the you oh put them together like what you just what you just said. It's like, you know, you like... It's a perfectly integrated and it's better than if the underwriting or the visual separate... If you put it together the writing and Inducks of the food and I'm talking about it add up to something. It's like, much Right? Yeah. Because they're happening in separate panels and it it enrich the entire story. And they continue to plot not plot, but they continue, you know, Barks embed they and and they start thinking, well, they we can't steam open that we'll envelope and tear up our resolution. So now they're they're getting the reader to start thinking about how do they back out of this thing. Right. And you know what? Patrick you said there is like, a really neat observation, I think? Because I I was thinking this too that it wouldn't have been as interesting if he had shown
another sequence.
Right with with another set of food. By by having the nephews just talking about it,
it it adds to it and and the reader almost feels like they've seen another day worth of these things or or these other meals. It it's it reminded me of of the golden fleece when the la keys are serving up their horrible dishes. We act only see two of the keys. Right Like serve, they're disgusting and very funny dishes, and then we see two other Barks keys just talking about their dishes to each other, so it's... It would have been repetitive. If he had done the same thing with all of them. Yeah. Carl
reinforces rather than the piece. The reinforces is like a visual thing with words after, like, talking about it It makes it seem more real right real thing.
That's the Barks of like, someone is a really great comic artist as opposed to somebody just like the heck who's doing things for money. And right that, we'll just do it just go it out. And and you he like heck a person who doesn't know go this not thinking about it. We'll just show the thing and talk about it. And redundant where somebody that carl
the stuff in way that really makes for a final
artistic product. Right. And it makes it much more readable.
Yeah. You guys... I don't know about you, but I I definitely feel a little more sympathetic to Donald. In this one, then in the this is the point right here where the kids are talking about. No. That would be cheating This is where the point was donald falls.
Right here... Like in your other story it happens early on this start And this one, Donald holds out and here, right when the store is when he cracks.
Yeah.
Which is.
Not good. And I feel I feel a bit for him. Right? I I understand a little more why he cracks here know he's see by this. Yeah. Like he he looks miserable.
We see we see baking soda on his night stand. It's pretty funny.
You caught that. I didn't see that yeah. The making soda in the water about... Yeah. He was talking about this Pepsi which actually know what it is. Day the baking so it goes along with bit. Yeah. Yeah. Barb uses that term a couple of times. I think it's just an archaic term for suggestion.
As far as I know, but but anyway, he... He does exactly what the nephews were were debating doing. Right? It's a nice touch. They they consider it but resolve not to. He just goes for it. He he steam it open so that he can write a new resolution
and and I... That might have been okay if he had just done that, but he goes the extra step he buys on the kids resolution
and sees that they have been
resisting
his goodies for that very reason
And he says, I shouldn't few things to himself, it shouldn't be such a heel, but I'm gonna see just how long those little pie is can move up to that if it's Noble valve.
Donald donald is going back to who donald is. Yeah. Yeah I like how the kids talk about the plane
some food and their little. Yeah. Yeah.
Al letter. Yeah Right.
So the the story picks up pretty quickly here are you guys. I like that we just...
I like that we just see a quick little
couple of panels for the next couple of meals.
Donald says you who voice breakfast, Patrick, you wanna tell us what breakfast is?
Chocolate creams and with honey Barks
and then we store it. Yeah dent not bars with maple sugar peanut pie and for lunch we got good goodnight. They're just... They're just cracking at this point. They're really, like, just losing it. Right. And,
you know, the the kids
Barks narrator box comments that the kids are going to pieces.
Do you wanna tell us warren about what they're up to? Well, as they sit on the this wonderful fifty style couch. I love that. Again that's
house that the long lean architect the furniture design. As a is they are gru and and making them their... Your... They see one of the... I think it is sit down dewey we. Yeah. Dewey is saying well, I'm just trying to forget my stomach by playing detective.
He's he's sort of distracting himself with this this desire to pick up this detective mega find glass and little kit that he's got. I love that little kit the little little bag. Do you guys ever play detectives as kids? Oh, sure. Sure. Absolutely
and detective
secret codes and invisible.
It was a lot of fun, especially I think in this era. I grew up in the age of get smart and that was the funny... The funny detective, you know, the Don adams character and and... But then of course, just the know the show holmes in me. My... I'm sure like holmes fan attic and I just love solving the mysteries I can I could see this really being attractive to the boys? Yeah. So this is another sequence where Barks is gonna echo himself a little bit He has one of the kids
set apart. Just a little. And then
there's a little bit of a documentary
moment where he's gonna take some pictures.
Dewey
claims that he wants to try out his camera that Grandma gave him for Christmas, so he has Donald pose, and then he has Donald pose in his cap and coats.
And, again, we can't see it coming. Know, yeah, detected business. Capital right the around in that one panel we don't really know what to kick found out, how we could've have found out So they took a again, he's like setting up their ending surprise and counseling just like us.
Right. Even though the stories are both resolution stories, they really feel a lot different as far as, like, that ending coming even though it's etcetera
it's like just like in the last story. That's right. You probably did that purpose.
Yeah I think so. Don't feel like it's I don't feel like it's redundant from the two stories. The two stores are very different. Mh. I agree. And and you're right, he doesn't call too much attention to the detective stuff. It's it's not something. Generally, it Barks the stories is I think. That surprise thing is set up earlier a story. Both of these stories is quite late story mystery to. How
little twice like that. Yeah. I think you're probably right. I like the next sequence a lot. The afternoon
snack sequence.
Wanna tell us warren what Donald sets out for the Nephews?
All my favorite candid c
you're on the table help yourself boys. I'll do some work outside. So gives him a chance to to go out outdoors, but and then can become across, sir. Certainly...
That's great how this great how the played Across is bigger than the boys. Oh, yeah. That's right. It it's local almost
yeah that perspective. But they're really uploads in the in the camera. Yeah. It's it's very funny that Can come quite are are the Nephew favorite treat in this one,
It's a pretty obscure fruit. I imagine it was... I... I'm gonna assume it was still obscure back in the fifties. Yeah. I think the Al he would pick weird things like, the big boys and the pre. You know. Right.
I I just think the word come quite. Is is puts a smile on your face. I mean, it is that's funny word.
And
Al the candy them after all, no wonder the boys love them.
You're absolutely
right Warren. It's it's just an inherently funny word. I saw some comedian talking about words that were funny in the rules. And think words, I think you mentioned that words with a lot of are just currently more funny. Yep.
So
The Nephews, you know, Donald
makes an excuse to go outside and then nephew and watch the Nephews spy on them. And they give into to temptation, and he rushed in and excited announces
that he's caught them breaking the resolution and and the nephews
right lead question. How did you know our resolution and if Donald.
Go ahead, Patrick. It's like completely
logical that he says I guess it this like you... But the kids are young enough, I guess the they just fall for it. Yeah. Right. Right.
Right. He can pretend that he's guest it. I mean, reasonably, either of them should been able to guess the others resolution
by their their weird behavior the last couple of days. Whatever.
So as he goes to open the envelope, two of the the two of the nephews are upset because they've been caught, quote sticky handed.
And
and he confirms opening that the resolution does say that that you not eat gooey goodies and and now we get the little moment though. Or the other nephew, Patrick you wanna tell us what the other nephew you points out, do we other the other nephew very stu pointing donald how about showing us your
perhaps you not perfect yourself. This can what knows? No something. Half do we double half. My resolution says simply, I resolved to never again, wear my cap in the house, and of course he's got it wrong. It's it's a fun moment for the reader. Right? Because the reader processes is in that exact moment that, you know, has changed resolution. Never wear your cap in the house, he's got it on
and it gives the nephews use a little moment to accuse and it's cute. Yeah. And I think it's a very cinematic sort of short page
Yeah. Lot moving kind of angle on kinda sean's going on because it's old in the house. He's trying make get interest like like on the last page when they're faced with the big giant play come across, and then the next panel was done and was looking through the window. It's a very easy thing to do. I agree. It's it's very... It's paced almost like the end. It's It's much lower steaks, but it's almost paced like a an ag the Christie
murder mystery review
know New year's murder this. Right. Yeah And within the artwork, we see this wonderful I'm at on that previous page again when when Dewey is starting to sprinkle the powder on the table. He makes it a point, Carl makes it point to talk about the table and Al Donald walking off pretty much convinced he's one. Look what Doing... I mean, this is that little...
I have to look at it twice. I'll be honest with you to say he's got the magnifying glass on the paper pad. And that where that's where I it. Oh my... That's brilliant. That is like Al little bit of that what's happening in the background of a hitch hitchcock film was happening in the background bag is a christie.
Yeah. And when when he's pointing it mcdonald's with the cameras right behind him. Alright.
Oh, yes. Yes. Yes. Yeah. This one really benefits.
From
reread. And and so it goes... It's warren. The reason that you're talking about the detective kit. Right, is is because that... Well well, first off, the docs resolve. They kinda clear up that, okay. Yeah. Maybe we both broke the resolution, but Donald points out that they broke. First,
and and that's the moment that Dewey has him dead to write. Yeah. Because he says if who broke who, if who broke who's resolution First is all that matters, you're the loser on donald and
he explains that he has a picture of him in that camera from two hours ago wearing. It does feel very hitch hitchcock. That really does. I love this so much. This is just one of most brilliant twisty endings. I thought the first story had that in that's in the ski, and and that was funny. This is remarkable.
The way that tricky
and. And the nephews they kinda of wrap it up where dewey explains
that it was not luck or an accident that he snapped that picture but that he had figured out from playing with his detective kit That's
you know, he was able to to let the little grains of dust
rest in the pencil grooves in the paper and he was able to read
that Donald had written. I resolved never again wear my cap in the house. And we got a fun little cap of Donald washing the dishes. I love the contrast between the c and the box. It's just a wonderful that they almost look identical,
but very simple, great closure. Right.
In a in a story that relies on props a lot with the camera and pan, the the business that business with the attach is really beautiful Mh. Is the last page. That accounts that you commented on earlier. States through the stories. Like completely feature there in the last page the design and the accounts Yeah, The rich pattern, but it is a nice stylish one. And as you say, it's kind of the home base that they keep coming back to. Yeah. So it sounds like we we enjoyed this one a lot. Patrick, I know you were excited to talk about this. What what what your overall feelings on this one? I think it's... I think it's a solid solid story around. It's nice balanced. It's got good draw Barks good the background
things are important in the way need to carry the story through need to make an interesting and crowded. You accept this story up to be, you know, Al pretty much all of the it's a difficult thing to pull off and I think Al it's got little bit of detective kind of stuff going on. But mostly it's got that Oh henry kind of born I'm trying to do something for the other person thing that that virus on both Right. I think that that was the thing that I remember from the story that really like talking to you guys I've seen some
between. So yeah, I think some are around. It's not it's not a plus story, but it's a very solo
will
So which one do you think is is the better? You you prefer this one. Right? Yeah. I prefer this over the first... The first one is a little bit to lose some Chaos for me and the in the story itself. And then like, the gag are really outlandish and they tend to be... It tends to be... I think that for Karl, Carl was more like into this story when he do it, what the thing was the other one. Just my opinion. And you argue either way because of the store very close as words Al like, get the same general subject matter and Other has a lot more outside stuff and what we're actually going on, but this one for me better... And I... I I think you nailed it.
What what about you, Are? What what are your thoughts? Well, I I love both stories, and that's not my final answer, but my... But I do like the way he'd linked them. And I like the way in the contrast Patrick, I didn't even think about the interior shots versus the first story. I enjoyed the first story a lot.
But when contrasting it to this story, this is a more mature story. This is a far more
cinematic story we use that term earlier. The other one is more like a Tv come. Maybe a small cartoon.
If you're gonna put them into which media you would use, I would I would say The second story is absolutely
well so well written and conceived and what I love about both stories is that Carl Barks made the decision to have one nephew kinda split off and and and bring in the twist. And that that was really consistent I don't know if he intentionally did that. It's hard to say he did he intentionally. He had kept done intentional It's not something he did off way. It didn't usually pull that pull the climax x store having an enough do something like that. So I think that virus... Go ahead. Be Yeah. Probably does that in the first story. Right. Liked how it works. Exactly When visit it, and they picked this story with the same general thing to we revisit it. This is what I think. I I I can't see carla
realizing.
I I agree. And and I think that what what what he loved about the first story was peeling Louie off and now we're gonna peel dewey off, but we're also going to I'm gonna think about how to
surprise the reader even more
and draw in the visual clues even better because we didn't see Louie with a camera in the background. We didn't know he was there. But this one, all the clues are there and very much like I could cocky and story. It all takes place in one one setting. And that's hard to pull off and he did it. It is. Oh sorry. Move I'm gonna give to the second story, a little bit of a bump over the first one. Yep. Excellent. Well said, you guys I love this one. Like, I I read this. It's... This was published in nine team. My reprint was in nineteen ninety.
Two probably fifty six. Yeah. And and I read this when I was twelve. And, like, this was a great age to read this one. And I I went back to this one a lot.
I did not re reread the first one very much at all to the point that I honestly, I barely remembered it. I think it's a fun
even a pretty good Barks story. But I find this one just unusually...
As you say, Patrick, it's not like an a plus story It's not like gold standard, but it's very solid and it... Is a that's it's it's. Yeah. It's an upper tier story. It's in incredibly entertaining. It's so fun to see it play out, and it's it's just got all these fun little touches, these fun little elements,
greatest fresh great backgrounds.
I I think this is a delightful story. Yep. So you guys let's let's check it on the community.
Before we wrap it up,
because these are actually both pretty well regarded by the community, if you check on Inducks, the site where people can
rate the stories.
The earlier one revolution
gets a seven point three, which is good for rank four seventy eight as of right now And that actually puts it in somewhere in the top twenty five percent of Barks ten pages if you compare them, like against each other. So seven point three four seventy eight. Secret resolutions is a seven point five and it gets ranked top two hundred and forty one.
And so this is actually... It it peaks into the top ten percent of
fan favorite Barks ten pager.
And and I think that's right. It's not like in the Al time
conversation, but this is a notably good story and kind of unusual that the follow is is better. You know, than the first one. So really fun stories. They're both very
worthwhile and and
and they make a great New Year's read. Yeah. True. Yeah. You guys thank you so much. I think I feel like we did a pretty good job of covering
our favorite panels unless there's one that, you know, we didn't get to talk about that you really wanted to highlight. I'll just say and I think Donald
it stream anger at the end of the first story was really a highlight for me to see him it with the artwork. And then the second story focusing on donald again at the table while he trying to swallow all these foods. I think that to me, the the artwork
and then Carl is focus on Donald, the character
to see what he could do to exaggerate that body that face what was really put in the test of these stories. Right. And how about you patrick any panels have trouble like taking this from Barks and finding one one panel that's, like, a lot better the others are like. You know, I tend to like the panel to panel stuff and the individual panel. So we choose a specific one like, it can't design. Right. Like I like the general construction.
Excellent. Well, gentlemen, thank you so much for joining me for this New Year's
episode. I hope that you both have a great year
a good twenty twenty three and
listeners, you can join us again for more episodes of the ten page podcast and regular
Barks remarks. And check us out on, you know, Facebook and Instagram on Barks remarks.