We have
Hello, and welcome to Barks Remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comics of all time. This episode is a ten page podcast, all about one of his short stories. Get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Welcome back to Barks remarks. I'm mark Sever a Grown man who enjoys talking about du Comics.
And I'm joined by a returning guest host who
I I forced to talk about and and think about
Could you
introduce yourself and and remind the audience your experience with the Carl barb? Com? Hi. I'm Sarah Santiago.
I really first heard about them
and you started talking about them, and you're kind of literally my only connection to them, but
I've been... I haven't been forced. I've been willingly be joining you on this journey,
but this is my first time with them. And it's it's not necessarily
my thing. So it's it's interesting to get experience with something that I wouldn't have sold out myself.
Yeah. And I and I really appreciate your perspective. You know, you're one of my Barks Newbies. I think that's something that really benefits the podcast. You know, I love to talk to fans and long timers, but I imagine that it's interesting for listeners
to hear someone talk about the stories from, like, that outside perspective.
Yeah. I hope that I bring a little bit of that but also kind of a a modern take on
how how these stories have stood the test of time. Yeah. Absolutely. And And not something that I really think about, you know, I... Because I deeply love these stories, but these stories,
you know, they're they're from the forties fifties and sixties.
And that's quite a while ago and and cultural
attitudes and thoughts and more,
especially my own have changed. And there are definitely things about the Barks stories that haven't aged well,
you know, a lot from a cultural point of view and
I would say from an economic point of view, he he has a very
specific
sort of point of view. A lot of these stories. Let's say. And
that
listener
is what we're really gonna be talking about and thinking about today. I'm calling this
episode
screw genomics
because this is all about the
economics
the the sort of philosophy
that under underpins
some of these stories. And
we're we're really gonna use this framework to think about, you know, what what does Carl Barks think about wealth
and about...
What does he think about economics? What does he think about finance? And all the kind of systems that under it. What do you think Sarah? Is it silly you to think about economic economics from
in a in a funny animal chronic, but... I mean, if your goal is to propagate I the young kids, then
No. By all means to give them as much of your ideas as you can. But other than that,
So, I mean,
many many kids have have been
exposed to screws Mick dot as a character over over years. And there have been a lot of think pieces over the years about kind of the the attitudes that Barks has and sort of the the culture
imperial
that is kind of inherent in in a lot of his stories. I think it's really interesting. I think if you If you really think about as stories as an overall body, you do get a pretty good idea of what the man thought about wealth money and economics. I would agree. And
today, we are gonna use that framework to talk about
a handful of stories. These are mostly gonna be focused on the ten pager
a financial
and
spending money, but we're we're gonna touch on a few other stories that really go into what, you know, what Barks has to say about finance.
About economics.
So a a story that we previously covered, the the trouble with dimes will we'll likely touch upon.
I recently got to talk about T law, which is a famous adventure story of his and is you know, very focused on kind of what happens Inducks closed economic system And then there's a a Goofy little five pager
called something fishy here. It's a light fluffy story. But again, it's it's really an interesting economics experiment. I have to say I love that Barks did this kind of thing. I love that he kind of explored these big ideas
from a comic book framework where... I think those, like,
five stories, you know, was five stories. Think you could you could probably do a Phd
on them as these kind of closed
economics experiment Right? Mh. Maybe a masters. Maybe a mess. Yes. Now like, they're not true experiments. Right? They're there thought experiments because he
He's writing them, but but I I do think they have some interesting things to say. Let let... Let's pull back a little bit. What's which you're kind of... What's your kinda take on
Scrooge mick Ducktales
both a
protagonist
and
a capitalist
Ty
Cracked. Well, I think that it's interesting
to see
how the
about
have changed.
Time. I think if he were writing this today, there would be a lot more worship Scrooge
as a billion. Whereas
here it's just used as is plenty character traits. I do appreciate that in a financial table, there's a farm setting and farming as hard work. And he's in there doing it with everybody else. And so there's not an attitude
of
billionaires being better than
other people or other people being
worthy or less worthy of
to bridge work. You know, I appreciated that. Yeah. It's it's a much more
traditional
take on on kind of the myth of the the capital.
Right? Like the the hard working,
pull yourself up by your own boot straps. Definitely a different
form of blue crap. I think it's got
a lot of elements of
that earlier
brand of
rugged individual awesome right? Where the amount of effort you put in is the amount of earnings
you get out. Where it's evolved into a focus on of the other side of that coin. Which they're now more focusing on
where
if you are successful, it's your own fault and you deserve, you know,
or misery or something else. Right. What... What's that called when you got it in the
the religious framework? The isn't like... Well, the I was thinking the prosperity cost. Oh yeah. Let's see. So I don't know. I guess I'm really interested in the question of, like, are we supposed to like Scrooge mc dot? In these stories.
You know, I've I've talked with some guest hosts
where,
like, one of them mentioned that she really appreciate.
He really
appreciates the fact that, like, Scrooge is not really a hero. You know, you you don't have to like him, but he's very interesting. And and I I like that. Right? I I like the idea that he is just He's a complex character. He's he's really interesting. There are definitely stories where we're meant to, like, route for him and support him. But but Barks had him be kind of like villainous in some stories
or at least last sim static. And and I think that's why he's ultimately a pretty interesting character. So I it makes me more comfortable to kind of enjoy these stories when I keep that in my back pocket like, oh, yeah. He's not
necessarily just He... He's the protagonist, but he's not a hero in all of. Yeah. That's a it's a really
complex
situation And you know, again, I'm I'm marvel at the amount of complexity
in these, you know, ten page tori and how really
Carl Barks develop his characters?
I don't know if we're supposed to like Scrooge, I don't know if we're supposed to, like donald even. I think if if we're talking about whether or not we should we are supposed to like characters,
the kids are the only ones that are
five likable. Yeah. I think I think that's right. I mean, he my take is that we we're not always supposed to Donald, but we're always supposed to relate to him. Right? We're we're supposed to see our our
insecurities and our our weaknesses
but are, like, well meeting as well. In Donald.
And then screws, it's kind of the same thing, but but less about sort of the well meaning this and doubt definitely not
everyday. We're supposed
relate to him as a character who worked hard.
We're supposed to relate to him as someone who's just thrifty. We're supposed to kind of appreciate the I mean, he was really born out of like a one note joke. Right? Like har,
he sure does like money. Right? That's that's kinda how he like. That's the the reason he exists. He gave... He gave Barb this interesting framework to write all these scans. And when you look at like throw jokes,
where the whole thing is, he sure us like money, you know, kind of in that rich she rich. That... That's the joke. That's the entertaining part.
And so Barks did that's really interesting is he created this whole person son out of that that that is more than that. One notes
Throw away bit. So
let's
let's not get too into the weeds without talking about the stories themselves. What we're gonna do is we're we're gonna come back to to these ideas we're gonna be talking first about the story that's called a financial table.
And this one
was originally printing wall disease Comments and stories number one hundred and twenty six in March of nineteen fifty one.
That... That's during the height of Bark golden age. And I I'd mentioned to you Sarah that this is a very famous ten pager
very well loved and remembered by the community. A lot of people who grew up reading it probably
remember as, like the corn crib story, you know, because this was un titled, but
it
is if you check it out on Inducks,
the site that where where fans can
vote for, you know, ranked the stories essentially. It has a very high rating. It's it's number one hundred and twenty nine out of all, like, forty two thousand or so.
Stories that are listed on index. And if you break it out and just compare it to the other ten page stories, you know, they they bounce around a little bit. But in general, you'll find that it's well within the top five of all of his story. It is ranked number four right now. The the highest by the way, the highest ranked of those ten pages is the the trouble with dimes, which is another of the economic stories
that kinda creates this, you know, closed sort of experiment.
So a financial favor
I think is rightly remembered by fans, and it's a very interesting story because it really is structured
like a favor. Right? Let's go through it, and I'm just I'm gonna stop at the page break, and and I'd I'd love to hear your thoughts about this. Okay. I love that you just reached stuff and grabs your own copy of it. Yeah. So this this is
it's it's definitely Scrooge center story but it takes place from Donald point of view. And
he is working on Scrooge
farm. He and his nephews are hired hands
And we open on Donald doing something very very dawn leg. Right? He's he's grip about work and heating
work. And and right off the bat, this is pretty unusual setup up. Right? Because we don't associate Scrooge with having a far
The story is gonna make a lot of kind of weird
exceptions
so that Barks can help this the unusual story that he wants to tell here. And we kinda go through the typical list of fun chores he's doing feeding pigs and milk cows.
And we transitioned to the nephews who are like the voice of reason in the story. And they're talking about donald,
Their uncle
complaining about work as usual.
And one of the nephews
says
He's too young to understand things. That boy. And and he goes on to say if you're gonna wear warm wool jackets you gotta work to get the wool. And if you're gonna eat poached eggs on,
you gotta work to get the eggs. It's a very funny little bit of a smiling Nephew being Chase by an angry chicken.
For stealing a things.
Right.
And and Donald, you know, kicks over the meal, he complains that he wishes he had a million dollars, so we wouldn't have to work. And the last panel of the page is where we first see Scrooge, and he's chi him that if you want a million dollars nephew, you gotta work for it. Nobody will give it. So what do you think of this openings, Sarah? It felt very much like something that we would hear. Nowadays.
Right, especially with our in our current economic crisis with the great resignation and and
labor shortage and nobody wants to work, you know, completely ignoring things like
wage,
stag nation and how many people have had to leave the workforce for various reasons because of Covid, but the thing that again, it's stood out to me was
that Donald was...
So he's still... Scrooge is still
participating in the work that he's lecturing Donald about. Whereas, you know, reading this through our,
we would see
people lecturing,
you know, oh, you need to work, you know, but they would be saying it from their yacht. And they're, like, fancy
beach vacations
and wearing their
Gucci and.
Right? Like, Scrooge is right there in the trenches
with donald Yeah. Absolutely.
Scrooge is definitely
not one... He you know, he he is walking the walk as well as talking to talk. So, you know, I think we alluded to
the idea of the protestant and work ethic briefly
already. But... But that's a big part of what this story is about. Right? The the the the idea of the product and ethic really under ge a lot of the kind of myth of Am america. Mh. And and it's the idea that there's really something inherent
and and hard
just in the people that came that largely came to America. It feels very outdated to talk about now. It's very Ducktales. But... But this is like the myth. Right? This is the people pull themselves up by their own boot straps. And and that is the kind of character that's Scrooge legit. Right? He is self made
as much as a a person can be So I I really like the opening. I I I shoot... I'm gonna lay my Barks out on the table. Right? Like, this is a complicated
story for me where I I both love it and I have some some big issues with. But Mh. But it's very tightly
constructed. It is set up like a favor. There's a reason that the ultimate title they landed on, you know, is a financial.
Mh. So on the next page, you know, it it Donald continues to fetch
about working. And we get a very Scrooge interaction where he kicks him in the bum.
And tells him, I'm not paying you ten dollars a week to sit down, you know, think about a way to get out of work and Sp is thinking very kindly
about his net fuse
saying that they're different. He's gonna raise their wages just ten cents a week. Just because he really
obviously
appreciates their work ethic and their attitude.
And Donald has this very, like, funny thought. While he's towing some plans that it be so much easier to just go to a store and buy these dogg on cucumbers or whatever they are. Right. And and this is a a big thing among people who consider themselves producers. Right? That like Citi folks don't
understand where the food comes from, they're disconnected
to production
This is both like a funny
hot take that that has been around for years. And and I feel like it is a fair true is Right? You do have a lot of people in the modern world who are
disconnected to kind of, like, where does their food come from I I mean, I think this is a very fair thought and he's he's making the rules in his favor here. Right. It's it's a good example of going back to the concept
of using this kind of thing in a story. Right? It is a good teaching tool. For teaching
kids
how their
food is produced and how it's kind of been removed from City life and oh, well you know, you have to grow the food in order to buy it. And from
the store. And Donald is demonstrating that really well even though he's in the middle of apartment so... Right...
It's also a great dis installation of how under under a capitalist system, we convert our labor
into money and and then into goods and services, it's... This is an amazing dis,
I think. Of of capitalism a very pure capitalism.
Barks is cheer leading capitalism.
In this. Right? Oh, always.
Yes. Always, but, like,
this one is just the the top of the mountain where he's like,
cheer from the top of the cheerleader pyramid.
Right. Right.
So
the page ends with Donald pondering again if if he only had a lot of money. And then we we transition to the part of the story that I think was really the most memorable.
This is really cool. Right? This is wildly,
like it it definitely... It falls apart if you think about it, So we've got a car logic it up here a little bit. But
we transition a Scrooge point of view where he is
an immense corn that he's got out in the back of the pastures.
And and so we kinda figure out the the reason for this unusual setting in this unusual scenario
is it's it's another of his attempts to keep his money safe.
I I love the look of the corn crib Sarah. It's it's immense. It's growing under the weight of all these, you know, all these got all these brace trying to keep it up. And he's just
looking and saying how you everyone thinks it's full of corn, so thieves have to bother to look inside. And Al he approaches it. He continues. If they knew I had three Huey, acres of money in there, they'd go moon.
And and really interestingly, he goes on to say, I wish people weren't so darned crazy about money. They make me nervous. Now me, I know that money isn't worth anything. It's just a lot of paper and metal.
And we get a classic
moment where he does...
Barks is gonna repeat the through line that he used in the most famous fruit story of all time.
It's what everyone knows about,
you know?
I love the stuff. I love to... Do you... Do you wanna give us read us his famous line Sarah?
So fruit is diving into the money and he says, but I love this stuff. I love to dive around in it like a corpus,
and burrow through it like a go for and toss it up and let it hit me on the head,
which she's
doing it it seems to not hurt him.
Right. This is
big. It's a big part of the myth of Scrooge.
Right. This is this is what he loves to do. This is the hook that Barks used in only a plural man
and he keeps it here. He doesn't always repeat these elements from stories. But but it's pretty I remember them... It's what I remember most
from duck.
Right. And one of the things that I found interesting
was if at first I read though, I wish people weren't so darn crazy about money they make me nervous as projection.
As him accusing others
of the thing that he fully em himself and then it will get to it later, but He does
confirm.
It's it's not greed that motivates him, which is what it feels like in every other Scrooge story. It's just that you know, if he loved to swim around in raspberries,
he'd just accumulate a lot of raspberries
if he loved to
swim around In yard, he'd swim around in a bunch of yarn, like, it's... This one it's it makes very clear that he's not in it for the grade. He's in it for the sensory pleasure
of
jumping in and out of it like a purpose.
Right. That is a big motivator of his. And and you know, Barks isn't known for his consistency. But but one of the things that he goes back to a few times.
And and that you you almost... He doesn't always say this directly, but he writes around the fact that for Scrooge dot, the
the joy and his money and then what Huey, accumulated is that it's connected to the memories of how he acquired it. He has these memories that are attached to specific coins. Barks brings this up in, like, his kind of origin story. From uncle Scrooge number one. So that kinda makes to as canon as it can be. You know. And anyone always be consistent with that but it's usually a through line in these stories. And and it's how most fans read them that that yes, he's greedy. Yes. He loves money.
Specifically he loves his money
because of of how he got it. So So the next sequence of the story is the Glad Gander sequence. Right? Got Gladstone is is Donald Lucky Cousin. You've gotten to see him a few times in these stories. I've noted before that Barb hates flat stuff. Right? It's like it's a it's a creation of his. That you can tell. He just he does not like him. He doesn't like his ethos and what he represents. And I think he's kind of meant to be like the the Devil Donald shoulder. Egg him on talking about how, yes, he hates where Gladstone never works. He doesn't have to.
And kind of b about how he could have a million dollars if he just wished for it. He could hold out his hat. It would fill up with money. And so it
where Donald
abandoned his whole. I I like that. I like that panel where it says get away from me.
It's it's it's a funny little bit. Even without thinking about how people could could mis interpret that. But he he joins with Glad stone. You can tell that he's kinda open to his way of thinking and he's hoping that maybe Glad will wish for enough money
that neither of them have to experience
dr jury. And we transitioned to
maybe the most memorable
segment of the story where the nephew see these black clouds gathering
that form into a tornado.
And, Sarah, do you wanna tell us about what happens
with the tornado, what it does is, the cyclone. Excuse me. You recycling loan touches down
specifically
in the Money crib. Takes it up like a cow and not movie twister
and completely out it. Right. And and screws, we can get confirmed that he was safe because he's checking under the crib for leaks. And and this fascinating. Right? Sarah, you probably know enough about to know how out of character this is. Right? Normally, if something
catastrophic happens to his money, he would be panicked and agitated
but he's very placid in this one and and when the nephews used to spare about how every bit of his money has been scattered all across the country,
he is just
calm and he says if I stay here and extends to my beans and pumpkins,
I'll get it all back, which is exactly how farming works. Right? Like, all farmers are.
Right.
It it is
definitely not how farming works it's, but it is how things work in fable.
Right? Like, I am willing to give Barks a little bit of leeway here. Because of the way he is, like, very purposefully
structured the story as of
In that sentence, you know, he says he'll get it all back not feel earn it all that. Right. And and all of it. Right? We know that the... That's ridiculous. Right? How can you get every penny of it that? We know that this is gonna... This is gonna be operating by
launch. Which Mh. A table, of course, is a story. It's a morality tail, and it's meant to teach less And in this case, the the lesson is about in industrial
drift and hard work. Mh.
So the the
The sequence of this story is pretty great. Right? We we transitioned to Gladstone and Donald loa and fishing together. And Donald manages to joel Gladstone into wishing for some money.
Glad says, he regards wishing even as a form of work. She's like, I'm just gonna... I'm not gonna strain myself.
And he says, oh, I wish a million dollars would drop in this hat I love Donald like, plaintiff to, like, hopeful look in these panels and then glad stones very alike une press look Al
indeed a huge sum of money
fills his hat
dropping out of the sky.
We learned that it's two million dollars or they're about and Donald is is immediately chimes in one million for me and one for you and one for me.
And he intends to get his kids and then travel the world with his windfall and and Gladstone thinks that sounds like fun and he'll join. But why don't you tell us what happens when he approaches the kids? The kids don't wanna go because they're worried about the pigs and chicken. That need their pin, which is true to farm life. I have
some neighbors who just took their first
overnight holiday in years and years in year and years and years.
So I know how hard it is for them to get away from their farm animals. Right. My parents have a farm in Arkansas.
With a couple dozen head of cattle, and it's such a thing to, like, coordinate
leaving them behind. So, yeah. And so the nephews, they they go on to tell Donald that that money you got from the clouds belongs to, but Scrooge cuts them off. Right? Because Scrooge
wants Donald and Gladstone,
to learn a lesson,
wants the readers to learn the last and two. He's kind of... He's very omniscient in this one. Right? He knows how this is gonna play out. So he tells them to let Donald keep the money, he'll bring it Al back.
And and Donald and Gladstone
go off in his old be fire around about with its number three one three license plate to
experience the world.
And then we drop in on other people in the area.
And around the world, apparently where where massive fortunes have been dropping into people's hands.
And we get this, like,
image of a farmer. Al couple of very stereotypical
farmers saying to heck with work and we is going to see the world. Just
abandoning their pigs,
abandoning their Barks.
And and you know, Sarah, this is the moment where the story kind of really
rings
untrue to me. I mean, first off. It's a favor. It's very fantastic. Right. I'll allow that. But, like, I just mentioned, you know, my parents on their farm. I think back to my grand dad who used to run the farm. If you dropped a million dollars into his hat while he was on his farm one day, he would be very excited. He would not
leave his farm to go see the world. No. I feel like there are very, very, very many American suit, even with given a million dollars
would
consider leaving the country. Let me try up. Let me do the math point. Convert. I mean, we're pretty easy math around the early fifth. D's. It's roughly times ten or eleven, you know? But yeah, It's basically times. I found it. Calculate. Yeah. So, like a hundred bucks and nineteen fifty two is worth one thousand one hundred and some today. So it was
before this, like, crazy bout of inflation right now. Times ten was a pretty good, you know, thing for most of the early Barks stories. Right now, it's about nine times Al less. Yeah. So, like, we're looking at times eleven, basically for any of the the stories from Barks Scrooge needs. And times is probably close enough. So Donald and Glad and everyone else, we assume each have about ten million bucks. I feel like with ten eleven million bucks any farmer is going to
upgrade their machinery or get things fixed
build new out buildings. Right? I told she's like They're just gonna abandon their farms.
Let alone is let alone Al we see coming up The whole world has abandoned their occupations.
Right. Like what this doesn't really take into a count is that there are all kinds of people. Right? You there's there's a lot of people where if you give them a million Barks or ten million bucks,
they're gonna go off the grid. They're gonna party...
They're gonna vacation Al day. There's there are genuinely a lot of people who probably won't change their behavior that much. You know, maybe they'll like, live... Live life a little larger, but but a lot of people do what they like to do.
Already, and and they they would keep on doing. What we've learned from studies with
universal basic
income is that people do work. Right? Like, as evidence
by the
that we have, right they have a time made a billion in quit Scrooge
hasn't even made his billions and quit. Right? What what happens is just that people get more choo.
With what work they do and and and they don't have to take the first crappy job that is offered to them. And therefore, they find more fulfillment.
They are happier.
And then, you know, they have their, you know, over here. Right? We have our month long holidays.
And then we come back and we go to work, not to say that everybody here is wealthy, but when you have
enough or even more than in enough, that it's
so
silly. It breaks down under
the lightest touch of scrutiny to think that people are gonna stop working. Right. Yeah. And and that
exactly what you are talking about. This this does not really
this does not really accurately capture human behavior in the way that I think he thought it does.
Right? It's it's... He makes the rules in his favor.
So... And and he's conducting this, he's conducting this cool little economic thought. Experiment. Right? And it is neat. It's neat to see it play out. It's very interesting to me. But I think you're right. Like, a lot of people
do the work that they do because they enjoy it. Or maybe they don't enjoy it, but the only thing they know how to do, some people if given this million bucks would do stuff that we don't
necessarily
mentally
think of as work.
Society doesn't count as work, but it is still work. You know?
Volunteering is is a form of work taking care of your
family
is a form of work, and and that's where this this kind of breaks down to me because it it doesn't really catch sure behavior the way that I think he thinks it does. Mark, what would you do is ten eleven million dollars just fell in your lap? Yeah. That's that's the question. Right?
That's the big thought experiment. I mean, I'd I'd pay off my debts. I would I would take a month and go see the world.
Just like Donald and Glad, I would go and see the world because I do love doing that, but then I would come back and basically figure out what what do I really want to do with the rest of my life? Now that I have financial security and I would probably
try and do kind of a mix of hobbies
and
enroll in some universe any classes to learn the things that I wanna learn, I would probably
take up writing
because I like writing
So, like, I wouldn't abandon work. But it... I I would abandon dr.
Work. Mh. Would I would I quit my day job? Right? I'm a I'm a speech therapist. I probably wouldn't quit my day job. But I would probably do it through regularly,
you know, and and and
fewer hours.
How about? You know, for me... Yeah. I would I would go I would go see the world. I would... And then you know what? I would come up and I would hire
so many people to work on my house And then I would hire so many more people to build me my dream house. Like, my
financial
fantasies
involve travel and house building.
Yeah. So maybe I abandoned work.
Right. But but we would both do some travel. That... That's where this does ring true. Right? Right. But like, are we just gonna drop Severino.
Are we gonna drop our hose in the middle of our... Tending to our proverbial cabbage?
Our pro proverbial cucumbers.
Probably not. But... Yeah. Alright. So let's let see where this takes them. Because this is the big morality part of this story. Right?
So Donald Gladstone,
make it to a town
intending to to ref refuel and get a fancy diner. But they find that every business
they
stop that has is boarded up has a closed owner gone to see the world. So.
And and they're basically
stuck in this town
because we we see that everyone has decided to do as they are doing very economically, we see these, like well dressed people I
playing with bags of money. Right? It's it's really hammering
to us that this money is worthless
if there are if there isn't anything
spend on. And that's that's an idea that rings true. For me, right? This is the this is the first... The idea of the perceived value of money. What is money money is paper and metal
that society of agrees has value Well, and it's a warning against
inflation. Right? Like, we've seen countries
have such
inflation so high that they're literally carrying around stacks of bills and wheel arrows
and it's all they can afford to buy,
you know, a day's worth of food with. Right. And and in this case, inflation is is gonna be essentially Scrooge le or or tool to together the whole
So so Donald and Glad stone are reduced
to... Oh, we we get this like, little towns towns,
who says nobody raises sheep for wool. Nobody. He makes the wall in cloth. Nobody it does a really good job of hammering home Barks point. Here. Right? That that that's that this stuff comes from labor.
And that that is definitely
true. Right? Like we don't get these nice things.
We don't get the things that sustain us without people
being willing to work for them. I think I think where you and I would probably differ from Barks is is the argument that he should be well eight for them. And and maybe they should
reasonably
expect to be able to also go see the world from time to time.
Or do what they like to do. So
so Donald Gladstone are walking through the reins, soaking
saying everybody has a million dollars, nobody has to work, which, of course, is a lie. Right? In the story. It's it's it's an... It's an irony.
These things. Mh.
And then we get this... We we jump back Scrooge and the nephews on the farm where toy goes on. Apparently, they are the only one.
Left where and Scrooge is caution the Nephews to guard these cabbage Louie won't be long till they're the only cabbage left.
And likewise he he
cha sizes dewey to guard the eggs, it won't be long to they're the only eggs slash. And it's the same line repeated for emphasis. Right. It gives the weapons.
Mh.
Which is
scary.
Yeah. It... It's definitely a little bit disarming to see children being given weapons.
Guns. And compared to being prepared to fight for resources.
Yeah. One of them is an old blonde bus kind of a economically old looking gun. Yeah.
But then the other is just an outright shotgun on But, you know, at the same time, this is also not odd even today on, like a farm. Right. Guns
guns are necessary
on Barks.
Pardon they? It it is hard to be a farmer. Whose
live
is subject to calling by coyote
and not have at least a shotgun done
to to scare them off. You know? Okay. So the danger is wildlife. It's not other people.
Right. Right. Yeah. Really
Yeah. Yeah. The average farmer is gonna have is gonna have some guns basically
for for that reason for boxes and coyote and and so... And that's not unusual.
So they they eventually
one day, donald and glad
stagger or Barks. They're looking way worse for aware with patched up clothes. They still have their bags of money because they're not worth anything right now. And he plead
to sc for his job back and Scrooge. What his screwed tell him? Sure. You can have your job back. But if you want breakfast to eggs a million dollars a apiece. And and so other people find their are way to beg jobs and buys meal, buy meals, and the narrator box tells us, does uncle Scrooge charge them? Yeah.
And we see this like menu board with prices. You wanna tell us some of the prices sarah. Cams are
one billion dollars
Cabbage are two million dollars.
Of corn, three million dollars plus to pack. How much is it pack? Oh, I don't remember. That's what Peter piper picked a pack of. Right? Right So much of packed.
A pack is eight dry court
about eight point leaders.
Sure they're so easy. Yeah. Yeah. And then an ounce of wool, which doesn't make you much of a sweater does it? Not even of the stock is four million dollars.
Right. So so we get the point hammered home, here. Right? That he he's the only producer. He's the only productive one around. So he's gonna have the market cornered on this. And and, you know, the, the fabulous part of this is the wrap up. Right? Eventually Uncle Scrooge gets all of his money back and things are again as they were. And we assume... Have the inflation went.
I know. Right? That that what happens.
Yeah.
And and, you know, we get this interaction between Donald and Scrooge.
You wanna read what Donald says, and I'll read what sp says?
You claim that money is worthless. Yet you've corner that whole mountain of it How come?
Scrooge sp says, you wouldn't understand Nephew. I love money. I love to dive around in Al like a purpose.
And burrow through it like a go
and toss it up and let it hit me on the head. And then Donald back in the fields with his hoe, says
disgusting.
It's it's it's a very pack wrap up. It's a great wrap up. It's come full circle
So Sarah, I think I I love this story. Right? I think it's very successful.
I think it's
incredibly well written. It it stands out to me. I have some some deep problems with sort sort of the like under underpinning, the philosophical
underpinning of the school. Right. I think it I collapse a little bit under the weight like that corn crib should have collapsed. But
I do find this very satisfying,
engaging
story
despite all of that. Well, what about you as as a Barks
newbie,
someone who's not invested in the idea of Scrooge is the protagonist and
I didn't hate it. As much as some of the other ones that don't
withstand the test of time are that bring up values
that are not my own I think as a story,
it is
crafted
very well. It's just that the the more is a little bit. Not my fake. Mh. Yeah. I mean, it it is... Let's let's be fair. It's a morality tail. So if the model
if the moral doesn't work for you, then then the story is not gonna be that successful. Can I read to you
a
a fun quote of his?
Oh, okay. Here's here's the quote I like of his from one of his changes
with a fan, I believe in Al letter. He said I was in Atlanta for a big comic book seminar in June and a week weekend at Disneyland for
Convention in September. I was treated like a Vip, but felt more like a piece of merchandise.
Oh, well, it's good for business, and it helps make jobs for many, many people. So that... That kind of like gives you a little bit of of kind of his attitude. I think that job create
that wealth
creation
in and of itself is a good thing. That's where I think he lines up with Scrooge that like Wealth gets wealth.
Alright. Listeners. At this point, we're gonna end the up. So just a little bit abruptly
I decided midway that since we're talking about two pretty significant ten page stories
that are them automatically
very related, this is going to be a two part episode. So
just join us next week for the conclusion
of this
episode that again, we're calling Scrooge genomics.