Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Mc Ducktales writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge con of all time. Join us as we have explore has longer adventure stories in their chronological publishing order. We'll talk about what makes them so enduring their historical contacts. And how well they hold up today. So get out your reprint and get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Welcome back to Barks remarks. I'm Mark Sever a Grown man who Enjoys Donald Inducks and clinical Comments.
And I am joined by another grown man a returning guest
So if if you can introduce yourself, please returning guests. Hi.
I'm Austin Kelly.
Great to be here because I'm a big Carl Barks fan.
Disney overall floyd got Monte carp but I was here. A couple episodes back for no such department.
And we finished that one, I brought up, you know, I gotta talk about big bin on Kill motor hill at some point. So that's what I'm here. We're back to talk about that one it's a great story. We are, and it is indeed.
You mentioned it. Big Bend on Kill motor Hill is an all time classic.
And we're gonna be pairing it with another great money than story today. We'll also be talking about the round money then. So those Austin will be our two, like official stories for this episode. But I definitely like to take some time at the end to think about other great stories by Barks and other creators
that have the money been playing a really pivotal role. And this should be a lot of fun because this this is our big Money bin episode. I think Austin that the money bin is like, a huge... It's a huge aspect of what people love about the Carl Barks stories. Right? Oh, I mean, for sure. It is just so
absurd
how much money screwed has and from the very start as we'll see in this story, which is I believe it's the first one with the money Bin.
It it just plays such a pivotal role in that Scrooge donald relationship and also
Scrooge versus the b boys. I mean, it just provides
so an abundance of really great plots.
Like, how many ways can the b boys try to break in you know, what can they send in to try to steal the coins the the... The the bills. And it's just one of those things that shows you, like, Barks was really
one of the greatest.
Yeah. For sure. It it is great. You know what you know what the money Been does, Austin is it gives him this, like, really
iconic setting that he gets to anchor so many stories
around. Right? Because, like, we spend a lot of time at Donald Depp house. And I'm sure we can all
recognize that it's kind of a non Scrooge
typical nineteen fifties,
forty sixties
suburban home and and he gets some lovely drawings and some fun ten page stories there, but it's it's not that icon. Right? But the money bin is instantly
recognizable. If you don't know
sp Mick Ducktales you don't know karl Barks.
Even people who are not casual fans
are familiar with the money been, it's a great metaphor for Obscene Wealth. And I... I've gotta a think too about how
how funny it is. Right? That, like, the idea of screws Dot, and his money bin... If you transposed
to the real world, it's... Like you said, it's totally ridiculous.
It's also, like, really offensive.
Right? That idea of, like, that much hoarding of wealth
it's it's gross. But but in the context of this comic, it's great.
It's a imaginative,
and it it really fires the imagination.
When you revisit these early screwed stories where parts is you know, establishing
the character and what he's all about. It's just so
absurd. He's just got so much money and you know, as we'll see, like, when the Beat boys try to get in, you do feel for screws, but there's a level
where you can look at that and be like, I mean, you have so much money, man.
What's gonna happen if they really steal it? Like, what I really like about only a portal man, is it at the end, like, Donald just kick Scrooge in the back. And he's just like, you'll... You'll be nothing but a portal man for the rest of your life. Like, you have no priorities but money. I really like that about Scrooge just characters. Just... It's so ridiculous, but it's just so rich with, like, stuff like that and what Barks could do in these, you know, early great fun
ten pages. It's like there's so much story potential within, but... I I think that's great. Yeah. For sure.
I like that you called it Rich, pan unintended. I'm sure.
And I mean, the money bin is
it it really is an icon, you know, I've seen... I've seen some fun toys of the money been before I've seen people I myself built it once in mime minecraft when I was goof around trying to trying to learn about the video game that my students were playing
It's gotta be one of the most iconic parts of these stories.
So let's see. Let's talk a little bit about the backgrounds of
of the story, and we are gonna cover a big bin on C motor Hill first because it is
chronological
first Austin,
we were talking a little bit beforehand remind me, this is the this the first appearance of the Bin. Right? I think we've got some other first
in this one or at least,
you know, sequentially
significant appearances.
Yeah. This is the very first with the bin, I think in in previous stories,
the money is just supposed to be in, like, a make Ducktales
or like it's speaking the the Inducks office building, I think I've seen a couple of times.
Yeah. So that's very cool. But, I mean, like you said, the bin just adds
that much to the setting. Like, that's very unique and and absurd specific to Scrooge character that it just makes this you know, this really fun setting so memorable. So this is the first one with the Bin
and the second story with the Beagle boy is the first one, of course, came out the month before, I believe
october nineteen fifty one,
a tear of the B Boys, which is also a really fun story. Yeah. We've got a great run of
just wildly invented management of ten pages here. Alright. So
few words about Big band on K motor Hill. This one was... This was first printed in walt disney Comments and storage number one hundred and thirty five. It is a ten pager. It is widely considered one of Carl Barks greatest ten gauge. And it was published on December of nineteen fifty one. Has this issued date. So we are gonna go ahead So big Band on Ke motor Hill opens up with the nephews and Donald
observing the icon building
Kiwi doing Louis asking Donald what that big building is on K Hill and and Donald is telling them all about it. It's telling... He's telling them that this is uncle sp money then. He refers to as a new money then We don't worry too much about continuity the money bin. Right? Because we know it's it's been the duct office building.
But I think once we get to the later stories, we're treating it as the the money then it's just always been there. And Donald is going out of this way to build up how Uncle Scrooge has constructed this building to keep his money safe. He's cleared it so that there are now houses so that you can see burg,
and he's made the walls roof ten feet fit. And as they arrived to their house still talking about it, they hear the phone right. And Austin, I think it's I I really like the name for the actual little piece of geography Till or Hill feels really evo.
Yeah. I always thought that was that was like a... That was just a cool name on Barks as part. I don't know, like, what that's referencing or what that really is just supposed to me, but it just sounds cool. Right? We're on the bit, I have to say, I really like that opening panel. The the drawing of the Bin just feels like very
dimensional and serious. And if you look like there's a dial on the side, like, there would be on a regular safe, but, like, Right. How would anybody reach that? And, like, what is it purpose. That that is weird. Yeah. This first iteration of it is clearly meant to look like an oversized safe. And it doesn't have the icon like dollar sign symbol that it's gonna have later. But but otherwise, what's pretty close. And my reading of the name is just, you know, it's obviously supposed to, like, refer to how steep the hill is. Right, if you try to drive here driver your car up, and it's gonna kill the motor, trying to get up to the top. That was my rating of it. Okay. Interesting. Anything think about it like that, but that that sort of does... That seems very bark in a sense that I never really thought about like that before. But, yeah, That... That's pretty funny. Well... And and in the the later life and times stories that dawn rosa it does, they'll have any little moment where he'll talk about the land Barks in the day
being called Kill new Hill before the advent of the automobile.
Awesome. So the next page, I really like this opening by way. Just a very wholesome
sweet way
to set up the story. So Donald picks up the phone and sc wants the boys to come over and check out the bin. So they're all super happy and they start running over. But before they can go up, they have to each take a card and it shaped like a square and then, you know, the nephew asked on or what they're doing. And it to show Scrooge that they're square guys, which is like fifty speak, which is interesting, but, you know, it's it's an odd gag, but it's it's I'm sure it's sort of a more topical thing that would have been funnier
seventy years ago. Right. And if you're square, you're like, you're like level, you're on the level, you're not not someone who's up to up to funny business.
But you're right. It's a good... It's a good time that's dated kinda weirdly.
Yeah. That you know, Barks is is praise because he's so timeless with this humor. But if you look into the stories, there are bits like that that only really apply i do, you know, the at the time what would have been present day terminology, but You know, it's all it's all good fun. And you're right, You know, this he's He's getting the Nephews hears these weird instructions.
Right. Because Donald has had to go out of his way to listen carefully to Scrooge
instructions And as they go up the hill and
approach the bin, they have to, like, zig zag around
Scrooge mind field. They then have to give a password
to get past the really vicious looking sulfur acid fill
it's it's a funny little password. It's it's kind of a money riddle. We wanna tell us what the money password is Austin. Yeah. I really like this. Donald speaks into the microphone It's sort just sitting there. And he goes, twenty forty gillian. What makes eleven nickel worth a dime a dozen, and
the draw bridge just opens up and they just walton in. I I think that's really funny. Like I like these gag, they're simply not laugh out loud, but it's They're just funny in a sense that you recognize it as a gag, and it's pretty cool. I wish like, it was always just complicated to get into the Bin because it really provides is like rich material for gag to open up the story. It really does lost. And and the last panel on this third page has gotta be one of the most iconic Barks panels, I think of all time and that it... like, it did a lot of world building. For how paranoid Scrooge is and protective of his money. Because once they enter the money been, they just see this ridiculous
array of Canon pointed at them. They have to lock under a port call list there are Barks traps and fly paper and thumb tax sticking up and other guns trained on
on him and and and it's hilarious, it's super over the top. It's also really, like invent and it fires the imagination Don't know if you were a kid who had, like, a fort were built any anything that you, like, really felt like you were protecting yourself against unseen
enemies who never came. Yeah... No. I I definitely get that. It does sort of invoke that, like,
childish image. And I think Scrooge does project that sometimes where he's almost like a child, like, he's so greedy and selfish and and secure. And if you've read a lot of, like, the Italian Scrooge stories, like, they take that to the next level where
sometimes screwed butler will, like, nurse him if he's crying or like, the beagle boy... Like, they take it to a really ridiculous
stupid level there, but I like this and in the Barks stories, you know, It is very invent like you said. Right. So the next page Scrooge shows up, and we get another really awesome panel on the upper right. There's just so much overlapping action. We have electronic eyes. We have a a dog on a chain. There's a microphone listening.
There's a random pair of eyes in the back, and there's a alarm that's just going off. So they want in this really nice looking elevator. And they over... There's this another really great panel. They overlook the Bin and you get all the money and, of course, there's, like a tractor in there, which has always been, like, common place, but this early on, like, that is just so ridiculous. It is awesome. And Donald over looking at these just like, what are you gonna do with all the money? And I mean, it's it's weird for Donald to ask him as if he's expecting him like, oh, I'm gonna invest it in in stocks, and here's what I'm gonna with. But like, in later stories, it would just go with without saying that he just wants to run through it and sue swim in it. And burrow in it like a go and that bottom right panel, there's a great pose of screws t through, like, it's, like, freshly fallen
snow or something. In the glad two Al where they printed this or they actually use that panel as the cover. So... Yeah. I agree with everything you said here and and you know, it's it's so interesting to think this is the first time that we're seeing all of these over the top bin defense that we're seeing this much money. Right? Because with them in Inducks office building,
we've seen him, like cram money into overs stuff vault but this is like an order of magnitude.
More money than we've seen before. And it also occurs to me that, like, I don't think Barks does a lot of this. Going forward the over the top, like, bin defense stuff. Like, he'll have stories where he's doing, you know, some other form of defensive that there's never this, like, big gone lit of all of these different defenses that I can think of, but I know that Dawn rosa uses this Al, like a template in so many of those stories. So on the next page, you know, Uncle Scrooge is just revel
and his cache having fun with it. And he asks Donald He gets in and mention,
you know, people who's spend their money don't know how to truly enjoy it. And while he's doing that, he asked not to take a look through one of the people's and see if they're any problems speaking about. And Donald is initially annoyed, but then he does immediately spot the B boys
on a vacant watt right down the hill that are bus digging a hole on the perimeter of the money bin. And Austin, what what do you think about the look of the eagles there? Yeah. The the big boys are not having their best day, they look a little like than usual.
You know, this is the second story that Barks had drawn them in. So, obviously, they're gonna look different than how they usually do
They seem very happy and, like, they keep that eccentric vibe that we know them for. But later on, like, they I don't think they would be this goofy looking and, like, they wouldn't be pulling this sort of a job in in broad daylight. But, you know, one of them smoking and has, like, his tongue out and the other one's just happily like, measuring land. So... And there are all of these very fast like, wide g on their faces. So... And they look like much more dog, like than they would later. So Barks is still developing that character design. It's a little peculiar, but I really like how they look here. Yeah. Definitely a little more,
like, ultimately how they are gonna look like than that first story, the tear of the people boy
Okay? So now we're really into the meat of the story.
We get that icon Scrooge
freak out. He saw over the b boys. The terrible beagle boys. And, you know, Donald
asking him what he's so worried about if he's got the bin so nicely kept and no one can break in, and it turns out that screws was too cheap to put in a bottom so they can drain it to quote what Scrooge says exactly. Now the beagle boys are going to tunnel underneath and drain my money out like beans from a leaky bag. So, yeah, that this sort of hone in on the the childish ish aspect... I mean, he's just sobbing un on the floor in and his hand is over his face And what I really find interesting is Donald is the one to take the the heroic stand, He gets into his his classic fighting post, and he goes, Well, you won't stop them by crying. Come on. Let's go down on them. Let's go down there and punch them on the nose. Which I really like, and that gets screwed going.
So they run out onto to the draw bridge and Scrooge has something really funny when he's walking across if you wanna read that off. Sure we get one of the occasional references to how much money actually has
And in this case, he says five hundred triplet Italian mo pavilion,
Q
quadruple
Italian,
send tri
Cent
centric
cent
dollars and sixteen cents being worth fighting for or his name not Scrooge Inducks. And of course, it's always and sixteen cents.
Austin I... I love this gag right? Because this is like elemental Scrooge Dot where he's saying, yes, I mean the walls ten pick ten feet thick. And the roof ten feet thick. But to save of money, I didn't put any bottom in the Bin. It's that great, like, penny wise pound foolish
you know, that he's his achievements is frequently probably gonna be his doing in these stories. Yeah. But that's a really nice way of putting it. It's like you know, for all his Barks, you would think he has the ability. And there's this is another thing that come up in the next story. I'll point it out when we get to it. But like, the fact that he's so cheap, like, is the re is part of his downfall Al lot of the time? That's what I like in these early B boy stories. He keeps it bin so nicely
kept, but there's always one flaw, and it's because he didn't wanna spend that extra some money on it. And that's why they're able to get in. That's where we launch that story. So it's interesting and it's like
Barks those these bits in in the early stories that he didn't throw in later just because I guess the relationship, the setups were already established, but it's like, I really like this extra touch. You know. I mean, his ingredient
will get to him. And it does, which I think is really fantastic. Yeah. So the next page is another kind of classic setup that gonna be a gag a lot of the time where they're so determined to get down there and confront the legal ways that they completely forget about his series of defenses and they run into the mind field and they get confronted by one of those automatic canon.
And they have to flee
back into the Bin. And we've got this nice little, like, Al our suspense movie set up here where it's it's indicated that he's made the bin so
so def
that if anyone did come in, they can't get out.
And and some got this dilemma out it's gonna take a full week to une hope all the traps in order to get out and stop the vehicles.
So, you know, they're they're mu over how they can, you know, get the beagle boys. And, again, this is what I really like. I don't know if this was because
the ten pages were always donald stories and not Scrooge.
So maybe I guess Donald had to play, like, a crucial role, but Donald the critical thinker who comes up with the idea Right which is You have to fill the bin with water, and it won't hurt the money, but it'll drown the beagle boys out of their tunnel like rats. That's exactly what he says.
And, I mean, that that makes sense, but wouldn't water soil those bills?
Always seemed very weird to me. Especially the way in the bottom,
screws is very
forcefully
shooting that hose over. We have a really nice splash panel at the bottom with the hose
crossing the band and some gold coins are shooting out. So anyway, they filled the Bin and they turn on the radio and it turns out that tonight will be the coldest this night in the history of duck. And again, this this relate back to Scrooge is
selfish ingredient,
being part of his downfall,
they freeze for the rest of the night because he doesn't have any sort of heating source because he refused to pay the gas bill. So they freeze overnight and they hear a big crack. And it's because the water that they fill the bin with has frozen over to ice. They wake up in the morning, Inducks is covered and snow. And the bin has cracked through the ten foot... The ten foot thick outer casing. And so the Ducktales crawl out from under, like, the rubbish. And the bin shoots down the hill onto the vacant lot where the beagle boys are hanging out. And the... And we end the story on that great image Scrooge chasing Donald with his cane because he had that stupid Id idea in the first place as the b boys are happily picking away with ice picks at the money.
It's it's great. We've got some really fun imagery here. You know, that picture of the band is a giant ice you basically
the Ducktales shiver around whatever they can to burn. There's a funny off offhand mentioned that Scrooge says he'd given a nickel for some if he only had some dry money to burn.
This is great. It feels almost like a cautionary
favor or something, you know? And, obviously,
it's all gonna be hand waved away. At the end, somehow,
Scrooge just gonna get his money back he's gonna repair the bin. I wonder how many times we could track companies
and he's had his been completely
destroyed.
Over the course of these stories. Yeah. That's that's definitely a cartoon or or rather comic logic for you, but I mean... It's it's all in good fun. The next story. You know, the Bin is back where it was. And I guess we can assume that he got the money back somehow. Maybe by, like, the police who I figured, like, might as well step in here. I don't know why the bin
sliding down
next to the B boys makes it their property
automatically.
It's confusing, but I I love that that final image with them just happily picking away and and Donald running off. Yeah. Great story. Yeah. This. And and, you know, you mentioned the cartoon or the comment logic. We've definitely had other
stories like like the famous only poor man where the money has to withstand its time in the water. Yeah. That that never made sense to me. I always read that story and I'm, like, how full proof is this really? Right. I I I don't know why Scrooge always went to, like, water and hiding the money in that for that story and also, like taking Donald idea here, filling the Bin with water. So Austin,
before we...
Before we switch to the next story, let's kinda check with the community
and
see where this story lands.
This one is regard plastic. Right? This gets a seven point five
on index, and that's good for a rank of two hundred and forty nine out of all of the forty some thousand Disney stories that are voted for on Inducks.
So so austin, and this one ranks really highly.
This is very well remembered. If you
take a look at it, as, you know, part of the ten pages that Barks did. This one is just a little bit outside of the top ten
It's roughly in the top, I think, fifteen or twenty years or so. There's there's only a few stories that land above this one as far as the ten users go. And and you mentioned this is a favorite of yours. You know, we've certainly talked about it. But why does this one stand out for you so much? You know, it there wasn't a ton like that I could I... Just upon first reading it, it it was just
fantastic. You know, there's that great imagery. And anyway I think it was one of the first Scrooge versus B Boy stories. I had read. And, of course, when you're we're starting out with those, I mean, they're all just fantastic. But upon, like, further analysis,
I was looking into it for this recording, like, there's just so much. We we already touched on, but, like, character rich and the the gag are funny
And there's just a lot of uniqueness to the story that, like, wouldn't make a return in Bark like Canon.
Again, of course, like they were the aspect that people like Rosa would resurrect because Don Rosa is Don Rose and He's gonna pull out every little bit of classic Barks and make twenty thousand stories out of it and But not as possible. Yeah. Treated is gospel
exactly. But no. I always thought this one was just great because
Like I said, I really always like donald. Even if his plan doesn't work out, I like him taking a stand himself and, like, I've got a great idea. And and even more so that, like, Scrooge goes with it. Again, it all fails, but at least he's trying. He might he might be incompetent but he's persistent incompetent little Inducks, you know? Right. And he's very well meaning this I think the reason this one stands out for a lot of fans is probably because more than almost
almost any other story. It just does so much world build. And Barks was he was not very consistent. You know, he loved to tell great stories so he changed things around. He he made characters
behave differently from story to story if he needed someone to be a little bit more coward in one story and brave and another. That's fine by him. And it's obviously fine by the readers. But it is nice to have some consistency and and this really does establish a lot about the character. Mh. No I definitely agree.
But I have to say, I think a lot of that inconsistency is sort of... What makes your story so memorable it they don't stick to that character formula. Right? I don't remember who said this. So this isn't my original thought, but but someone online said Barks understood people are humans And just from day to day, they'll change their motives
or, you know, what they wanna be or how they'll treat certain people or different things. Like, that's what i really like about the ten pages. If you read them how I do, sort of chronological through the original dell books, like, from month to month Donald is a completely different character every time, You know? Which I really like. I mean, they're, of course sort of types of the forms of Donald that would come back again and again, like, you know, the Donald who thinks he can master her job that he's horrible at and the Donald who's sort of like, Scrooge just lack and the donald who's the the well meaning uncle and... But anyway, there's just so much variety in those stories. I really like that about the Barks stories overall. Yeah. The characters definitely
contain.
So I think the best way to transition into our next story the the round money been is to just kind of acknowledge that over the years and over the stories,
Sp is gonna constantly
trying new ways and different ways to protect his money. Right? It says overriding of obsession. It is his his joy and his purse because he has so much money and he keeps it so
liquid, I guess that that it's it's always this tremendous pain in the platform to deal with. So one of the ways, one of the many times he's gonna change the configuration of the Bin is going to be in our next story, the round money bin, which
was quite a bit later. This one was published in July of nineteen fifty three couple of years later. And
so... And and so this one was a
companion piece. This was the backup story. To the famous horse traumatic story So
this is actually gonna be one of our very first stories that we get to talk about in the one shots that's are in in the podcast that's secured in an issue of uncle group because we are time jumping a little bit here as we do sometimes with the ten page podcast. And so this one's been reprinted quite a few times.
Now I we have nine different printing of this one. Including the original in United States. And
now, it's it's stacking up a great story, and it's a great story in it's own right.
Any any initial thoughts on this one?
Not a ton. I mean, it's it's another great twist on the Scrooge versus B boy formula. I guess it is sort of worth pointing out This was Barks his fourth b boy story. There was Tara B boys, big bin, the Famous only a pearl man. And then this one. And in between there was an Italian story by gui, Martina and Lucia Shadow
That had the big boys and
There was also a Tony strobe short from another four color Barks. So, yeah, these are still early b boys, but as we'll get into, they are more resembling their modern form, than they were in big Bend. Yeah. By quite a bit. And boy those italians, they didn't let any
didn't let any mo
before using these iconic characters did they? Definitely not. And I actually think Gui Martinez
who wrote that first the italian B Boy story was the one to translate a lot of that Barks material into Italian for the first time for the flagship to title
in the late forties and early fifties. So he was definitely
familiar with the Barks work. So he was probably very willing to jump right at it and throw those B boys in that makes perfect sense. That's a that's a cool bit of info. Thanks for relating that. So this one... Let's let's dive on into it. You know, This one opens up with screws pacing and his money been. I'm noticing that it's a little bit more, like it's not a lot of very we've got a lot of piles of money here. It's really it's really nicely drawn very artistic. Awesome, what I really like here is that Scrooge is not responding to any external threat to his money. He's just pacing and generally worrying about it. And he's worried that his his old bin just isn't up to the task of keeping it safe anymore that he needs some kind of a new stunt. To keep the money safe. And he kinda thinks it out and he talks about how he keeps these points just for sentiment.
And so he could have them changed into green Barks,
which, of course, sent me advantage of saving laws space. And so he he gets this great idea because that's gonna make him a lot cheaper to learn.
He goes to the bank, and he asks the for bank teller if there's a fee to change coins and greeting Barks
And when the when the teller working there, it says, no. There's not how how many dollars
he tells him, I don't know, but they measure three cubic gamers,
and we get a good little
blanche
response from the from the clerk. This this This is a great opening Austin.
Yeah. No. I I think it's really fantastic opening
We were talking about the italian stories earlier, and those have three tiered pages.
So there's three rows panels to work with as opposed to Barks is four. So they're very, like calm and, like, spacious with their setup. I read stuff like this and it's like they would have literally taken ten pages alone to get to this point. I think what's really nice about Barks and stuff is he can condense it to the point where he gets right to it. Right? And he can fit in this ten page story that honestly, I think could have been a thirty two pager he wanted it to be. Like, he could've have expanded it. He condense his that much into this little space. I think that's really great. Al. Sure. Yeah. Because this one is a little bit of a mini adventure. Right? There there are some ten pager that I I think are almost like many adventure stories and something little more gag heavy. I really like that we get again a little bit of world building here. This is probably something that he kinda threw in i, but it's really key to Barks to to screw just here to what says that he keeps all of these points for sentiment.
Right? So it's more than just the money to him. Rosa again is gonna run with this idea later on and say that, you know, he keeps the coins that he has, like, specific memories that he keeps the coins and bills.
So it it's a great opener as you said, It gets right into it. Take this on to the next page, which is which is three months later.
Yeah. Before I go on that, though, I do wanna... You mentioned that panel
where it keeps all the coins for sentiment. While we were talking about Martinez
translations. I think in the original Italian printing, he calls himself, like an old fool for keeping the coins for sentimental reasons. So I get he's just... I was just found that interesting in the Italian. They make him like, a soft y, but he's he's... He's annoyed to admit that he's a soft you know, he's Al old fool like that. I was like that. Right. So anyway, on the next page, he gets a call that they've changed the money from coins to bills
And they have a... He is a mir Barks
car
of ten thousand dollar bills,
which is of course, the Scrooge is is, you know, a amir Barks car money nothing, but a mir box carve of ten thousand dollar bills is
insane. So we get a really nice setup up here with the nephews where Donald and is... you know, you were doing louis down fishing by the river.
Like they were in big top bed, I think also and these tanks are shooting by. Uncle screwed with an army of money trucks is Donald puts in. And, you know, I always like these stories just go by real time. Right? I mean, besides that three month skip, it's like we don't just skip right ahead to the next page where it's all in the bin. You know. The Donald just is sitting by and and the trucks are going by and, you know, he just curious. Just wants to see what's going on. So him and the nephew you start chasing after them, which I always thought was cool, like, that child like curiosity of just seeing a cool site like that and just wanting to know what's going on. Yeah.
Well, said, and you know what, it's important that we see the money in most
right, going to its new destination and being ga because it's gonna be like an important setup. He's gonna book in the story for that. And and, of course, he does mention Austin a keeping thing on this page about his his first time talking about sentiment.
Oh, yeah. I I actually didn't notice that.
He looks in his pocket and he sees that there's one coin he overlook, which is
the very first time that he had ever earned. So of course, nothing bark does is
just meaning lesson and we'll be thrown away. So that'll come into play later, but I always found it interesting that it wasn't kept behind glass, which is going something that came in later with the magic spell stories it, you know, that plays a key part into. But
I find an interesting. He would just let that sit around. He wouldn't even know where it is. You know? Right. And this is just a case where Barks is gonna, like
retroactively
assign more importance to it. It's kind of just a sentimental
throw away right. Here, but this is the first mention,
of his number one dime. So this is a neat couple of couple of first that we've got here. And then Au
have do you know what the actual
largest
Us currency
denomination is?
Wow. It's a good question. I actually have no idea.
I don't mean to put you on the spot. It's a ten thousand dollar bill. It really is. That's that... you know, he could've have changed in something higher. I wonder if Barks looked that up. It's not like a... It's not a denomination that was really used very often. I think it was only used like bank to bank or something. I'll put you on the spot again. Do do you know who who the person on the front of the ten thousand dollar bank notice?
Probably like, some... Because they discontinued that while ago, Didn't they? So probably like some some president from, like, the early twentieth century. It is in fact Salmon key Chase, the secretary of the treasury from eighteen sixty one to eighteen sixty two.
Have you no idea why? So they do follow that currency onto the... That money on to the next page. And that's where we get to see the actual round money bin of the title. They, the that's find that screws is
the money into an old water tank on a different hell called Park hill, which is much less than imposing than home help. And donald approach sp, and he's like, a gas that he would put his money in such an un unsafe spot and he starts to question him about it. And sp has answer for everything. He said that, you know, there's all this Barks land for half mile around how could of burger get it burglar, get into this
without being seen and how could they get out?
And so Scrooge, he we wrap up this page with Scrooge, just popping up with fried at his delightful full plan and Donald giving kind of this knowing
look suspecting that something won't won't turn out very well. I'm I'm guessing. He kinda rolls his eyes here.
That's an interesting read on that because like, that's to me a very classic bark smile where... It he he usually just has it when Donald like very happy you're pleased with something.
I never thought about it. Is him like rolling his eyes almost like, well, you know, he's screwing himself over as he always does. But that's that's definitely an interesting take because that's totally...
It's it's definitely a possibility that's how Barks intended it to read almost like, like Donald could almost represent the reader in a way where, like, you're reading this and you're like, Scrooge is like there's no way anyone could break in and and reading your, like, of course,
everyone. There's Severino way someone could try to break in here, you know? Yeah. I I see that being a akin to him telling Scrooge at the end of poor old man, you know, if you've got... If you've got happiness, I'll take vanilla. So take us Take us on x paging into the interior of the tank. Awesome. So Scrooge excursion fights the nephews into the Bin and we see the cash being loaded in, and it's actually like a pretty big, you know, vast image, I really like this panel
and enter the beagle boys as they're being mentioned by screws inside, they're standing beside and this and, one of them says the, I think we can track crack that tank mates. And goes why crack it. Let's roll the whole tank away. Which is like when you think about it, it is kind of an obvious choice for a burglary just to sort of get the bin off of that stand just have it roll down and then take care of it then. But anyway, the beagle boy is looking very
streamlined and Yeah. Not as well v. Yeah. Not as Goofy as they did like, less than two years before and big bend. And we get a caption panel, thus the gauge of battle is flying which I guess is supposed to relate to the weird image in that panel of, like, the glove and the sword, which doesn't really make sense. Or I I thought that was peculiar. But anyway, Scrooge Donald relaxing in the Bin and the telephone guy, someone to check the phone is at the door. So he walks in. It is very clearly
a disguised beagle boy with black glasses over him. I love all sky B boys, Austin.
I I love their super obvious disguise and all these stories. Yeah. It it is sort of a classic Disney comics trope for... Or just in cartoons and comments in general, the super obvious disguise that fools everybody and and is
just so ridiculous. But And the little kids that are the leaders get to feel they get to feel a little bit smarter on the.
Yeah. They get to feel like they discovered the whole thing But... Yeah. So we closed the page with Al a whole army of beagle boys in the back and in a pickup. Showing up to the guard and asking if they can go into the bin
because they're painters for whatever reason Scrooge needs is old water tank painted. And this is a really cool
with the b Boys news onto to this next page.
It's very clever. This is a classic trip right? We're a couple of a couple of pawn artists will coordinate so that one of them sneaks in and is able to receive the phone call from the other one and So the b that's pretending to be the phone repairman
claims to be waiting for a phone called a check the lines, and of course, it's from screws guard to confirm that the painters are on the up and up and so that this deal is able to pose Scrooge and tell them yes it's okay for them to come in. A few thoughts here. One, I love it when the beatles are clever. Right? I like how they alternate between being kinda dumb creatures that are... Have terrible judgments but also they get these awesome plans off. And then, like, two, this is a real...
This is a real scheme that is like used for fraud and the real world all the time. This is like classic confidence scan. It's interesting. You mentioned that because, like, I read this. The the first time I had read this, a while back. Like, my mind was blown because, like, you said, it is genuinely, like a very well thought out scheme and as we'll see, like, there's really nothing that can stop them from pulling the job off except for, of course, Scrooge in his coming genius Al we'll see later on, but it's like It's very interesting. It's very well thought out, like you know, later on,
the B boys were very goofy, and there will always be a hole in the plan that screws would sniff out and and that would be sort of the climax of the story. But like, this one, you you really can't get out of it. I always like that about this one. Yeah. I like this team. It feels very earned.
So, of course, you know, once the pain or leaves, once the telephone repairman leaves,
The duct spot that army of
that army of what they don't know yet or Eagle boys coming up the stairs.
And when Scrooge Calls his Barks to verify Donald discovers that his quote honest, telephone
repair, cut wires.
Yeah. That... I mean, it... You know, I always get thinking when I read this one's, like, how did the telephone
repair get by and and screws didn't get that call? You know? That's a tiny little thing that I always see. It comes them mind. But anyway, on the next page, the beagle boys now, I guess, just, you know, with no disguise at all or at the door and they're threatening to throw a tear gas bomb into the bin. And again, screws is, you know, selfish and and ingredient is causing his downfall.
Donald ask him if he has a distress flag or an sos rocket, and screws didn't buy any because as he says
distress signals cost money. You know, and he, he says he never dreamed, he would need such things, but I would figure here, like, with all his experience, Huey, would expect someone to always be breaking in, especially the beagle boys. Right. So the the b boys get in, they tie up the docks and they're sitting there thinking. And and
Donald is is sort of getting that. I told you so moment and just sort of getting that devilish grand and Scrooge just cisco go, don't talk about it. I'm suffering. And he just sits there with a miserable face. While the beagle boys are down in, like below torch the stand that the the money is on and they're very carefully coordinating this. Like, I think it's super cool. You know? I mean, if you look at this panel, like, they're all very well coordinated. I mean, there are five here, but I think there were like twelve in that pickup truck originally. So they have enough meant to pull off
seriously.
Complicated and well done job, which I always thought was super cool. Right. Yeah. And and it's a neat little essence of Scrooge here on that page where
he's talking about how he's gonna smart
next time. And Donald points out. Again, this is very like, donald at the end of only a portal of man to meet Yeah. Tomorrow, you outs smart them, then they'll have to smart you again. Poor are guides. Right? This is locked in this never ending cycle. So, you know, austin, the next couple of pages
are really about the beagle
scheme how it pans out because they're able to... Or stephen has a little narrator spots that asks can the be gonna with this, the bin does indeed roll away. Right? Just like from the title and the in the very... And the very presentation of the story, the reader
secretly wants to see the bin rolling away. It rolls down the hill with the duct getting scrambled completely inside. And the Scrooge guards who I'm sure he's not paying that well. Noticed that it's gone missing
and the put mighty Decent
painters are able to tell them that it rolled off So they point out where it's rolled away. And
again, this is the B boys being really clever. Right? Because if they're able to show themselves to be helpful
and it's gonna decrease their suspicion. Yeah. I I always like the, you know, they're they're being very clever like, you know,
pointing out to the guards where the bin was rolling away even though they could have just totally pointed in the opposite direction, and try to throw them off. But anyway, on the next page, we have a really cool sequence where the beagle boys that are now un disguised and and just sitting out there not as painters. But now claiming to be house movers that mister Tiktok hired to move the tank. So, you know, police think something's up. So the b boys call up to Scrooge
and ask him to to, you know, confirm that he asked them to move the tank. And there's a v boy holding Scrooge a hand
neck and a finger a inch up his, like, tail feathers, which I always gone really cool. Yeah. And the B boy threatened him say yes, you will go Al dump a can of each powder down your neck. So screws, of course, is no choice, and he just meet uniquely, shoot is head out the window and goes, yes.
So the guards are off. And, you know, like we've been saying, I mean, Scrooge says it himself here, like, the beagle boys have really pulled a perfect crime. Like, it it is really genius in a way that they wouldn't be this smart in later stories, which I always thought was super cool here. Yeah. I I really like the effective
versions of the vehicle boys. You know, like, later on when
when they're facing off in the paul by machine, I like to see them a real match for Scrooge. Right okay. And
that was another example, two of the, like, comedic torture that Barks will use to, you know, not not be too edgy So later on, you know, into the evening name, the B boys are rolling the tank away planning to take it to their hideout out ranch and out valley.
And Scrooge
loans that they're getting away with his tire fortune, and then he realizes, wait a minute, he still has his dime, and it's of course, the first time that he ever made and that's gonna get them free in no time. And Donald is spa because he's like, what are you gonna do bribe them with a dime? But he points out that the dime has... It's so old, and it's been with him so long that it's worn as thin as a razor blade. And so one of the nephews is able to get it and use it to cut the ropes. And it's a great Scrooge moment because it's pointing out that, like, his sent Al is actually
a useful thing. It's actually a good thing. It's what is gonna help him get his fortune back. So the the docs
except for screws, all jump out and head off to contact
the cops.
While Scrooge stays behind. I I do like though that they're just being thrown around and and Scrooge just comes up with this idea. They're just, you know, flipping around and Scrooge banging his head when he gets the id idea about the first time. And you think about that, like, if it was done it's like a duck episode or a film, like, that would just be a really fun sequence to just watch back because that would be pretty cool. Yeah.
Yeah. So we're not we're on the last page. Right? Ten page and Scrooge is going through the bin. He gets the money out of the window. He has it all poor out.
So he gets a hay bail from a farmer and starts bailing out the money, which I actually think is something he did in a later much later story. How green was my lettuce? Which is a really cool one. I've always like that story.
So we get to the final page, and this is just an awesome panel with the, like, eighty thousand cops in in the bin and just just a beagle boy looking in and they all of this devilish grant.
So, yeah. The B boys,
Scrooge jeep creepers.
So the... The b the other big boys are sent back to jail and Patty wagon to which
copper Barks creepers jeep,
and then Scrooge drives up to the bank with these Ducktales of money to which the teller
explains creepers jeep, which I always like that touch at the end. So status quo,
everything's gone back to normal a really nice story. I wrapped up really nicely there at the end. I I love that last page. That little rule of three. Right? Barks is so good about following the comedic rules three where you do something just three times. Right? Two times is not enough to make it funny. Four times you be two many. Three is the perfect number. In comedy.
And and it's it's great. Jeep creepers, it's full of cops. Pampers jeep is the B boy's back again. Pre jeep, not you again because it's that same bank teller.
Awesome. They're very funny closer. Yeah. Just just another great story to
fairly early Scrooge stories that do a lot of like a lot of great world building work and establishing what makes the money been special and interesting
and what's special about Scrooge
himself. What do you think? How does this one stack up to, like, big again on Film motor Hill? I think they both have their strengths. I mean, Donald, of course, was the
just by requirement of the walt disney knee flagship title. He was the Barks character on big Bend. So I think Bark sort of had to use Donald more in that one. Because, of course,
Round Money been was originally printed in the third Scrooge centric book that dell put out, which was, of course, with the horse story, so that was originally a Scrooge Barks
story as opposed to a donald one. So Scrooge definitely plays a bigger role in Round money Bin, which I really like.
And I do like the literally the genius
un break, you know, free of plot hole or, you know, holes in the plan thing that the B boys come up within and round money bend, but, I mean, You know, it's it's like we said there's some really nice drawing in in big Bin also. So it's really hard to choose a favorite, but they are both two classics if I have to say, really great stories. Yeah. Absolutely. I I agree. I I'm not sure where I land. There's I don't need to compare them, but they're both excellent.
I do love the round money bin as a great double boy showcase.
I think that I think it stands out in my mind a little bit more, but they are they're both excellent.
The community loves both with them. Right, This one, if he check it out on Inducks
not ranked quite as high, but is still a very well regarded ten pager. It gets to seven point four compared to big bend seven point five. And it's a bit lower down three hundred and seventy six out of all the stories. Yeah. So it's outside of, like, top twenty five or so, but... But I'd probably
put it in my personal ranking unit I have a pretty high up there I thing. I definitely agree. And I don't know if Huey, mentioned this very often, but, like, I do wanna point out that on the index thing it might not seem very big, you know, two hundreds
story or three hundred and seventy six or whatever you said for round money Bend, but that's out of forty one thousand. Right? Across literally millions of readers of of so many countries. So, I mean, forty one thousand is is a pretty large number. So for these to be both in the top five hundred I think is pretty good. Right people definitely love this pair as as I think we both do. Yeah. Top five hundred as you said, because this
that ranks all of the creators.
And
when you're in the top five hundred, you're thinking probably about thirty to forty percent of the moving b more story something like... So really highly
within his full channel,
Let's see. I think we did a pretty good job covering these stories Austin.
I'm just curious if do you have any other
money bent stories their favorites of you words. Oh, yeah. Definitely. There. There are ton of great ones. What comes to mind immediately is the Money well, which is also Barks.
I think that's the first one with Grandpa Beagle, which is sort of an interesting character.
I always like that one. There's some great drawing in there
we were talking about tricky experiment before recording, which is an eight major Barks did in the early sixties.
And another
another kind of round money bin too.
Oh, yeah. Then that's right. Where he's able to, like,
hook up some some machinery
and
control his round money been remotely and avoid the B voice to some pretty pretty comedic effect. I do like now on a lot. Yeah. That's a very funny one
There's also road in ransom, which was something
adapted by
a bunch of different artist, but that was actually based off a story that box submitted to Disney
in the mid fifties for a Scrooge cartoon
that has has never been made, but that's actually a really funny story.
Gladstone printed a two variants back in the day.
But basically, a rat gets in screws has bin and screws wants to shoot them or, you know, get rid of him, but the, you know, the rat holding on to a then ten thousand dollar bill. So Scrooge can't get rid of the rat because he's got the money, but he also can't keep the rack because he's gonna keep eating the money. So he's gotta a cool dilemma. There's some great ways to he things through that. That's a really fun one also. Nice. Yeah. I'll have to check that out.
All throw and i mention of the two safe safe, the one where
he coats
his money with, like,
an un break material,
that's a fun variation on it. And then we Gottfredson
safe safe where he's gonna shoot his money bin in
oh, what's the name of the ind
glass the gyro creates?
Oh man. I can't remember. Well, anyway, that's another fun variation on the Bin What is the one where Man
is like, using those ones to cast all of the different, like, meters and elements against the Bin. That shows that's another one that shows some great bin defense by Barks. I like that a lot.
That I think that is for old time sake Would be one. Now you have Gladstone.
They're... That's actually coming up in a Fan graphics book and of oversized bark stories. In the fall. So I'm definitely gonna get that Nice. Yeah. And of course, Rosa
has really run with the the Bin safety element you know, and stories like oh, cash flow, and I mean, you could almost name a random story because, like a ton of them are about assaults on the money then. Yeah. Cash flow is a great one. I do wanna throw in two Italian stories
one we just got last year
by Lucia,
jumping Jupiter,
which which is absolutely
insane it has to be seem to be believed.
It's...
These crazy aliens from Jupiter get in and they eat metal, so they're eating up all of screws coins, and he gets Donald on the case and they've gotta get the aliens up, And that's a crazy one. And there's also Rum romano scar is a fifty money bin cap.
Whereas
Donald comes up with the great idea to make fifty money bin on K motor Hill and transfer the money from month to month, so the the beagle boys have no idea which one it is,
you know, where the money's kept. So that's a really fun one.
That's what of
Yeah. I'll have to check that out. That does sound fun.
Speak of the Italians, there's, of course
Marco Road great money ocean. I like that one a lot.
Yes. I forgot about that one. That is also fantastic. With the they're million
one. Yeah. Yeah. We could we could sit here all day and name
great money been stories because there are so many of them. The B Boys versus the money then. That's maybe one of roses
good classics that includes the blueprint. Of the money been itself. I I wanna throw in one last one. This is another Romano scar Italian one.
Because my friend Joe To sylvia, actually did the American script, the one we got it from Id w couple years ago. And that's Mommy Theorists.
Wear Scrooge,
and it's got broker Inducks in it. So that's a crazy one
Scrooge puts his money in a pyramid, and that is just off the wall, bonkers
fun... I think it's like mid seventies. So that is the fun one that I actually just read a couple months ago for the first time.
Not that hard to find from, like, a bunch of different Id w printing. If anyone out there wants to check that one out. Very cool. Well, thank you so much, Austin. This has been a fun conversation.
I love to revisit these ten page ones. They're they're a lot they're all... They're almost as fun as getting to do the adventure stories sometimes even better. I hope that readers will
I hope the listeners will tell us what their favorite money been story is.
And
join us in the future we get to do more of these.
Awesome. Yeah. I I know I totally agree. Great conversation, great fun. I mean, it doesn't get a lot better in comics in general than early fifties carl Barks. So... Yeah. It's always a pleasure to talk about this. For sure. Alright. Take care. Alright. I'll see you.