Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of sc Mc Ducktales and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge con of all time
This episode is a ten page podcast all about one of his short stories, get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Alright. Listeners, thank you so much for joining us. We have another
episode of the ten page podcast
and I'm delighted to have a fellow Ducktales fan
joining me. I've I've been having a lot of fun meeting people and
and geek out with with fellow duck fans in the course of doing this podcast. So I'm gonna ask him to please introduce himself and if you can tell us a little bit about your background
in Duck Comics. Yeah. Hi. Thank you for having
And care. I'm from Sweden
scandinavia. In your.
Reading
that comics since the the mid eight is. I was like six zero seven, I think. And
mostly
plus through the weekly donald that
that's
still coming out the.
And the from the the beginning I got to
understand that some of of the creators are more significant than others. And, of course, i'd got to learn about Barks.
From the store I think. So... And I'm really happy to be here with you. I hope the listeners can handle my Swedish accent.
Absolutely. Pierre, I'm I'm delighted to have you on, and I'm sure that the listeners can can handle
your Swedish accent because, you know, I feel like Donald Duck belongs to Scandinavia as much as it belongs to the United States. Right? So I really am happy to get your perspective on some of these stories,
especially
a very american
story.
Like the one we're gonna talk about today, which is was Turkey trouble.
And deals with the extremely American holiday of Thanksgiving.
I'm excited to release some of these out of order for the ten pager. So I can tie this to our American holiday here. And i, you know, I'm looking forward to getting your perspective and hearing some of the ways that they dealt with publishing these stories.
In Scandinavia because they're are so beloved
around the world. The the stories are so popular
in.
Right?
And I am fascinated
by that facts,
because the stories are so
incredibly american
Very capitalist
too. And and for them to be popular
in, like, the the social democracy sees.
Mh.
That fa me Pierre did... You... So you said you figured out that Carl marx was great pretty early on. I started reading them and learned about Barks around that same time in, like, the mid to late eighties.
I'm wondering
was was it kind of a community thing where you knew other people who enjoyed that Donald duck magazine
Well, the down the weekly
was since list. I think the biggest
comic gets sweden.
Everybody know you and notes
about the these new economics. So it was a it was like I didn't stand out because I read the the electronics. Yeah. Today I kinda stand out more of upwards That's still there is quite a big Swedish community that that's read these economics in the box in particular.
Even among
dance today is we. So I never felt, like, totally alone.
Right. So they didn't... They didn't hold on to these this childhood
pursuit. Right? Yeah. Exactly.
Yeah. I mean, I I grew up and I knew absolutely
no one who liked these. My brothers would read him occasionally because I had him lying around. But but I always did feel a little bit embarrassed as I got into my teeth
being such a big fan.
But thank you for joining me and and giving your perspective on this one. You know, I've given my myself permission with these
ten page podcast
stories
to be a little bit less prepared.
So they're a little bit less where we're gonna we're gonna be a little bit kind of free flow. So I am gonna talk about this story sequentially. And I'm just gonna kinda shoot it over to you if there's something where I'd like you to talk about it. That's great. A little bit of a little bit of background info in the United States, this one was published first in walt Disney's
comics and storage number seventy five. And
I see an alternate title Turkey
turmoil.
Right? And and I think some other story might have been called turkey trouble at some point. So I should distinguish this is one that was first published back in nineteen forty six.
Here in the Us. So I think this is a fun one. It's it's not like one of his all time
best ten... Ten page ones, but but I really like this one. Pierre, you are telling me a little bit though before we started
about how they kinda reframe this one in Sweden. Do you mind telling the listeners a little bit about that? Yeah. Well, it's just the Us. Thanksgiving is really holiday sweden. They changed it to Easter,
which is swedish holiday as well as Well, it that's work being
changed from thanksgiving
to Easter,
and I think I wouldn't have thought about being strange if I hadn't read, like, the English or know as well. But it makes sense. It's a
change that makes the story much more accessible for
to issue distribute readers, I think. Yeah. That's really interesting to me. And and as I think back on this one, it's right because there's there's not too much thanksgiving about it. Right? It's it's all about the big holiday
meal bases
being prepared for it. Some of perhaps other holiday stories
we're probably harder for them to change, because they're more explicit about, like, Thanksgiving
and and maybe dressing up like,
or things that. I think that some of... The... I can't remember we try, but so some all the other late
thanksgiving stories. The editors actually had the turkish really drove onto to the pigs and they moved the story to a Christmas side. I should never looked Al that up beforehand, but i.
So since most of these stories did and up meetings,
at least in in they eighth they had to, like put some that's gotten ibm idea
touch to two of them to make sense. It's always a trick to localize something like this. And so you've read this in both Swedish and English. I. Excellent. Well,
let's get into the story, and you can tell me you know, anything that you think is notable in in you know how you originally
read it. Great. So Turkey trouble, here opens with the Nephews
in a state of gloom. And I really like the little splash panel. You know, they both got... They've all got these like, clouds of gloom literal
over their heads
about the fact that Donald says that he can't afford to buy it turkey for thanksgiving
dinner.
And, you know, I wanna just talk right away about those little gloom clouds. I saw different
it's fun how they've been translated into different languages
because they had it up on index.
So they're they're just walking through the city.
Feeling gloomy about how they're gonna have to resort to eating wee, hot dogs,
if he can even find some and speculating. They might end up just having to eat potato pan cakes.
And
there's a fun little side gag where one of the f fuse says that he wishes Turkeys
were so thick around here. You had to kick them out of bit you're way. And he keeps a little piece of paper. And it ends up being a raffle ticket,
very convenient.
I mean
for a Turkey
of course that where a drawing is going be held to to find out if you're the winner
at twelve ten o'clock which is almost the time right now. And so they're gonna head to that raffle. Any thoughts on this opening setup here? Well, as you said, say it's
a very convenient opening. And I think Barks
does work with those like, convenience.
Yes. Things happen
because the store needed and I have have the feeling that for some people, it's kinda
bothering them. But for me, it's just effective story story telling it's like, the build up is quickly done. You can get do the fan checks and well, try the actual story that this is as well. As we will see.
Yeah. I I totally agree. I I had that feeling sometimes and and as I've been revisiting these more, I'm like, I really admire sometimes he really just gets into it. So on the next page, you know, they're racing over. It's a very fun panel of them with our feet Al blur.
They're looking at the the number on their ticket, which is two three six zero three seven. And we kinda pan over
to the hall where the Raffle is being held and and sure enough. It's their number that being drawn at that moment. There's a blind folded man who must Gladstone it. And
the person who
drew it is in the process
of telling the audience that someone needs to come forward
by the count three before they're gonna draw another number and
and and the nephews user over here in this. And so you you wanna tell us how this page goes? Yeah. Well, very comes me
counting.
Pass through the word the word three they arrive. And subsequently,
they are led to another room and they start wondering what right do they have this prepared this either way, but they are soon to realize that it's not the to dish. It's a living turkey and quite grumpy looking Turkey as well. Yeah. I I really like the setup there. Right? The audience kinda gets the Al little for about that there's something wrong with this turkey that they've just won because
why would it be in the back room? You mentioned that the Turkey on onto the next page, they meet the Turkey and, you know, they they're shocked to see that it's alive
and
pierre, I love how Barks has drawn this grumpy looking turkey
I don't know about you. Yeah. It's while is Scrooge, like say Al artist, it's giving the characters
specific expressions and, like Summer, their qualities Al
character and this poor turkey, which
he
isn't really
ready to be a winner, and he's he he he's not ready to go and where. Also
big heavy it turkey and the kids
don't get far. Right. It start
carrying it way but they soon give
exhausted. Yeah. I love... I love how they try to, you know, forty it all bound up at first.
They have to rest all weary. And we see the Turkey also very weary while their rest, thing and, you know, they they get their wagon Al first thinking that they're gonna tow it in the wag and and and then at some point they figure out that they can pitch to the wagon. And, you know, what what is it that they come to realize by the time they get home beer? Well, they kinda
good.
Attached to the
Turkey. They
name him then lady him raffle
I I think in the English original, isn't it too? They they para it. Right? Raffle,
which is just the good affect adaptation in English. And they get to think that they haven't got a dealer box or rather nice pet. Yeah. They they pretty quickly start to think for them as a pat. And while they are bonding. As they've kind of made that transition to thinking of it as a pet, Donald is getting home. He's having in kind of gloomy thoughts,
not having a great option
for a thanksgiving.
And, you know, he over hears the nephews talking about their Turkey
and looks Al the window. And what's Pierre, tell us about his immediate response to wrap up page. Yeah. Well, he sammy
responsible adult do. He grabs the hatch and runs out to kill it.
Yeah. I like that. Not Without a second thought, he's just got an accent ready.
Yeah. I like the line he gets off here white meat dark meat. Drumstick sticks on the roof. Here I come. That's
caught a of frame.
Yeah.
And so, you know, the nephews
immediately tackle him because they have already... They've have resolved it in their mind. He's no longer dinner. He is a pet. So I guess at this point, this you're right. This wouldn't have been too hard to rework into Swedish.
And to make it talk about eastern dinner, because they must just sp that they don't have anything for their easter dinner. Exactly.
So, you know, this kinda of sets up a little bit of attention. Donald like, you know, you've got a Turkey and we've got thanksgiving coming up. We've got this big holiday and what are we gonna do? Mana nephews you bring up a new suggestion kind of out of nowhere. Again, it's a little convenient, but we're going on to the next stage, the next sequence of the story where they they've heard about a turkey shoot and
Donald is excited. He's full of blu about being a great shot.
And so he goes to grab his like, his rifle and he heads to this turkey shoot. Is this a term that that you knew? Well, I even think, it turkish if you
express. Right. So there there is like a term Turkey shoe. Right? I think that really were like an old time competition.
I think this was a thing and it... It's not anymore. So a turkey shoot is an opportunity for someone to take advantage of an easy situation.
And I guess it's named for when Wild Turkeys
would be scattered by a hunter.
This does talk specifically about, like, this sort of hunting event, where you would shoot at these cards. So this is a very specific american. I don't think they're really aren't anymore though. And I like this little club, the south side Joe's.
This kind of club
you know, a fellowship club a thing in Sweden. Well, I I guess,
pretty much
relatable.
So that that works quite well. I think
Yeah. And it works in English too, but it definitely has a pretty dated v. Right. These are like these these kinds of clubs are kind of kinda going by the wayside in in united I think I think about like, the
order of moose and the alex
I really like this setup. You wanna tell us about the the turkey shoot setup up here?
Yeah. Well,
the good have the good news helping up five targets for Donald to try to shoot down and he needs to permanently needs to hit three four of targets. And if it does, the turkey is supposedly case.
Right. And the nephews user chatting with the
the Joe who doesn't seem very worried about the prospect
of Donald hitting the targets all the way across the river.
And
and and we come to learn that this is their only turkey.
They're running a racket here. Right? Because it's a bait bird.
They plan to eat it for their own thanksgiving dinner. They're just gonna use it to make to make some money off suckers because no one ever
wins. And so they never need more than their one like showcase turkey.
And Pierre, you wanna tell us why no one ever wins Well, it's staged. Not only are the targets far off. They are also
impossible to put down with the rifle. They are a bunch of sheet.
Yeah. Because one of them is, like,
bracket into place.
And and we learn this because, you know, the Nephews
resolve
that
to to help Donald win this one. One of them needs to... They need to swim behind
And they're using their p shooter
This is a fun little data at element that. Right? Because in the nineteen fifties, forties and fifties, p shooters would have been and little American play things. This is that something that's kind of a cliche in Sweden pier? Yeah. Well, as as you say, like, in the first half of the twenty century. That was one of the fun stuff kids.
And and it's one of the fires that this is from a long time ago. But Yeah.
So they're using their p shooters to knock these targets down. But when they come to the final target, they realized that One of them is gonna have to go to some real risk
to make it look like he's shooting that last target. They're gonna... He's gonna have to go back behind and and knock it down at just the right time. What do you think Pierre?
It's
it's what they are. It's not something you are advised to to do at home. I think yeah.
I like the little side gag at the end there. Right, where he gets his his tail feathers,
whichever nephew you get Ducktales feathers
clipped off. Why don't you tell us Pierre, we transition
to the Turkey being delivered. You know, Donald has won the turkey the south side Joe's have lost their turkey
and
tell us about the turkey delivery. Yeah. Well donald.
Quite edge changes just to kinda get this dinner.
The turkey is not us and just to become dinner.
So
donald it up to him with his
ex, but the turkey gets the first
strike and they begin tight and it's quite violent fact
up with them both be
more or less
just
by by this moment, the nat get added to finish off, the turkey
down having found, I guess,
a brother in Barks or
friend at least he refuses to have the third gig kid off So no. No. They have two pets turkish. Yeah. Exactly.
So so Pierre, I love this page. This is my favorite a page of this ten pager
I love the way the Turkey bus sat of his cage
already fighting
I love the the fight panels
that Donald. I love his fighting posture opposite the Turkey
I just... I love that the concept of this basically a knock down drag out
fist fight with the turkey.
It's such a funny imagery, and it's the reason that I wanted to do this
specific story for our American Thanksgiving
episode. Like, this one makes me laugh out loud. I I just... I love this page so much. And when we get to the page, the panel, and you mentioned where the nephews are ready to
finish him off with the Al,
and and he says, what? Bump off this turkey. I love this turkey. He's got spirit. And he just toss the axe over the fence.
Not not a very smart maneuver there. But
but a great image. I I love it so much. And it's Al nice because,
Donald gets to find a friend.
Yeah. That's not too commonly in the stories.
Usually ends up is either
getting angry himself with others or authors
get to know it by again.
It's right. It's a it's a kindred spirit. Right? As he sees it, because it's says
and short temp.
As he is.
And and I love the the last page here that we're getting to early we close out the story from the perspective of some random neighbor, who is puzzling over the Ducktales behavior. Right? Because they've got
two Turkeys
in their backyard,
and he can smell them cooking
cabbage.
And
and we see Donald cooking what he seems to be regarding is a really lovely
vegetarian meal and getting ready to enjoy it. And
as he transitions to go tell the kids that dinner is ready, what what do we see from outside the window here?
Yeah. Well, i'm outside, do we know the turkey's
are getting ready to have there. Thanks
they dinner I guess. And
Al the docs
believe their kitchen, the turkey is supposedly to sneaks aside when the doctor turn. It's all being finished. The plates are empty,
and the the kitchen are filled out the turkey tracks all over.
Right. And and we get this great panel
having just
completely devoured their thanksgiving. We have the two Turkeys are completely fat and stuffed,
very content looking.
And Donald has this great word balloon where he sums up. The whole story. He says so that's the story. We we got these turks he calls them. For thanksgiving dinner, and instead they ours.
And how do we close it out pierre? Yeah. Wow.
The next Obviously,
we given up and they put the sign
outside of the house
for sale to turkey's bonus done for hamburgers.
We'll be back in five minutes.
Right.
So
so
it's a very tight story. You know,
these ten pager, I don't cover them as much on the podcast, but they're really wonderful. And this one is like, I don't think it's
remembered by fans as being, like one of his legendary ones, but it's just a great example of a really solid one that tells this very
punchy,
quick
very funny story with, like a absolutely
perfect ending. I really love this one. What did you think about it Pierre as just like a regular old Barks story? And then is someone, you know, leaving this from from Sweden. Yeah. It's... The store the pacing of the story is pretty much perfect. You never it never shows style. It's one detail after another and
happens
right in the exact movement that they are supposed to have the story
and it's
lots of good dialogue. As you have mentioned,
and the fighting scenes and I mean, in one second, he has to exit is said, then it puts out is right. So, I mean, there's lots of bad
for kids got. I was it's about now. I was thinking that this one is kind of violent.
Did that... Is that weird or does that how that go over? Yeah. I think it's... I mean, if you compare it to to the donna
animated shorts.
It's it's a same spirit. And it's just. I mean, it's it's Al always in a fun
good manner
happy mode. The kids and done are pretty much always on the same side, It's some of these stories have them put against each other, but they're there working together to get the good if Family dinner.
But...
Yeah. It's a a story with ending and the lots of violence.
That's great.
I I think this story is just a total delight. And I think it's a great example of like a a Barks
holiday story.
You know, I like to talk about, like, favorite panels
in these. Are there any of them that really stood out to you that you really liked Well, there are quite a few... I mean, this story is from nineteen forty six. Right? Yeah. Okay. And those gear,
I love but, like, he's just started to find this
game in search. He it's quite
that is getting to really enjoy
drawing these stories. But on page...
Let's see.
On page seven, the first panel you got Al
link directly
to us
towards us as a reader. And I'm not sure that would be allowed to today it even put the gun directly to the viewer, but it's really nice, like, compose Yeah also like the five scene as you mentioned
will be between
downtown and the second third. And the factor is the second last panel of part was a really fun to look at.
Those are all those are all good choices. You know, you're right. That's really striking how he's aiming the rifle
right at the reader. This is a kind of a random panel to highlight. But I love the panel that just shows on that same page where he's shooting.
It's got the south side Joe. Very casually clipping his nails
to show how un concerned he is
about
losing their freshest turkey. And, yeah, we we already highlighted some of them. But but almost every panel with Mcdonald's Turkey
just just cracks me up. It's so funny the way it's like grit. It's teeth. It's Turkey. It's non existent Turkey teeth.
Standing off with Donald and how they kind of form that bond over violence
And and the Nephews Turkey as well
he he does such a great job of making these very relatable
expressions
on these drawings of animals.
They they really
land and they're very memorable in a very short number of frames i think. It choice
it's striking and to be able to... Because the turkeys are also supplied. They do look like turkey that we see. And still they are able to
express both anger and
it's pretty good work. Barks.
Yeah. And I'm not sure if you have noticed but Barks actually
signed this order with this name. And where where is that? And this one? It's quite hidden. It's on page four. The second panel. On Al of the cams,
Kitchen, It says box studs. So... That's right but Yeah. That's a fun little piece of trivia. This was, I guess, one of the... I remember reading that and it's one of the very good catch. Thank you. One of the very few panels
stories where he sneaks in a reference because of course, he famously
was not allowed to put his actual signature.
These are all walt Disney's Donald dot. For the longest time. Exactly. Yeah. So
thank you so much Pierre for for talking about this story with me. What is there is there anything that really stands out to you as someone reading this from Sweden that, you know, maybe the translators couldn't account for that just... You're like, oh, this is this is an American element.
Well, we ordered they talked about the hot holidays, of course. But then in the very beginning, of the kids talk about what they will have to be because they don't have turkey. And they say,
venus or even rotate the pancakes.
And the translators also shades that to, like, Swedish
counterparts. That's
and for some reason, I'm not sure why. But in the very very end when they have gone to
get hamburgers,
the Swedish translation
says they have gone to have hot dogs.
We
I looked up. The this story came out in nineteen and seven in sweden, it it just got quite late. And I'm pretty sure that was hamburgers since we abide by the. I'm not sure why they changed it, but maybe it was still bit to exotic sure. That's interesting that this one didn't make it over there until the late seventies
I think I think that's because the...
I I mentioned
the
Al,
the main
the this comic with... It started to come out in nineteen forty eight. So lots of the stories from before that's. They make it into the
much. So were they publishing everything and pretty much that that one single publication
whereas, okay. So in America,
you know, they were doing the
both the four color one shot un walt Disney's comics and stories and then the added donald dock and uncle screwed. The the four colors
magazines
and
subsequently
some dollar kind of speech. They were either
published into
several parts,
like they cut up the stories.
So each Magazine had seven pages and then it was to big Convenient next to me. And in the fifties, they started to publish
four color
in Sweden, which allowed, like, donna
adventure stories
was allowed to be like this essay it should be. Nice.
Yeah. That's really interesting. I really appreciate getting your perspective
as, you know, a scandinavian
fan because I know that these are so important to all of the countries
of Scandinavia.
This one, if if you look at it on index, this is pretty well regarded. You know, the this one has a seven point four out of ten, which is good for rank four hundred and forty nine. Out of the forty one thousand some comics.
So
that that compares pretty favorably to a lot of the ten pager. It's obviously not like regarded one of is classics,
but it's definitely in that range that would suggest it's your your solid average
early Barks.
Ten pager. But I I do find this one is one of the more memorable of the thanksgiving
themed ones.
Or me.
So... Yeah. Lot of fun. Any any other thoughts, anything else you wanted to mention Peter? No. I think we know that through this story quite nice. It's
as to say, it's
not not really really classic. And well when you read it, you really got to appreciate, like, the good day work of of got Barks. I I mean, he he put out one of these ten
Scrooge well. Twenty years.
Well one story a month. And he kept, like, this quality about the storytelling
and in
the drawings and it's quite amazing when you think about about
the story this is
just plain fan Absolutely.
You said it very well. Right? This is a big part of why we
are such big fans of carl Barks. Right? Because this is just kinda one of his average stories
and and it's delightful
and he kept up this pace for so many years as you said. So Thank you again so much for joining.
Looking forward to, you know, some others that'll benefit from your perspective. And
as always, listeners can reach out to us on the Facebook page, Barks remarks or Barks remarks at gmail dot com. And
we'll have more of these ten page
podcasts
coming out as well as our proper
adventure length story. So Thanks again and
happy thanksgiving
to American listeners
and
happy other
holidays
to to anyone in the international
listeners.
Please.