we
Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Mc Ducktales writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge con of all time time. This episode is a ten page podcast, all about one of his short stories get ready to enjoy our remarks. Welcome back to Barks remarks. I'm Mark Sever, a grown man who enjoys Inducks comics and I am joined by a very special guest today, another grown man who enjoys and does more with comics,
and I'm gonna let him introduce himself. Hello everybody. This is Patrick Block lia is economic Barks. My draw donald doc Scrooge and Al relatives, and I'm happy to be here today. Talk about a car Barks tour with him. Thank you so much, Patrick. It's such a treat to get to meet dock au
who I grew up reading, you know? I can remember several of your stories reread a couple of them recently. I I read the...
Which hazel sql that you did. I got a huge kick out of that one. And two of those. It was the the Christmas one first. It's a really second story and then fourth story they wrong
with some the Al story. Oh, I didn't I didn't realize you done too which? One red. I read that christmas christmas one. Yeah. It was the second second that drawing story for Disney. That's awesome. And your style is definitely
reminiscent of Carl Barks. Right? You would
consider yourself strongly influenced. I'm guessing Yes. I grew up learning to read on Carlos comics and
pretty much my whole goal is a Disney artist is too.
Recreate that duck that I remember as a kid. That's the i approach comes. Yeah. That's awesome. That's that's my favorite take on it. Right? I think some people might argue that maybe fans like us are a little bit stuck in the past. But Sure. We are.
Yeah. Exactly. You know, the Don Rosa
is very purposeful about his stories being set in that version of Barks universe. Do you imagine that yours are set in in, like, the early fifties? Yeah. I don't really think about it too much, but I find myself not using cell phones or computers and things and the stories. Just naturally, like, I just don't have tendency to very often to do that. I think I might have been a couple of big months stories where we put a few modern things in for the most part Yeah. Generally, it's taking place in the mid fifties when Carl was doing his best work. And I think probably the same as true was dawn that we feel like Carl's material because stories, you know, is
exe for, like, twentieth century
comic or. I think he's like one the very best if not the best person at doing the whole package himself. So I think that's the quality of the material that brings us Like, I I read a lot of comics as a kid. I read Al all the dell stuff bugs funny portuguese.
I was little lulu was when I was really young was one my favorites too. But Barks and stuff you stood out quality wise. You beyond most everything else. Well, as someone who is in the midst of a
many hundreds of hours of podcasting, you won't get any argument.
From, You know, his stories stand the the test of time and they're ind. Yeah. And that's why, like, everyone around the world
appreciate some too. Number everyone can relate to Donald and his family and the things they go through because all families everywhere are basically the same. And you've had the opportunity to meet demand himself. Right? Yes. Met car Al few times, and I actually got to kid the first time I met him, we had just finished up three little cabins, my wife's
valentine's a day story. And I sent on Al Barks I sent Carl copy book com. And then we got invited to Steve Jeff birthday party for Carl. And following year, and Carl actually brought the call with him and pointed sound that I know played Al shelly I know you and we got together and talk. And it was like, a real joy that he had, you know, actually read the story and he knew the plot and knew what was going on with you liked it was like the start really relationship as far as, you know, having him breathe it. Like it. That's what was really all about really for me. Know just made my career like, successful just on the basis of his opinion. And that led to a story with him somewhere nowhere we're he enough john lost covered the story, and he was no longer in a position where get ink. He was his mid nineties days thinking is harder you know. Than painting when your older are getting shaky your thinking is the first thing to go. He actually had me
story, and I got to take it to and his birthday party Will Disney world, and we had a absolutely great day I get to talk to him for, like, a couple hours, but just being ham shape debris and we talked about shop talked about comic Barks that we like the adventure comic and he actually remembered, like a... I brought him a picture of the wash tubs story from nineteen thirty three and he actually remembered it and named The v from the store. I couldn't believe it guy his age from a story from nineteen thirty three that had been more about beforehand and you knew the bell and it was like, is it incredible memory? Oh, that's awesome. What what a thrill that must have been? I I definitely look for. I'm gonna have to gonna have to have you come back for that story because that'll be, you know, one of the last episodes that we get to do. We fun that will be. And and then so you get to work as well, you and your wife are an you were together on the stories. We do. Shelly is a really great gag writer as for his donald goes. She has a personality locking like dog, you know, things that don was do jacobs gets all mad it has a terrible things go flying in the air side dollar man. I'll write down with the plot line. I'm the technician guy who creates like a place. I'll give it a hard fund out and show and start gag and like works perfectly. It's like, like she's the greatest stag for donald that exists anywhere. That's.
I've always worked at same way. That she'll add guys and make it funnier and tell me when I've screwed up, and then then she'll throw out stuff. Disney will never approve and we have to turn you back. Right. Because this is how it is, and it works out really well. You have a it's good working relationship as far as duck stories. Well, that's great. What it what a great way to get to to work your craft. Man, I I am so excited and what i really it is to get to talk to a creator about one of the most legendary
of Carl Barks ten pager. I gave you the choice, and we we eventually landed that you would join me for the trouble with dimes. And this is didn't know that that was the the official title the story. Like, in a lot of these stories don't have titles on them, so you have to make it up and drive to me, it was always wear time. Story. Right. Right. The dime story. And, of course, but yeah, at some point, someone... I I picture, you know, some really weird meeting where a bunch of the people at, I don't know, Mont or another rainbow. Someone sat down and said, okay, This one's a fish gonna be called... Is this Hawaiian Hide away or the Many hoo mystery? And right And that's how I have, you know, some stories remembered the wrong way. Yeah. A lot of my knowledge didn't really collect chronic books like boxes, and bag them and stuff growing up. And I really didn't get in contact with fandom and with, you know, collecting in general until where i broken broke into comics. So I don't have a lot of the issue numbers and title names in my head. It's just like my own personal list, you know? And really broken away from that I do know that in this period of time, this is my favorite period of Carl Barks stories. Mh. I think from from February fifty one until October of nineteen fifty two, there's like about a dozen or more... But I would consider master ten page storage. They're, like super stories and you can't talk any of them. Just the best of do. It's an incredible run. I I don't think you'd get a lot of argument from most doc fans that that's just a an amazing series of ten pages So so you said you've got a list. Right? You and do. Do you have Al list We're really quickly love to hear your favorites. Well, this is my favorite from this favorite period. Because other favorite
outside him. But this particular cluster of great story is the more and where the story where the really kid lost out in the blizzard. It's that right. Two stories after that April fools story, which is one of my favorite the wallet story. That's one of my very favorite stories. Is wonderful And there's a swimming pull story where the kids go off the Donald tries decides to build a pole and gets into all kind trouble bailey.
Pool Barks, that's that's the classic. And then the very next story is the rare Diamond story, which is this where we going to talk to about today and then skip a story and the story after that is the Merit badge story where they out the lake and trying run the Merit badges, and Donald screws around with her building and different things messes it up. Right? Little little little boone head reference.
Yeah. And then the story after that is the hook playing hockey story to do anything to try to avoid school until he end up in a meeting of the truly officers. Yeah. Just a great little town. It's says particularly while you're story. And then two stories down the right from there the court famous Cornelius Cute story. With the status. That's one of them most famous and all the stories. And it
and I mentioned to you that that's the first first comment book I Severino read, so it's a special place to. Tremendous store that had one panel when they bail everything. It's like like a room mind. The story after that rocket wing the pigeon. I always like love that story. I'm not sure why. It's like one of my favorites the lock and wing the racing pigeon And the story after that, is the story about Gladstone
source of block. They're trying to figure out what the heck going on. Why is so lucky and it I I remember the couple fighting throwing the dinner out the window. Donald gets a pie and face Gladstone catches the food to tremendous through skip the story, got niagara falls and barrel story. Oh yeah. And that's an amazing story because I didn't actually see to what happened. You? And you would think it so obvious. But Karl was tremendous about hiding the climax access of the stories and pulling people. And in ten pages, that's extremely hard to do. Next story after that is the Gladstone story where they're hunting gems in the desert. And that's a really great story. The media right comes down and on the Gladstone plot. It's wonderful. And finally,
skip story, we have been recognized, which is one of the all time great stories with the Toy kind thing that the hepatitis donald but nobody else. It's like, it's like, tremendous story. Yeah. List of a dozen masterpiece stories is like, to me, the absolute pickup, Carl's production. You know, a lot of the stories are simple, but they're all about the best ones are the ones that are about home about Severino everyday things that happened everyone. And I think it's... The reason that it feels so great is everyone can relate to Yeah. Definitely agree. There are some all time classics in there. I'm I'm looking forward to covering many of those are gonna get their episodes. You know, I can't... Obviously, I can't do an episode for every ten pager or And there's so many great ones. You it's there are
really is but I'm definitely...
For back to school this here, I'm gonna do one that probably packages two or three of those true stories. Because those are all lot fun. They are awesome.
So
so, Patrick, let's go ahead and cover a little bit of the background
of this story if you're ready.
This one was as you mentioned, we're we're in nineteen fifty one at the height of his... What most fan say is his golden age. It has a Al publication date of July nineteen fifty one, This one was published in walt disney disease comments and stories one hundred and thirty. And i do like to pan to our international
listeners, Patrick and and share a couple of the titles from around the world. So I'll just mention a couple of fun ones really quick. The Italian title is papa
a pizza
which is Donald Ducktales the twenty piece. I guess when they translate it, that that was the denomination that they went with. And then let's do...
So in in Spain. This was published as
voice. Got a lot of titles
there's a in that. This duck is Al eagle. I think, yeah. This duck is an eagle
wanna
references the eagle and the. Sure. Yeah. That's great. Alright. So
Patrick, we're gonna go ahead and just go through the action of this story. I'm gonna
I'm gonna kinda break between pages and we'll comment on You know what what we think makes this story such classic.
So right off the bat I'll mention that this story is really fast because it's all about collect
and ra
and and scarce
and it seems like bark is gonna be really poking fun of the the idea of things being being valuable for no good reason
is the way I think he would see it. And it's... We were talking beforehand that it's extremely ironic Right? That he worked in in this medium where there there are people who collect con
phonetic,
what do you think how... How... Do you have any idea how he
responded to the the value and the scarcity of his classics. Well, I know that he didn't think anyone right his con. You know, he he would go to a drugstore on the slide, watch the kids looking at the comics and pick up super superhero the stuff. And you would pray that they would up donald that uncle scratch complicated and never thought it happened. So I'm sure they felt that there was no value to his comments. And of course, Even more I ironic because the fact that at the Publishers house would take his artwork and they threatened the trash bin after front it. Therefore making Artwork work today, some of them more expensive and rare or comic going to fun. That's right. Yeah. Yeah. Quite the irony. Alright. So so let's let's go ahead the trouble with dimes. This opens up with kind of these two simultaneous
actions by the Nephews and Donald. Right? We've got Huey, doing Louis are applying through a catalog of rare coins. While Donald is pacing in the background,
stressing out
about the dime the He owes his uncle Scrooge.
And the nephews user, you know, they're explaining to him that rare coins can be quite valuable. But Donald is just so focused. He is as he often is indebted, and that's all that he can think about. At the end of the page, the Nephews read that people will frequently find rare coins and old books and albums and that seems to trigger a memory in Donald. And Patrick, I love when Barks has characters
pacing in in worry. Yes. It's
awesome. This page has one of the funniest escapes to me personally of any of these stories It's the second panel. You know it's like, so funny. Like, the story starts off hilarious. Because Uncle donald got any rare coins, kid kids any coins I get her rare coins if any guys Barks up. He says, in fact, coins in my life was somewhere, haven't even got a dime to pay donald, ten cents Io. I should have old coins, but I can't hang on to the young one long enough to read the day. Panel four is killer. Thanks funny. You know it's not so much what he says it's the way that he says it. You this Barks had the knack for words and putting them in the order Al simple as possible and yet they've reads so fresh and funny. And that fourth panel just knocks me over. Like, every time I really it's like, so so funny. And then the end of each page, this is typical for Barks not last panel. Makes you wanna turn the page. Car Barks so hard on me storage. You this store is a very simple story. It's just basic panels there's no splash panels there's nothing unusual about the story. As far as the way it's laid out at all. And, yet, one of the most interesting way just carries you through from page to page. It's all done to characterization through gangs into logical
building and those, things get out of control. I I like your comment a lot about how thoughtful he was because because you're right. So on the next page, you know, Donald has had the realization that, hey, he does have some old coins. In an album from his great great grandpa
and he's relieved to to find them immediately.
And Donald is of the mindset that, you know, these coins are so old that they must be worthless.
Gonna try and pass it off to to pay off his uncle Scrooge. And so at that moment, Scrooge does arrive, and we've had this great, like, sn from Donald as he's
as he's paying off Scrooge and, you know, we've got the simultaneous action where the nephews go to look at the remaining coin from the album. They they've been having so much fun learning about rare coins that they're gonna go ahead and look it up. And as Donald arrives,
he is celebrating that he past that worthless coin off Scrooge,
characterizing him as a sucker. But the Nephews correct him and they let him know that in fact the diamonds worth five dollars. It's a very action packed page where they start running around Barks here is, like, starts off, like on a pretty good run, break from page two donald running for the album. And I like to get the gag third panel. Yeah. Here they are two old timers, that must be rare than eyebrows on eggs, yeah typical funny gag from from Coral... Probably no one else has ever used in the orleans. Yeah. He's got some great scripting flourish here. He does, and it's so simple. You know, his like, you know, Inducks indicates so much with just so such Al little thing, which makes all the emotional things and all the things that they're doing that much more impactful. But I I like how you pointed out how much like motion there is in in this very like domestic, you know, home set story because you're right, Donald
everyone's running around. The whole story is like that and increases. Know yeah story goes on people start ripping around, thinking through the money and doing all kinds of stuff further along. Yeah. The and this...
Alright. So the next the next page has donald kind of, like, the morning
that he just gave up this five dollar. I didn't look up the inflation. But but, you know, obviously, five dollars in the early fifties is is a good bit of money. It's not like a fortune or anything, but close a hundred dollars today? Yeah. That would have been my guess. So the nephews
suggest that, you know, maybe you can buy it back from from Uncle Sp and Donald like having you been listening. I don't have any money the nephews I love the way that they're flourishing the... The other coin. In the background because they point out you've if you've got another rare coin that you can sell for five dollars.
And so we transition
to the the coin collectors,
the the coin store.
Patrick, what's the coin store called? A mold and mildew collector's items Yeah. It's great. And and Donald is calculating
that, you know, if he can get Scrooge to give to give him back the old time for a new one, he'll He'll be able to sell that and he'll be up to nine dollars and ninety cents but when he arrives at screwed office,
not his money been yet, but his office, Scrooge is is naturally
suspicious of why he would want that Al dime back and he
suspect immediately that it might be valuable. But Donald passes it off as a sort of keeps say. There's a tremendous gag in year panel five after they suggest you sell the dime for five dollars. He's running out that we're looking at dom saying. Kids, sometimes I think you're almost bright. And you know, points out the fact the kids are almost always smarter with donald more on the ball, and he's more emotional and this sap to run off and do things without thinking about them. Right. It's a gray little turn of phrase. So Donald is realizing that Scrooge is is characteristic
gonna drive a much harder bargain than he'd like. And so he's forced to offer him a dollar for that dime because
in screws words,
he didn't become the world's richest man by trading even. Mh. Some some great reactions of of Donald just fuming.
And when he does pay him the dollar,
screwed direct him to what is labeled as is petty cash
and tells him he's gonna have to... He he takes Al less and telling him you're... He's gonna have to look through it. Because he's just stir around with a rake. And you wanna tell us what what Donald finds there Patrick. After digging a big hole hours is later, he finds a whole jar of don's looking... It looked just like the dime was looking for his so And I I love how at the end of the last panel. He's he's figuring out how much money it's worth This is a fortune, I can just get hold of these Five times five is twenty five, twenty five times five because i hundred twenty five times five money money money signs. Yeah like he's like this is going crazy. I love how he has a dig to the money to find the ancient jar dimes. And this is just a few issues before we first see the money been for the first time. Right. Voice she's down to red. Yeah. So it's like, you can feel like Barks leading up to the money bend here. He's probably rolling it over his head we're does keep all this money?
Where. The idea came about. Yeah. And this little bit of acceleration in the store, you know, we we started to see the shape of of where
time down on the desk. Yeah. It's great. So so Donald Rush is out and and tells screws that he'd like to buy five of these old dimes. Right? Because he can't buy them all at once. Right? He's got...
He's got funny he has in hand.
Yeah Exactly. And so he races down back to the coin shop while Scrooge puzzles over him being such an attic for keep safe. And
he presents... And we actually get to see the c at the coins store. I just saved to... Yeah. He's sees a funny looking little bit character. He's very... I I find him very memorable.
Maybe that's just because I remember him and and Don Rose sequel as well.
But.
But he he calls Donald Al lucky Lucky chap. And now the the shape of the story is taking place. Right, Donald,
Donald can't help himself
from doing what he's gonna do here, where he's gonna accelerate
every time he gets Scrooge
he'll buy some more of the coins, he'll return to get more seed money and Barks does such a great job of stories like this where he lets Donald hang himself. Right? He's he he creates his own trap for himself. And you can't see it coming.
And at this point, we don't know what's gonna happen either. You know, it's so hard to write the stories. Short ten pages, and i'll give away your end. It's too early. And you wanna keep that surprise for your audience at the end. And I remember the first time that I read this story I love seeing the coin guy. And Donald making money it's all working out. I don't see where it's gonna go. It's point, I I haven't figured out.
Well, one of my very favorite drawings of uncle Scrooge. The Barks that we did was the third panel here where Chris Scrooge serge is sitting with his his chin if he had one sitting on his hands. He's wondering I never knew donald it's such Al attic for keeps things. And it's such a great fresh night face. It is this this one is what like you said, there are no splash panels or anything, but it's Al about the the great expressive. In it.
And Scrooge is kind of an audience surrogate here. Right? Because you said we don't really know where it's gonna go and Scrooge is just He's very curious and on the next page Al Donald returns to buy a hundred and twenty five now, of the coins. He keep six, Scrooge has to figure this out. So so he pulls out a spy glass and he tracks Donald, and he sees him going into this coins...
And collector store. And Scrooge
immediately
processes what's going on. I like that he's not clueless here. He understands the idea of collectible.
He doesn't like it.
And he does view this as as him being sw here.
Yeah. This is a great point in the story. It's like speeding up, you know, it's getting over.
Donald it's this losing it all together and losing all reason
for much he can get and even though the hunt that keeps steak id idea no longer works. Clearly going with hundred and twenty five keeps. Scrooge says my lens to negotiating when donald runs in tells him he was a hundred and twenty five. He says that again later in story. And only time, I don't remember that happening. I'm using that particular phrase. And it suggests like, I guess, Scrooge is old fashioned and it's an unusual expression frame use. It definitely is. And I caught it in one of the other stories that I did very recently. And I had that. But but you're right period?
Definitely from the same period and very very rare. Right? That's yeah. Not not very common. Interesting. I love ways looking Al telescope.
Laying out the window.
And is that great shot going in. Excellent so I love having this conversation with you about this because it's it's only now making me appreciate how genetic this story.
Stories. Al the story is one big thing. Not individual panels so much. It's it's just one big blonde amazing.
Never miss a beat. Never use anything extra
storage. And and it's all about the race and
Barks and forth. Yeah. Twenty points the
page. And thinking it is the case so the homepage this is the page where it's all going back. It's the also that's dot oh.
Yeah have Right.
So so on the next page, we see to Scrooge is determined and he's gonna teach Donald lesson
two things. They're great. He's digging down
into his petty cache
until he arrives at four barrels that are
buried towards the bottom.
And any he calls out that... It's the first billion that he ever made down at the bottom of the pile where it's been for seventy years. And lists some of the rare coins that he's got, bush of pine tree shi, pieces of eight,
Did do you know patrick what a pine tree showing is?
I do not. I had to.
Yeah. I don't know what the pine tree showing is. No. I definitely didn't until I looked it up before doing this episode, and and it's
it is the first coin mint by
metal coin mint in North America.
It was mint by the
the... Some of the early colonists and in interesting. In Massachusetts,
I... Yeah. Now like
unauthorized, mint
outside of the crown knowledge but obviously a little gag about how old Scrooge is there. Yes.
And and so Scrooge finds what he was looking for a few more of those old keep say.
Yeah. A big sack. And and,
you know, the... This u moment is really called out. Bark calls it out in a narration box that where he says Donald doesn't know that his quote business
has been discovered. And and before Donald can buy six hundred, I I guess, six twenty five coins from him. So Scrooge
tells him let's not have any more of these small deals. He offers him ten thousand
of the keep six and crucially,
says that he'll trust him to pay him later. Mh. It's just great. And dude... Yeah. Those did he's out of his leg now. It's all of a sudden Don's dude. I love that. I guess my favorite two panels maybe funny in the story of those top two panels. Coin collectors make me sick, they don't start collecting until coins scarce and I'm the guy that makes them scarce. He's throwing those coins back. Thinking, you can seem go almost almost. He's like i'm covering his barrels, you know, huge barrels is deep in the money with. I'm glad you read that quote because that is a great I
feels like one of the most Scrooge
Quotes ever. I'm the guy that makes some scare. So because he's like this wealth forwarding. Yeah. It really could be right in there with the jumping through the coins i could go for and snacking and it's the same kinda deal Yeah. Yeah. Absolutely.
And I love you you talked earlier about how relatable these stories are, you know, Donald is being ridiculous here, but we cannot we can understand. This is such a human
true and greed. Something Al would do if we could absolutely so really.
And and so on the next page, Donald is doing more of that comedic calculating.
And he's, you know, figuring, oh my gosh. I'm looking at fifty thousand dollars, which genuinely is a fortune
Al at that era and and a a a nice summer of money even today, and he he says uncle screwed you're the biggest best friend I ever had
any he thought balloons that he almost called him a sucker
on the way back and Patrick, what a great moment when he gets to the test dealer. Do you do you wanna tell us about the interaction with the dealer? Well, this is like the part of the story that I remember the best with this with this coin dealer guy. And he runs in Al this huge sack i because I got ten thousand times for you this time mister.
Instead of being happy like, the first two times, but the guy that runs the coin Oh, no. You have got ten thousand times here. How terrible? What's terrible. By boy, where coins are like potatoes,
really valuable when they're scarce these ten thousand dimes would wreck the market take them out away in the woods and bury them. With like, hilarious it's so funny And it's like the funny thing is, I guess is a guys so calm and collective and so business like early on. And here it's like the stocks destroying the market of the coin collecting They won't be worth anything whatsoever.
It's
holding the sack. He has
he's literally holding the sack And and this is such Al this panel I think what he's trying to do with this page is really point out the ridiculous
of collecting.
Right. On the previous page, those coins had had their assigned value
And now there's more of them and all the sudden The story has always reminded me of a little tiny trial on story. Oh, yeah. If you remember the story with the with the bottle caps. You know? Absolutely.
Do it bower caps. These people and travel Al I never saw any money currently. They just like trade goods and stuff, and they get these bottle caps to get one, I think it's a wonderful thing. It's the same kind but. Basic
principal about society. And little test... This is like a little test version of that story. It's true. You know, it's it's interesting boxes is almost like running these
hypothetical economics
experiments in some of the...
Often.
No. Particular stories. They're like, tremendously great moral Ducktales. Also
the corn crib one. Right? That would probably qualify as well. These are like the kind of macro
things that that
egg heads would sit around and think what would happen if you introduce this? Kinda thing if you read it, You know. It's a school kid. It would technically you learn more about economics then any ten books that they've forced down your throat taxes because is like funny so is. And, yeah. So obviously true. Easy to understand. Yeah. For sure. And
space on the last panel of this page is like like one of his angry
looks it is. Yeah. And he he he is extremely angry, and he he immediately blames the nephews.
Right I don't I don't think very fairly, but it it is a it works in the comedic sense, and we gotta... We have to bring the nephews back in. Right? Because he's he's gonna close the story. Another another thing about this story that makes it different Al lot of the ten pages. Is this story really doesn't have the climax. It's got this moment when knows the things have gone disaster holding me back. And you got the upcoming two things that are coming up. But there's two sets true. Yeah. But there isn't really a moment story we,
this is the climax of the story. It's like just like whole story is a single unit that you can't pick out parts of it and say this is that and this is that that goes together and there isn't any any moment that's exactly the con. Yeah. That's true. It has it has an interesting structure here at the end.
So so the nephews are are running away from their threatened corporal punishment.
Which, you know, it's a common comedic trope at this time.
And
and and they basically sum it up by saying this morning
the kia uncle Scrooge ten cents tonight he owes him ten thousand dollars. He says it's all our fault. And that night when they and eventually get away, I guess or Donald cools down. They're kinda mu it over in bed. The.
Oh, it's great. And they decide to have another look at that rare coin catalog, and they read some fine print about the dime,
and they make a great discovery.
And Donald catches them at night. Pouring through that sack full of dimes,
looking for the one that is stamped with the eagle
upside down.
Because that one is actually worth twenty thousand dollars.
Oh this is where that eagle reference comes in and this Spanish title. Right. Now it comes together. And this... The cool thing about this last panel, and the this thing is like, you know it you can get sprung on you, you're not expecting me but the thing is it's a real thing coin. Yeah. You real there collectors, you know once quite bit. This printed upside down like that and be worth for for So it's like it brings a a real world thing into the story. And another one of those just quirky aspect
of collecting where the error can be worth... You know, I I realized when I grabbed this issue,
lava uncle Scrooge that the the the one that I have from the month before was printed with two covers.
And so, you know, clearly, that is my
upside down eagle. Put that in your money been collectible.
Oh, man. What was I gonna say? Oh, I was gonna also point out that we're just a few months away from him using this element in the guild man. It's referencing that that dentist camp too. So and that never current The second panel on this page is really interesting because of the way it sums everything up to nicely. Mh. Yeah. But nephew saying that the the ten cents, ten thousand dollar thing, you need that in there. You know, you needs the reader needs to have the amount summed up and it's done in such a nice straightforward fashion, like, really makes the story perfect because if you are real careful about the numbers, you might be confused at this point. Basically sums it up. Yeah.
It it doesn't feel like it's catch up. It feels very organic. So so the closer of the story flashes to to sc,
and he's decided that he needs to bone up on rare coins as well. So he's got the same catalog.
And and he's chuck to himself as he comes across the entry for the. That he unloaded on Donald the dimes that he unloaded on Donald. And and as you mentioned, we see him use that utterance again to own my lands to go
and he leaves out of bed and horror and and races the next morning aiming to get the coins back from Donald. And you want... You wanna tell us how it how it concludes here, Patrick is well, it's too late because these the lands and this is that was fast I've ever seen Scrooge run too on that next morning panel he's really rolling for prescription all does that off Scrooge don't same movement that fast to they slammed straight and the donald coming out of the mold and they'll do collector's items in store. And Scrooge you you. Yes. The kids found that upside down done, and I cashed it in. So it's turned around, You know, the...
Minute ago, donald was on the receiving end of things. And now it's sc, which don't really expect to happen. So the last panel Scrooge just running right to left chasing
Donald, like he was chasing the kids a minute ago. Huey, sw by cheap rob, your poor Scrooge door, and then the final gag which just we be able to gather up the green Barks men and don't overlook any of that's upside down. And it's like a perfect little gag at the end. And that's, you know, that's really why I said there was no real client? Because this adds to that... Yeah, these three these... Really these three pages of the climax story. Which is amazing. To me Yeah. It's like, you know, I I don't know like a write a story where it carried on that well. And, yeah, it still feels like it's a real contact when you get to the end. And so bundle ones. This just one of my very favorite stories and always will It is it is definitely a classic You're right. It's a great little cap at the end. The gag out. We know that callbacks are funny. Right? And the call to the upside down error that's that's another little punch at the end. I was always surprised with this one that
this really does feel like one Donald is close supposed to learn.
Lesson.
She think. Yeah. But he but he does come out on top. Mh. He does. And, yeah, it's like it all reverses because all of a sudden Scrooge on the losing side and sk is chasing gong what a minute ago. You the night before Donald is chasing the kids, and then the kids have the final gag and say so they're the here. Right. And and they they got it all by by reading and just just being interested the only people who were informed to start with you not to start to borrow ball rolling, and they are reward Al the end by, I guess, by picking up some green Barks and peeling like they've succeeded Mcdonald's being scared getting beat up Scrooge. And discourage is angry losing losing out. That was like the kid stories were always my favorite. I like these kids when the kids are involved. I... Like the stories more and when it's just donald they're just screwed. It's great
there they're such good avatars for the reader. Right? And and yeah there's so much great wish fulfillment and how resourceful they are. Yeah. I i suspect that
carl growing up in the in the west I'm not having other kids around We talked about that before. And he always wanted to be a voice scout. He told me he likes scouting, but he never had the opportunity, so he... Like, this was his chance to imagine being a scout. That's like really cool. That's why that he could. His kid's like related to the kids and used them so much. Because it was like, wish fulfillment from when music kid. Totally agree. Yeah. The the junior wind checks asked Barks definitely feels like him imagining,
you know, what he could have left you could done. Pretty So so what what a great story, Patrick I... I'm I'm so excited to to get talk about this one. It works. It's a very tight
story very fast paced
and very little story. It's just a little
everyday kinda tail. But, yeah, it's just someone one Yep And I find that I appreciate those stories more than I did as a kid. Right? Because I can kind of see how well constructed they are. Now I I did an episode. I think I told you recently I recorded, but i haven't released one on hair of the beagle boys, that first one with the beagle boys, and I I didn't realize until revisiting it at at this age, how much of a like,
a stage play that one almost is.
Really tight, really great Yeah. The this this is definitely a gray era for these ten pager.
Is.
Any other thoughts about the the overall story? I know we've we've talked a lot about just how well it works.
Why Made a little sum of the whole whole thing and Al little little paragraph. Let me tell you what I what I was thinking. By all means. More than most of these ten pages,
This one builds on everything that comes before. Has zero ways is text visually simple and perfect. And that sums it for me. You know just is just... It's tone down... Carl been writing stories and drawing stories for long enough period of time. He he's fifty years old. This point about fifty. And he'd been working since forty three nineteen forty three drawing you writing the things. I think this is the point in time where it was no longer any kind of a chore
he wasn't tired of yet, You know it was still fun. And his thinking was, like, really supplemental snow. Like in a couple of years his thinking starts to, know, be stiffer. But at this point, his writing is still going up I think you still, like improving as a writer at this point. Carl thoughts too bad when I talked to Carl I asked him like, how he about later stories. He told me that he thought that he had kept him his while was drawing dropped Barks if finally.
There's plumbing whose gag could creation of bags and placing and a story we're still improving up to be. And I would agree with him, but, you know, even though he was, like, suffering someone being bored, maybe with the later stories repeating things that generally speaking is writing... Did get tighter sharper as he went right up to the end for the most on.
And at this point, you these mature both aspects. It was writing and drawing. Drawing, I think, picked first. Think it's, like, forty eight forty nine. It's like, starts to get beautiful sup one can't be. And then his writing hit... And about this point, he reached the point where he was at, you know, just amazing z right or two. And, know, that comic with that combination of narrative pictures and the like a a halt and
in order to make the best stories you can be it's a lot easier for a single person to do it. Than a team. You know one of the problems with most comic books stuff isn't the fact that the artist or the right isn't isn't as good as it could be. But the fact that you've got this sort of assembly line for automobile
way of putting things together, which doesn't really fit it express autistic meeting particularly well. So I think, you know one of the reasons Carlos is as good as he other orders never had the opportunity of doing everything. Right? Yeah. Having that one one unified voice. Obviously, it makes the difference I I think you're totally right. You can see at this point he he's just
eminent comfortable
with what he's doing. Right? And he's got got amazing confidence.
I I do like to cover a little bit about kind of the the community perception of the story. And, you know, we've been referring to this one as as a classic.
The community definitely agrees. If you check this one out Inducks,
when you know, which is the community web page where people can rate their stories.
This one is very highly rated it gets a seven point eight out of ten, which is good for right now, eighty Severino out of all
forty one some thousand
com, which I believe I remember right places it as his most highly rated ten pager.
Really?
Yeah. I had no idea. I think... Yeah. I mean... I made a little... I made myself a little spreadsheet at one point. Amazing...
Yeah. So I wasn't wasn't bet... I would have bet would've than one like fancy like, the quite cornelius cute story, where it's like more it's got big panels and like, you know, i about bet on. I wouldn't thought that this would would have been why people had superb taste
right to pick a simple story like this. I think this is legendary for a reason. But you wouldn't be far off because that one, you know, which goes by stat
spend drift these days that
story. Yeah.
I I like it. Right? It's it's it's a it's a liter, and it's got a bit of a gap in it. But I think that one is like the second or third.
Is it's somewhere in the top five again of the ten pager. The the adventure stories stand out more in people's minds so they tend
much higher
for for obvious reasons, but. But these are these are wonderful in their own right. And so, yeah, this is this is very highly regarded by the community. I do like to mention when there have been notable sql and follow ups.
Don rosa did a sequel to this one that is one of my favorite of his stories. The money pit. Mh.
And I I think it may be
I think that one's
appreciated because hi that one stands out to me as one of his best follow ups to a Barks story, I think. Mh. Yep. Oh, you know, we've you've you've talked about some panels. You've highlighted some, but I I do always ask guests to mention if they have any that really stand out is like their they're very favorite of the story. Well, as far as being memorable, it's definitely when he goes back to the last time of coin. You know, it's like it's not a specific panel. It's that section of the story when... You know, It's like, you have got ten thousand times here. How terrible
right comparison to potatoes. It's like, it's, like, wonderful. I was that was the section of the story that from me when I was kid just killed it. You know, I was like, was so great? I I agree with you. I find that one really memorable. I think that's a great contender for best panel. I also really like donald
over the top expression of greed
before
just a couple of panels before that one that you mentioned when he's doing the calculus over,
you know, fifty thousand dollars
drooling he's
we're pretty much. Yeah. And and then at the end, the great collision between
Donald and
Is.
Just just so much great motion in this one. There's one tremendous... The two panels with Scrooge digging through the money for the to get to the dimes too little areas. Yeah. Way they're flying back behind you My keys go for
dad. Excellent.
Awesome. Well,
my anything else you wanna mention before before we wrap this up so up patrick I think that pretty well covers everything that I was thinking
part as the the story. It's... You know we talked... We covered pretty well. I thought yeah. I I agree.
It it's been a delight to have you on. I'm so grateful. For this and hope I hope to get to bring you back for others. Well, I certainly enjoy it very much. And I never get to talk about story of depth like this people is a real pleasure. Yeah. I find that I really
start to notice new things when I when I really
over these details. Yep. There's Al lot to see the new bulk story. For sure. Well, listeners,
feel free to chime in on the bar remarks Facebook page, and we will hopefully
see you back. We're... You'll hear us back for for more
episodes of the ten page podcast, and our regular
episodes as well. Thanks again, Patrick. Thanks for helping me.