We have
Hello, and welcome to Barks Remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comic of all time. This episode is a ten page podcast, all about one of his short stories. Get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Welcome back to Barks Remarks. I'm Mark Sever of Grown man who enjoys Inducks comics,
and
I am joined by a very special first time guess that I'm I'm very decided to have on the show. I'm joined today by John Lust,
and and we are gonna be talking about one of Barks all time great ten page stories. For this episode of the ten page
podcast. So I'm gonna ask him to
introduce himself and and tell us a little bit about his background
with Carl Barks and with dot com.
Okay. Hi, Mark. Well, I started with I was a newspaper reporter
edit
photographer
for a small newspaper chain for about the first ten years of my working life. Previous to that when I was in college, I actually sold my first comic book story to Western
publications, which was published at that time under gold,
I did a Daphne Ducktales
pager. And then I got into doing newspapers and I didn't have time to do that I mean,
comic books. And so
after
those ten years, I've been doing comment writing comic books, and for about twenty five of those years,
I was writing Inducks stories, Disney deduct stories, and
I
started out
being teamed up with my friend Bill Van horn,
and I worked Al little bit with Carl
sort of That's complicated.
And I'm met all number of times. And after we died, I got to
complete some Karl and un completed stories, some of which have appeared here in some of which happened. So... And
unlike a lot of the hardcore Inducks
fans
Inducks
writers
let's say, like, Rosa or
van horn I did not really grow up on Barks
I
read one dot one Barks story. I remember from when I was a kid. It was the
ten cent Al, which was magic with spells
second appearance. Oh, yeah. And I I enjoyed that. But I didn't know who Carl Barks was.
And
shortly after that, I
discovered superheroes and I was buying comics for myself
finally.
So I was lost on
superheroes until somewhere in my college years. And
then I found a couple of
Barks
comics Al a garage sale, and
it was the golden helmet and a trick treat. And I was I was Al English major and a journalism major, a that double major. And just as a writer, I just I was just totally blown away by those. I mean, I couldn't have been more
surprised and shocked And that's when I became a Barks fan. And So I approached
this maybe from a little different perspective. It's it's not
nostalgia for me. It's like, oh, my god. This is these were particularly the goal helmet, which is my favorite Barks adventure. Oh, yeah. And
it was like... And and trucker treat took of finding fine. Sorry, too. But
it was like the... These are two of the
comic stories, best stories period. I've ever read. And I was just Slack jaw
dumbfounded
completely bold over but years later when I got to meet Carl, I took those two comments with me, and I don't think he had ever had anybody and these were the most beat comics you could imagine. Right. And I love Yeah.
Well well love, and he picked them up and he just waved him in the air back and forth because they were, like, paper obviously, paper, but they were especially thin and floppy,
and I don't think he didn't had any po
in such bad shape that he'd been asked to
sign. Most people are having
probably be because you know, and
that was fun. Now I've still got those Scrooge away somewhere in my collection, but
Anyway, and and as I said, I I did
sort of collaborate with him on
as story. And pat walked
through that and they did a great job on that. But there was some interference on
part of some people at the Barks studio,
that kinda sent a story in a weird way away from what Carl had in attend. And so years later, I...
With my editor
approval, we we redid that story as somewhere beyond nowhere. I and done. Yep this dr it, and
I think it's much closer to what Carl like. But it it's unique to have two different versions,
completely different versions of one of Carl stories like that. And... Yeah. And and it seems like
Don Yet is usually involved when there two different versions. Yeah. Yeah. Well it's so good. And is such a huge Barks fan, and
my editor is no longer
working at the... Unfortunately, Byron as far as Eric and as far as I know, is no longer editing that Gladstone.
But he... Yep was his favorite artist, and I supposedly was his favorite writer, so he wanted to tame us together when whenever possible and done Al the the little things that I did of Barks
after that too. So... That's really neat. I I came across that that you had done another... An additional version of it kind of been looking up some background for the episode and I haven't gotten to to see that one, so I'd be really interested in checking that out. So I was just gonna say, there's a lot time unpack in in your opening. Right? Because you you are
As you mentioned, I've gotten to have Patrick blocked on here. He's
fantastic artist I've had a couple of other duct creative,
Henri,
House, and
Y,
the the editor at E, I think he's done smart as well, but you're first time I've had someone on who's done Inducks writing, And
I I just I wanted to acknowledge that I'm I'm a really big fan. You know, you mentioned the Gladstone era.
Just
chuck and appreciating your appreciation. And since you mentioned the Gladstone error,
you were getting into that. There only
three
lancer brought on it Gladstone. And in Cla one, the first right.
For was Rosa,
then it was and on, and I was friend's bill,
and it's sort of work together a little bit. He's some of my plot on the last issue of his own series called Nervous Service rat. Yeah. And I asked since bill doesn't
Al for the most part.
I was sort of his liaison on when I went down to the San Diego Comic con and and talked to Gladstone stone and got information on how he could submit. And when bill started doing this stuff, then he started... He was doing, you know, donald up uncle sp, and then they asked them to do Ducktales and he's and he said
do you wanna do some
with me. And so that's really where I started. Oh, wait a minute. Before that, Mh. Before that...
We did some... I did a couple of one pager and a couple of two pager,
and that's really a great way to start
Everybody when they start writing. And I know it's through in the duct world, but it's probably true and and any established
universe
common universe. They wanna do, like, four zillion different characters.
And they wanna do that a forty eight page or sixty four page
story so forth and, you know, But starting really small is great because it teaches you how to get just what you need in, and it helps teach story structure
too. So anyway, that's just my reflection on how to get started. These those are great that sounds like great writing tips to me, and and I'm definitely interested in talking about story structure, you know, as we go through our story today.
And I don't I don't wanna wax on too much about it. But, like, you mentioned beat up comments, you know? I oh it's I think it's blurring thing it's boring
on but I... But But this is the issue.
Yeah. That that this was probably one of the, like, first three or four comics that I I ever read. And and just by everyone. I I
so... And for people who...
Who don't see each the video you're talking about... I think it's Ducktales number seven. Yeah.
Win windfall on mount Ga guide. I don't I don't remember all my titles, but I remember that That's such a a memorable title to me and it's such a Za story.
And and those that collaboration that you and
It's funny to me to to think of him as bill. Of course, I think of him as William Van Horn. Right.
You you and William Van horn had such a great collaboration. I I have really grown to appreciate his stories over the years. When I when I saw them originally, they didn't always grab me the way that I. There's a certain, like, Barks
goofy
really odd ball sen
to them that's just incredibly unique and and and very funny. Glad I to hear you say that.
Yeah. I think
bill has this different approach. And although he's done long stories, and I've done a few long stories.
Most of our is in shorter pieces.
And bill is all about to X yeah and sioux football
and bill is
like Barks,
god is training as as an meter. Right.
Yeah. And I think that of fetch both of their work very much. So.
But bill
favorite comic was Crazy cow. Oh, and
that that's That's obvious. Right? Right. Right. And if you look at bill's
own series his nervous rex, which is being printed. Sure. His style is a a natural drawing style is more in the crazy cat. Version. You know? I I'm glad you said that. I can I can definitely see a lot of hair
George George Har? Right? And and that kind of whoop
very
realistic. And and I think you're waiting. That
sometimes decision and Yeah. And even in bill's Ducktales stories, you can see place placing
weird little things in the background.
And buy still a little bit of that where it have different, like duct paintings in the and and the background and you know, I on four zillion du and in and a picture
hanging on the walls
But yeah. It it's a very different approach than just about anybody else does. Yeah. It's it's very unique. I think in Disney comics. And it's rare to see someone who is not kind of trying to ape Barks, you know, for for a good reason. Right? Because he is the mass so like, I understand what you're talking about There there's something very kind of quiet and understated about that, like, I I can't keep coming back to the word and our but, like, the the van horror stories, they just... They have these rules, but then he just constantly breaks them in in in a way that that's very funny.
Very like early loo tunes very early Barks. I think one of my one of my other hosts. Pointed out that he he is like the air of Barks early stories. Yeah. I I think that's that's a good distinction to make as opposed to is later
stuff and and so forth. And bills ending to stories tend to be very soft
in most cases. They don't have doing...
Sometimes I wish they had a little more punch.
And
I think when we work together the stories out a little more punch. But but that's built. And and it's a very... If you look at crazy cat, they would do the same thing. It's it's not characters punching each other at the end or you know, of
falls. It's just character just talking and a little bit of
philosophy
or,
you know,
wisdom or or They kinda trail
like No. Off. And that's how
bills stories, not all of them, but some of them a lot of them do. And you just have to appreciate it a different level. Right. I think so. Alright. So thank you so much for Inducks me in talking about you know your own work. So
as I mentioned,
we we get to talk about a really great story today. I think I think that most fans if they were asked
to name some of their favorite ten pages. There's there's a pretty good chance.
That people would name this one, you know, in the first ten or so. I have
I was gonna bring this in later, but you're you're... Are you gonna bring in index writing on this? I do. I usually mention Inducks at the end, but you're welcome
I've got I've got something to add to that when you get to that. So... Yeah. Absolutely.
But... Yeah. Yeah. This this is really classic. This is one of the ones people boys talk about. And
I was thrilled that you allowed me to to do this one. It was one of a couple that we
talked about me doing, and the other one
was flip.
And I... I've got all the Barks library and I've... I've got so many of these stories in, like, triple or fly
and so forth, but I pulled one of the color Barks
Al
And mh. I was shocked when I went through that and the... I think, five stories there they've got three of my favorites. They've got on,
the Hip no gun story U. Flip,
and that's all in a six month period. Carl was really hitting on all cylinders
there As far as I'm concerned, this is, I think, fifty two into fifty three. Boy. I mean, what a great What a great period?
That wasn't... I I know that wasn't a happy. And that's also
about the time said he did the golden Helmet. Right which I think is one is the great Barks
long
epic story. And the darkest of his stories too.
But what a great period? You know, I mean, it it apparently came out of a period where it was very unhappy.
And it just shows you how you can kind of rise above that, but how sometimes so much comedy is based in I am on paying to to some degree. Yeah. It's just very interesting me. Yeah. You said it. What what a great period of time for him? That's part of the details? That I always mentioned, this one had a cover date of November of nineteen fifty two, along with many of his other are great. Stories around that span. Yeah. It was originally published in walt Disney comments and stories number one hundred and forty six
And
it's it's had a pretty good number of reprint as you might expect. And in the Us, it's had eight different reprint.
And, you know, they they weren't titled originally. So there was a couple of proposed titles that have alternate titles people used over the years and only kinda just settled on on. But and one alternate title was a town called.
And I think a lot of the most memorable ten pager.
John can kind of be dis distilled down to their their hook or they're high concept. Right? And right.
Like flip
has has the great coin flip element By the way, that guy at the beginning of the story that side character, He feels like such a van horn character to me. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Just Al a random side there, But but this one, you know, the... It's the... It's the egg story. It's the chicken story. People know this story. And
And, of course, a big part of why I think this one really hits for people. Is that Barks has such a personal connection.
To the story into the concept.
Right?
Because... Right. This this was his like, this was his backup when he was transitioning,
to
taking up the Comics full time.
He he reported feeling a little bit uneasy about putting a, I guess, putting all his eggs in the the basket of of comic book making.
And so when he and his wife at the time moved out to San Ja
his backup was chicken Farming. Right. And and you get the sense from that that he was writing out of out of personal
experience. Right? Yeah. Yeah.
When we talked about me doing
the broadcast the two stories we're talking about where was this one and flip.
And both of them are kind of top plot based stories,
particularly this one. Yeah. And I tend to prefer more character based ones, but the structure on this one
and the way it's plotted and it... It's it's almost a blue blueprint to how Karl did stories, and then we'll talk about that later. But
one of the other reasons I wanted to do it be because I knew to Carl was a chicken farmer, Right And and
so some of this is, like, based on personal experience,
and there's
one panel in there is so ironic once you know that. And
what I didn't realize at the time until I started researching for this
podcast was...
I didn't realize that this was
often the the story Karl got Al his favorite ten page. Yeah. Yeah. I I encountered that same fact and it's so funny. I've been... I have kind of a running thing where I track all of the stories that he has called his favorite over the years, because, like, he did it for so long but, of course, he he'd answer different ways. But you're right when he when he talked about the ten pager,
at least, this is usually the one that came up, and I I think you can really feel his personal connection. It's easy to remember at it's easy to visualize him kind of yeah thinking about his own experiences.
Sure. And it's a goofy
funny concept
that that was that was the only thing. It's just a goofy.
Sorry. Yeah. Absolutely.
Let's see.
Before we actually dive into the story,
I... I'm just gonna read a quote from an interview he gave.
He he had said that when he left the studio, he really wanted to get to a dryer climate
because quote the air conditioning was knocking the hell out of my sinuses.
And so you... He said that the only way he could think to make a living was to have chickens.
And so he he he basically he didn't wanna have have anything he had to take, like, to take care of on a routine.
And he said they made him a little bit of profit before he phase them out.
But he ultimately found couldn't take care of chickens as well as right and draw. And, you know, comics were what made what paid him more money. So thank goodness for that. Right. And I think comics are not noted for being a particularly well paying field. So anytime it pays better than your day job, quit date.
Right. Yeah. You've gotta gotta a jump on that. I'm sure. Right So...
Alright. So,
John, we're gonna jump into
the the meat of this icon story. And I'm just gonna kind of na some of the
the broad action on each page and and in in between the pages, you know, you and I gives some commentary on the the art
or anything that strikes us. But especially, I definitely wanna think especially about the riding. Since I'm fortunate to be joined by you for this episode.
So so right away, on
opens up with this
I think it's a an interesting device. Something that he has used
before. Right? It... It's got Donald and daisy and the net. Fuse driving. They're they're just entering the town of onwards.
And and we see that it's population
thirty. I I think that's kind of an important element, right? That it's this tiny little bird. Oh, absolutely.
And
So you know, to me this this device that he uses is is this, like, passing
through town,
and and he is gonna take some time to kind of do a big flash. Right? The bulk, the meat of this story is gonna be this flash that is told
He's telling it to Daisy, but really he's telling it to the reader.
And he uses this great hook, which is the town's goof ball name of.
And as Daisy is pondering,
why on Earth, it's called.
The the Nephews in Donald are kind of distracted by put donnie
disguise
and having this conversation about, you know, you can't possibly
intend to drive through the town. It's not safe. And
and, you know, I I love this. Right, Daisy is an avatar for the reader? Who's wondering what the heck is going on. And so yeah. And then go ahead. Got up. Know. No. That's...
Now
what I wanted to say about this page is... And and you're absolutely, right, that easy
serves as the he has a very small role in this story. She this there at the beginning and at the end. But with not daisy, there is no reason for donald to do a flash.
And without the flash, if you told the story just straight, donald wouldn't be the narrator.
And being the narrator really add something to the story. Gives it... It it says a lot about Donald attitude
and and
towards down
until forth is revealed to the narration
addition what happens and so forth.
But I I could be wrong on this. But it might be the only story where donald there separates his own direct. I Know. That's I I think there's another story that has
this same structure where he did one of those soft remakes. Do you remember the one... I I don't remember the true title, but I think it's called, like, mount much more where it's it's kind of the same thing where they're driving
through, and he's explaining about this
disaster that he inflicted. I'm sure you're right. I used to be I'm sixty nine now I used to be able to keep all five hundred almost all five slots in my head. And I just can't do it. I don't even remember all my stories at this point. But Right. I mean, I have the benefit of being an obsessive
podcast host. And and, you know, doing these active searches when it when it's... But you're right. This is a very rare story structure
for Carl Barks, and I... That's part of why this one has to stand out. Right? Because Oh yeah. It's a great point you made. He... He's a very reliable later, but we see his... We hear his attitudes
about kind of the town and and what happened.
Right. And it it's great. This is such a great setup. Two
on it's very economical. I even though, you know, in ten pages,
voting Al pays is quite a bit of
percentage of the story. But
in the very first panel, you get in the name of the town that is only thirty people, at least only thirty people now would have been bigger before donald they had just
donald there. And
you get... And if you look at the for the readers who aren't following along with the comic in front of them, Daisy has this kind of physical
look on her be
and that first panel. And then as you watch the panel progression, the kids are explaining
kids in dog are going like, okay. Do we have to go through
and and and don't have any other way around and here's the disguise and Daisy eyes get bigger, and there's there's actual sweat marks coming off of her I I guess that's what they are. And anyway it's so concerned and she's on the fifth panel. She actually looks kind of frightened.
And by the last panel, she's actually looking angry with Donald like,
yes. By all means explain what's going on, In terms
of physical action accommodate, there's almost nothing that end this page
except it's very funny, and it's all based on reactions. And and
to some extent
Donald point of these absurd disguise and cell and the kids.
I did wanna mention that the sixth panel and you have donald
and Daisy
actually going through the town and to emphasize what is sleepy...
And and oh, I'm sorry. Going back to base. Panel. You have the town in the background and donald and a
daisy
and silhouette and And so it really focuses your eye on the town. So you get a sense of
location and so forth And then on that next to the last panel, they're going through actually going through the town and to emphasize what a small
sleepy town it is,
there's someone in the on the side it's somewhat of a stereotype. It's.
Sleeping, you know, taking a Cs
and there's a dog in the street,
sleeping, and there's a cat there who's just kinda looking at the dog and
or oh there's a car coming. No. How unusual?
You know? Right.
You know? And
and there's a sign on the wall going count sale, which is not what you would get in most
communities. And just describes it tells you so much about this community and so much of the... It's just a beautiful piece of storytelling
setup so absolutely.
Just a handful of these details, he paints such a a great picture and this really economical. He's only got ten pages.
To do that. And and when I started writing comics, one of the best pieces of advice I got from an editor there was don't just have the characters
talking and doing stuff. Try to get fit in as much as you can. So it'd be very economical
and
maybe you're often trying to do two things at the same... Same time. And
Barks does this beautifully
throughout that first page.
So yeah that's all had to have about that. Those are great details. I I really appreciate that.
And I... I'm gonna add that I love the the boys look of apprehension at the last
That that Everything about this first page is so
intriguing to the reader. It's not a mystery story, but Barks is setting up this mystery.
What the heck happened in
and how is it connected to the docs? And I agree that Daisy acts as the reader here And when... I'm sure when I was reading this story the first time, I had the same reaction as daisy.
Yes.
Heck is going on.
You know, it's just so perfect. Yeah. That's all.
That's perfect. It makes for such a great page turner.
So
so on on the second page, we do start to get kind of the lay of the land. Right?
And Donald actually presents it as a story. He says the story begins a little over a year ago when I rented that farm on the hill up there. And we get kind of a gradual
look at this hilltop top farm that the doctors are gonna
gonna inhabit for a while.
And as as you say, we get a great sense of place of.
Right? The farm
stands
Mh.
Quite a bit above the rest of the town. And can we learn in this panel where where Donald looks really a mu or or for Lauren that the town used to be called pleasant Valley.
So so we're building a little bit. A little bit to what's gonna happen.
And and basically, it he explains that they intended
to... This was one of Donald Get rid
schemes, he wanted to become a chicken farmer,
but did he say, he said, I'd heard that farmers were getting rich so I set out to raise chickens. That line cracks me up because... Because you don't generally hear about farmers getting rich. Right? I and
that was actually...
When I read the story where like I was going... Yes. This is why I've that if nothing else was why I wanted to do that at the story because call
knew that you didn't get becoming a farmer.
Yes.
The contrary commentary on and stuff and
un donald,
and I personally...
And mcdonald's not a very pleasant person
throughout this story. And... Right. It it doesn't... I think Carl had a great respect if you look at, like, the middle and story
or the story he's delivering
the mail
again Blizzard and s for. Probably had a great respect for the working man and for the particularly people who doing things every day, and we didn't get much attention. But I don't think he had much respect for
people who wanted to get rich quick. Yeah And I think that's one reason
Donald
doesn't get treated
trade very... He's not a heroic occasionally, he's a royal character. He's not in this story. Right.
That's a great point. You're right. He really
he really
this hard work.
But you know, he hates Gladstone gander or one of his, like, most famous characters you can tell. He does not like him.
And so, you know, they... Barks does a great job of just setting up Donald and the nephews learning the ropes,
farming chickens,
We see a little bit of passage of time and we learned that the chickens are not growing
or rather they're not... They're not laying eggs the way that donald dixon specs them too. He's just feeding and feeding them. We see his little
johns into the town for supplies
his noisy truck is is annoying
the locals. We get this sense that they they really
dislike him being there. And by the end of page two, Donald become impatient with their slow rate
and he whips up
this, like,
collection of vitamins and minerals to make them legs. To do you mind telling us about some of the things that go into it? Pool
oil,
tu time,
main pure and heat pills.
And this is
one of... I think this is the first
indication actually, going back a panel, can I go back a panel just very brief wait? Absolutely, anything on this page is game right now. Okay. He's holding up one of the chickens,
and the chicken looks like it is gotta it by the neck.
And and he's looking at his glance of... As his like pure murder and the chicken looks very nervous and
I think those
these chickens need a special buyer
me. And his solution to that is to
come up with this
special mixture of
we call vitamins and manager
just... It looks
a perfect way to poison
Right. And
this is really the
thing where his get rich feelings sort of manifest them himself action
and
we'll have many other
instances of this. But each one of those
makes things much worse. So this is the first one. Right. Yeah. He's he's really gonna sabotage
himself in this. So
we we see the results pretty quickly of this very Barks
he makes. The Nephews tell him that the chickens feathers are really quickly falling out.
And I like John how he he flashes back and forth, right, between the Inducks on the farm and down in the town, and the the towns people's reaction to everything.
It's a it's a great structure.
They see the feathers all gathered there and they they think that they're in for an early
snow
and
and and, you know, if you think about some of the progression of this, it it it it doesn't really
It falls apart under scrutiny, but it it definitely works with, like, comic book lodge. Right? I think it's very tight for chronic lunch.
Because this this early snow approaching makes them all realize that they need to seal their roofs
against rain and snow and so everyone in town goes out to tar their roofs which which is something that people really really do or did? I think we probably mostly use other materials now.
And and by the end of the page, Donald is trying to turn this into a into
something that can benefit him, he realizes, hey, we can gather and sell these feathers to pillow makers.
Yeah. And and so Donald has tendency in this thing to go from his thoughts go from, like, a to immediately to z instead of b is c or d. And, you know, in terms of... Let's get rich and he doesn't think things out. So
And I I just wanna
say a couple things here.
Yeah. One the those poor chickens, it's it's I wonder they're not dead.
Y'all lucky, they just
lost their feathers.
But
they're both pathetic looking
and frankly kind of funny.
Yeah. Is And
it's
getting to your point about comic,
and I know what you mean by that, but it's... I wanna break that down
what in comic books, at least in some creators for some creators,
particularly if you're doing humor,
If it's not shown on the page, it doesn't exist unless you want it to. And so the villagers,
the tone people
who are down below
looking up
and seen all this white on top of the hill. It's not a mountain. It's a hill.
And the fact that they haven't seen any snow coming down,
They're all wearing...
Doesn't... Definitely not summer I did not some where, but not not atlanta particular
You know, it it's it's not obviously not cold out. They haven't seen any snow. But because we don't see it, they can jump to the conclusion like winter coming in already, you know, early winter are coming, you know, it...
And then
another bit of calling logic is that everybody in town immediately
together,
right, is are their roof.
Yeah. They they a
party, like like
Barks raising or something.
So...
Yeah. That was
And and then to see
donald and the boys,
breaking all the feathers
together Al if there leaves
and not really thinking about what might happen afterwards.
It's it's hilarious and
comic.
Right. Right. It it's great. I really appreciate your calm interior. This is exactly
why I what to to come on.
Okay. So
if you are versed in kind of the the tropes of classic cartoons
and and our gang and little ras schools and and all this plastic quantity,
you probably already expect what's gonna happen. When you put get a bunch of tar and a bunch of feathers
introduced. But... But I I love John, how even though this is incredibly predictable,
the payoff,
what's gonna happen.
On on the very first fiasco, is is just magnus.
And and I I agree with all that. The only thing I would say is If you're ten years old and you're reading this or even as an adult and you're reading through and it's like, what happens next you may not sync that far ahead, and you wouldn't think it was caused badly
does.
Right. That and that's true because this you know, I have the benefit of hindsight and thinking about the called early implications.
Yeah. And I I had the same experience reread it. Yeah. Yeah. And and so...
So as Donald says a horrible winds storm, came up and and the dub try to you know, block off the feathers from blowing away. But but the inevitable happens,
the feathers all blow down.
Into Pleasant Valley,
we see the town's folk,
particularly,
who will learn is the mayor,
you know, running for their lives less they be sm
and we do see the mayor trip himself into
a tub of tar
and and one of the women in the town cries out. Our city, our beautiful village,
hard and feathers.
And the great comic sting at the end of this page is the mayor saying if you think that's Al calamity,
take a look at me the mayor.
And and he is. He is exactly as hard and feather as you would expect. And as the classic
and
everyone knows this, but I should I should say it out loud. Right? Tar and feather is like a a classic form of I mean, if you go back far enough, it's like it's torture,
but classically in American
society. It's a humiliation.
Against someone usually that you wanna run out of town. Yes.
Yeah. And and in real life it must've have just been horrific. But
common watch.
Right. Right. Right. But
I wanted to...
That that panel where the mayor is
his he's running down the ladder.
And he has cleaned up against the house as as the feathers are coming down, and there's a And I looked at that when I was reading the reread the story, and I got, oh my god. Look at the ways coming down low that letter. Nobody
could possibly come down that ladder safely in real life, and then you see the payoff in the next panel we're he can't safely go down the letter.
He's he's running down the ladder and you can't run down a ladder.
And he just goes
tips right over into the tire. And as beautiful. That last panel where you see the mayor
covered in tar and feathers. U.
That's the second...
If you count
the opening panel,
which is the double panel,
This is the second double panel of five
in the story.
And that's
really unusual for Karl to
have
that many double panels
and ten day story.
It's a lot of space, but it works
to
emphasize,
like, the the punch often at the end of the the story.
That of the page where you're you're seeing the the the highlight egg for that that section.
And
and and such a visual
story except for their opening
and closing, a visual, and this story, I think one of the reasons it's such a favorite for is
it almost has an epic
sent to it, and I think these additional
paths help help with that. That's a... That's an excellent point. I'm glad you mentioned that because I I didn't pick up on that. But as soon as you said it, I'm like, oh, yeah, those those full, you know, full width panels. They they Al so I think really give you a sense of the town itself because there's a little bit of breathing room and it's so important to kinda place us within the tabs. So
Yeah. That's a great point.
And you know what I... What I was thinking too when I got to this part, and then I went back to reread it is
and
I've I've mentioned the rule of threes on the podcast before it's like one of those academic things that people who analyze medium and and it makes them sound smart, but it's really very pedestrian.
Right? But but the rule of threes, it is something that Barks was very good at. Right? And in comedy,
three is the perfect number.
He... It does such a good job of abiding by that. We're gonna get the three big catastrophes
here, and this is this is our first of.
Can we talk about rule of three for a second?
Please yes.
Okay. You're right. Three is sort of a classic number. There's
another
component to. I don't know if it truly plays in to this one.
But in comedy right... Well, first of all, if you looked at the old at the old animated cartoons, I've mean, talking about really early. Like
so forth. They would often repeat the same action
like three times or something. And part of that was just
saving them from having to reach withdraw things and so forth. Right. But there is a sort of classic
pattern
of of doing three, but the other part that from a joke right
standpoint, I just wanted to find this because I've I've heard references to rule three before. Here on the podcast. Yes. What I've listen, but
from a joke
standpoint,
rule...
Rule three comes in somewhat in that you... What people mean is that you get a pattern with the first two references
and a gag. I'm trying to regular bag. And then the third reference
totally breaks that pattern. It's part of the cycle, but in a totally
unexpected way. I just wanted to explain what role free met in a different
context.
I'm not sure if that comes in here.
Although each of the disasters
is unique in its own way.
But Right. This is... This is the first big one. Yeah. And and that's a great explanation that I I haven't fully flushed out. I do think sometimes the the the third is is more about the elevation. And the escalation of it instead of the sub version
in the stack story office.
But if you look the mass...
The Brutal mastery stories, which I know you've talked about another podcast. You know, in the B mastery story, as Donald is
somehow
an expert at something. He's very pom and self
and
maybe a little annoying.
In each of those. But...
And then I have counted but you now, the first two, maybe three, and then he breaks the pattern with the and
at the end where something goes
preposterous to be wrong. And so that's that's sort of an example, the the rule three.
I don't know if it's if it's necessarily a three in each case, but it that the rest of the
of that is very much in in that realm. So anyway There's
usually that curve ball. At the end. Mh.
So on the next page, you know, we transition and dot Donald, of course, is still is still explaining this.
He notes that they were pretty unpopular
after that point. And they're finding that they're not... Their money is no longer
welcome in Pleasant Valley, and they have to drive all the way to Inducks for supplies.
And it's not
improving. They're still not getting the hands to lay eggs.
So
one of the nephews
suggest
selling them and and Donald is really annoyed. Al these chickens and so he says that's right. The pot is the place for lazy hands.
And the Ducktales
this is gonna begin sort of calamity number two, the one... One of the many
for the town. They start to drive the chickens out to the market
in the manner that you would... That you had heard Cattle, basically.
Right.
And And as you mentioned get this great, like, long shot of them driving the chickens through town. Right. And it hurting
it's preposterous the idea of hurting chickens. It would be like... And I would love to do a story where this actually happens. Where you're trying to hurt cats. It's it's about... That would be even more disastrous possibly.
But pretty Earnings chickens is is great.
Sure. Yeah. It's pretty pretty straightforward.
But funny action on that page
So, you know, the next page is really gonna be all about the kind of predictable
chaos.
That these shipments are causing.
And and but when they get into town, you know, someone
says, where do you leg one cowboys think you're going? And and he tells them well we're going on the railroad station.
To ship the chickens and and the local says listen dumbbell. You don't drive chickens to market like cattle. You haul them in coup,
And and, you know, I think Bark really likes this kind of humor where you've got people acting, like like rooms,
or or green horns or chi tacos codes depending on, you know, where you are.
And and it doesn't really make sense with the Nephews. They're usually much smarter than this, but of course, we know that that he'll adjust their kind of clever nest as as needs be for the story.
The new don't really have a strong place in this style yeah. World this story.
Donald could have stuck in hired hands
and it was hurt.
Could've have been gus goose if if Barks was horrible that would.
That might have even been better.
But
but it could've been almost anybody. And
I mean, this story is basically perfect. So I hesitate to say to save...
No. No. No.
But...
Yeah. Yeah. It it's really donald
versus the villages.
Right. Right. They're they're in incidental. And and we get some of the kind of predictable chaos, but it's still really great to see, you know, chicken
walking through cement chickens messing up a China shop worse than a bowl night
a little diner gag where where A man says waiter or we ordered our chicken fried not. Walking. And and I end up having to retreat Barks up their hill. Right.
Fleeing from the villages or so upset.
Right. And
that says a six panel where the chickens
are in the
Tri
Sean.
For people who aren't in the... From the Us, there's a term called
bull and a Tri shop. Mh. And Barks is playing with that. The whole idea of of having a boy China shop, You just know that there's going to be destruction.
Yeah. That's a good point. Eric because we... Yeah. It is a a good little American Isn't.
The the next page is basically all about the audit of chickens that Donald performs when they get back to the farm. He counts and he realizes that they're missing one of their ten thousand chickens.
And so, you know, we've got this this funny moment where Donald
en angrily stocks down into the town
demanding
that they return his missing chicken.
And it's pretty funny because the mob is the the the... I mean, they're out for his blood. But
Donald who you you mentioned he's he's a bit of a jerk. He's a big jerk. In this one. He does have the lawn his side. And so
the towns people trying to fan out to look for this one chicken.
And by the end,
we realized that there a baker poke his head out and says no need to look for gentlemen I've found the chicken, and he angrily points to it being immersed in the dough mixer
with with his wife, the other baker crying about two thousand lows of bread ruined.
Do you wanna... Do you wanna read Donald
end of the exchange there? You should be jailed for not having lid on that Movie trap.
Because, you know, so
aware of other people's feeling things and the cooper chicken
that chicken is just. They've got a chicken of that. And it's just covered with Google
poop, and there's not a bit of the chicken that you can actually see. And and there's a woman in the background
who's
she's just sobbing.
She just
controllable.
And
it's said oddly
disturbing and funny
panel at the same time.
My main comment on this, and I guess my only other comment really on this is that power, got a a police officer and he's going... We have to help help him find his chicken and much as we hate to do it. And the caption goes the law was on my side. And, again, this is a good example of why donald it's so nice to have
in the but what that panel made me think about when I was reread this is donald
is... If you trans post uncle Scrooge
personality onto Donald. That's what's happening.
Donald is always concerned about the bottom line. He not really concerned about anybody else and he's always concerned about making
money and his property and so forth. And
Uncle
Donald is my favorite character.
I like Uncle screws, but he's not really the most pleasant person, but Donald is essentially uncle Al the story. That's a great catch. You're right I can totally imagine Scrooge
posed in that shot.
The other thing, there there's a men little detail that there's a new hanging in the background
that that oh you're bright.
The towns people clearly they're they're a lynch mob, which which is is just disturbing.
And and, of course, you know, historically that there there's a lot of reasons why you wouldn't see that today. But then it was a common trope that that was used in comedy
as well as as...
And it's it's funny that they're they're out for blood and the police there is basically the only one saving Donald.
Alright. What each of these pages is such a nice tight little almost episode in this short story.
The the next page kinda deals with the the after aftermath here
Donald
explains the towns people sued me, and Bark shows him in front of one of bark Al like wei owl judges.
Being fined
for
being found liable for nine hundred dollars damage.
And and there's a silver lining though, the nephews
explain. I I really should read it in the progression because the pacing so strong here.
They say don't be so... Don't be down on donald. We've got good news for you,
and he says what could be good news
and they explain the chickens have started to lay eggs.
You know, the the reader is basically
forgotten that this point because Barks has distracted us with so much. Right.
And and so that turns the story around a little bit. Donald is really resided, and he goes up to to the homestead to calculate.
And, again, a great bit of dialogue, he's
sc furiously.
Barks occasionally does these great calculation gigs.
Between tons of feed at five seventy per C w t ten thousand eggs per day divided by twelve and by seven and and he calculates that they need a dollar a dozen for the eggs to break even.
And and unfortunately, the price is at forty cents at that point. And and so they they engage in some
speculation
where they store these massive amounts of eggs, they start storing them until the house bulge
waiting for the price to go up. Yeah.
That
again going for the bottom line. Although, it's understandable in in that
situation. But
I I guess
just Al little bit that I wanna
Ducktales sort of there. Mh. When I was first reading, this story is so the panel were just got the wi out on that owl go Al donald, and he's going... I find Donald Ducktales Liable for nine hundred dollar damages
and Donald going plain highway Robert. And I love the two panel progression
where Donald
excited kind of a smile on his face as he's doing the figures, and he's a expecting to come up that he's gonna make a fortune.
And then the next panel, he's
gets the results and we've gotta get a dollar a dozen for eggs to break even. I mean, just the
between the expiration as case are to me are quite funny. And
the only other thing on that is on the x the last panel,
They've got all these eggs and crates and they're... They've tried... They've moved the stove out of the house right.
Boiler room,
and the house
is.
There's no room to go in, and it's literally bulging
I just think that's very
funny. It's some great
car.
It is. And and you mentioned the the expressions. I'm glad you did because if you look at every panel,
on this page,
every
expression is so radically different and and so expressive and and...
I mean, he he was such a master at this.
Alright. So we're we're getting up so that this that final disaster here. Right? We
we have
some
transition
The passage of time, the eggs are piling up. Again, cartoon logic. Were not... The story is bliss we're not gonna think too hard about how long these eggs are gonna last
outside like this. I I gather that, like, high quality eggs you act can keep them
shelf stable and don't need to ref them for a while, but but I'm guessing not for weeks and weeks.
But anyway, they're they're accumulating them. The price is gradually
climbing and and they say that Donald says it's about time. There must be a million eggs in that mountain.
And eventually, the Ducktales here on ominous
creaking,
and it is the bulk head giving away. Bulk would have been a good vocabulary word for me as a kid.
And then we we transitioned down to the town to get the perspective of these eggs
all
coming down the mountain and
a couple of
horrified looking towns for. One says oh my living soul, and and we get that we get the panel that we've kind of been
anticipating. Right? It's got a gray on p
sp
as the town is just utterly
inundated by the this million eggs crashing into the valley. Yeah. And
it's sort of...
It's another double wide panel. U.
And it
instead, you know, splash panel, it's a fluke down.
And notably,
I mean, I think you're supposed to apply
understand this. Because this is a Disney
comic,
nobody's gonna die in it, and you've seen a bunch of... You see the town
on the other hill climbing up out of the way, and I think you're supposed to feel that all of them magically
got out of town,
and so nobody's harmed or or killed and all this. Sure. It was probably a picnic day or something.
And I... The only other
thing I wanted to say is... And is...
Has there ever been a worst way to store a
I a million of them
on the top of a hill hillside is a a board
in the way. Of them absolutely.
Yeah. And this is such a great payoff. Right? Like, and and we're not supposed to think too hard about, you know, why, like, Can't we see the shelves and and and so on and and, you know, I I always assumed everyone got out okay, but it's it's just he has done such a good job of setting up the progression of the story and the geography of it. That that that it just... It lands so well.
And... But we're not done yet. We have one more page.
Where we we get the actual
payoff
which is that the town
convene their disaster council
the Ducktales
for their lives as they must
and and they decide. They determine that the the eggs are too... Basically they're two wet they're too runny. I like to imagine that they can't actually sip them up because they're just like, two vista they're not a regular liquid.
So they they the only way that they can move that massive eggs is to cook them.
And
he says and to cook them we'll have to, and I think this is the mayor
says
set the town of fire.
And so we We see Donald Mcdonald explains the villages,
fried eggs, the hard way, the mayor comments,
I never dreamed that I the mayor would burn down the city hall. There... There's a little aside about it being assured. I'm I'm gonna a guess that are
an adjuster probably wouldn't approve of this. But again, this is chronic logic. And
so they The the poor towns people watch and say our beautiful village is pleasant Al no more when we build again while have to give our town a new name And and so we have indeed found out the story of why that burg is called
Onwards.
And and, John, do you mind giving us the little little economic sting at the end, the last two panels?
Okay. So
they're
we're back back out of the flash,
and they're they're leaving
Donald and
daisy and the boys
are leaving
and
they kind bad that's why what got its name. And that goes but you would think those store hats could have spelled it
left of an e at the end. Mh.
For something fancy, after all, Those were my expensive bags. And that's that's the end. It's it's kind of a soft ending. It's it's
odd way. It's sort of a van
if you
based on our. And it's just a little bit of philosophy,
a little bit of emotional...
This is what I'm thinking about. And...
Yeah. It's a very ending, but it's kind of appropriate out all this an
and
action and so forth Yeah. It's a it was a just a neat story. I'm actually very surprised that this story zen has got approved by
is hit karl editor.
Right. Although,
carl did Al lot of things that you could not get away with today. Are
I think Carl probably got more lia leeway than a lot of real creditors because We have a lot of goodwill for his output. I've gotta imagine yeah. Absolutely.
I mean, he was one of their stars for sure. He didn't
of that, but they did. And right but
going back... Yeah. There there was a panel
in in retrospect to getting away the things If there's Al panel, I think, yeah. On the second page where he's holding the chicken by the road and the chicken is looking during their U.
Before, you could never get away with that and in what is
supposedly a kids comic.
Right.
These days. And It certainly couldn't get away with it and Disney.
Anymore. It's not in the last few years. They've been
sort of a change and how
Right. I think there are but approved these days. And
it... Yeah. I... He just got away with
a lot in the story. And but it it totally works. And sometimes you have to try the edge and go over little bit
to make something really memorable.
Yeah. I very well said, I think.
And and you mentioned it's a soft ending, but to me, it feels like that pen ultimate to be, you know, the the conclusion is such a right such a doo that it it it you got a kind of exhale.
At the end that I think. Right.
So
That that was really good. I we had a lot of great things, I think, to say about this.
What larry I... I I know we've already talked about this. Right? I think I think I'm an agreement with you that this is certainly an all time great.
But your overall thoughts that maybe we didn't cover about what makes this such a special ten pager.
I think
covered pretty much what I thought or I have some additional...
As I said, one of the reasons I wanted to pick this story is because it's such a good
window into hell carl created stories. And carl had Al animation background, he was in story department at Disney doing donald dot shirts. And
so... And I
think his way of doing comic books
was probably
the same way he did animated stories.
Where he would create create as
try to think it was... He would have a setting
or an idea, what he wanted to do in a story.
And you've probably heard this too, but Yeah. My.
He... You know, he wanted to drop... Snow. No. Nobody wants to trust. Snow. But he... But he wanted to do a certain type of store
certain study. And
so he would come up he would write as many gag as as he could think of to go with that setting that's flow of action. And then he would try to fit them in
some kind of
chronology, some sort of... And then he would create it would finalize the story based on how the gag fit together, and it would influence I'm sure how the story progressed in terms of content and so anyways, it doesn't sound like a very literary
way to create a story, but it if you're doing Humor, it works really well. And if... And this is
so important if you have a really good sense of structure, you can do this. If you don't have a good sense of structure, then it's just chaos.
But Carl had that that sense of structure. And within
and in this case, he had three main gigs. I mean, three main things that go wrong. And then within them, particularly in that second one, he has many gigs
within the gag within the Medic,
you know, the
the Ducktales mean, to me the
chicken and the batter the Right. Al. The chickens of the
china to shop and so forth. And
I just thought maybe more than most stories
This is such Al a clear example of that here and so that was one reason I wanted to pick this story. Yeah. I I think you're right. There's so much kind of nested
within. Right? Because he's got... He's got this, like, classic bookings. Structure.
He's he does a great job of the book.
He's got kind of the rule of three progression.
He's got the mini gigs within the rule three. And even within the mini gag, sometimes he has these little
reaction shots. These even the expressions are funny. They're almost like mini gigs within themselves. Or or a little... Yeah. Or like the sign of the the the judge is bent and so forth. He like just throw away bags in the background.
He just fits in so much.
Right?
It's so funny but but so tight is...
It's it's a great story. I
I didn't get to read this one until pretty late because I I missed a lot of the reprint and didn't, like, find it until later when I was
kinda filling in those holes in my collection. And I was like, wow. I can't believe I've never seen this one.
But but it's such a stand out story to me. And and I've already alluded to this. Right? But this is very well regarded by the overall Ducktales community.
We always talk about how these stack up on Inducks
compared to to other stories. And, you know, you're you're another creator. I should preface this by saying, of course, index is like an imperfect measurement
and it's It's gonna be biased towards, like,
creators like Barks that people are the most familiar with and these stories that are
sticky. But it is a good a good gauge of, like, just how the community feels about the stories. And this one comes...
This has a rank as of when I was making my notes at least. It had a seven point seven out of ten.
Which is good for number one hundred and fifty seven out of all, you know, forty two thousand
Disney comments. That are disney stories that are ranked on the same. That's very
high for a ten pager. Because most people, most fans
yeah they're gonna prefer the
the advantage spas. Yes.
That's a great point. Right? That those are much more memorable.
I just for that reason, I Al couple of times I kinda plucked out the ten pager
and I compared them to each other. So if you're just looking at his ten pager
on their own list, then this one generally clocks in at about numbers seven
or so. Also that's
interesting because I had a note.
I looked at another tonight,
Steve Bark dot Letter c Barks Yeah.
T a. I don't are you with? No. That's a great resource. Definitely. Is. It is. And
It's amazing resource. And
they have
ratings for the stories too, but they...
Whoever whoever does it
have a different approach if if I
understand right, with their...
He does he or she does is
they look at how many times, the story has been reprint. Right. Which is a different measure.
Yeah. Another great way of looking at it.
Worldwide. I assume that probably has changed is it was first posted. But... And
let's see.
This comes in
Al
in for the comics and stories, the ten pages,
This comes in number five.
Out of ten out of the top ten. Nice.
And
the
flip... I'll just a few flip
come ties for number nine and
some of the my own favorites etcetera here and matt ring
six and
stat
spectrum,
You say call statue
galore. Number four, I know you did a a a broadcast and I had that in it. Right. And
if they have
my... I'm a little hard pressed to go with a def definitive
favorite, but if I had to pick one
one, I would go... And you've already done it or I would have requested it. Sure.
But the
the lemonade story,
with
first apparently
yeah. Winter time wage. Yeah.
Yeah. That
that's probably my favorite.
Box in is number two
on this list. And then
for the most reprinted stories, with the money Bin crib where Scrooge storing all his money and a crib and perch
tornado
with my whip and outrageous is is that everybody becomes a rich.
That's number one. So.
I didn't all. But but
I was g to see so many of my favorites. Show up in the top ten. Yeah. I think there's a sort of Canon
among fans. Right? There's some pretty broad agreement on the top,
like ten or top twenty or so everyone's gonna kinda of position them. Sure they're a little bit different, but but I I think you ask Inducks fan. Sure. This is this is gotta be a top ten story
somewhere around there.
I mean, I Right here and there, I have a couple of them that I would probably qui with
It's fun to share this. I'll I'll maybe I'll share this list as part of the release for this one and and people can Can debate slash argue over it.
But but I I think broad consensus. Right? This is an all time great story.
If you If as a listener, if you haven't read this one, it's really like, what are you doing? Go go ahead and read it. And and don't listen this podcast until you do.
I will say, you know, I've I've...
When I've listened to this podcast, sometimes I don't have time. I'm just listening, and I don't have time to look at this joint. It's so much richer if you're following along and reading the stories Yeah. But
it... I think it's probably a coincidence,
but
it's interesting to me that two of Carl best stories are about eggs. Yeah.
The other one being lost in the End...
Which many people consider his very best
story
with the square eggs. I'm sure some other stories wearing eggs. Played apart, but
maybe easter egg
story. But
But... Yeah...
Yeah. Definitely has to be in the conversation.
Well, you know, this has been a a real pleasure, John. I I really appreciate you joining me before before we wrap up,
we we... We covered this pretty thoroughly. Right? They're there
almost
too many great panels in this one
to to do this feature. But but are there any favorite panels that you would like to highlight that we didn't
already get to kind of call attention to
No. There's some that I've mentioned that I I really like. I I will
mention,
you know, a lot of these flash panels
or these blue panels
are
ones that I particularly enjoyed.
But
one thing we didn't I didn't mention we didn't talk about is the number of
panels in this thing. And I actually just looking Al at one. So, yeah. Go for it. Yeah. There's
Barks. I mean, I I don't remember his editor
name, but
Yeah. Apparently, it
Barks his editor was telling his artist to go and have black placements. You know, it it
not all artists think about placing strong blacks and their
pieces. But
Barks
was
sort of
unique and how he used his silhouette. And and there's
there's
the big reason for using silhouette to save yourself from drawing. So... Right. And I
I have
I haven't mentioned it, but I I my... The thing I'm doing the most these days I'm doing Al funny
web webcam called last kiss. For yeah. I was I gonna encourage you to plug that at the end. And I talked to you there. So so say it again.
Well,
last piece,
which
happened because I bought a
rights to an old
series called first kiss.
And... But I take
old chronic art and mostly romance, but not totally.
And I red dialogue it, and I do it online, and it's on Go comics, switch with the website, and...
But... And my own website is
last
kiss
com
dot com. Don't go to last guess dot com. Asking
dot com.
And
anyway,
Anyway, in the roma Al clinics
from particularly for Toronto,
there's a huge number of silhouette.
And
I know it's because the artist which just trying to save time.
Carl certainly was trying to save time
but he used them so artistic,
and sometimes
it's like that first
silhouette
we're donald and daisy or in the car. You would have gotten
no benefit from him drawing in their characters.
From the rack.
And a lot of the other reason to have silhouette is
besides the art history of it, is
to to focus on the things that are not in silhouette. And Barks that's the master of that, and
there's
there's a large number of
silhouette here. And
I think that nick so silhouette is just donald on going up the hill after
on
The the gru Grip one
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
That's so funny to me. I was kinda mention that one, too. Right. Right. Right. And it's You would have got and you couldn't have done a close up because you wouldn't have been able till it was going out of town or you could've you could've have, but it just wouldn't have been as effect him. And he was so good at that. And we could just talk about that. And some of the characters
and some of the panels are running the town drum and so silhouette, and that panel was the nuisance.
They're
two of the characters, and you don't need to see them. You see them in silhouette
with clubs and their hands.
And it's such a strong statement of of what they're thinking and what they wanna do. You just wouldn't have gotten anything else. And and it focuses you on everything else in the panel too. So I I just wanted to bring up the seller.
Yeah. That's like... That's a good one to mention
because they are... He uses them in these really Barks
moments a lot. And you really see that on the last page where the Ducktales are... They're fleeing there in silhouette. As the towns people gay on their they're burning town, there in silhouette, and then that final cap, you know? Mh.
That the Ducktales leaving town again and so silhouette.
They are really great
otherwise, it's kind of all the same the the the panels that you might
mention as favorite. They really are very predictable
in this. It's it's all of the really
spectacular cad catastrophic,
things that happen. But I I really wanna again call attention to the expressions,
especially as you see them
on
what was the that page. But you mentioned his near the chicken that he is holding by the neck. But
also his changing
expressions
on
that,
I think, that eighth page
we're just just incredible. And a great example is that merging of his art and his writing storytelling. Oh, I just noticed something. Mh a little different. But, you know, we talked about the chicken being held by the neck. I think it's on page six
six with town.
Towns is holding
donald by the neck. Yes. That's a good plan. Is this a little good reverse
action
and is
telling them you about how you don't... How you have to haul chickens
in dates so forth
That's just a nice little
reverse bit that there. Yeah. It's it's a great touch.
Alright. Any any anything else that you'd like to mention before we wrap it up?
We we've covered this if anybody could cover it more. I don't know how.
That's right. Well, John, no. No. I just
thank you for having. I really appreciate it. Thank you so much. It's been it's been a real pleasure
to to get to talk to you about this great story and to get to wax on
about, you know, when I... When I was nine and ten and reading a lot of stories
that you wrote,
This this is another one that I read till it was dog
Al. That that's a big of mine. The two
no room for human error, the the robot one.
Can I ask?
Yeah. Go ahead. Are there any any lines that, like, really stand out to you that you're just really really glad that you wrote,
you know, what what... In in the dot com
specifically.
I I can't quote any of them, but I can tell you I'm particularly proud of
some of the
rh
I did on and some of them where I'd, like, stamped and deliver where I've... He's doing...
Like, singing the model
the model of this of company where where
he's got deliver pizza, and I don't remember if it's thirty minutes sixty minutes and he's doing that. And I did that in the
remake
the... Some somewhere Beyond
nowhere where I have ways delivering.
I I'm particularly proud of those. I can't quote any of them.
But
yeah. I'm
diverse
proud
of
that comic you just held up
no room for human error, which was a long story for me. And
someone pointed out to my friend pointed out to me
that
I actually d
a person a character in a.
Probably the only time a character has been to.
True. It was a robot that it was a thinking tall.
Sent and
robot. I I love I got.
Dialogue and that. That this is gonna cut us off in a moment. But can I tell you you you have in this one You have Scrooge say, oh, deliver me from the wilbur?
And I... I love that little side there.
I love the Al you do.
Listeners,
thank you for joining us for this very special episode of the ten page podcast, feel free to reach out to us. On the socials
add barcodes remarks, and we'll talk to you next time.