We have
Hello, and welcome to Barks Remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comics of all time. This episode is a ten page podcast, all about one of his short stories. Get ready to enjoy our remarks. Welcome back to Barks remarks,
we are back with a very special episode of what I call the ten page podcast Usually, we pick one or two of Barks short ten page stories to discuss. But today, we're gonna do something a little bit different
and I think very special, we are gonna talk about a group of no less than five
stories from the du man's
very early career. And and I got a little more pro log, but I've got a c
that I'm very excited to have bad So I'll let him introduce himself. Hey mark warren harmon and back again enjoying these
early comments so much really looking forward to our discussion and kinda tracking Carl Barks his early career. So excited. Yeah. This will be fun. Yeah. I I agree. I am very excited touch on it. You know, when I when I started this podcast series, I was thinking long and hard about it. And I really was like gotta focus.
On those adventure stories, those longer stories, you know. That's my format
and and I really wanted to stick to it. Because there were just so many of the ten pages.
But but I ultimately did decide that it made a lot of sense to be a little bit flexible so that I could get the the special ten page podcast
episodes in and like I compromised where I was like, I'm gonna stick with the spirit of what I'm doing by by numbering those longer at so and labeling these others as the ten page podcast. But but it means I didn't make that decision
until
a couple of months in. And so it means that I I passed by all of these great old stories that really showed some of his, like, evolution So so I thought about it. And I was like oh, this is this is the perfect
compromise, You know, we're gonna we're gonna talk about five really
interesting stories here, none of which would really...
None of them really have enough meat in them, I think to merit their own episode, even a shared one. But but what we're gonna do today is talk about those stories
summarize them in a lot less detail than we usually would and then we're gonna
think about what it says
about the Ducktales man's early career
and his evolution. So so warren
how do you feel in general? You know, about these early ten pages the first part of his career. Right. Right. And and coming off of his partnership with Jack hannah, and finds pirate gold in in nineteen forty two where he kinda got a taste of the comic book
industry and and got to experience the art as you said, this is that was a great word, the evolution of the artist and the writer. And I think why I think these stories are so important is that they
paved the way to what he mastered later in his life.
So you see a lot of that moments in these stories that say, hey, I remember seeing that kind of thing happened in lost in the Andy or like of the north or those longer form stories. So here's a man who at the age of about forty or forty one. He's over forty is over forty. Yeah. And he's got this twenty three year career left and this he's just getting started,
and that just amaze me. And this why I'm so excited because I think as an individual and as a creative individual, I think he just wants to tell the stories It it's it's really critically important that we understand where Carl Barks.
Yeah. I I fully agree.
That's why I definitely think it's important to cover these stories as part of this podcast project.
But but I also think they're very enjoyable and fun. And you made a great point there about this stage of his life. And I think about that a lot. Right? Because, like, he... This is... I don't know how many careers in into his
into his life. But this is certainly not his first career. And this is a really big change to have made at this age at this stage his life. I would say this is his third career. You know, when he started out and and he started with the the the Cal eye opener and and he had that publishing and editing experience with the incompetence in Minneapolis that he had to work with for those early years. Then he got fed up with that and went to
California back to California and and looked in liquidate did it Disney. While working in the story department and working on the donald Dutch shorts, and then he said, look, I'm gonna move seventy five miles with my first wife, Clara to the small community.
Where the weather is beautiful, the mountains are beautiful, and I'm gonna set up my little freelance practice there and see what I can do. I mean, this is his third attempt and he's known in his forties, and I can kinda relate to that. I I jumped from one long career in mini minneapolis listen at the age of forty two, I moved to Rochester and started something new. So... Yeah. Yeah. Definitely. Yeah. I I relate too, you know, I'm I'm at about that stage in my life right now, and I'm I'm looking at a little bit of a shift within my own career
and doing doing this series it's impossible not to think of that. And and it's I I find it really inspiring. Right? Because he obviously had a lot of his best
work ahead of him still. Oh,
extremely inspiring, and he had the talent no question. But what I think was
incredibly fortunate about this period for him. Everything lined up the stars aligned. He had people who trusted him. They didn't second guess, him we'll talk about the first story here and how the editor just said Wow. You know, here you go. You you can do this in yeah, they they did get them a lot of latitude for these. Right? But but I also get the impression that he was one of those people who really tried to, like, make his own luck. You know, he he put himself in the right place. He obviously
built up a lot of goodwill as someone who is reliable,
working on those Disney shorts and and these, you know, it should be said that these serve as a great bridge
between the work that he did on those cartoon shorts, especially Donald Duck, and what he's gonna go on to do with the dot com. But, you know,
when he got that opportunity
to do pirate gold with Jack hannah,
my read is that they really liked what they saw.
Yeah. And and they really must have liked the sales
outcome.
Oh, yes. And I think that probably gave him the confidence to think that he could he could do this. I I understand he gave himself a little bit of an insurance policy where he he brought a bunch of...
Did you bring a bunch of chicken Scrooge with?
To send and.
Yeah. Yeah. Yep. He brought his chickens and his chicken coupe and like the way they say with his wife and
they kinda set up a little kinda like, okay. This doesn't work out. I'll be a chat before.
Here's is the fall path. Well... And and and is he had previous careers doing other, like, very outdoor
rural stuff. Right? Didn't do some like some sort of ranch hand or trapping or or not this twenties. Yeah. And his twenties and growing up. I think he was always outdoors.
Yeah. Yeah. Absolutely. Well, I'm I'm getting excited to talk about these. So are you ready the launch into warranty? Do you any any other pre game. I think I think we'll just kind of talk about the evolution here and it starts with well Disney comics and stories
number thirty one.
Yeah. Let me let me list them off really, but So we're gonna be talking today about the Victory garden from walt Disney's comics and stories, number thirty one in April of nineteen forty three, followed by the Rabbit foot and the next issue. Walt disney Comments and stories thirty two then we're gonna be covering
Salesman Donald in issue number thirty nine, followed by the Ducktales the iron pants and number forty one. And finally, the chemist number forty four. And
let's let's talk about why we're doing the ones we are. Right? I I think
I think that any project like this we really have to cover the victory Barks. Right Warren. What why is that? Well, the Victory garden was Carl Barks is first
opportunity to draw an original
ten page story for walt disney comments and stories and and since he moved away from Burbank and and the Disney studios and kinda ended his career with walt Disney as a staff he pulled pulled all his stops and became a freelancer He settled into this area where he could really
exercise his creative
skills. And
they gave him this opportunity. It says in donald Al book, and I wanna give credit to the research here that
he believes the woman's name was Eleanor Packer who was an editor who gave him that opportunity to draw this story. Now this was not an original
story either though. Think the the thing to note here is that he was handed to script or an outline. I and it was as he says, it was a rather
indefinite sort of script. I worked it over and it made more sense out of it. And it was one of the things that they were kinda testing Carl Barks here in his ability to come up with something
that would cap cap
and get the editors at Western
printing excited. Yeah. I I think you've got it. Right? He...
The bit that I have that Jeffrey Blu had written in there
of the graphic novel that I read most of these in.
Just notes that, you know, he was allowed to strengthen what he thought. Needed punching up, but but that he focused most of his effort on the art. So did. And the art is fantastic. Anything shows in my opinion, it shows an evolution from finds pirate gold and
of this expressive donald Inducks that we see today. I think it's closer to what what he ended up with. I think he had a had great opportunity to to really work on the art on this story. So yeah. Let's let's talk about the Victory garden. Should we start there? Yeah. Absolutely.
We're. We're gonna go chronological.
So...
Okay. So so go ahead, Warren tell us tell us about the main action that give us a good summary
of the victory guard. Yeah. It's important to note that regarding were real popular Al the Height of World War two in in America, United Kingdom,
Australia, other parts of the World Canada.
And these were
gardens that
citizens of the countries were encouraged to grow to help the war effort. To grow their own food, but what I thought fascinating about it was it was a spirit builder. It was a Al builder. For the citizens
during this incredibly horrible war and and it was an opportunity to get out and plant community gardens and vacant lots and in backyard and so the The story the Victory garden opens with Don is nephews
real real quick. I'm sorry interrupt, but... Oh no. That that's that's important. I appreciate you defining like, what a victory garden is. Right? Because it's presented in this story is something that every reader. Would would know about. Did you know what a victory garden was before you originally read this story? I did. My my mom was ten years old in nineteen forty three, and she remembers planting her victory garden in Minneapolis. That's cool. I
I had no idea. What a Victory guard was. I learned about it literally from this comic oh about the age of ten years old. Oh wow. And and I had to... I I can't remember if I asked someone or if I looked it up pre Google, but I I did not know because there's no real direct reference in the story. To war. Right? They just they're are just talking about we're gonna start up a victory garden Yeah.
And and it really interests me that you don't really see them in other pop culture.
Like, go. You don't really see them in other comics. You you rarely
see them referenced in movies of the time. Right It was Al an effort that maybe was grassroots roots maybe it started. I don't know if the government encouraged it. I probably did I I think there was a big, you know, problem and effort. Yeah. To to get them and and we... We know that there was a lot of
Donald duck
propaganda,
material, mate, too. So I I have to think that this is probably
something that
maybe got reworked out of some of that because You know, I wanted.
Donald really went to Barks for the war first. He did. A good friend of mine just sold his entire
Donald Ducktales war collection
at Heritage auctions, and he lives in Minneapolis. And
anyway, donald Duck, that I think the other
part of this is that we're at the height of World war two, but you made the point and it was the right point that that Donald Inducks became sort of the the visual
symbol of the war for Disney as walt Disney entered the war effort, and I'm gonna say, whether I'm right or wrong or whatever, I'm gonna say that Donald Inducks or past mickey mouse and popularity during these years in terms of, you know, in the comics in the short cartoons
popular
consciousness.
Right. No arguments here. Absolutely.
And that's what excited me probably would got me excited about collecting donald Inducks. So, yeah, the story begins with Donald and the boys wanting to plant a Victory garden and
what I really love is that as they begin planting this victory garden an earnest, you see these three cro sitting up on the on the line and
immediately reminded me of the of the cro in the movie dumb that was premier two years earlier.
They're sassy. They're kinda commenting the Mag pis... I have a feeling Carl Barks is inspired by the Cro from Dumb. And as they are excited about seeing this victory garden, though, they
they see food on their table, and so they
rip off the pole and start getting eating the food. Donald gets fed up with it and calls them sa and throws things at them and and That's yeah. Right.
To her.
Because because they're, like
his his war effort,
exactly
exactly and who knows if the cro symbolic in any way to the to the axis I doubt. But but it's... They're sort of the trouble makers here. There are there are three of them. Yeah.
Yeah. So the the overarching theme here is Donald attempt to plant a victory garden. Every chance he gets gets t, and so he he tries it in his yard. He goes to a vacant
lot
in the neighborhood.
Beautifully, I just have to point out at the... What is it? The corner of faith and hope? I love that. And such. And then he he does everything to try to deceive these crow and dress up you know a women's custom,
and it doesn't fool them And so every attempt whether it's the crow or the boys playing football on the garden, he plant in the vacant lot. He just he just gives up. And it... I love the ending when
the boys and conveniently go to the seat store find and invisible seeds. And they t the grows by opening the bag and there's nothing there. And they presented it to Donald and his bed, while, he's
Severino from his football
catastrophe.
It throws the bag against the wall in the next morning voila.
The Victory guardian is growing in his bedroom, Really fun. That that that was a great synopsis.
Warren that this is a really interesting
story to start with. Right? Because some some parts of this really do feel like it's right out of the cartoon, you know, that especially that element with the, like, invisible seeds, that feels like something that would happened in one of the cartoons whether they're like, this is gonna be fun.
Slaps stick and silly, and we don't care why they're invisible. We're not gonna explain that they're just they're so small that they're they might as well. No. It's Invisible seeds give donald the invisible seeds. We like that visual of the vegetables growing out of his hardwood floors, Yeah. Well, again, you have remember Carl Barks just coming off his story ideas at the animation studio. So he he he wrote this like occurred too. And and this easily could have Inducks cartoon to and as you said. In fact, Carl Barks would take... Because we're so few panels in in these
three row comics. There's three rows here. Right. And there are ten pages. He would take each panel and put them up on the wall of his home as a story board. Like the motion like the movies. And he would replace them and move them around and them, and that's how he
saw it because that's what he was trained to do at Disney.
I thought that was fabulous because it it has the feel of that cartoon. But when he turned the story and, they loved it. No edits. I mean, it was... You sold us mister Barks.
Yeah. And and this was, like, so crucial for him. Right? This was, like showing
showing that he can do this
mostly on his own. Now I'm I'm... I have no doubt they trusted his story writing, but they're like, we got this existing story. Let's see what you can do with it art wise. I I like that element where we see the little chrome language. This is something we don't get to too much of. Right? We're Right?
We covered another story pixelated pair where we see translated
pair
here we seen pros or or Mag or whatever chatter away, like like human characters.
Right? Right? Now that makes it so appealing to certainly the audiences that are reading this and gives it an element of fun. And
something else notable
in a lot of these is they feel because they're in the early forties. They're gonna feel much more out of time
compared to a lot of his later stories. Like a lot of them will have dated elements,
but this one to me, you know, you see those old time football helmets
just the very concept
of the victory garden. But... But... Yeah, this one feels dated in a way that
that I find very charming. What do you think of his early art his early character design here. Oh, I love it. It the the angry donald and the throwing donald and the the jumping and leap and and shouting donald is classic. It it it has that common element in the very last page of him throwing the bag a seated at the wall. Look at his pose there out of the bat. He's just everything. And then and then the last panel is a classic last shot Inducks cartoon. He's looking right at the camera, every character that's been in the store is in the store in the panel. And the the crow have the last word. I think it's just a beautiful ending to a funny kinda rom, like you said a slaps to ramp and that's what what they were doing here. Yeah. That... That's a good
explanation of that end panel. To me, it feels very abrupt. But as you as you point out, it is like a cartoon
ending. Loss, bit good stuff. Where let's let's get off to the races warranty because we got we got a lot of story to talk about here. So, you know, we've we we've just covered his very first ten page story that he was interested to do
that he was given the chance to adapt we're gonna transition now to the first
completely independent story that he did. No no c artist, no written source material, we're gonna get the Rabbit foot which is a Carl Barks joint drawn and and written. And this is a story
about that old trope of the lucky rabbit but, right, the idea that that it's a little luck and a good luck charm and, you know, this is kind of before Remarks is going to have the Nephew.
You know, Barks sparks is gonna make the nephews be what he wants them
Sometimes they're
very rational.
But sometimes they're they're very child like in their
love for this kind of belief. Right? I I I have belief. I believe in it. It's that sort of, like, when you wish upon a star element
that Disney, I think in general really likes. Right? Rewarding the the faith of kids and and pure hard. So
this is a story where the kids are gonna present to Donald
this token
that they just got from an old Indian, which is an old trope that has aged well, but it was a very very common place. If you needed something mystical,
you get it from an old Indian. Back at that time. And Donald is gonna be presented as, like, the very rational foil in this one who doesn't believe in good luck. But but he is going to
it. Right? And it's gonna make him act in a very rash way because the the gist of this story is that Donald is gonna set out to prove
that their Rabbit foot does not bring them luck. He is gonna let them put themselves in all kinds of situations
that are
advisable
that are dangerous
that
Cps would not approve of. But Right.
But but every time, the Nephews are gonna walk away un unscathed, you know, they they're gonna cross a rick bridge
safely.
And and he's gonna... He's gonna poo it as
able to hold up an elephant, and, of course, it's gonna collapse under his way. They're gonna use it at to to get a free ride
on a little carnival ride, proving him wrong. And then ultimately, this story is going to come to its conclusion
with something that we'll see in one of the donald duck cartoons and escaped Gorilla.
Do Do you remember that? I don't know the name of the cartoon, but I do know that there was... Yeah. There wasn't an animated cartoon that feature the gorilla Yeah. And and that and the gorilla in this that that escapes from the zoo is, like
terrifying. Right? Like it's it's braun in a very very frightening way as was the one in the cartoon, and I didn't fact check this, but I think that cartoon must have come out first. I believe it did. And and remember, the the whole
cinema
industry was taken over in nineteen thirty three, ten years earlier by king Kong and and you've got this fascination with apes and in right with Tarzan and Movies. So I think Barks just again, just really smart just knew what would attract the viewers and the readers. Yeah. That... That's a really good point. Right? The the country, the world, the pop culture was like, Gorilla crazy.
Mighty Joe Young, son of Khan Joanne Yelp. Yeah. A quick, you know, peru of Google tells me that Mountain G weren't really discovered by the outside world until nineteen o two.
Wow.
It it really struck the popular
imagination for decades there. So
so, anyway, the the boys end up using this Rabbit foot to avoid harm,
and then Donald will get the right idea that he's gonna capture
so subdue this gorilla with the charm of the rabbit foot, the lock of the rabbit foot
And and he ignores their warnings that's
common during their rabbit foot is actually gonna bring him bad luck
and and so
he ends we end this story with him
narrowly
escaping
being
killed by the gorilla
being rescued by some firefighters.
And
and and we get a a good old old corporal punishment gag at the end where he's, you know, annoyed at the nephews
threatens to
give him the lick of their lives
and
accidentally
himself bringing the the strap.
He burn
himself and ends up in the hospital and a full body cast.
Great story. I I I have the point on
a couple of things that I thought of well watching this. I going, wow, this is This is like what, five years,
six years before Glad gander, and and we're
we're playing with that luck theme. And we're having
fun with it with the rabbit foot and the three nephews and how determined they are and how their luck if you think about it from the bridge and from the
the right at the Al the carnival, it all mirrors the kind of what Gladstone would have. And it must have been a successful
trope to
to have Barks continue that on with the character.
Yeah. Totally, he's
he he's
preoccupied by luck. Even early on.
Mh. I've got a remark again just how, like,
terrifying the gorilla Barks.
And lots of panels
that feature of the gorilla close ups.
But I love the panel and this one that where he's imagining
himself being louder as a hero
in the newspaper. Says heroic doctor sad do's Gorilla and the sub adding is not brave just lucky says modest hero.
I love it and look at his eyes in that too. I that's a great panel. On that same page is one of my most the most creative panels and that's where he's
shaking the tree branch, the grill and and donald
word balloons match every shake of the limb. I thought that was really clever.
Right. Right. Great art in there. You know, I like how we just weren't and talked about
our specific favorite panels from that one, because that's gonna be the way to do this.
Did you have any favorites that we should in perspective have highlighted in the Victory garden?
Oh, I I think the the Victory Garden...
I I'd love... I love the closing panel. I think I'm the Victory garden the second page is probably one of my favorite poses for donald.
As he says get out of here use.
I think that's probably one of my favorite
panels and it shows donald bucket is full, frustrated,
angry
twelve. How about you? I I I agree with you. The last one is an easy call.
The the one where the nephews used peg him with the slingshot pretty great too.
Yeah. I think the the the artwork is just getting better and better here. And as he's given free independence on the Rabbit foot story,
he's...
And I I really get the sense that the Carl Barks
has these stories up here and he's just wanting to tell them. So I really believe in he said in one of these interviews that he never liked working on two stories at the same time. He had to finish one before he began the next one and so I think he was one of these tireless workers.
I don't think it was a nine to five job. It was while he was sleeping while he was walking while he was whatever. He came out
and he had these ideas
Yeah. For sure.
Alright. I think we're ready to go on to Salesman Donald.
So, Mark, I think a third really important story in this series that we're doing is salesman Donald.
From walt Disney Conference and stories number thirty nine and November forty three. I the reason is there many reasons
and yet it's sort of the anti
of the Rapid foot story. And because
we see
the boys needing donald now to go do their thing, and the boys are... And and this is really about donald bragging about being the best salesman ever. And he is
greeting the Nephews who
whose whole goal here is to raise enough money to buy a
an express wagon, but it's probably just a a a boy's wagon.
Yeah. I'm just picturing a classic radio flyer wagon, but I didn't hear go on that. Yeah. So they're out to sell egg beater.
And they've they've tried and donaldson. I can do it. I can sell throughout the entire neighborhood. I'll sell out. And so kind of counter to Donald
success and luck in the... I mean, it... Where he's always struggling, he really is successful in this story, and he's out
selling these egg to the most unlikely
people in his neighborhood, and there's some great art here. The Nephews are getting frustrated with his his kind of luck now, you know? And
and I love this because there's so many things happening in the story. You you made some really interesting characters
donald persistence. And is joy with his
incredible skill as a salesman is is seeing on almost every page here.
Until... You... Something's gotta happen here. And so they get it to the last egg beater and this little shack in their neighborhood where they
They meet this feisty,
hermit, who you don't see right away, but you hear right away and he's kind this Al laughing
little prank is all I can come up with. And and and that's a joy just to watch Donald try to foil him through the door.
And and then, of course, we end up
seeing him at the end of the story where Donald
eventually is successful
and sells the hermit the egg beater and the hermit it just breaks down, and just says, okay. I'll buy it.
But I had fun doing it. I just think it's a fun
one of my early memories,
a fun
story filled with tons of gigs,
lots of great artwork
the introduction of quirky characters like the hermit
started here So... Yeah. That's that's salesman donald. I think it's just a lot of fun. How about you?
Word I'm I'm so glad
that you picked this one. For for a couple of reasons. Because this was your choice.
You know, I asked you to throw in another that you really cared about in this area that we're talking about this forty forty three. Right? Forty three. We're still forty three here. Yep. Yep. And and I wanted to limit this from forty three to forty five.
This is a new experience for me because I had never read this one. Okay.
I think I've read good ninety five percent I was output but I've... I've missed a couple of dozen here and there,
but this is my first time. Talking about a story on the podcast that I I read the previous day, and this one was so much fun
and and it's so tight and I I loved the Hermit.
Right? It it's it's the Genesis of these other Goofy characters that Donald gonna try to sell to in, like, land of the tote bulls. Yep. And
at least a couple of others.
Right. It it's it's the idea of trying to sell
a gadget that you don't need to someone like that is is inherently funny. Right.
And then the tight setup up he does were donald vows at the very beginning.
To sell
only to people on his block.
Gives him that limitation, right? That sets up why he's gonna be so dogg
about trying to sell an an egg beater
to to a hermit that just hates people
doesn't cook for himself. I think it references he only eats like roots and herbs or something.
I it's a vegetarian, yeah. Mh.
And the...
It's it's a good pre procedure to all of the little, like, over the top battles
of will and battles of width
that
he's gonna have donald go into against Gladstone
against neighbor Jones.
Sometimes again, Scrooge
and and other people, it's It's like it feels like the the birth of all of those. Gladstone said that because I I agree with that. And I think it's also this battle of of width and will with his nephews. I mean, if you think about it, he's trying to up... One up his Nephews and... Here they've gone through the neighborhood, they need the money. And he goes, I'll sell them to the same people you tried. And mean, he's he's he's childish,
but he's also
so so confident that he can do this. This is the the download we see grow out of this story here. And we're still in forty three. We're still the same first year. I I love the...
I love the discuss that they give him when he like flatter and flirt
but a housewife life at the very beginning of it. Yeah. You love the hard on that page too and his his eyes
lift it up and he goes well, I'm afraid. I you won't be interested in the humble kitchen gadget. I'm selling your hands are too delicate for beating eggs.
Right.
Yeah. He's so is I. And and we don't really get... That that's a characterization that he's gonna
he's gonna abandon.
But... But it's a fun little ben. Yeah. Yeah. Any any other... Any anything else you wanna highlight from this this really really cool early story. I'm so glad that you picked this one. Oh, thanks. And I and I I think one of the early
examples of a repeated art technique that he used here, and he may have used it a few times before which the silhouette well when the boys and he and donald are walking down the street,
and and it's just a it's a great way to break up the art in the story.
The little side panels and and just the little just the visual gigs are just great when the hermit shoots ink Al him through the the key hole,
that little
very interesting panel of donald just looking at the camera and looking straight ahead rather,
and when he says, that's an insult. You don't see many panels like that. Yeah. It definitely feels like very cartoon influenced. Yep. So I think bark out just Al blast with this one with all the gigs. Definitely.
I've got a... I've gotta mention how great the bit with the different doors is Yeah the rubber door the the the layer of doors to he has all these trick doors that can only have been designed for for this kind of battle.
Right? So and and he kind of
gives it away at the end that he's like, annoyed that he lost, but it's the most fun that the hermit ever had. So so he's clearly been waiting for for this kind of
test of of width to come along. What do you think of the Herman? Oh, Oh, he's hilarious.
He
his his wild over the top bush this.
Bark does that with, like, herman in the hermit.
In another story.
And I didn't know there was a precursor to him. So he... He's he's awesome. He's hilarious. And I think what you like about him would what finds him charming is that he's constantly giggling
and he's constantly laughing as if he's just enjoying this and you didn't mind buying the egg peter because he had fun. And to me that just... It just makes the story that much more pleasing and, of course,
that they're asking for more money at the end and donald the...
Again is after them this time with a with a branch.
Oh, yeah sorry if you liked it. Yeah. And and you know, may me think of how much the early in mid twentieth Century did this thing too or, like, queues
kids got on the hook for these kind of, like, low grade salesman jobs all the time. Right. Looking through the old dow and gold key,
comics, they're all these schemes to get kids to sell seeds
and
and and other stuff for prizes, and they inevitably
resulted in parents having to buy their stock off them.
That's right. Alright. So rolling along,
we are at
my favorite of of the bunch of them,
which is the Ducktales the iron pants.
And
that this is such a highlight
to me of of his early
Era comics.
I read most of these stories in Glad
comp. Their
their album that collected a bunch of them, and they gave this one the title. It's called the Ducktales the iron pants.
They
they put bark
great oil. Is the Al oil or A lit though?
It it was Al oil first then became Al lit though I have but. I have the small it though. It's a smaller lit though. It's just great with the the Nephew to donald. Oh, yeah. That just just a wonderful
image, a wonderful painting.
Of donald attacking the boys snow for it in full suit of armor.
He doesn't get to do a lot of these more gag based
oils, you know, A lot of them are more like the adventure or the kind of slice of life duck
stories.
I can only think of, like, this and truman officer Donald.
Sure there's a couple others, but this one kinda stands apart. This is such a great great painting and but anyway, the story is is awesome. This is one of the best donald versus the nephews.
Ten pages.
I I think ever.
Despite being from this very, very early period. Right?
It has the Nephews playing outside having some good old fashioned hole some snow fun.
Donald
decides to walk by them He's clearly good them. He's clearly setting them up. To
get in in this kind of battle with them. Because he he's gonna engage in that that trope, which
doesn't exist any longer. But I think the idea in the
the middle of the twentieth century was that a man wearing a top hat was just begging to have it knocked off by a snowball.
So so Donald ins indicates this big snow war with the nephews by walking by them in a top hat, and he sabotage it. He's
fixed it with an elastic band, and he's stationed a big snowball ball,
which he uses to kevin in, the trench that they're in.
Warren did that... Did that bit remind you un comfortably of of the trench warfare from just a couple
years a couple decades or or before this?
I didn't see that. That's an interesting take on it, though with the boys and the trench and getting
bombed if you will. But... Yeah, I mean, we're We're only twenty years away from World war one and I only thought about it this time.
Okay. But but the this has escalate. And the nephews used to side they have to answer back. So they're gonna build this cool snow for it.
And when Donald comes back, trying the same trick, you know, right
which which he should know better
if they
escalate things by breaking an egg in his top hat, which which sets him off and he invades their snow for it.
But but they've had all this time to prepare now. And so
they are hitting him with all these
great snow tricks
that really fired my imagination as as a kid. You know, I see this little snowball ga gun that they're attacking him with or this little this little rico a bit Or what do you what do you call the little weapon that they use that's
two
heavy object objects t to Al align There's a name.
Can't know. I don't know what that is. Yeah. We're finding errors. But, you know, they they wrap him with a couple of snowball Barks around
Al line, and they they get him good.
And they they realized that they may have over shot. Right? Because he heads into his work shop with a vengeance.
And we've got these.
We've got these, like, actions where the nephews are
preparing their defenses,
s up their snow for it.
And and then Donald is asked doing some un seen escalating.
And when he finally emerges,
it is
such an amazing panel worn. He is wearing
a suit of armor that he's is black sm up in his workshop. It it... It's
suited for Inducks
it's got his bill. He's got... It's... You know, it fits his bill. He's holding a sword
and and he comes out ready to invade
convey them.
And and they're just trying every trick that they've got. To repel him, but because he's armed,
they they can't stop him and they they start to throw tools and rocks at him and eventually, he's able to
approach their wall and
slice a
and and slice the square out of it with this sword. And I love the
word balloon where he is just going so over the top threat be beyond.
He calls out,
nothing can save you from me. I am un invincible.
I am doom
itself.
Okay The... This one is a masterpiece.
They finally
resort to a little bit of car tune logic where they they've got this flame through
Coke.
A trio of brothers with with the flames are already yes.
That they've used to kind of melt and then
solidify the walls of their forte They get one of them gets the bright idea to burrow and the snow behind donald and ultimately heats him. He heats his suit of armor up,
you know? And and do they do manage to heat it up enough to repel him.
And and it concludes
with Donald
tending to his wounds on a large black of ice
as the nephews
getting ready to haul up for the winter and they've they've turned the su armor into
a radiator
stove and our roast
roasting wiener.
Warren, that this is such a great bit of of wish Fulfillment and and
Kid Empowerment and Donald versus the nephew use Gladstone stick violence.
I I don't mean to... I I've... I'm big here. I'm talking too much about this one, but But this, this is like the story that I was like, oh, I I gotta talk about some of these classic ones because I don't wanna mis talking about the Ducktales the iron pants. I like this story a lot and thank you for
for your passion about it. I remember this one as well. Not as well as as salesman donald, but I I I do have the Lit graph
that to me just makes me laugh every time I walk by it in my room and look at it. And just... I just love it. You said it it it's classic dial versus the nephews.
What I really like with Barks is doing here is that first
reveal of the dock Armor,
it it's a out loud panel. I mean, and the Ducktales the armor says very little. He just keeps storming the castle and and it a couple of humorous elements I love.
He not only fashioned this out of the Gem stove company where he got the armor from.
But he put a little plume on his hat
arm. I mean, this he went over the top, I mean, it's but
great art, great
characterization
invent,
but those panels when he is introduced with the sn all the way through to that declaration
of I Al doing itself. He doesn't say much at all, Inducks. I think he just says one little line is he's coming out. He goes, whole Barks,
think it's
buff,
can stop me now.
That's what cracked me up so much about this story. Yeah. Yeah. Well set. And and you're right about that awesome touch where you can see the logo of the stove company
on. That he he's like, turned a boiler or something into it. A little little fore foreshadowing there too to the last panel.
Right. And you're right, he's just like this this unstoppable, like, sort of juggernaut or not men
slowly
men
his way towards them. Yeah. This one's a ton of fun. It looks like we are ready to talk about our last one. So I'm I'm glad to close out this one by talking about matt chemist.
I think this one is really
really interesting and really fun. And I remember reading about it in
a
issue that Glad stone put out where they paired it with the sunken and yacht because they both had like these little elements.
Where the...
There was a little bit of, like, real life that kinda bleeds it and bled into it. So, you know, I'll let I'll let you summarize the story here, and then I'll kinda talk about the little feature that they've published in that comment on it. Yeah. Yeah. And again,
the... This particular one,
Barks, I believe comes from Walt Disney Comics and stories number forty four.
Yep. That's the one. And what I like about this story
and it again, it is a newer one to me, but when I read it,
I just love the way again, the Nephews and donald play off each other. Anyway, we see the Nephews and they're they're playing in their
their chemistry set and and donald is really interested in what they're doing.
And says, hey, you ought a he he'd take some of the chemicals, and he just says you ought to just add this and they they were they warn him, and they'll be careful. Something horrible could happen it could blow up. And he goes
fully. And so he pours it in the cylinder bowl that the chemicals are bubbling in flies up in the air hits not lend head and all of a sudden Donnie has this incredible
transformation into a brilliant chemist.
He he looks the same. He's walking kind of days. He's got a huge on bump on his head.
But he starts talking very in very scientific kinda funny terms, and he
says we've got to
got it take me seriously here. I'm gonna talk something.
And he says I'm gonna be the Mighty chemist in the universe.
So he creates
this
concussion that he proudly announces Inducks might Yeah. Doc is Al explosive chemical that he
has it has developed, but it's dangerous. So we have to drive far away from Inducks
to if experiment with it. So the boys say well, we just do it here in the backyard. No. No. It's too dangerous so they go out and but they get outside of Inducks berg and they
ideally over a cliff and battle begins dropping these
bottles
of duct mite over this
one thousand foot high cliff and says, be careful it'll explode while he does this over and over again at different sizes and nothing happens.
So he goes down to the bottom light to match looks in there, and then it just blows up. But instead of being hurt, he's proud that he has
created this incredible potion
And so
they go back off, and they pour a little bit of this in the car for gas and it speeds down the road.
They all say buy cruel world, which is just fun. So after they're they're splash the water from the car that with the with the duct might in it goes into the water Donald is now absolutely
convinced that he can send a rocket to the moon. Well the boys get concerned and they go see a doctor called u... Doctor Uc court a brain expert,
and he basically
explains to the doctor that they're worried that this
Ducktales might is going to cause more problems,
and then he's built a I ship to fly to the moon. So the doctor just basically gets up says so what, he can't harm any anything there.
So they go home, Donald got the rockets chip build. So the boys show up and Donald is already in his rocket, and he's ready to take off and he he wears off
the the boys dry last to stay put but he goes all the way at the space. He goes all the way and he's extremely startled now. And he goes around the moon and he heads right back to her. And he crashes,
leave it or not in his own backyard. And when he is told that he has done this incredible achievement, he doesn't believe it. I think his his his little amnesia is little
personality shift to the man the Mad chemist comes back around. And he says, I can't believe It went around the the moon, and everybody's proud of this accomplishment, and they ask him if he could mix up some more duct might. And now it doesn't even know what Ducktales is. Right. So
that's that's the color of the of the story there. Yeah. It's a perfect one... One of those
first sort of etch sketch stories
where there's something
that's like, really over the top, he literally
leaves earth
and then Barks is gonna have to kind of reset it back to the status quo. I really like this one. This one stood out to me because it feels like the art... It's it's still very early. But the art feels like it's really starting to mature
by now
in this field
Yeah. I agree.
Race to the moon. I mean, there's other stories that come later. That pick up on this great early artwork.
Yeah. And this one, you know, it it's kind of a evo of the fire bug,
which is another
kind of early not quite as early, I think but our early ish favorite of mine where he gets some kind of
insult to the head that changes his personality.
But I really like the look that he's given when when he's kind of
in this other guys as the mad chemist.
This one's really cool too that sort of escalation of the action
where they're driving out to have ever increasing vacant lots
until they just get get out deep into the wilderness.
To to to blow up his weapon. And it's hard not to think for me about the Manhattan project.
Right? This one feels like such an allegory
Because
what are we in with this one? Is this nineteen forty four?
Where are we in in relationship with So so this one has came out in May of nineteen forty four. That's the date on with wikipedia. And
the
Adam Bah,
I to give giveaway. Well,
but the real one,
fat
that that was detonated in forty five.
So.
But everyone like, this was something that everyone
kind of new was going on, but
That there was clearly this race Right, going on. No one
Civilians didn't know the specifics of it. But they had an idea that both sides were working on these
these super
So this was on everyone's mind.
And and there's this like, really
kind of frightening Gladstone
with this one. I thought, no question about it. Yeah. Some evil under tone, I mean, Up and oppenheimer was working on the Adam bomb for us. Is that correct? And yes
Yes. Exactly.
And this one has also this really interesting like, sort of true life
component of it. I don't fully
understand it. But apparently,
some of the chemistry work that Barks depicted at the beginning of this
actually was like pretty realistic. And and was was ahead of it time. You can find a couple of articles online about this
kind of under the the heading of Donald Inducks accidentally use meth and a comic before it was discovered that the studio got this article from these readers, the scientists
who were also big fans.
Of the dot com that were...
I'll just read read this
verbatim.
Yeah. They got this
letter from a doctorate from Joseph Lambert of the California Institute of Technology.
He he's pointing out a a reference in a technical article called the spin states of carb,
and he says that despite the recent extensive interest in meth chemistry much additional study is required.
Among the experiments which have not to our knowledge been carried out as yet. Is one of a most intriguing nature suggested the literature of no less than nineteen years ago,
and the foot in that technical paper directed readers to issue forty four of walt Disney comments and stories.
And and he he goes on to say that Donald referenced to c h two
in panel two point one was years ahead of its time
as the existence of that elusive chemical
had not been that chemical intermediate and not been proven
as of nineteen forty four. This is like that very right
academic
language that that scientists or or smaller use when they're kind of being a little bit on the nose a little bit funny. The inclusion of this foot Inducks quite skull early article,
stemmed from the discovery that doctor Got and I sherry mutual and independently Gladstone standing esteem for the Adventures of Donald Inducks.
It love it. It was talk to Gasp Barks who rediscovered this early invention of carb.
So
There's there's a lot of reasons to appreciate this one. I think it's... I do think it's one of the best of the early stories.
But
but I also think that that that little technical
detail
merits highlighting here Oh, that... That's great. That thank you for sharing that. I was unaware of that. But it it shows that Donald Barks popularity is spread across
so many different
generations and different different professions. Right? And I also like the notion that that we're not the only
grown men here who who's still like dot com Right? The this this was several decades ago and these these various team scientists.
So I I like that. Any any other comments on this one, the Mad chemist warren, Well, again, it was a newer story for me,
looking at it.
In the issue that I have.
I'm just... I'm taken by the artwork and how much more Barks is experimenting with
outside of this world and looking at the moon, what the moon might look like Just so many great little little gigs Yeah. I'm gonna have to dig into this one a little bit more and Yeah. This one's a lot of fun. So
warren, I I wanna send size just a little bit. We can kinda wrap things up by by talking about by kinda reflecting on this period,
I love going back and looking at these. I still think they're bark in his most formative
time. I mean, I mean, he's he's be coming the story and artist that he
he's he's good. He's not great yet. But he's he's good and he knows it.
And then, again, I just think it's wonderful. How much freedom the editors gave him to do these Yeah, he's really getting some great confidence from doing these. And Alec, it was kind of... It was really unique what he got to do. Right? Like the the Disney comics,
the Ducktales stories that he was doing them. Right? Like, I don't think there were other creators
around this time.
Who are being given this opportunity. Am I... Am I right? For the comics?
Yeah. Yeah. Oh, yeah. No. He was it. That was it at the time. I I think there we had the different cover artist often they
creditors.
Up until issue number thirty one, the Victory Garden. They were reprint newspaper com comic strips and they ran them and they ran out. They they said we're done. We have to do something else in that that desperation to find new content
for this walt Disney comics and stories format this monthly format
This was a great career starter for for Carl Barks
because they couldn't reprint any more newspaper strips. He he really was
Disney comics
for for a long to
we had those space for twenty three year career. Yeah.
We had those newspaper classics.
We had the great conference in Mickey Mouse comics that'll be collected over and over the the, like, Al fe
Strips and and others the art tele the the comic strips right.
Right. He kept walt Disney's comics and stories going.
He set the templates
the the series, he was writing them
monthly for for so long that it's safe to say that, like... The the comments line wouldn't have likely gone on and become as enduring without him.
Let alone, the Donald Inducks
line, you know, that's gonna get spun off and then uncle sp,
Right, That's gonna become his his own...
His own... It it might as well have been called Carl Barks uncle Scrooge.
Because it wasn't a monthly title at first. No. I not to begin with and all the four color long form stories. I mean, We know that the greek fit the Victory Garden came in early forty three shortly after finds pirate gold given his break but when did the mondays ring
the next long form story? When was that published? That that was September of forty three. So he gets to do about a half dozen
of the
of the ten pager
before he gets to do. That that one, of course is very significant as his first
independent
full length adventure story. Right So Disney had doing the full length stories to to fall into the four color format.
To do those, He did these monthly.
Know. He's very productive. He was a busy artist and a busy writer to be given all the freedom
to tell all of these stories that he wanted to tell is a great benefit for the readers and for for you and me. Even even if he himself didn't feel
as free sometimes to tell some of the stories that he liked We we didn't cover
lifeguard days is in this early period. And that's the one where he was forced to to reduce the b of a of a duck bathing beauty character.
One of his early
bout of of being censored.
We didn't come figure. It it's a it's a duck. So it's Al Inducks. It's a doc with bo so pretty... It's a little bit disturbing, but ultimately, he did have to, like, flatten
reduce her her chest
to get past the editors.
We didn't get Al about neighbor good neighbors. Right? We got first iteration of, like, neighbor jones, and he he uses a couple different versions of name Jones. Mh. So the... These were never like as a kid
I didn't like these as much
because they felt very primitive. I didn't really have a an
appreciation
of his his career arc. And then also, you know, I didn't read them in that kind of order or anything, naturally. I I did I read a bunch of these for the first time
in the Gladstone graphic novel, which was number twenty seven
in that series.
So, you know, I didn't inherently appreciate it. I I figured out oh these are his first stories. That's interesting. But they weren't ones that I went back to. I probably only read the Ducktales the iron pants
two or three dozen times
compared to some of the stories that I read
scores of times,
which is to say, I do. I do love these stories. But,
you know, more as an appreciation of what they say about what where he was in his career at the time. Well. Right. I do wanna mention
where
these stories kind of fall as far as the community.
Right? So Yeah. I I love to check them out on Inducks.
And I'm gonna
I'm gonna talk about them. Let's talk about them in order of lowest first.
So so the victory garden... Right. That this one clock in pretty low. This one has a six point nine
out of ten
which puts it as
number
thirty seven thousand
and some. Out of the forty one thousand
some stories. Very low for a Barks story.
And and obviously, it wasn't written by by him. In fact, I I forgot to mention this, We don't know who wrote it. Like, we don't know we know that it was handed over to him by the editor, but we don't know who Scrooge it. Correct. Okay Written by anonymous studio hack basically
or or anonymous publishing hack. Like it's it's a fine story, but it's it's very thread there. But that's interesting to me. That seems a little bit unfair when you consider,
you, how significant of a story. But but taken as its own story. Yeah. It's it's not the best. Yeah. And then
next the the next highest one is the rabbit foot.
Which jumps up okay. Quite a bit. So we've got a seven point one out of ten good for
one thousand
seven hundred and forty fourth out of all forty one at some thousand. That did jump up quite a bit just that six point nine to seven point one. It leaked up quite a bit. Right. And that was his most full original story. So Exactly. Clearly it landed much better in in the community as as a
purely Carl Barks
story. Yeah. Good to know. And then
Salesman, Donald is next. That gets a seven point two out of ten. And it's... It's into the top thousand, it's rank nine hundred and seventeen
out of forty one something
And then we've got the Mad chemist. That one Barks quite highly for
a an old one at seven point five out of ten.
Good for three hundred and twenty six. I do think that one might get a little bit inflation just because of the, like, the the the ones that kind of
bleed out into the pop culture, people remember them better. So I think they've higher... And I do think it's a very good old story. And and then the dock in the iron pants is the clear winner
at range.
Two hundred and ninety one out of forty one thousand. Some
good for seven point five again, out of ten.
I would agree with that one being probably the top story in terms of story. And and and I I might... Personally, I might swap the index ratings for
Salesman donald and the Mad chemistry diet. Wasn't as crazy by the med chemistry. But Again, you're right. I think it captured the imagination of the world at that time and that's that's very fair. I Al I I was really impressed by how good that salesman domino was. I I enjoyed that a lot. I was planning to get read that from. That's I think I think of my favorite of all of them today. Nice. And and I just... I love the Ducktales iron Pants.
Oh.
So much. I I think he's just you can you can really feel he... I think he's doing what really entertain him in that one because.
It's so over the top. Alright. Well this was fine. Yeah. So much like. I agree. This was great warren. This this this is a lot of fun. It's it's fun to take this neat complimentary group of stories from the same era
get to cover them. I'm I'm not planning to cover any more of the old ones. So this this is gonna be our stand
for all of these.
Thank you so much for for taking the time to appreciate these early Barks.
Always great to revisit these stories.
I love it and looking forward to our next opportunity. Awesome. I I'd love to hear what listeners think about, you know, their their own preference for these stories or if there's one that they really think that we should covered
in this early period. Feel free to reach out at Barks remarks at g gmail dot com or on the Barks remarks, Facebook page.
And until next time.