we.
Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Mc Ducktales writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge con of all time time. This episode is a ten page podcast, all about one of his short stories get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Alright. So welcome back Barks remarks listeners. We've got a special
episode today. This is the first of what I am calling the ten page podcast. This is not a regular
episode of Barks remarks. So I'm I'm leaving it number but in these episodes, we will be to discussing
one to two of Barks famed ten page stories. I've got a great conversation planned with this Halloween
themed
episode that is going to be all about Donald Duck worst nightmare. So
I'm gonna let my guests
introduced herself, tell us your name and and say something about Halloween.
Hi. I'm Sarah Santiago.
Returning guests. And halloween fan, but living in Scotland has made
celebrating halloween a little bit difficult because it's just a day here. It's not all month long spooky season. And then the architecture where I live is mostly, like, apartment building
type, you know, flat. It's really kind of dis
incentivizing
to
have to climb up, like, five sets of stairs per building
for ten things of candy.
Sure? It's it's definitely not as popular here I I... I'm a big sp season fan. You know, It's it feels like
I'm I'm game for it to bleed into the whole of October. So So... And do you have kids so you get to do trigger treating, which I miss from when my little sister was little. And then before that, from when I was little. Oh, yeah. Trick treating is like, the Al g, it's the best. So a lot like I mentioned, you know, I wanted to do a halloween soon. And and the natural
story for a Halloween
episode is
Carl Barks Trick treat. Right? It's the only... As far as I know, it's the only full length one that he did that was directly about Halloween needed a bunch of ten pager
But,
you know, I'm really trying hard to
stay true to my podcast format of doing them chronological as much as possible. So i think this is gonna be a nice way to kinda compromise on that and we'll see when Trucker treat actually comes out. But that one's a really fun one. It's based on
Al old donald Inducks Cartoon
that is directly halloween themed.
So this this one actually is gonna cover We... We're gonna be talking about Donald Duck worst nightmare.
Donald dot Worst Nightmare, or sometimes you see it as Deed worst nightmare is
not like, directly halloween themes, but it's very
scary. I think it's one of the more frightening looking ten pages around. So I feel like it's appropriate. We're gonna dive in have a little bit of fun for the ten page podcast. I'm giving myself permission to be a a little bit less research. Than I am for the Adventure stories. But how about you Sarah? Were were you able to to hold to that structure of of not researching this quite as much or or or not?
No. But thank you so much for dropping a new special interest directly into my lap that I didn't even know I would want to have. We can go into it when it comes up. But,
yeah, I went down the the a rabbit hole today for about two days.
Let's see. Let's do it. Donald Inducks
worst nightmare.
This one is published, you know, we're jumping around a little bit. The majority of our stories that we've covered have been part of the four color or one shot series that was put out by By del Western Publishing.
And
most of the ten pager
were released in the series Walt Disney comments and stories. And and this is a very long running comic series.
Until until it ended a few years ago, I I believe it was like for for a time, I believe it was the third longest running comic with series after like action comics, which has superman and detective comics which has batman. So this is a very
come line, a lot of it run
includes these Barks ten pager And and that's where Donald Duck wears nightmare Appeared in walt Disney comics and stories.
Number
one hundred and one in nineteen forty nine, so we're not jumping around too much with this story. And then it's it's had quite a few reprint. It looks like it's had nine printing total in the Us counting that original one. And
we don't get to talk too much about daisy in the adventure stories. You know, he he kind of reserved her more for these short ten pager.
This is a nice appearance of Daisy duck here. And
are you are you ready to go right into the? South. Ready.
And again, this is it's certainly not like going to scare
anyone but it has much much more creepy
imagery than the typical
Disney's comments and story, ten pager debts.
So Donald Duck Worst nightmare opens right in the middle of him having a nightmare.
His his... The first nightmare
in the story involves him being chased by... What he calls men from Mars.
And he's running. He's barely escaping them. He jumps off a cliff right into the gaping mall, the open mouth of a really
du looking like martian creature, and he wakes up screaming as one does from an nightmare and we get some nice spa
dialogue from him and the kids.
Where, you know, we we learned that he's been having these really bad nightmares it's nine so far this week and each one has been worse than the last.
And
you know, I I read this at age eight or nine and was really struck by how creepy those men from Mars, those Martian monsters were Sarah. Well, you're in luck because I am your resident Barks expert
due to my undergraduate
work being in planning terry geology.
And I did wanna point out that... At this time,
we did believe that Barks supported life. There are...
I I remember
seeing
national
graphics, which you've said that Carl Barks was very into.
Showing what we now know are dust storms
basically changing the, you know, color of the surface of Mars that at that time we're mis misinterpreted as seasonal vegetation. It's amazing. You know, with vegetation,
they were thinking, oh, maybe there's life too. So people got very imaginative over here on the creative side. Right? So
then from Mars,
could have been a very real
scary thing.
But you know, you couldn't fat check. Right. These these struck me as is really interesting. You know, like, kind of not just like, oh, he's having
scary nightmares about men from Mars. But, like, now they're kind of fodder from kids to have these nightmares as well. I guess, this is a few decades from when that they used to believe they were canal. Right? Some of the the Geologic... Oh, yeah. Yeah. Very cool. So on the next page, you know, the Nephews are talking with Donald about He's gotta to take care of his insomnia. He needs to see a doctor, and he says he was... He he did. He was prescribed some sleeping pills, but he's he needs to be convinced to try the sleeping pills. The nephews hope that he'll just sleep so soundly He won't have dreams.
But sure enough, we're gonna transition to his his next nightmare which has him driving just about the world's most perilous
Mountain Roadway.
And this this is very stressful to me. I've driven on a couple of
mountain paths like this. And if you're ever on one of these, it it's terrifying. And so I can feel my stress level rising.
As I read this story as he is rounding a sharp curve onto an oil slick and tumble off the cliff,
transitioning to the Nephews calling for a doctor
in the wake of this next nightmare. Right. He is It's kind of a universal
scary dream. And so I have a version. I even had it two or three nights ago where I'm
stepping on the brakes and pulling up on the emergency break, and I just cannot
stop from coast
or, you know, sliding or hitting, you know, tapping whatever in front of me. Yeah. And that itself is a very adult dream. Right? Like that's not something that a kid would have because they don't have the experience driving that we do. The... It's... So it's not a driving dream. It's a falling dream anybody could be a passenger in a car on one of these cliff side highways that falls, and that's universally
terrifying.
That's a good point. You know, a lot of these nightmares that he has are kind of these these universal experience. And and the dialogue and these, I think it's worth noting that Barks really sets up how terrified
and how life ruining these are right now for Donald. The most awful cliff I ever saw, and then a sharp curve ahead oil on the road, and my brakes are shot. You know, it's just... Like I said, very stressed full very suspense building,
and the looks of terror on these pages that Bark straws for donald, I think are are a lot worse than they are in the adventure stories because, you know, Donald really believes himself to be a moment
from death because these are nightmares. Right? So on the following page, you know, they've summoned the doctor
and we get this sort of
list
set up. Right, Ducktales has already tried remedy number one, it was implied to be the sleeping pills and now we're on to remedy number two. This is a a trope that he uses a lot. You know? This is... This makes for for an easy
sort of storytelling
device. Where we go down this list. Right? So remedy number two is the doctor describes it the very like Late forties looking doctor describes it Al
exercises to relax his thinking nerve. He must work at something.
But he hates very much to do. And and it's funny than nephew you say he hates to do anything. So the doctor presents him. Do you... Do you wanna describe Sarah let the doctor produce and him as his suggestion.
The doctor puts away his stethoscope after listening to doctor to Donald head, of course because that's what you do with the stethoscope.
Right. And he pulls out a little circle of What we'll see very soon is a do.
U. He's holding it very delicate
his little pink are up. Would you like to crochet little toiletries?
Of course, that's terrifying to Donald Crochet.
Yeah.
He he explodes with with just otter horror and content contempt. Right? Wait.
Make lakes like girls and old ladies do? I'd rather be boiled in prune oil.
So based on that response, you know, with his completely made a protocol here the doctor decides that this is perfect. He's got a crochet
This is going to quote relax your nervous tension and you'll sleep like a tired log. So Donald that we transitioned to Donald crochet bus,
while simultaneously just stew and freaking out about how he'll be disgraced forever if any of his friends hear about it. And he's he's drifting off to sleep, and, unfortunately, he does transition into another nightmare
into a hire dream where he's about to be made to walk the plane. So I did wanna comment on crochet,
knit, you know, needle, yarn cross, of any kind. Yeah are they are a legitimate therapeutic
d dresser. I just read
burnout.
By a couple of, you know, legitimate researchers
on how to deal with burnout in your life and you know, taking up knit ing or crochet, etcetera etcetera was
legitimately
one of the tools that they recommended as far as what they call completing the stress cycle, but also it makes you feel
like you've accomplished some... They're very good. For getting your brain to calm down out of high stress
situations.
So so this doctor is is he's a little bit of a quack. But he's also got a a real protocol that has some.
It really does. It... No. You're right. It really does. You're doing something that requires you to focus
by nature very peaceful very medi.
You know what? What stays in my mind about this. What kind of makes this story live in my brain is Donald response to it. Right? This is, like, classic, I I have to present myself as a human man. I can't how myself.
I think every time we've got like a sports championship,
There tends to be some story about how one of the athletes
will center himself by doing this. While he's on the side hands
You know, it... It's still notable. Right? We still give him this kind of like, oh, this is kind of sub
because he's like this mainly athlete and he's knit. Right. That was kind of the the rabbit hole I went down into today. The history of knit the history of crochet,
and the history of men's
involvement.
In those activities. Right, You know, we have a lot of evidence
a lot of other crafts, but not so much
knit because what knit unit soft things that degrade very very fast. And then in Europe, we... In the thirteen fifties,
we see the emergence of the knit Madonna.
Theme in arts. So you have, you know, Jesus kinda hanging around, doing baby things and mary
knit, and that is kind of an indicator that it was a thing at that point. That was done by women in the home. Right? But of course, and picture it. You you say the knit madonna and I can immediately picture it. Yeah. But then of course, things that are used full and can be,
you know, are taken over by men and they start to create guild, knit and guild.
In in France first. And then of course, They spread to Europe, And basically, it was it was always a thing that men did. You you see old paintings of shepherd
knit while they're watching their fox. And then now point, it clearly became
rebate. In World war one, the men were sent off, women were left behind and to support the war effort.
The women were asked
to knit cold weather Gear. And it looks like it never really changed back into a thing that everybody does. In one generation, and then with the advent of sort of mass media, that that could be the death of of something. Right. It just fell out a fashion completely in the eighties once once those kids from that time of austerity got to the age where they were adults in making their own decisions. It fell into a big decline. But in the twenty first, century, we're seeing a huge resurgence. Right? Have a hobby.
Yeah. But it's not a necessity As we're re examining
gender and gender roles.
We see a lot more men entering the field. Right? So what Donald is that being asked to do though is crochet, and Crochet was developed in a lot of ways to be an... A cheaper
less labor intensive
alternative to lace snake. And so that's why it's a pretty little do that the doctor is holding up. So we are
in the midst of Donald nightmare, his new nightmare on the next page where he is surrounded by very ferocious.
Hungry looking sharks. We transition, you know, the nephews are
calling the doctor,
know, saying we've gotta gone to remedy number three. But he cautions them that, you know, that's only for the the most desperate cases.
He needs to keep it up with the crochet toilets leads. And so We transitioned to him the next night again, drifting off while he's crochet,
and, unfortunately, it's into another night marie he seems to be in the great north somewhere, and he has wolves on his tail. And the last panel
He he says every time I look back, I see more wool must be ten thousand.
That just felt very like night. To me, right? The way he described that. That seems like how nightmares work. You know, you would Severino
you wouldn't really encounter that many walls. But in your nightmare, it makes sense.
Exactly. One of the things art wise that I found kind of cute was the that the sharks that were circling him after he walked the plank and the wolves both had their tongues out. Right. Yeah. That's what sharks do. They've got these, like, very cartoon ish hungry brands.
Yeah. Somehow to me, it makes them almost like more malevolent like they're going to take pleasure in eating him, not just not just eating him for assistance.
Absolutely.
On that next page, you know, we transitioned to the end of this wolfe nightmare. And he's
trying to get away, but he's just fallen Al eye
clinging two Barks and he's fallen again into there. Into their gaping laws. And so this time, the nephews have called the doctor again and asked okay. What what is remedy number three? And, you know, the doctor kinda braces them that this is for it's the only remedy in the world that is worse than the ailments and he tells them that their uncle needs to be frightened by something that is more horrible
than he can experience in dreams. To right And so the nephews
kinda steal themselves and they figure out that the best thing that they can do is to get a Barks in the scariest thing that they can get in their town. And as they're coming back with the Barks skin Donald, is again drifting off while crochet,
and he has
and encountered an open cage at the Zoo with the lion about to pound on him. And so on the next page,
you know, he's trying to get away from the lions, the nephews and counter him in mid tier as he's being attacked by the lines.
They... They hand to mind attacking him as the Barks, and he just... He just kicks the the fake Barks in the butt and says graham Ruined to to a guy who's just been eaten by a lion, you're not even a good shutter. I I like that line. I think that's some good sharp dialogue there.
So, you know, the nephews
they've failed, they kinda go off probably to return the Barks skin on their way through town, they encountered daisy.
And she is naturally, like, puzzled that why they've got this Barks skin. They they kind of are too worn out probably to think about, you know, that Donald does not want his dirty secret here exposed. They explain what's going on. To Daisy and tell tell her that he's got this do treatment
And Sarah, you wanna tell us about her response and any thoughts you've got? Crochet dual,
Donald Crochet,
that I must see.
She's she's genuinely
excited and and and happy and It it doesn't seem like it's a ton kind of
delicious, like, oh,
I'd I love to see this this thing that is
beneath him. You know, I wanna see him
suffer. Right? She's genuinely
excited.
Right. Yeah, she she wants to appreciate it. She thinks it sounds darling. This is obviously
not gonna make Donald feel
feel empowered
or like he's accomplished something, but she's very excited for him. She... So he... I guess, you know, she could react He could've have chosen to depict her thinking that he was less of a man. And he chose not to. He's obviously got this other point of view that he's gonna express through Donald And I can't tell whether bark
himself. Feels more like daisy about it or donald about it or both. You know what I mean? I think that's an interesting
observation.
Overall, I would say that he's
feeling
the way that Donald feels about it and kind of
that attitude.
Right. I think he's still writing a character
in daisy that he may not identify with. But is still capable of writing a character with different views than he has. Yeah. I I think you're probably right. And I think the only thing
about it is that he really does present donald Al just being utterly over the top. Right? Like,
his his rev is is is truly ridiculous in this. So
there might be some commentary on how silly this is. But, you know, he he just so naturally falls into that
This is such a city pursuit. Right. He's... And he's writing... He's writing an
insecure man extremely well. You know, whatever
insecurities
Donald Duck has, whether it his masculinity
or anything else. Barks really understands them and for portrays them very well. Yeah. There are gonna be a lot of these stories where Donald is very concerned with being quote, a hem. You know, this is...
They literally use that term key in in a lot of these, which really fast needs me because today it's it's it's it's priority, right? That the term itself is ridiculous.
So We transitioned to Daisy meeting up with a friend of hers.
As far as I know, we never encounter this friend again. She's
she's named miss Double chin. This is which I think references that she's a turkey. They're kind of scheming to to encounter Donald Crochet she and and her friends as a man who crochet this is just darling and it and that's all they're interested in. Right? They think this is just darling.
But the the use of that word, you know, is kind of pointing to how their viewpoint is in.
Right? Yeah. Darling
isn't a masculine
or even a neutral
word? No. It's it's you're you're absolutely right. It's a very
fe
word and and also a little maybe a little bit in in infant.
Right.
Because it it really implies
something that is cute. Mh.
And and so Donald is horror stricken that his secrets been revealed. He sees the two women approaching his house. He here their plans
to have him give a talk on Crochet at their club meeting.
Or exhibit some of his doyle
and and he lights out the window at the back of the house into his into his car, and he leaves and the women pursue him and a tax that they've just failed. And Right. So it's... I find it interesting that they want him to give a talk. Al the needle work club and exhibit the do.
Because it speaks to how
they, you know, ema escalating language aside. They are genuinely interested. They do want to see good work They do want him to
participate and show off what a great job he's doing because he's doing a great job. Right?
He he knew the language.
He is able to keep doing it without frustration. So he's probably doing it well.
That's right. But he he can't he can't take that compliment.
No. Because he's so afraid of it. But I did wanna talk about a little bit of the history of crochet in the Us.
Right.
So it was became popular in Europe and the eighteen hundreds to em
ones that they already had. Callers,
you know, just any little... Anything
that could just make it a little bit less
dreary. Right? And specifically,
what Donald is doing is was introduced to the Us
from Irish people who are fleeing the Family, or nice. And then when they immigrated to the Us, you know they they introduced it to the people of the Us. Right? In Ireland, it was a thing that men and women in children all did. You're not gonna code something that that's gonna sustain you as only for one gender. Right. And then coming to the Us
afterwards,
it does seem to have followed the same path as
knit has where it you know, where it becomes something that just women do. But it crochet was
an aren't that men utilized two for manly things because they needed to make and mend nets and and such for hunting and fishing. Oh, yeah. That makes sense. Right? A lot of these... A lot of these crafts were born out of just necessity and survival. You know, I'm reflecting
that I've probably literally never said the word doyle out loud in my life before recording this podcast. Right?
Would you say that they're archaic now? Or is that just because I'm I'm a dude? No. You're you're absolutely right, and it as we moved away from handmade
decorations,
it did kind of become the realm of
grandparents. And it's it's not a thing that with the kind of resurgence
in interest in these craft in the twenty first century has really
taken hold again. Right? We don't to... We don't feel like we have to put a do down
on our console table before we put a lamp down. Right? Right. In the way that we used to. Yeah. That that to me feels very old fashioned. Right? And and it also feels a little bit fancy. Right? Like, I associate it with, like, high tea almost Oh, absolutely.
So, you know, we're kind of entering us a high comedy part of this story, right, where
This is gonna be Barks case. Yes. Yeah. We're we're in a car chase here and it's been a transition to this over the top pursuit.
By the women of Donald, and he's about to basically enter
his own version.
Of remedy number three. Right? He's he's he is so disgusted
at the prospect
of having to
with these women
about his hobby now,
which to be fair to him, I don't ever get the impression. I do... I get the impression that he's good at it. I don't get the impression that he enjoys it. Add any break.
Well that was the whole point that it was something that he didn't want to do. Right. And I don't think he ever
comes to to enjoy it. I could easily see the story having taken the large that he comes to enjoy it, and, you know, maybe still feels and secure about it. But...
That's not the case. Right? He he never he never comes around to this,
and he's just
completely horrified.
Al being discovered. So so we're transitioning into
his actual nightmare come to life. Right? He he drives up this terrible Mountain Trail he plunge off a cliff. He lands,
he lands into what he identifies as the pool at the shark farm,
you know, with which it's ridiculous. Right? Because you don't
As far as I know, you don't farm sharks, at least not of that size,
but
but it works for the context of the story. He does mention, you know, this is as bad as those night nightmares I've been having. And
once he
once he emerges from the Barks pond on the next page,
He's confronted by Daisy and her friend having caught up with him. He has to decide is he gonna... Is he gonna try to get past them? Or is he gonna go back and try and get through those sharks and he does he chooses the sharp and he... He punches his way past them saying I said Van Moose.
And, you know, I think we need to bring back memos. I really love the word demos. I do see that in a lot of these stories.
It's definitely a a word that I remember from these kinds of cartoons.
Right. And I think it comes from the Spanish Bam. I think it's just like a option
an
Negotiation of Domino's let's go, but so so the women
after he emerges,
miss K, she she kinda figures out that he's deliberately swimming away from them. So they know that they're they're not welcome here.
They pursue him... He's hiding out in the trees,
and daisy
separate so that she can call in the cavalry.
She gets on the phone. It's and
they they get together their
companions for needle,
a flying squadron of companions of needles were. Her friend is supposed to call the members of the petite padding circle.
It's just this this great... The point Embroidery Club and the Tuesday chatting circle.
Right.
This is Barks idea of what ladies clubs are, and I'm sure that there's some truth into
this
in this era. Right? This was probably
probably his observation.
And it's it's certainly a cara, but it's funny.
And then know... Her friend is missus Chatter. This is Chatter. Yes. Of course because the... These are the women who are getting together to
do their craft and gossip.
Is is what's implied. Right? What else are you gonna do? Right. And and and then have this kind of thing too, but it's coded differently. Right? And... Well, absolutely is not.
At least not viewed to be about gossip.
You know, everything kinda comes to head on the last page of the story where he's swinging through the trees,
it's striking me that that's maybe supposed to evo Tarzan.
Right, who is one of these he, man. Key men, and he runs out of trees
right over the Lions cage at the zoo. And again, he's confronted with this decision because there are there hundreds of of women now in closing closing in on him. And he's so he... He has this panel where he has to decide is he gonna allow himself to be caught and he thinks this is worse than any nightmare I ever had and he makes the... The ten thousand women in closing on him are scarier than the ten thousand wolves. Right. Right. And and so he says out of my way, Tab cats, I guess you're not so terrible
after all. And and we we close out the story, it transitions to days later, we come to understand that Huey, Dewey Louis have been frantically searching for their uncle who's gone missing since. And they're asking a zoo keeper who is bathing like the world's cutest little baby giraffe And it washed right in a flash tub. But if if he has seen their uncle.
And and, apparently the Zoo keeper has. He confirms is he a little guy about so high. Huey, let the nephews know that he's been living in the Lions cage.
He sleeps sixteen hours of stretch wakes up yells, I'm cute. I'm cured and goes back to sleep again. And and story.
And this just it's very funny. Right? It's... It is
unbelievably dependent on this idea of of I'm gonna say the words toxic masculinity.
Oh, absolutely.
Right. So
it's only funny if I think if you read it as this, like, cultural
artifact, just
the... This notion that the very idea of a man being caught crochet.
And and that man is so insecure that he would rather
live with the lions
basically.
It's very over the top. It's very funny. I remember even as a kid reading this thinking. That's pretty weird.
That's.
But you know what? There were so many of these expressions
of of
security in culture sure that it didn't seem that weird to me. Oh I would have picked up on it immediately. I was I was tuned in to this kind of, you know, double standard my earliest memory was at age three. I was walking out the door to join my dad and my uncle who were fixing the car in the garage. And my mom yates me back in and made me wear a shirt and I did not think it was fair, then they didn't have to wear a shirt. It's Arizona.
It's hot but I did.
Right. Ever since then, I've been very
very
sensitive
to those kinds of things. I would seen it, but I I wouldn't have
necessarily thought like, oh, this is a thing that society should change. I would have just seen it as a... Oh, this is fair. Yeah. Kind of personal thing. Excellent.
And and that's to your credit. I don't think I was completely oblivious because, like, I didn't I didn't have a lot of the interest that a lot of the other boys did. Right? Like, I enjoyed some sports, but I was never
animated by, like, football or wrestling.
Even as I read these comments,
themselves. Right? I read these when I was older. And I I always felt very sensitive to the facts that, like, most kids if they were into comic books heavily, they were gonna be into the superhero comments. Right? So I always felt like oh it's, you know, but it's certainly nothing like the
expression of deeply masculine and security that Donald has in this story. And it's It's so funny. This one really stands out to me when I started this podcast and I was thinking back on these ten pager, I was like I didn't Severino reread them as frequently as I already read the adventure stories. Right? Because the... Those are the ones that really call more attention themselves. But I'd I'd say seventy or eighty percent of what Barks did are these ten pages and even shorter little gigs. So this is a huge part of his work. But this one stands out to me. I find this story very memorable for those two reasons. Right? We've got this, like, over the top toxic masculinity
and then these the nightmares themselves make this very memorable because I think they're they're scarier than what you usually find in a funny animal comic. Even bark other ten pages of this era. When did you when did you think of the story itself? Absent
just, you know, what it had to say about masculinity
and
men's
interest in in these now
hobbies. I mean, can you separate it from?
I don't know.
The elements of it you know, the the scary
and the him over overcoming a fear by, you know, doing something scarier. Those are really very
real and human. Right? There are some things that I'm no longer scared of because I've done scarier things or survived worse situation.
Right. You know, maybe it could have been a different driver that was.
Making him run away and face all of these spears. But I think that's a good thing. To to show a character
who maybe even in panic but certainly
once the panic passed, he's like, oh, yeah. Okay. I've processed that fear. Good. Yeah. I... I'm remembering now that there's a story that's similar to this where I think the nephews are trying to get away from spring cleaning. Right? There's something that's not quite as I mean, it's it's gender, but it's it's not as loaded as, like, Barks
sake. Right. So, yeah. I I try to think. Could you have made this story without that? Like, ear of
femininity, because it it is very baked in. But I do think that this story has a very cool progression right, in in ten quick pages.
He he sets this up very snap.
And and it's a very fun story. It's
it's toxic because Al get out. But
But it's a great read with some really sharp I Al as far as panels that I really like, there are so many cool panels artistic in this. Anytime he's really trying to pick the fear you know, I see the Lions, the silhouette of the lions on the last page. Trying to reach Donald. That's just you the women in circling every every aspect of is drawing really conveys to me Donald
fear and error and this one. Mh. Yeah. This and and this one stands out, I think to a lot of fans as one that that rates pretty highly.
None of these ten pager
very few of them rather rank nearly as highly as most of his adventure stories if you look them up on Inducks. But I do know that this one...
This one is Al little bit higher rated
compared to most of the... Of his ten page stores. As far as the art goes, I love that I love how colorful it is right. And I love how fast the pacing is so that you don't have a whole page of being at the doctor's office. You don't have a page of swimming with sharks. You have such a quick transition that the pages are very... The pages are quite variable.
Right. It's very brisk. Right? Yeah. And and visually
compelling. The drawings are so engaging,
and so compelling. Right. And and yeah, his ten pager are very sharp. Very ready. You know, looking looking at where this one lands on index,
This is rated as
the one hundred and ninety best of all the Disney comic stories. So this is probably in his top ten or so. Best remembered of the ten pages.
Yeah. So it's it's a well like story. That certainly hasn't
aged very well as far as its gender politics
aren't concerned. But I I love the nightmare nightmares. Stuff. That's basically where where I stand on this one. The nightmare stuff is so invent and so cool. It's a shame that it's
involves. Yeah. And the callbacks
to kind of each individual nightmare are very clever. Right? Like, he ends up, you know, falling down a cliff in a car like he did in his dream, and he ends up in a pool of sharks at the shop farm instead of jumping the, know, again, gender politics
side I do like that, you know, he didn't end up with ten thousand little circling him. It was you know, a hundred and women or whatever.
Right. But the the fact that an illusion was made, you know, I can I can see that and and recognize it as a quality illusion even if
the gender politics are so wrong. Yeah. It's it's a very invent
i tightly paced story.
Alright. Well, Sarah, thanks for joining me and listeners. Thanks for joining us for this first of hopefully more ten page podcasts.