Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of sc Mc Ducktales and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge con of all time
This episode is a ten page podcast all about one of his short stories, get ready to enjoy our remarks. Well back to Barks remarks. We are back with a very special episode of what I call the ten page podcast
Usually, we pick one or two of Barks short ten page stories to discuss. But today we're gonna do something a little bit different
And I think very special. We are gonna talk about a group of no less than five stories from the Ducktales
very early career. And and I got a little more pro, but I've got a c host
that I'm very excited to have Barks so I'll let him introduce himself Hey Barks more harmon and back again, enjoying these
early comics so much. Really really looking forward to our discussion and kinda of tracking Carl Barks his early career. So excited. Yeah. This will be fun. Yeah. I I agree. I am very excited to touch on it. You know when I when I started this podcast series, I was thinking long and hard about it. And I really was like I've gotta focus
on those adventure stories, those longer stories, you know, That's my format
and and I really wanted to stick to it because there were just so many of the ten pager. But but I ultimately did decide that it made a lot of sense to be a little bit flexible so that I could get the the special ten page podcast
episodes in and like I compromised where I was like, I'm gonna to stick with the spirit of what I'm doing by by numbering those longer episodes and labeling these others as the ten page plot asked. But it means I didn't make that decision
until a couple of months in. And so it means that I I passed by all of these great old stories that really showed some of his like, evolution. So so I thought about it, and I was like, oh this is this is the perfect compromise,
you know, we're gonna we're gonna talk about five really
interesting stories here. None of which would really kind of them really have enough meat in them, I think to merit their own episode, even a shared one. But but what we're gonna do today is
talk about those stories,
summarize them in a lot less detail than we usually would, and then we're gonna
think about what it says
about the Ducktales man's early career
and his evolution.
So so warren...
How do you feel in general? You know, about these early ten pager the first part of his career. Right? Right? And and coming off of his partnership with Jack hanna and finds p Gold and nineteen forty two where he kinda got a taste of the comic book
industry and and got to experience the art as you said, this is i was a great word, the evolution of the artist and the writer. And I think why I think these stories are so important is that they
pave the way to what he mastered later in his life.
So you see a lot of that moments in these stories that say, hey, I remember seeing that kind of thing happen in lost in the Andes or luck of the North or those longer form stories. So here's a man who at the age of about forty or forty one. He's so over forty. He's over forty. Yeah. And he's got this twenty three year career left, and this is just getting started
and that just amaze me. And this why I'm so excited because I think as an individual and it's a creative individual. I think he just wants to tell these stories. It it's it's really critically important that we understand where Karl Barks was. Yeah. I I fully agree.
That's why I definitely think it's important to cover these stories as part of this podcast project
but but I also think they're very enjoyable and fun. And you made a great point there about this stage of his life. And I think about that a lot. Right? Because, like, he... This is... I don't know how many careers in into his
into his life. But this is certainly not his first career, and this is a really big change to have made.
At this age at this stage in his life. I would say this is his third career. You know when he started out and and he started with
the Calgary eye opener and and he had that publishing and editing experience with the incompetence in Minneapolis that he had to work with for those early years. Then he got fed up with that and went to
California back to California and and looked in liquid did it Disney, while working in the story department and working on the Donald duck Shorts. And then he said, look, I'm gonna move seventy five miles with my first wife Clara to the small community
where the weather's is beautiful. The mountains are beautiful, and I'm gonna set up my little freelance practice there and see what I can do. I mean, this is his third attempt and he's now his forties. And I can kind relate to that.
I jumped from one long career in Minneapolis and at the age of forty two, I moved to Rochester and started something new. So Yeah. Yeah. Definitely. Yeah. I relate to... you know, i'm I'm at about that stage in my life right now, and I'm I'm looking at a little bit of a shift within my own career
and doing doing the series it's impossible not to think of that. And and it's... I I find it really in expiring. Right? Because he obviously had a lot of his best
work ahead of him still. Oh,
extremely inspiring and he had the talent. No question. But what I think was
incredibly fortunate about this period for him. Everything lined up the stars is aligned. He had people who trusted him. They didn't second guess and we'll talk about the first story here and how the editor just said, wow. You know, here you go. You you can do this in Yeah, they they did give him a lot of latitude for these. Right? But but I also get the impression that he was one of those people who really tried to, like, make his own luck you know, he he put himself in the right place. He obviously
built up a lot of goodwill as someone who was reliable
working on those Disney shorts and And these, you know, it should be said that these serve as a great bridge
between the work that he did on those cartoon shorts especially Donald Duck and what he's gonna go on to do with the dot comics. But, you know,
when he got that opportunity
to do pirate gold with Jack hanna,
my read is that they really liked what they saw. Oh yeah. And and they really must have liked the sales
outcome what is. And I think that probably gave him the confidence to think that he could he could do this. I I understand he gave himself a little bit of an insurance policy where he he brought a bunch of
You print a bunch of chicken coops with with
to sandwich
sin.
Yeah. Yeah. Yep. He brought his chickens and his chicken coops and like they say with his wife and
they kinda set up a little kinda like, okay. This doesn't work out. I'll be a typo before.
Here's the fall back. Well... And and and is he had previous careers doing other like, very outdoor
rural stuff. Right? Didn't he do some like some sort of ranch hand or trapping or or not in his twenties. Yeah. In his twenties and growing up. I think he was always outdoors.
Yeah. Yeah. Absolutely. Well, I'm I'm getting excited to talk about these. So are you ready? The launch into were? Do you any any other pre game Well I think I think we'll just kind of talk about the evolution here and it starts with Walt Disney comics and stories number thirty one.
Yeah. Let me let me list him off really quick. So we're gonna be talking today about the victory garden from walt Disney's comics and stories, number thirty one in April of nineteen forty three, followed by the Rabbit foot and the next issue while Disney's comments in stories thirty two then we're gonna be covering
salesman Donald in issue number thirty nine, followed by the duck in the iron pants. And number forty one. And finally, the mad chemist number forty four. And
let's let's talk about why we're doing the ones we are. Right? I I think
I think that any project like this we really have to cover the victory garden. Right? Warren. What why is that? Well, the Victory Garden was Carl Barks is first
opportunity to broad original
ten page story for Walt Disney's comics and stories and and since he moved away from Burbank and and the Disney studios and kinda ended his career with Walt Disney as a staff or he pulled pulled all his stops and became a freelancer He settled into this area where he could really
exercise his creative
skills And
they gave him this opportunity. It says in Donald Alt book, and I wanna give credit to the research here that
he believes that woman's name was Eleanor Packer who was an editor who gave him that opportunity to draw this story. Now this was not an original
story either though. The the the thing to know here is that he was handed to script or an outline, I and it was... As he says, it was a rather
indefinite sort of script. I worked it over and it made more sense out of it. And it was one of the things that they were kinda testing Carl Barks here in his ability to come up with something
that would cap
and
get the editors at Western
printing
excited. Yeah. I I think you've got it. Right? He...
The bit that I have that Jeffrey Blu had written in their care of the graphic novel that I read most of these in.
Just notes that, you know, he was allowed to strengthen what he thought needed punching up, but but that he focused most of his effort on the art. So and the art fantastic i even shows in my opinion to shows an evolution from finds pirate gold and
of this expressive donald duck that we see today, I think it's closer to what what he ended up with. I think he had a a great opportunity to to really work on the art on this story. So Yeah. Let's let's talk about the victory garden. Should we start there? Yeah. Absolutely.
We're gonna we're gonna go chronological.
So...
Okay. So so go ahead, warren and tell us tell us about the main action that give us a good summary
of the victory garden. Yeah. It's important to note that victory gardens were real popular at the height of World War two in America, United Kingdom,
Australia, other parts of the World, Canada.
And these were
gardens that
citizens of the countries were encouraged to grow to help the war effort. To grow their own food. But what I thought fascinating about it was it was a spirit builder. It was a Al builder. For the citizens
during this incredibly horrible war. And it was an opportunity to get out and planned community gardens in vacant lots and in backyard. And so the the story, the victory garden opens with Don is and Nephews
real real quick one and I'm sorry to interrupt. But... Oh no. That that's that's important. I appreciate you defining like, what a victory garden is. Right? Because it's presented in this story is something that every reader would would know about. Did you know what a victory garden was before you originally read this story? I did. My my mom was ten years old in nineteen forty three, and she remembers planting her victory garden in minneapolis. That's cool. I
I had no idea what a Victory garden was. I learned about it literally from this comic probably at about the age of ten years old.
Wow. And and I had to... I I can't remember if I asked someone or if I looked it up pre Google, but I I did not know because there's no real direct reference in the story. To war. Right? They just... They're just talking about we're gonna start up a victory garden. Yeah.
And it really interests me that you don't really see them in other pop culture.
Like, no. You don't really see them in other comics. You you rarely
see them referenced in movies of the time. Right. It was Al an effort that maybe was grassroots. Maybe it started. I don't know if the government encouraged it. I it probably did. I I think there was a big you know, propaganda efforts. Yeah to to get them. And and we we know that there was a lot of
Donald duck propaganda
material mate too. So I I have to think that this is probably
something that
maybe got re reworked out of some of that because I... You know, I wanted on there. Donald Ducktales really went to bat for the war effort first. He did a good friend of mine just sold his entire
Donald duck a war collection at heritage auctions, and he lives in Minneapolis. And
anyway, Donald Duck, I think the other part of this is that we're at the height of World war two, but you made the point and it was a right point that that Donald duck became sort of the the visual
symbol of the war for Disney as walt Disney entered the war effort. And I'm gonna say, whether I'm right or wrong or whatever, I'm gonna say that Donald Ducktales surpassed mickey Mouse popularity during these years in terms of, you know, in the comics in the short cartoons.
Popular
consciousness. Yeah. No arguments here. Absolutely.
That's what excited me. Probably would got me excited about collecting Donald Duck. So, yeah, the story begins with Donald and the boys wanting to plant garden. And
what I really love is that as they begin planting this victory garden in earnest, you see these three crow sitting up on the on the line and
immediately reminded me of of the crow in the movie dumb that was premiered two years earlier.
They're Sassy. They're kinda commenting the mag pies I have a feeling Carl Barks was inspired by the crow from Dumb. And as they are excited about seeing this victory garden go, they
they see food on their table, and so they
leap off the pole and start getting eating the food. Donald gets fed up with it and calls them sa and throws things at them and and it's. Yeah. Right. Yeah.
To.
Because because they're, like, sa his his war effort
Exactly.
Exactly. And who knows if the crow symbolic in any way to the to the axis I doubt it, but but said they're sort of the trouble here. Are. There are three of them. Yeah.
Yeah. So the the overarching theme here is Donald attempt to plant a victory garden. Every chance he gets gets t. And so he he tries it in his yard. He goes to a vacant
lot
in the neighborhood.
Beautifully, I just have to point out at the... What is the decor of faith and hope. I love that. And some
And then he he does everything to try to deceive these crow even dress up you know a woman's costume,
and it doesn't fool them. And so every attempt whether it's the crow or the boys playing football
on the garden he planted in the vacant lot, he just he just gives up and it... I love the ending when
the boys and conveniently go to the seed store and find invisible seeds. And they t the crow by opening the bag and there's nothing there. And
they presented to Donald and his bad while he's
hovering from his football
catastrophe.
He throws the bag against the wall in the next morning Voila.
The victory guardian is growing in his bedroom. Really fun. That that was a great synopsis
warren. That this is a really interesting
story to start with. Right? Because some... Some parts of this really do feel like it's right out of the cartoon, you know, that... Especially that element with the like, invisible seeds. That feels like something that would happened in one of the cartoons where like this is gonna be fun,
slaps stick and silly and we don't care why they're invisible. We're not gonna explain that they're just they're so small that they're they might as well. Now, there's invisible seeds, give donald the invisible seeds we like that visual of the vegetables growing out of his hardwood floors. Yeah. Well, again, you have remember Carl Barks coming off his story ideas at the animation studio. So he he he wrote this like a cartoon, and and this easily could have been a cartoon as you said. In fact, carl Barks would take because were so few panels in in these
three row comics. These three rows here. Right. And there are ten pages. He would take each panel and put them up on the wall of his home as a story board, like the motion like the movies. And he would replace them and move them around and red them. And that's how he
saw it because that's what he was trained to do at Disney.
I thought that was fabulous because it it has the feel of that cartoon. But when he turned the story and they loved it. No edits. I mean, it was you sold us mister Barks
Yeah. And and this was, like so crucial for him. Right? This was, like showing
showing that he can do this.
Mostly on his own. Now. I'm I'm... I have no doubt they trusted his story writing, but they're like we've got this existing story. Let's see what you can do with it art wise. I I like that element where we see the little crow language. This is something we don't get too too much of right where... Right.
We covered another story,
pixelated pair where we see
translated
para
here we see these crow or or mag vampires or whatever, chatter away like like, human characters.
Right? Right? Now that makes it so appealing to certainly the audiences that are reading this and gives it an element of fund. And
something else notable
in a lot of these is they feel because they're in the early forties. They're gonna feel much more out of time
compared to a lot of his later stories. Like, a lot of them will have dated elements
but this one to me, you know, you see those old time football helmets
just the very concept
of the victory garden. But but, yeah, This one feels dated in a way that
that I find very charming. What do you think of his early art His early character design here? Oh, I love it. The angry donald and the throwing donald and the the jumping and leap and and shouting donald his classic. It it it has that comic element in the very last page of him throwing the bag as seated Al the wall. Look at his pose there out of the bed. He's just everything. And then and then the last panel is a classic last shot in a cartoon. He's looking right at the camera, every character that's been in the story is in the store in the panel. And the the crow have the last word. I think it's just a beautiful ending to a funny kinda of rom. Like you said a slaps stick ramp, and that's what what they were doing here. Yeah. That... That's a good sum of that end panel. To me, it feels very abrupt. But as you as you point out, it is like a cartoon.
Ending. Awesome good good stuff. We're let's let's get off to the race is warren because we got we got a lot of story to talk about here. So, you know, we've we've just covered his very first ten page story that he was entrusted to do
that he was given the chance to adapt we're gonna transition now to the first
completely independent story that he did. No no c artist, no written source material, we're gonna get the rabbit foot which is a carl Barks joint. Drawn and and rip. And this is a story
about that old trope of the lucky rabbit foot. Right? The idea that that... It's a little luck token and a good luck charm And, you know, this is kind of before Or is going to have the nephew. You know, Barks sparks is gonna make the Nephews be what he wants them
sometimes they're
very rational.
But sometimes they're they're very child like in their
love for this kind of belief right. I I I have belief, I believe in it. It's that sort of, like, when you wish upon a star element
that Disney, I think in general really like. Right? Rewarding the the faith of kids and and pure heart. So
this is a story where the kids are gonna present to Donald
this token
that they just got from an old Indian, which is an old trope that hasn't an aged well, but it was a very, very place. If you needed something missed,
you get it from an old Indian back at that time. And Donald is gonna be presented as like the very rational foil in this one who doesn't believe in good luck. But but he is going to overdo it. Right? And it's gonna make him act in a very rash way because
the gist of this story is that Donald is gonna set out to prove
that their rabbit foot does not bring them luck he is gonna let them put themselves in all kinds of situations
that are
that are dangerous
that Cps would not approve of. But That's great.
But but every time the Nephews are gonna walk away unscathed. You know, they they're gonna cross a rick bridge
safely.
And and he's gonna... He's gonna put poo it as
able to hold up an elephant. And, of course, it's gonna collapse under his weight. They're gonna use it to to get a free ride
on a little carnival ride proving him wrong. And then ultimately this story is going to come to its conclusion
with something that will see in one of the Donald Duck cartoons and escaped gorilla.
Do you remember that? I don't know the name of the cartoon, but I do know that there was a... Yeah. There wasn't an animated cartoon that featured the gorilla. Yeah. And that then the gorilla in this that that escapes from the zoo is like terrifying.
Right? Like it's
drawn in a very very frightening way as was the one in the cartoon, and I didn't fact check this, but I think that cartoon must have come out first. I believe it did. And and remember the the whole
cinema
industry was taken over in nineteen thirty three, ten years earlier by King Kong and and you've got this fascination with Apes and and
Tarzan and movies. So I think Barks just again, just really smart, just knew what would it track the viewers and the readers. Yeah. That that's a really good point. Right? The the country, the world, the pop culture was, like Gorilla crazy.
Mighty Joe Young, son of College julian young yep. Yeah. A quick you know, Peru of Google tells me that Mountain Gorillas weren't really discovered by the outside world until nineteen o two.
Wow.
It it really struck the popular
imagination for decades there. So
so anyway, the the boys end up using this rabbit foot to avoid harm.
And then Donald will get the bright idea that he's gonna capture
subdue this gorilla with the charm of the rabbit foot the luck of the rabbit foot.
And and he ignores their warnings that's
common during their rabbit foot is actually gonna bring him bad luck
And and so
he ends we end this story with him
narrowly escaping
being
killed by the gorilla
being rescued by some firefighters.
And
and and we get a a good old corporal punishment gag at the end where he's you know, annoyed at the Nephews
threatens to
give him the licking of their lives.
And
accidentally injure himself bringing the the
strap.
He and inadvertently injure himself and ends up in the hospital and a full body cast.
Great story. I I I have to point on
a couple of things that I thought of about watching this. I'm going. Wow, this is this is like, what five years,
six years before glad Gander and and were
we're playing with that luck theme, and we're having
fun with it with the rabbit foot and the three nephews and how determined they are. And how their luck, if you think about it from the bridge and from the
the ride at the at the carnival, it all mirrors the kind of Gladstone would have. And
it must have been a successful
trope to
to have Barks continue that on with the character.
Yeah. Totally he's...
He's preoccupied by Al luck. Even early on.
I've got a remark again just how, like
terrifying the gorilla looks.
And lots of panels
that feature the gorilla close ups.
For I love the panel in this one that where he's imagining
himself
being lauded as a hero
in the newspaper says her heroic ducks the do's gorilla and the sub
is not brave, just lucky says modest hero.
I love it. And then look at his eyes in that too. I that's a great panel. On that same page is one of my most the most creative panels and that's where he's shaking the tree branch to the grill is and and Donald
word balloons match every shake of the limb. I thought that was really clever. Right. Right. It's great art in there. You know, I like how we just weren't and talked about
our specific favorite panels from that one because that's gonna be the way to do this.
Did you have any favorite that we should in retrospective have highlighted in the victory garden?
Oh, i I think the the victory garden
I I love... I love the closing panel. I think on the Victory garden on the second page is probably one of my favorite poses for donald.
As he says get out of here use sa. I think that's probably one of my favorite
panels that just shows Donald bucket is full, frustrated
pan,
dull How about you? I I I agree with you. The last one is an easy call.
The the one where the nephews peg him with the slingshot pretty great too.
Yeah. I think the the the artwork is just getting better and better here. And as he's given free independence on the Rabbit foot story.
He's
And I get I really get the sense that Carl Barks
has these stories up here and he's just wanting to tell them So I really believe and he said in one of these interviews that he never liked working on two stories at the same time. He had to finish one before he began the next one. And so I think he was one of these tireless workers.
I don't think it was a nine to five job. It was while he was sleeping while he was walking while he was whatever. He came out and he had these ideas
yeah for sure.
Alright. I think we're ready to go on to salesman donald.
So Barks, I think a third really important story in this series that we're doing is salesman donald
from Walt Disney
Number thirty nine and November forty three. I the reason is are many reasons
and yet it's sort of the anti
of the Rapid foot story. And because
we see
the boys needing donald now to go do their thing and the boys are... And and this is really about Donald bragging about being the best salesman ever. And he is
greeting the nephews who
whose whole goal here is to raise enough money to buy
express wagon, but it's probably just a a a boys wagon.
Yeah. I'm just picturing a classic radio flyer wagon, but I didn't hear go on that. Yeah. So they're out to sell egg.
And they've they've tried and don says. I can do it. I can sell thought the entire neighborhood, I'll sell out. And so kind of counter to Donald
success and luck in the past... I mean, it where he's always struggling. He really is successful in this story and he's out
selling these egg beater to the most
unlikely people in his neighborhood and there's some great art here then nephews are getting frustrated with his his kind of luck now, you know. And
and I love this because there's so many things happening in this story. You you meet some really interesting characters.
Donald persistence and his joy with his
incredible skill as a salesman as is seen on almost every page here.
Until
something's gotta happen here. And so they get it to the last egg beater and this little shack in their neighborhood where they
they need this feisty
hermit, who you don't see right away, but you hear right away, and he's kind of this gl
laughing
little prank is all I can come up with and and and that's a joy just to watch Donald try to foil him through the door.
And and then, of course, we end up
seeing him at the end of the story where Donald
eventually is successful
and sells the hermit the egg beater and the hermit just breaks down and just says, okay, I'll buy it.
But had fun doing it. I just think it's a fun...
One of my early memories a fun
story filled with tons of gag
lots of great artwork,
the introduction of quirky characters like the Hermit
started here. So yeah, that's
that's salesman donald, I think is just a lot of fun. How about you?
Warren I'm I'm so glad that you picked this one or for a couple of reasons this was your choice.
You know, I asked you to throw in another that you really cared about in this era that we're talking about this forty forty three. Right? Forty three Yeah Where's still forty three here. Yeah. Yep. And and I wanted to limit this from forty three to forty five
This is a new experience for me because I had never read this one.
Okay I think I've read a good ninety five percent of his output I've... I've missed a couple of dozen here and there
but this is my first time talking about a story on the podcast
that I I read the previous day. And this one was so much fun
and and it's so tight and I I loved the hermit
Right?
It's it's the genesis of these other goofy characters that Donald gonna try to sell to in, like, land of the tote pulls. Yep. And at least a couple of others.
Right.
It's it's the idea of trying to sell a gadget that you don't need to someone like that is is inherently funny. Right?
And then the tight setup he does were Donald Vows at the very beginning
to sell
only to people on his block gives him that limitation, right, that sets up why he's gonna be so dogg
about trying to sell Al an egg beater
to to a hermit that just hates people
doesn't cook for himself. I think it references he only eats, like, roots and herbs or something
I think he's a vegetarian. Yeah. Mh. And the... It's it's a good procedure to all of the little, like, over the top battles of will and battles of wit
that
he's gonna have Donald go into against Gladstone
against neighbor jones.
Sometimes against sc and and other people. It's it's like it feels like the the birth of all of those.
Gladstone said that because I I agree with that. And I think it's also this battle of of wit and will with his nephews. I mean, if you think about it, he's trying to up one up his nephews in here they've gone through the neighborhood. They need the money. And he goes, I'll solve them to the same people You tried. I mean, he's he's he's childish,
but he's also
so confident that he can do this. This is the the donald we see grow out of this story here. And we're still in forty three. We're still the same first year. I I love the
I love the disgust that they give him when he like flatter and flirt
Al housewife life at the very beginning of it. Yeah. You love the hard on that page too and he his eyes or lifted up and he goes well I'm afraid. I you won't be interested in the humble kitchen gadget. I'm selling like your hands are too delicate for beating eggs.
Right.
Yeah. He's so
recognizing. And and we don't really get that that's a characterization that he's gonna
he's gonna abandon. But but it's a fun little ben. Yep. Yeah. Any any other... Any anything else you wanna highlight from this this really really cool early story. I'm so glad that you picked this one. Oh, thanks. And I and i I think one of the early
examples of a repeated art technique that he used here and he may have used it a few times before was the silhouette
when when the boys and and donald are walking down the street
And and it's just a it's a great way to break up to art in the story.
The little side panels and and just a little just the visual gag are just great when the hermit shoots ink at him through the the key,
that little
very interesting panel of Donald just looking at the camera and looking straight ahead rather.
And when he says that's an insult. You don't see many panels like that. Yeah. It definitely feels like very cartoon influenced. Yep. So I think Barks had just Al blast with this one with all the gag. Definitely.
I've got... I've gotta mention how great the bit with the different doors is. Yeah. The rubber door
the layer of doors to... He has all these trick doors that can only have been designed
for this kind of battle.
Right? So and and he kind of gives it away at the end that he's like annoyed that he lost, but it's the most fun that the hermit ever had. So so he's clearly been waiting for for this kind of
test of of wits to come along. What do you think of the hermit? Oh, oh, he's hilarious.
He
his his wild over the top bush.
Barks does that with, like, herman and the hermit.
In another story.
I I didn't know there was a precursor to him. So he... He's he's awesome. He's hilarious. And I think what you like about him, what what finds him charming is that he's constantly giggling,
and he's constantly laughing as if he's just enjoying this and you didn't mind buying the egg beater because he had fun. And to me that just it just makes the story that much more pleasing and of course
that they're asking for more money at the end and Donald
again is after them this time with a with a branch
you liked it. Yeah. And and you know, made me think of how much the early in mid twentieth century did this thing too where, like, kids
Kids got on the hook for these kind of like low grade salesman jobs all the time. Right? Looking through the old Dow and gold key
comics, there all these schemes to get kids to sell seeds
and
and and other stuff for prizes and they inevitably
resulted in parents having to buy their stock off them.
That's right. Alright. So I'm rolling along,
we are at
my favorite of of the bunch of them,
which is the Ducktales the iron pants.
And
this is such a highlight
to me of of his early
era comics.
I read most of these stories in glad tones
comp their
their album that collected a bunch of them. And they gave this one the title. It's called the Ducktales the Iron pants.
They they put Barks
great oil is this an oil or Lit.
It it was an oil first then became a lit though. I have it. I have the small though. It's a smaller lit. It's just great with the nephew torch donald. Oh, yeah.
Just a wonderful
image, a wonderful painting
of donald attacking the boys snow
in full suit of armor.
He doesn't get to do a lot of these more gag based
oils, you know, a lot of them are more like the adventure or the kind of slice of life Ducktales
stories.
I can only think of like this true officer Donald.
Sure there's a couple others. But this one kinda stands apart. This is such a great great painting. And but anyway, the story is is awesome. This is one of the best Donald versus the nephews,
ten pager.
I I think ever.
Despite being from this very, very early period.
Right?
It has the nephews playing outside, having some Good old fashioned wholesome snow.
Donald
decides to walk by them. He's clearly goa them. He's clearly setting them up
to
get in in this kind of battle with them because he he's gonna engage in that that trope, which
doesn't exist any longer. But I think the idea in the
the middle of the twentieth century was that a man wearing a top hat was just begging to have it knocked off by a snowball.
So so Donald ins this big
snow war with the nephews by walking by them in a top hat and he's sabotage it. He's a fixed it with an elastic band and he's stationed a big snowball ball,
which he uses to cave in the trench that they're in
where did that... Did that bit remind you on comfortably of the Trench warfare from just a couple
years a couple decades or or before this?
I didn't see that. That's an interesting take on it, though with the boys in the trench and getting
bombed if you will. But yeah. I mean, we're we're only twenty years away from World War one and... I only thought about it this time.
Okay. But... But the this has. And the f used to decide they have to answer back. So they're gonna build this cool snow.
And when Donald comes back, trying the same trick you know, right,
which he should know better.
They escalate things by breaking an egg in his top hat, which which sets him off and he invades their snow.
But but they had all this time to prepare now. And so
they are hitting him with all these
great snow trips
that really fired my imagination Al as a kid. You know, I see this little snowball ga gun that they're attacking him with or this little this little rico bit or what do what do you call the little weapon that they use That's some
two heavy objects t to Al align. There's a name. I can't i know. I don't know what that is. Yeah. We're finding errors. But, you know, they they wrap him with a couple of snowball around a line and they they get him good.
And they they realized that they may have overs shot. Right? Because he heads into his workshop with a vengeance.
And we've got these
we've got these, like actions where the nephews are
preparing their defenses
s up their snow.
And and Donald is doing some unseen escalating. And when he finally emerges,
it is
such an amazing panel warren.
He is wearing
a suit of armor that he's black smoothed up in his workshop. It it it's
suited for a Ducktales it's got his bill. He's got... It's... you know, it fits his bill. He's holding a sword.
And he he comes out ready to invade
invade them.
And and they're just trying every trick that they've got. To repel him, but because he's armored.
They they can't stop him and they they start to throw tools and rocks at him and eventually he's able to
approach their wall and
slice a
and and slice square out of it with this sword. And I love the
word balloon where he is just going so over the top threatening yeah.
He calls out.
Nothing can save you from me. I am invincible.
I am doom itself.
This one is a masterpiece.
They finally
resort to a little bit of cartoon logic where they they've got this flame through.
Cook.
A trio of brothers with with the flames hour yes
that they've used to kind of melt and then
solidify the walls of their fort. They get one of them gets the bright idea to burrow and the snow behind Donald and ultimately heats him heats his suit of armor up,
you know, and and do they do manage to heat it up enough to repel him?
And and it concludes
with Donald
tending to his wounds on a large block of ice
as the ne fuse are getting ready to hole up for the winter, and they've they've have turned the armor into
a radiator
s and are roasting
roasting wiener.
Warren this is such a great bit of of wish fulfillment and and
kid empowerment and Donald versus the Nephews
slaps stick violence
i I don't mean to i I've... I'm big footing here. I'm talking too much about this one. But but this this is like the story that I was like, oh i I gotta talk about some of these classic ones because I don't wanna miss talking about the Ducktales the iron pants. Well, I like this story a lot, and and thank you for
for your passion about it. I remember this one as well. Not as well as as salesman donald, but I I I do have the lit graph
that to me just makes me laugh every time I walk by it in my room and look at it. And just I just love it. You said it it... It's classic donald versus an Nephews.
What I really like what Barks is doing here is that first
reveal of the Ducktales.
It it's a laugh out loud panel. I mean, and the duck in the armor says very little. He just keeps storming the castle and and but... There's a couple of Huey, elements I love
he not only fashioned this out of the Gladstone
company where he got the armor from.
But he put a little plume on his head.
Armor. I mean this he went over the top, I mean, it's but great art, great characterization
invent of, but that those panels when he is introduced with the sn,
all the way through to that declaration
of I am doing itself. He doesn't say much Al all, I think he just says one little line is he's coming out he goes whole var
think of the thy buff
can stop me now.
That's what cracked me up so much about this story. Yeah. Yeah. Well said. And and you're right about that awesome touch where you can see the logo of the stove company
on that he he's, like, turned in a boiler or something into it. Al little little foreshadowing there too to the last panel.
Right. And and you're right. He's just like this this unstoppable, like, sort of juggernaut or not men
slowly men
his way towards them. Yeah. Yeah. This one's a ton of fun. It looks like we are ready to talk about our last one. So I'm I'm glad to close out this one by talking about Mad Chemist.
I think this one is really
really interesting and really fun. And I remember reading about it in
a
issue that Glad put out where they paired it with the sunken yacht because they both had like these little elements
where the...
There was a little bit of, like, real life that kind bleed it and bled into it. So, you know, I'll let I'll let you summarize the story here and then I'll kinda talk about the little feature that they'd published in that comic on it. Yeah. Yeah. And again,
the this particular one Barks, I believe comes from Walt Disney comics and stories number forty four. Yeah. That's the one. And what I like about this story,
and it again, it's just a newer one to me, but when I read it,
I just love the way again, the Nephews and Donald playoff each other. Anyway, we see the nephews and their they're playing in their
their chemistry set and and donald is really interested in what they're doing
and says, hey ought he he take some of the chemicals and he's says you ought to just add this and they really warn him. They'll be careful. Something horrible could happen a good blow up and he goes
fu.
And so he pours is it in the cylinder bowl that the chemicals are bubbling in flies up in the air hits down on the head, and all of a sudden Battle has this incredible
transformation
into a brilliant chemist. He he looks the same. He's walking kind of days. He's got a huge
bump on his head.
But he starts talking very in very scientific kind of funny terms. And he
says we've got to
kinda taking me seriously here. I'm gonna con talk something
And he says I'm gonna be the mighty is chemist in the universe.
So he creates this
con that he proudly announces as Duck might Yeah. Doc is Al explosive chemical that he
has has developed, but it's dangerous. So we have to drive far away from Duck to experiment with it. So the boys say well we just do it here in the backyard. No. No Too dangerous, so they go out and but they get outside of Duck and they
ideally over a cliff and battle begins dropping these
bottles.
Of Ducktales mite over this
one thousand foot high cliff and says be careful it'll explode. While he does this over and over again at different sizes and nothing happens.
So he goes down to the bottom lights match looks in there, and then it just blows up. But instead of being hurt, he's proud that he has
created this incredible potion.
And so
they go back off and they pour a little bit of this in the car for gas and it speeds down the road.
They all say good goodbye cruel world, which is just fun. So after they're they're splash in the water from the car that with the with the Ducktales in it goes into the water. Donald is now absolutely
convinced that he can send a rocket to the moon. The boys get concerned and they go see a doctor called you doctor You quirk, a brain expert
and he basically
explains to the doctor that they're worried that this
Ducktales might is going to cause more problems
and that he's built a rocket ship to fly to the moon. So the doctor just basically gets up. And said so what he can't harm any anything there. So they go home, donald got the rocket ship built. So the boys show up and Donald was already in his rocket. And he's ready to take off and he
he roar off the the boys tri lasso him to stay put, but he goes all the way of the space. He goes all the way and he's extremely startled now he goes around the moon and he heads right back to Earth and he crashes
believe it or not in his own backyard. And when he is told that he has done this incredible achievement, he doesn't believe it. I think his his his little Amnesia or his literally
personality shift to the man the Mad chemist comes back around, and he says, I can't believe it went around the moon. And everybody's proud of this accomplishment and they asking him if he could mix up some more duck might. And now it doesn't even know what Ducktales is. Right. So
that's that's the kind of the end of the story either. Yeah. It's a a perfect... One one of those
first sort of etch sketch stories
where there's something
that's, like, really over the top, he literally
leaves Earth
and then Barks is gonna have to kind of reset it back to the status quo. I really like this one. This one stood out to me because it feels like the art... It's it's still very early. But the art feels like it's really starting to mature
by now in this.
Yeah. I agree. Race to moon. I mean, there's other stories that come later that pick up on this great early artwork. Yeah. And this one, you know, it it's kind of evo of the fire bug,
which is another
kind of early not quite as early I think, but her early ish favorite of mine where he gets some kind of
insult to the head that changes his personality.
But I really like the look that he's given when when he's kind of
in this other guys as the mad chemist.
This one's really cool to that sort of escalation of the action
where they're driving out to
ever increasing vacant lots
until they just get get out deep into the wilderness
to to to blow up his weapon. And it's hard not to think for me about the Manhattan project.
Right? This one feels like such an allegory
because
What are we in with this? One is this nineteen forty four?
Where are we in in relationship with
so this
came out in May of nineteen forty four, that's the date on wikipedia. And
the
atom bomb mind the giveaway. Well,
the the real one,
fat
that that was detonated in forty five.
So you're.
But everyone, like, this was something that everyone
kind of knew was going on but.
There was clearly this race, Right, going on. No one...
Civilians didn't know the specific of it. But they had an idea that both sides were working on these
these super weapons. So this was on everyone's mind.
And and there's this like really
kind of frightening
undertone with this one. I Well no question about it. Yes. Some evil undertone. I mean Oppenheimer was worked on the atom bottom for us. Is that correct? And yes.
Yes. Exactly.
And this one has also this really interesting, like,
sort of true life
component of it.
I don't fully
understand it, but
apparently,
some of the chemistry work that Barks depicted at the beginning of this,
actually was like, pretty realistic
and and was was ahead of it time. You can find a couple of articles online about this,
kind of under the the heading of Did donald Duck accidentally use meth and a comic before it was discovered, the the studio got this article from these readers these scientists who were also big fans.
Of the dot comics that we're...
I'll just read read this
verbatim yeah.
They got this
letter from a doctorate from Joseph b Lambert of the California institute of Technology.
He he's pointing out a reference in a technical article called the spin states of carb.
And he says that despite the recent extensive interest in meth chemistry much additional study is required. Among the experiments which have not to our knowledge been carried out Al yet. Is one of a most intriguing nature suggested in the literature of no less than nineteen years ago, and the footnote in that technical paper directed readers to issue forty four of walt Disney's comics and stories.
And and he he goes on to say that Donald referenced to c
two
in panel two point one was years ahead of its time
as the existence of that elusive chemical
had not been that chemical in media had not been proven
as of nineteen forty four. This is like that very right academic
language that that scientists or followers use when they're kind of being a little bit on the nose a little bit funny. The inclusion of this footage in a quite scholar article,
stemmed from the discovery that doctor. Gasp Barks and i share a mutual and independently Gladstone standing esteem for the adventures of Donald Duck,
It was love it. It was doctor Gasp who rediscovered this early mention of Carb.
So
there's there's a lot of reasons to appreciate this one.
I think it's... I do think it's one of the best of the early stories.
But...
But I also think that that that little technical
detail
merits highlighting here Oh, that... That's great. That thank you for sharing that. I was unaware of that. But it it shows that Donald Ducktales popularity is spread across
so many different
generations and different different professions. Right? And I also like the notion that that we're not the only
prone men here who still like duck comics. Right? This this was several decades ago and these these various esteem scientists
So I I like that. Any any other comments on this one, the Mad chemist warren? Well, again, it was a newer story for me
looking at it
in the issue that I have.
I'm just... I'm taken by the artwork and how much more
art is experimenting with
outside of this world and looking at the moon, but the moon might look like just so many great little little gag. Yeah. I'm gonna have to dig into this one a little bit more and... Yeah. This one's a lot of fun. So
warren, I I wanna s size just a little bit. We can kinda wrap things up by by talking about by kinda reflecting on this period,
I love going back and looking at these. I still think they're Barks in his most formative
time. I mean, I mean, he's he's be coming the storyteller and artist that he...
He's he's good. He's not great yet. But he's he's good and he knows it. And
again, I just think it's wonderful. How much freedom the editors gave him to do these. Yeah, He's really getting some great confidence from doing these. And like it was kind of it was really unique what he got to do. Right? Like the the Disney comics,
the Ducktales stories that he was doing about. Right? Like I don't think there were other creators
around this time who are
being given this opportunity. Am I am I right for the comics?
Yeah. Yeah. Oh, yeah. No. He was it. That was it at the time. I I think there we had the different cover artists. Often they
competitors.
Up until issue number thirty one, the victory garden. They were reprint newspaper
comic strips and they ran them ran out. They they said we're done. We have to do something else and that that desperation to find new content
for this Walt Disney comics and stories format this monthly format
This was a great career starter for for Carl Marx,
because they couldn't reprint any more newspaper strips. He he really was
Disney comics
for for a long time. I mean we had those newspapers for twenty three year career. Yeah.
We had those newspaper classics
We have the great Got for and Mickey mouse comics that'll be collected over and over the the like Talia
Mh trips and and others the art Taliaferro the the comic strip is right.
Right. He kept walt Disney's comics and stories going,
he set the template.
The the series, he was writing them
monthly for for so long that it's safe to say that, like, the the comics line wouldn't have likely gone on and become as enduring without him.
Let alone the Donald Ducktales
line, you know, that's gonna get spun off. And then uncle Scrooge
Right? That's gonna become his his own
his own... It might as well have been called Carl Barks uncle Scrooge.
Because it wasn't a monthly title at first. No.
Not to begin with and all the four color long form stories. I mean, we know that the greek fifth the Victory garden came in early forty three shortly after finds pirate gold give him his break But when did the mum ring the next long form story? When was that published? That that was September of forty three. So he gets to do about a half dozen
of the
of the ten pager
before he gets to do. That that one, of course is very significant as his first
independent
full length adventure story. Right. So Disney had him doing the full length stories to to fall into the four color format.
To do those. He did these monthly.
Know he's very productive. He was a busy artist and the busy writer to be given all the freedom
to tell all of these stories that he wanted to tell is a great benefit for the readers and for for you and me. You even if he himself didn't feel
as free sometimes to tell some of the stories that he liked. We we didn't cover
lifeguard days is in this early period. And that's the one where he was forced to to reduce the bo of a of a duck bathing beauty character. One of his early
bout of of being censored.
We didn't that of here. It it's a it's a duck. So it's Al duck. It's a dock with b size pretty it's a little bit disturbing, but ultimately, he did have to, like, flatten
reduce her her chest to get past the editors.
We didn't get Al about neighbor, good neighbors. Right? We've got our first iteration of, like, neighbor Jump and he he uses a couple different versions of neighbor jones. Mh. So the... These were never like as a kid
I didn't like these as much
because they felt very primitive. I didn't really have an
appreciation
of his
his career arc. And then also, you know, I didn't read them in that kind of order or anything naturally. I I I read a bunch of these for the first time in the glad graphic novel, which was number twenty seven in that series
So, you know, I didn't inherently appreciate it. I I figured out, oh these are his first stories. That's interesting. But they weren't ones that I went back too. I probably only read the duck in the iron pants
two or three dozen times
compared to some of the stories that I read.
Scores of times,
which is to say, I do... I do love these stories, but,
you know, more as an appreciation of what they say about. Where he was in his career at the time.
Right? I do wanna mention
where
these stories kind of fall as far as the community.
Right? So I I love to check them out on Ducktales.
And I'm gonna
I'm gonna talk about them. Let's talk about them in order of lowest first.
So So the victory garden. Right? That this one clocks in pretty low. This one has a six point nine
out of ten
which puts it as
number
thirty seven
thousand
and some out of the forty one thousand
some stories very low for a Barks story. And and obviously it wasn't written by by him. In fact, I I forgot to mention this, we don't know who wrote it. Like we don't know We know that that was handed over to him by the editor, but we don't know he scripted it. Correct. Written by anonymous studio
basically.
Or anonymous publishing hack. Like it's it's a fine story, but it's it's very thread there. But that's interesting to me. That seems a little bit unfair when you consider
you how, how significant of a story. But but taken as its own story. Yeah. It's it's not the best. Yeah. And then
next, the the next highest one is the Rabbit split. Which jumps up quite Al bit. So we've got a seven point one out of ten, good for
one thousand
seven hundred and forty fourth out of all forty one at some thousand that did jump up quite a bit just that six point nine to seven point one, it leaked up quite a bit. Right. That was his first full original story. So Exactly. Clearly, it landed much better in in the community as as a
purely Carl Barks
story. Yeah. Good to know. And then
salesman Donald is next. That gets to seven point two out of ten. And it's it's into the top thousand. It's ranked nine hundred and seventeen
out of forty one something.
And then we've got the mad chemist, that one ranks quite highly for
an old one It's seven point five out of ten. Good for three hundred and twenty six. I do think that one might get a little bit inflation just because of the, like,
this the ones that kind of
bleed out into the pop culture, people remember them better. So I think they've vote on hire. But but I do think it's a very good old story. And and then the Ducktales the iron pants is the clear winner
Al ranger.
Two hundred and ninety one out of forty one thousand, some
good for seven point five again out of ten.
I would agree with that one being probably the top story in terms of story. And and and I I I might personally I might swap the index ratings for
salesman donald and the Mad chemist. I I wasn't as crazy by the mad chemist. But again, you're right. I think it captured the imagination of the world at that time and That's that's very fair. I am... I I was really impressed by how good that sales donald was. I I enjoyed that one Al lot. I was blind. To could read that from the hours. That's I think I think of my favorite of all of them today. Nice. And and I just I love the duck in iron pants.
Oh, yeah. So much. I I think he's just you can you can really feel... I think he's doing what really entertained him in that one because it's it's so over the top. Alright. Well, this was fine. Yeah. So much.
I agree. This was great more and this this this is a lot of fun. It's it's fun to take this meet complimentary group of stories from the same era,
get to cover them. I'm I'm not planning to cover any more of the old ones. So this this is gonna be our stand in for all of these.
Thank you so much for for taking the time to appreciate these early Barks.
Always great to revisit these stories.
I love it and looking forward to our next opportunity. Awesome. I I'd love to hear what listeners think about, you know, their their own preference for these stories or if there's one that they really think that we should have covered
in this early period. Feel free to reach out at Barks remarks at g dot com or on the Barks remarks, Facebook page,
and until next time.