We have
Hello, and welcome to Barks Remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comic of all time. This episode is a ten page podcast, all about one of his short stories. Get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Welcome, come back to Barks remarks, I'm mark Sever,
a Grown man who enjoys dot com.
And we're back with another
Donald jobs themed
episode. We're gonna talk about the brittle mastery
jobs this time, and I'll talk a little bit about what those are, but first, I wanted to
introduce my guest host this time. I'm gonna mention their names and and just as I did for our previous jobs episode, I will ask them to mention their most Donald Duck Es.
So we've got Al H
and Ruben Os,
Mi miguel, why don't you go first?
Hello? My name is Michael H. I am a young man from Norway. We're growing up loving on the comments.
The problem was done there
I Severino had was I was an extra movie sets for
series,
and then I was set to play jumper around like a gorilla and more
repeatedly.
From gag
episode where we're me and a bunch of other kids have the messed up the the name of the school on the side. That's a good one. I can I can definitely
pitch sure that being being something donald would go through? How about you, Ruben? Yeah. Hey. I'm Ruben.
Twenty one year old, the norwegian.
Man boy.
I enjoys mail dot com of course. Group and
for works and jobs that I've done, I've come from a family of sawmill workers, so I believe parks could've have made a lot of times actions
is down that working and and dangerous situations, of course. Yeah.
I've also worked Al a pretty fancy
cafe
which I believe the loa would have screwed up pretty nice... Yeah. Definitely a lot of good comedic potential there. Well, thank you both for joining me Ruben, this is your your first time back. You join me for another of the B Mastery stories. We got to cover the master rain maker And Mi miguel, this is your your first time joining us, and I I really appreciate
both of you being on. I really like having that scanned
perspective. Right? You guys are both from Norway.
So you get to...
Get to share a little bit about what it's like to be Norwegian fans.
So the Brittle Mass
stories. I'm I'm I'm using
the
the title of a collection
that Gladstone did way back. In the late eighties, I think. There there's a collection of several of these stories and and it's a really great description of this very, like, Carl Barks
story type that he did
about a half a dozen or so times.
Right? They they're... They really stand out. They're very funny. And I I think they're one of the most, like Carl Barks things that he ever did. Basically, the deal is.
Donald has a job at the very beginning of the story. Right. We don't see him get the job. We we always just jump right into it, and he's really good at it. It's usually something
obscure
were a little bit weird.
And as the master would suggest, you know, master part of the title would suggest. He's very good at it. And we see him during the course of these stories, getting celebrated
by people
for for being a master
generally,
and then, of course, because he's Donald Inducks, something is gonna go disastrous
wrong. So that that... That's kind of it in a nutshell. Right? And and so in in this collection,
that I'm holding up,
Michele and Ruben, you can see it here. This one collects five of the stories And and they are as
again, mentioned, master rain maker is widely accepted I think is the best of these stories. We covered that one. That was a lot of fun. But I it's... I believe it's actually the first one isn't it using this for what? It is Yeah. That one was back in nineteen fifty three. You're right.
Very highly rated. It usually... If you look it up on the index, it's it's roughly, like, top ten or just outside of the top ten of his, like, best rated ten pager.
And then we've got
our featured story today, the one that's gonna get kind of the the majority of our focus is the master record. I think the three of us here probably
agree that it is the the next best of them. What do you guys think? Are we in agreement that Rain maker is the best of them? Yeah.
But the master record is certainly completed the story I thing think about this the second right after the rain maker when I think about this zone mastery
stories. Yeah. The rain maker one is. Absolutely
superb to me when my Al time favorite ten pages of Barks, actually when my favorites stories of Al time of uploads. Yeah. It's awesome.
And the thing that rain maker and rec, I think have in common is that they both have like, this iconic
Donald has a relationship with his vehicle.
Right? He's he's Al. He he's got a crop dusting plain in the rain maker.
And he's got a wrecking ball and the wrapper. And so those just make for some really
iconic
images.
But we've also got
the master glass
was featured in this collection where he's gonna be a glass maker. We've got one called the mass
remover or he's like a moving specialist.
And then this one, this collection also included the the only one that's not called master is
spare that hair, which could've have been called the master Barber if
if they want it. I would argue
that maybe it doesn't fit perfectly
just because, like, he doesn't have to flee the country at the end.
But we can we can get into it after after we talk about what what does and doesn't kinda of fit that formula me. I believe I could mention that, I believe in the norwegian
grocery stores and stores at this point. There actually is a collection that's
collects all of these or of them. But a handful of these job stories and b
in original data editions, of course. That's awesome.
Looks like if finally in collection for children to read them get into these stories. Yeah. Because they're made in this small smaller size so it's easier to hold for kids. Nice.
Yeah. This is the second week in a row where on Barks remarks where we're talking about Donald jobs just because it's such a great, you know, it's it's so relatable that... John Donald had so many different jobs and Barks has mind a lot of humor over the years, out of Donald jobs. This is like it own special category that I I just I love these so much. I think they're... I think they're hilarious.
So you guys, let's do this. Let's launch in to
talking about the master record, which is again gonna be our our focused our main story here today.
I'll open up with a little bit of detail about the story This one is
most of these are a little bit later than the ones that I've been getting to focus on, like the main adventure episodes.
Master record is dated September of nineteen sixty two and wasn't published until Al Disney Comments and stories two hundred and sixty
four. It is the second highest rated out of all of these
mastery
stories. So,
I guess, to give us our kind of benchmark, mass or rain maker if you look at it on Inducks. That gets a seven point five rating, which is good for number two hundred and fifty out of all, like, forty one forty two thousand
stories rated on end up. So that that's really high. This one is pretty pretty high as well. It's a seven point four.
Good for number four hundred and fifteen. I think I calculated at some point either seven point one or seven point two is like median for Barks stories. So that this is a well
regarded one. And
If you're a little kid reading this just the idea of donald with a wrecking ball, I think is is awesome.
But this one has a really great opening.
It's it's it's very over the top. It's very
It's got a very silly tone because we see Donald
starting his morning routine. And
and and it has the narrator box in English it says books are written about the might of men who build houses.
But consider the night of those who wreck them. And and Donald is just
he is getting out of bed and he's in this like, strong man pose,
and every
element
in the... Every visual on the page is supposed to clue us in to the fact that he is a tough guy who is focused on
wrecking
buildings,
There are some wonderful
site gag
and and the nephews user as they often are in these stories are very supportive of him.
They're essentially his assistance.
And in this case, they're telling him about the order that's just come in
that says the school board wants him direct the old duck High school. They're getting him a stack of of pancakes a economically tall stack of pancakes
for him to get ready. And you guys there's just such a huge number of great site gag
on this page. Ruben,
are there any favorite site gag of yours that stand out? Oh, I will you at just
let's plan first flash panel there has so many like it's
underneath it does not a matter thermostat It's playing phone hard blank, and underneath those planks, you can see odd rocks. So it's... That's it that petra is betty is just laying on planks and rocks. As well as
which is like an abrasive
cleaning thing that's very I know. And I just love... I love his breakfast
and I know just how we looks at this page and those also in the next page. Well, I've written them notes here. Human themed machine because the first panel is like
sn, like just the mechanical steam thingy. It's just is it's like iron
mechanical
big iron man. That even though it's just so small and a time man Huey, breaks through everything. It's just so mad and just love Al the bullshit. What... And you said it even though he's so small. Right? I think I think that's part of the comedy here. Donald Duck is kind of a shrimp in here. What do you think Make miguel, anything stand out to you on this page? Yeah. I really love the the titles of the books. And special panel. No really low Barks. Often have these little gadgets with book titles.
Yeah.
What what are those titles in in your
translation? I'm curious about that. Well, the first book is called with the four of Troy. And the second one is the distraction of Cargo and the full of rome.
Right. So they're all these plays on cities that have fallen And of course, the fall of Rome is a real
scholar work, but but then they he continues it. And it's a little
what's the word... It's a liter in English because it's the crushing of cart and the top wing of Troy.
Oh, I I love the breakfast serial that they serve him.
It's it's got whole iron wood nuts fortified with zinc copper calcium, limestone
brass and ball bear.
He's just
sn the whole way. I don't know if it translates similarly and yours. Well, yeah, it's pretty much the same thing to make difference
it's marvelous. I love it. Yeah. Yeah. Because we we have a very new
translation from around two thousand and five look this basically a direct translation of the regional
Excellent.
And
every... This this is an incredibly strong opening the page. I love this one. Yeah. I just wanna make mention that in the
second last panel on this page, I love how the is, like, just pushing those pancakes down this throat. I believe it's is one, two, three, four,
six or seven pancakes. He had a look for. Just pushing down with those is throat, and it's chewing and jumping
It's just a machine. He's not mechanical, man. Yeah. He is an Al
of tough in this one. Yeah. Also
I really like what you've been said about don't being such a small guy. Barks
is really good of showing the dx as small. Small people with the in this big world. Right. He gets a lot of comedy from that.
So very strong opener on the second page, you know, the Nephews are presenting him with his work
uniform, which is an iron hat and mailed god bless. And
just to emphasize his tough he kinda punches
the post of his mailbox
and
and breaks away some of that. And and we transition
to the the old cool house where
people from the school board are presenting it. And Donald is
seated in his wrecking ball. And and Barks is gonna really
get a lot of mileage out of, like, ant
this wrecking ball, it's very funny. There... He's like an extension of it in this story. And he's studying it. And we we kinda learn what makes him a special a master wreck is that he has this really deaf touch. Where he winds up with the wrecking ball and
slams it into this cool.
And
Michele tell us what happens with that with the the windows there. Every will loop also separately.
Into meat, little stable. Right. Yeah. It's awesome.
It's really typical goldberg Barks great humor. Just so Yeah. It's really showcase
background from from the story board department. Yeah. Really automated. Yeah. Yeah you get a great sense of motion with this.
And and so on to the next page, you know, he continues to give it this treatment. He continues to, like, he soften up the building with... As he says a pump pump here and a sump pump there.
And
ruben... What... How does he like finish off the racking of of this school house? Well, we talked about personal
personalization, the
machine in the working goal. And after the bail building is just soft but looks like, almost looks like some jelly or just some... Yeah. It looks tough up. It it can't be described. Described And the neck on the next panel, the
rag ball working machine whatever whichever I wanna I call it, is standing on it sticker.
Yeah.
I just love that.
Just to get little tap on the top of the chimney made. And of course, I I don't believe this I... I cannot not see how this work would work button and life even in this car too. But all the materials, everything that building is made enough is sorted out laid in files. It's just perfect. This is this
material can just read stacked into a trailer and marie reused anywhere else. That's right. Yeah. I... My wife is oracle text and she studies like green building. I have a feeling this would get the the lead
certification.
It as you said, it's a it's a real bit of cartoon logic. It's very funny. It's very imaginative.
And and at the end of the page,
Donald is taking about to an appreciative audience, and this is a a big theme that runs through these a lot. Right? He likes to play the proud.
Yeah.
Boy. So that... That's that's our first one. Right? In in these stories, we generally get to see Donald have two really good
successes.
That's all Barks needs to show us to demonstrate. We know he's
already good at what he does. The next order
for his services
is to tear down the old
accordion factory.
Which is a steel building and donald notes that steel buildings
require special treatment
I really like how an English Barks kinda words this. It's it's not necessarily poetic, but it's very killing. He says most necessary
is some strong bracing at one end. And then Mikhail, do you wanna tell us what is the next most necessary
thing. Well, the only use is breaking ball machine to pick up some razors
before it then take the great
is it four ton heavy
iron ball and then mac
factory to a great little c. Their melody and it all wraps together like
a cord.
To the to a makes a little melody in
see notes. I love this visual so much you guys. This is so funny.
It's it's again very cartoon logic. It's totally ridiculous.
But it it cracks me up. Right. Absolutely more less. It's my favorite emissions of the and this story. And the fact that it is the accordion factory, and it's like this steel building that has like like factory
roof it's like p because that's angles
right. And repeated the
system almost, like
or something Yeah. Exactly.
When
pushes it together, It works just like Al recording it's it's like of course. Yeah. It's it's excellent.
And and so now we get the third
assignment. Right? This is the one where things generally go wrong. And
he... The nephews are commenting how his jobs keep getting bigger as famous spreading, and he is approached by the mayor. To clear the site for duck
news sea seaside Barks.
And on the way, Donald asks, are there many buildings on the site to be demolished?
And the mayor kind of sneak clearly says, no. Just just one or
structure. And that structure is old for Inducks.
And and we get this visual of this just massive
stone for.
What do they call it in your guys? Just florida.
Okay. We old four Ducktales. Right? And domino's
is is not a common word in English, but it just means
completely sturdy and tough. And again, it's it's just over the top how difficult this gonna be and donald has this great days pose like he's bitten off more than he can chew. Yeah. I just think Was should've have mentioned that it looks
strangely few futuristic. It looks really modern. It looks like it like some for the building. Yeah. And I don't see why Barks would
make that choice. I think search buildings for more common than we I think.
Yeah. Yeah. I mean, I read this as, like, I mean, growing eye up in
outside San Francisco, there was an old fork that my dad would take me to to visit sometimes that was like
just mass of, you know, concrete
structure,
kinda like this. But you're right. It almost looks like it belongs on the coast of the mediterranean or something to me. I don't know the style. Doesn't doesn't look very for dot burn. But it it needs to look utterly
massive and then... Yeah.
And absolutely looks like one big of something. Like, it's the same material and there's no screws and anything thing, it's like this is one big piece right. Right. It might as well be the rock of gibraltar.
So Donald gears
smash into it with designer ball, the nephews user of serving, and they're like, well, it's gonna take more of a wall than that.
And and so on to the next page, you know, Donald gives it a really good wind up. He says in English. I'll I'll give it the olympic ham hammer shoes, I think is how you pronounced that. I think it's like something to do with the hammer throat from the olympics.
And be comments that the wall is ten feet thick and asks them if he cracked it just a little bit, but no in fact, his four ton iron ball has
cr.
So he's gonna get
a ten ton ball and and we transitioned to him at it for hours
and hours.
And the nephews user are tired and they... They're noting that it
it sounds like the iron ball is lost its ping. Maybe the fort softened up a little bit. And Donald asked them. How's it going? I... I'm so tired. I can't see to the end of the boom.
You wanna...
Miguel, do you wanna tell us how it's going for him? Yeah. No. Not going very well for a portal. It's for ton Iron ball. Al
oh, this is the ten ton iron board. Yeah.
Been down to this tiny tiny Al little marble. You're hanging there That's right. In in in the original, they they comment that it's it's worn down to the size of a p. It's absolutely with amazing. How it's worn down and it's not even a Scrooge in the
for Right. Yeah. This this a really... Go ahead we miguel. Yeah.
No also just want to point out the great visual rule at the beginning of the page when mcdonald's wrecking machine winds up like a baseball player.
Just gives us the subs.
It's
that's a good catch because that's one of my favorite panels. That's one of the one of the best that's a great great piece of work.
And and so, you know, we're on the next page, we're really concerned that Donald is gonna fail here
because he he hasn't managed to do anything. But he approaches and he listens for a week spots with his quote expert years, and we see him kinda home in on it, and he explains the nephews that his expert Barks.
Say that his pounding is loosened Al earth fault under the fort. So he directs them to bring me a p shooter and what's left of the ball.
And and we get this awesome
a ridiculous
sequence where he uses the p shooter to fire the ball at the floor, and the whole thing
slides off the cliff into the c and, again, you get some great applause. Thoughts
this is just great because Barks here makes us worry. The tone is gonna fail. And then you don't. It's
grow to even bigger proportions. And I just noticed
just got covered on the Barks here, you see the second panel on this page and then look at his hands, that doesn't look very function to me digit... Or It may... Maybe they do, but it they look kinda too dimensional. I don't like to look like I hands from that. Yeah. You're right. That that that is not the best piece.
Of
Barks are. That that that one looks like a little quickly dry And also the eyes aren't completely
point to at the same direction.
I wonder what happened here. Yeah. Well, he's got quite the face.
Honestly
so usually, the third one is where things go go wrong. But he keeps this one going on a little bit longer than usual, but it is gonna be the investigation for for his downfall.
So Donald is basking in the
of Duck. He's he's even got a a parade
everyone Loves Donald it's a little bit over the top.
The Nephews
comment, he's popular. He hasn't an enemy in the world. But we do see that Donald does
have an enemy. It's a little nat, and the narrator box tells us that the Matt's home was destroyed when Donald south the floor into the sea. And Donald is given another assignment by the nephews while he's fend off and trying to swat at that nat. And he verbal
the address of his new assignment
which is seven sixty
eight
Plus avenue, and he arrives at the top brass club, a pretty fancy,
it was described as a s, but it... But it looks
very fancy. What are they call it in in your guys? They're simply naming it
feed the recruitment vest, which means yeah point the find
what's Yeah. The the pretty ones club located in on the west side. Right on Any thoughts? Call is using
reusing
gag from no such.
Yeah.
Yeah. That's right. Because because this nat spoiler is is going to be his downfall. Right? It is...
It is gonna cause him to mix up the address, which as you mentioned is is what happens
in no such environment.
He he he felt free to reuse all sorts of elements of his stories as hundreds of stories.
And and we get this fun sequence next
where he's giving the the quote shaq, his usual softening treatment and we see that the there are people
inside the club and we get some pretty comedic
moments of them dealing.
Ruben, what's your... What what what do you like on the inside? Well, what we say is we see a update figure. I believe it's the mayor that by way, I love saying the big we had a dog earlier, but I love saying the big later. He's said a bathtub, and the wool behind them is starting and shrinking, and it doesn't like it. Of course, the auto on the shelves, the sculptures they're falling down, the sn are running to to save it, but I cannot they fall to to the ground break. And of course, I love the next one.
Where there's just women man standing up from his cherry reading a book. And him is there, I
really looking news.
It is. It is a pretty silly looking. Yeah love it. I love it. And and he's just... Well, what is Al this nonsense, I believe is saying something like that.
Oh the next panel. I Can't even Scrooge it. Take it... Oh, yeah. How it falls off the the wall and and thugs. It's it's a pretty funny sound effect in English this is food. Mh. And and so, you know, they're all freaked out. They they hide in the sellers thinking the martian are invading or something.
And and so Donald delivers the the finishing blow, the K rock.
And knocks it right off the foundation. And and on the next page,
he
realizes
his mistake, the the club members are glaring at him from the exposed seller.
He's asking himself to I make a mistake. This is seven six eight Plus Avenue. Isn't it?
And and that little nat giggles
as it flies away revealing that it was supposed to be one sixty eight Plus Avenue. It's it's a silly
plot device
But it but it works, you know, Donald Hub
is...
We've we've gotta see his downfall. Bark never likes to leave him.
With this amount of glory. Mi miguel, do you wanna tell us how we how we wrap up the story? Yeah. As they say
in norwegian techs to say
whole moves start fall, like Hub
will make you fall. So we find down and you doing
don't have the so code.
Done
built
igloo. And then use some I speak to shop down this.
For of penguins.
Yeah.
Right. So he's still getting pause, but it's from a bunch of of of penguins.
It's it's a very silly closer. I don't know that the closing is is the strongest part of the story. But it but it works. It's it's cute. The the point is he's had to... He's had to flee the country, basically. That's that's how these often do. He ends up on the run.
And and that That is the master for rec gentlemen. Yeah. Any any any overall thoughts from you about our our featured story here.
Ruben you go first? Yeah. Well, actually, I kinda disagree with you on the end because I thing is right.
And I love how we can actually see donald in is new head.
Because often, it's just like either on saying, Oh, no. He ran off to concrete or you just see packing its bag and running away from his trouble or anything. But harry, I actually see where they end up. And you see him miss happy here because can continuous profession that is still gets the attention and he needs. Yeah. That's.
I actually love that. It's great to see. That's a good point. You know, usually, he's like, freaked out, like like in no such environment. Right, when he was... It's interesting no such environment. It's an adventure story, but it kinda works almost as one of these. Right? Where he's he's just freaked out by the idea of what he was usual used to be a master of and he has to abandon it. But here he liked it enough that he he kept it up in this other form. But what do you think, Miguel, do you like the ending here? I think they're landing is really it's a real quick accounting. Goes the same recent said that don't don't get this
attention. And that's probably what was the most important frame. To to get some those. And it doesn't matter if it's thing penguins or
the dub knows people. Yeah. I I love this one. I think the The wrecking ball element of it is so fun the way he smash the buildings.
As a kid, it really sparked my imagination I I imagine you guys had your own, like, phase as kids where when you loved construction vehicles of all kinds.
Right. To me, this one is like, just perfectly
engineered to be a great, a great
ten page story to entertain kids. Yeah. I think it's a great introduction for young children.
Learn Al these stories
to introduce them to the coverage because yeah. It's kind of machinery and it's community. You guys
actually kinda exciting. Yeah. Make interaction introduction for
children ring dot com. Right. And and it's just the wildly over the top how he is just so tough and rough at the beginning. I I love this one. So I think I think this one is great. I dare say. I think it I it might be a little underrated to be honest Al to to be, like,
the community calls this to four hundred and fifteen
That that's a well regarded story, but I don't know. I I love this one. I think this is awesome. So let's go ahead and transition next.
To...
Why don't we go kinda chronological
with the others?
I guess that means that master
move.
Would be... Oh, I. I guess... Yeah. Because we'll hold smoke writer for later.
Master mover
is the earliest apart from master Rain maker of these. So the master mover was released again in March of nineteen fifty nine. That one came out in Walt disney disease Wisconsin and stories two hundred and twenty two. It's pretty average
to low average rated for a Barks story. It gets a seven point one from the community
Inducks good for one thousand
four hundred and seventy
four. So I'm a little bit lower on but but been fun story. And
I like master remover a lot, but it and also it's it's a kind of an odd story in some ways.
So what we're gonna do is I'm not gonna go through this one blow by blow. I I'd like to just offer a bit of a summary of this one, and then I invite you guys to tell me some of the elements that you thought you really enjoyed
from this one and what made it notable. But we we know our a formula. In this one,
Donald is... Has totally mastered
the business of moving people. And we see sort of the typical
set up where he gets a couple of challenges.
He has to move. He has to move a father's
teenage daughter
at first is his first challenge.
It's a little bit it's a little bit sexist. I'm not gonna lie.
It's it's mostly harmless,
but
but but it's fun... It's a funny little bit. He's gonna end up moving some jewels
from a jewel store has kind of the second,
you know,
challenge
that'll that'll be a fun way where he asked to get past to them.
And it it sets it up really quick. Right? And and then Barks is almost less interested in the moving aspect of it, then where he's gonna end up because his final job, the one that's gonna test him
is that he has to move he has a really quote easy moving job basically moving some zoo animals for this natural as who wants to essentially re hone them into the wild. And and the real crux of this story is this ridiculous
minor bird who
is basically gonna bully donald into letting him go and convincing Donald
that he can help him with great advice
for moving the rest of these dumb animals in exchange for prune.
Is it p in in your version guys?
Barks clearly finds prune very committed. Doesn't he. Because this is, you know, the beagle boys classic favorite that that one beagle.
But but, you know, he's warned not to let this burned out and not to let him get prune
because they make him over overcome and they make him think he's tough. And and essentially, the min is gonna use his minor language
to mess with the other animals and and force donald to have to let him out in change for the prune
that for some reason, he happens to have.
And it says miracle commitments. You don't drive around with P not carl all time?
I mean, who who... Who doesn't? Oh, maybe just gonna make him thing. Right. Right. And he's gonna end up, you know, it takes place on this, like,
canyon
out at this in this remote location. So he's gonna end up calling these these bald eagles at the end to fight Donald. And that's how he gets the prune and and he he's gonna end up thinking that he's super tough. And there's gonna be some, you know, comedic mishap with these eagles
and the mine is gonna get his, like, come up.
And and at the end,
donald does not have to, like, flee the country.
Right? Things don't go horribly wrong in front of a big crowd. But he does get completely scared out of the moving business.
And and has to, like, resort to to con last and building up his strength by eating proof. So that's basically this story in a nutshell.
Who wants to go to bat for this one? What do you... What do you guys think? Do you... How do you feel about this story? Well, I would like to start. I just want to mention that when I read this yesterday, I made some notes and
about halfway went through the story. I noted Is this a moving story, But the the section with the animals, I see that he's supposed to move them, but it just doesn't seem like one of those middle stories to me. It's just double
versus the animals. And it just doesn't feel like a mas history in that sense that it doesn't it doesn't move that much. When I see a, I believe like, moving sort insurance stuff like that. And of course, it's funny and
moves animals this time. Just doesn't feel like one of those
jobs numbers stupid. Yeah. I kinda debated
on the second part, I will say on the first part, very much so
mazda america Al job.
Right, because because it starts out those first two, it it fall... It follows the formula pretty well, but it really stretches out the one where things go. Go horribly wrong. What do you think the Al? Yeah. The story
so start Al a
very typical
mazda history, but then it's it really shifts into this a lot of issue Huey,
animals. And then we also get we get some nice kind of cr bird. Certainly bark most
entrepreneur
animal,
except for for actual heroes.
Yeah. I I think you're right. This mina is a real wise guy.
And and is definitely
supposed to be Al animal. Right? Like, it's got it's got human type cognition,
but we're definitely supposed to read it as an animal. So the the Minor really ticks me off. He's very abrasive. Right? He's he's a jerk. Yeah and I I guess I didn't really mention the fact that like, the suspense of the story is that Donald has to move these animals across this very rick bridge. I I like that element to the story. That seems
that seems pretty cool. Absolutely. It's it's simple.
It's
perfectly cliche, but it's It's simple, and he just needs to move like, this animals from point eight pound point b, and you can see both phones have bought be on the side of the of the bridge. So it's a very a simple idea, it's a simple. It's not something you have to rep head around. I like I like how his this job kicks off. Right? He's like, let's see what species you have in here. And he opens the van and just immediately gets chased across by.
Got a lot. That is kind fun.
I just wanna mention that
because I did actually make some notes about the opening... Transfer for the first mission, he has to move his t teenage daughter At first, I thought why because she's lying on the carpet on my floor. Just talking on the phone. And I thought like, this is really dated.
T teenager is just talking on their phone, but then I was like, oh,
are on their phone Al time still.
Right.
I I've I've been a the major in the digital era and I set my phone and just snapchat all the time. So it's kinda like this timeless was idea that Right. That the teenagers that need to talk to their friends of the time and they... I catch. Think you can't get away from your bones. Really liked that idea actually. Yeah. I'm also
grown up during this digital age being twenty five. And I really would like to seen my Barks with
made out of
today's
teenagers or basically
glued the phone screens. Yeah. He would've have... I'm sure he would have had a lot to say about the rise of of phone culture. I think the only real difference
today is that a lot of kids
hate to talk on the phone,
They they prefer tech Right?
It's... I guess it's not as as daunting if it's your friend. But, like, I know my I have a teenager my steps son. Is is eighteen,
and he can he can video chat or he can text but he will not audio chat. And and I think a lot of teens are like that. I it it's pretty funny how he gets her away with this like really long loop of x wire. It's it's cute. And I I do like... I like how he gets the jewels, the diamonds past the the Robert. They're planning that. That was very clever. I noted that because that's straight,
I don't know. It's.
Right. Right. There there's a situation where you can almost picture that being a sub supply and a a story with uncle Scrooge. Right? He poses
as just like a
a jan and hides it in a harmless looking coil of hose to to take it out. I like... I like that the that the Zoo keeper just kinda like drives them there says, alright. Yeah I got I gotta go now. You you guys can handle it. He. All these warnings about the Min bird. My friend is a little cruel that is just gonna leave this
one doctor because it... The wings of this bird is clipped. I know. All... These random animals that he's just gonna let loose. He his this seems like a bit of a
path to me. It is pretty funny when the miner gets, like all full of prune.
Right. And he's this total, like, Huey, seems like that that little guy in the bar who's had a few drinks, you know? Yeah. Right.
Just the same thing. About prune being, like an middle alcohol on this. Yeah. Awesome. Alright. So so there's the master
mover
next up in terms of chronic chronology.
Alright. And and next up in the chronology would be the master Gladstone. This came out just couple of months after the master mover in November of nineteen fifty nine. This was in Donald Duck number sixty
six. And it's not a very highly regarded one. It's got that kinda low average
score of seven point one.
And it's a
number one thousand eight hundred and seventy six. It's also a pretty short story. Is it is it anything
nature. Yeah Yeah. Yeah. This is a five page. What do you guys think? Do you think he could've have... I wonder if this was, like, intended to be a ten pager
and he just didn't feel like it had the material. I I didn't remember that until I really did a dive into these. Was like, oh, yeah, this one's not even a ten pager but it definitely fits this mold because he's got this very weird job
I mean, repairing glass, that's a a very important thing, but it's not definitely not a common job. And he's really cra
problems
that that are like worthy of his talents.
He doesn't like the idea just fixing broken windows from kids
playing with ball,
balls, like, his nephew.
We get almost as quickly as the master mover. We get a couple of his, like, little success where he repairs
a fish bowl for some some ladies fish who's named her goldfish Poops.
And then and then a a fancy, like automobile
ent has his eighteen ninety nine
light bulb has been
smashed by a near site Wood packer.
And and it's it's very cute, but again, it's very quick. And ultimately,
he's hoping
for, like this
opportunity
and he gets it. When the new Tv tower needs the giant clock
faced. And he offers to do it for free
if the Tv people will
broadcast it.
And we get this this pretty cheesy sequence
where he's like, really ham it up for the cameras,
showing off the powered tuning for that he uses for these tasks.
And as he aims it to get rid of the like, smashed glass, the Tvs end up broadcasting it. To all of Ducktales.
And they... He he... He ends up shattering every bit of glass in town.
And he doesn't get the chance to flee at the end of this one because he's been corner up that top the top of that clock tower by pretty much everyone in town.
It's got a funny silly little ending where you said he's in the spot, like just like he wanted. So that... That's a pretty quick summary of the master asked.
Why don't we start nico
what do you think about this? What works for this one what doesn't...
Well I think so
is there very short but well structured?
And
dom Huey, is where more in
it's more focus here because this more adult savers
this
makes and fall. Compared to the others
yeah. More barely. Because the auto one see just it's mostly bad actually.
It's just my standings and bad luck. And this one. He actually
because it wants that famous so hard.
This is what that makes makes it come Barks him. Yeah. And and I I think we don't sympathize with him as much in as one because he is so desperate for it. Right?
It it's it's fun. It's got its cute little elements
I I really like the sequence
with
the the two lead up sequences where he fixes his poop he's fish ball,
and the the gentleman,
those little quick characters are good example of Barks creating some fun little one off. The the the automobile ent. You look at him and, he's in one of those autos that's old
even at this time and the sixth steve's. This is like a a
sixty year old auto. And and he's just just funny. But the this one... It's it's fine. It's not a story that I would
seek out if it wasn't kind of included with these other ones, I think. I also like this
background yikes box we use two times with Al black seal silhouette of Tom's car and all the little tools that is for now. Yeah. That's true The springs and hammers are just pulling out of car showing out what thing he's going. Yeah. Yeah. That's a good catch. That is that is a nice little Element, and I do really like that. Yeah. This this is a fun story. I I I... I'm glad I'm glad we got a few of these brutal master stories.
Yeah. I think I think this one is, like, it's not that great eyes though but, like, with follow Barks little jobs stories, I think it's I add to the collection. I think it's fun. It's like it's cute. And
I actually really like the...
And I really like that part at the end where he's in the spotlight. And of course, as everyone wants to chase him at top for this pad at the top of this tower, there's actually three spotlight like
him in the night. I thought that was really funny. I really picked me. Yeah. And we do get a a neat
callback at the end as everyone's glass through a town starts to break, you know, one house we see there goes our windows and our rare god
and poops these goldfish fish bowls that lady has a little little return there. Oh oh, yeah. That's great. Cute. Small is
takes and four more. Just not that Remember. Yeah.
No. It's more of a support to
story that I I don't know it was if it was placed first in the in this and store first appearance. But Yeah. I wouldn't be surprised. I didn't check, but I I'm... I imagine it probably wasn't the lead off story. It's also rare that we cover stories that were in not not in uncle Scrooge or Al business comments and stories, but a donald duck issue. Yeah. So right, guys. So
the the last story that was included in the original b mastery
is called spare that hair and it's, you know, not it's not quote the master Barks, Like I like, it feels like it should be.
But that's fine. There that hair was in Wall Disney Comments and troy two seventy two in May of nineteen sixty
three.
So I I think that might be the latest
story that I've really talked about on the podcast.
It gets a seven point two from the community, number eight hundred and twenty nine. Store at least in the top thousand on index. It's a good solid
later
Barks story, I think. And and we had talked about, like, does this one really fit the mold
because unlike the other brittle mastery
stories
basically, the premise of this one is that Donald is an extraordinarily
good barber,
and
can do really cool things. With people's hair.
And and at the end, at the end of this one, there's gonna be an escape to gorilla.
That comes to his barber shop that he states for a real customer
and he gives them kind of his barber treatments.
And and the ring master that he is previously helped
is gonna get upset at him for messing up the gorillas threatening looks.
But Donald is gonna like win out. Right? He's gonna threaten to cut off the ring master's Fancy pistachio.
Unless he pays him for the grill his haircut.
And Donald just ends up enjoying the circus,
watching the harmless looking gorilla. At the end of this one.
So I don't know. It it it definitely
juice a little bit, but I guess when they did this collection, they they felt like they needed one more story.
I personally think that maybe they should have picked either the smoke right story or the beauty business story
might have fit the mold a little bit better. But
this is a fun one. What did you guys think? I we really like all this wish little gas at the beginning of the story. We're don't having this
sites. What's the name of it again? It's...
Oh, it's sai. Yeah. Right? Yeah.
The the hair gigs and this one are a lot of fun. Yeah. And they are typical of the the master story because don't listen a master on it those
showcase is mastery and very
Huey,
visual ways. Yeah. It's a fun one. But what's your favorite of the rubin, what what which of the, you know, different haircut sequences
do you like? Well you gonna love the ridiculous square Yeah. The first pull it's just... It's not ridiculous listen it's some Barks. Definitely.
I like that one. Yeah. We get he builds an egg head for someone he gives someone a screw cut instead of a group cut It's it's all very fun. It's very light. I don't think any of it is nearly as engaging as, like, the rain maker concept
or the wrecking
concept.
That he just hit such a home run with those two. I really like the screw cut though because in progress I saw a guy with that haircut was.
You really have that haircut. And yeah. That was.
Nice. I I always felt like it was a little bit over the top cartoon logic that Donald doesn't realize that
is an an escape girl gorilla rather than just like a a tough a tough looking guy from the circus.
So that that always can even annoyed me. Yeah. I can see that.
It's a stroke in classic animation and a classic comic Barks. So
right. I will see if I can go with it. Yeah. Gorillas are always escaping.
Yeah.
Especially in the jorge. Yeah. Any any other thoughts for spare that here, anything else that's stood out to you guys? Well, you know,
for fifty sixteen hundred years old every three years ago, they meant that com books with dangerous interest. I don't see how this story helps with donald the drug down with the coming but
That's right.
That's right. He uses. What does he call it? Like,
powder of am
or something. It's it's just called dreaming power norwegian. Oh, it's it's
fortified papers of you. For. Yeah. Know what we're supposed to take that. They are right. He's totally, like dragging
dragging this little sixties kid. I I find some of this one a little bit off putting, to be honest. It's not it's not my favorite story, but but is a little bit stronger, I would agree than like, the master glass or I think I might like the master
better than this one even though the community
ranks this one a little bit higher. Well, from what I can see, it looks like... And I actually
like the first part where it just shows up so many in different ways come and fun ways that he like. This is Barks.
And of course, like rely on is well kinda odd but it's like yeah. I I.
Yeah. I only the first half. I think it's really Scrooge the first time. I agree I I remember this story. I think that's... I think that's the right take on it. So really strong beginning, and I... It's the ending that I find a little bit off putting. So it it feels like maybe he had it
and then he couldn't quite get that ending that would have kept him like, one of the true Brittle mastery
stories. Yeah, the beauty business is a really late one.
And it's technically I think a Donald and Daisy story. That mean.
Yeah. I... And I don't have that one in front of me. So we we can talk about it, but I'm going from memory.
The beauty business
is
a nineteen sixty six one from Walt disney comics, and stories three zero nine.
Seven point one
rang
today, you know, all these or what it shows on end index right now.
One thousand two hundred and eighty five. So not a very highly regarded one. I...
The the the beauty business one, it it kinda rep me. Just just the ending with the the the Crown. It's it's pretty test.
It's some... It's an intriguing story telling. I'm sure that one has its fans. But
That might be one of my least favorite
well known
ten pager. The whole thing old Chrome is, maybe again, your
or Al Id that call used from the competition around nineteen forty forty six, I think. There was a competition in Us about drawing this the world's ugliest woman.
Or didn't win, but he did the participants in the there's fascinating.
A little disturbing, but but interesting.
Yeah. That one's more... It's more of a daisy story. So I guess, like, it's it's hard to even call it a Brittle mass for story but it's definitely got some of those elements where he's like really good Al what he does.
That's that's april May and June and it's too. I don't think I've ever talked about them in the podcast Daisy nieces. So that's kinda fun. Yeah. And I just remember that I keep mixing up spare hair and the beauty business because it's like all
in a barber,
edition
right.
Yeah. He's he's behind the a chair, you know, We're exactly
he's working on people heads.
What can I say? It's
there's similar in that way and also the opening, I find really
based spaces that people's looks and that's where I keep mixing them up. And also I think that maybe I don't have the front meter here right here on right now, but I take you Barks elements information right there. And I also loved... I think it's a great ip idea yeah. The daisy is like... Because I remember right, what they system
last one in the story to be
master with but right. Yeah. For.
And it just keeps, like messing up or luke messing up or looks messing up or looks. And that makes it.
Like... Well, and it's it's her niece is they're kind sabotage. Yeah
Yeah. And let me
mention them. Because I like I kinda like that concept. And
disturbing to look Al that I like idea. Yeah. It's fun. There's some weird ideas in that one. Some weird attitudes from, like Daisy is is very like.
Concerned with a shame.
Right. It's interesting that Donald is usually anxious about his mass validity. And these stories and and that one he's like, totally
totally down to be a mutation, which is kinda neat.
And then Daisy gets all the anxiety about, you know,
I guess some of this nervous miss about, you know, spending time around other women.
I think that one could definitely be kind of close to one of the mastery stories. The only other one that we haven't really talked about is the smoke writing
one, which is a really fun one. I I Don't have that one in front of me, so I'm not like, even gonna offer up a big huge summary of that, but but what do you guys think? Does that one fit the bill? I think it fits the mold except long since wheel. Yeah.
It's just very
good
Good Al it. Right? He's capable.
He's making all these, like, sky
images. Right? And then Uncle Scrooge hires him to promote him in his campaign
for a mayor or something like that. Yeah. The I remember right? That's and things definitely go horribly wrong as he,
you know, fills duck with awful
smoke. I just gonna mention it's a nineteen fifty six, November story, and while Disney comics, and stories one ninety four.
Community likes it pretty well. It got a seven point two good for nine fifty five. So
Go ahead. What what other thoughts did you have on that one? Well, I just want to say that read case, actually,
and
it starts out with them just
right with smoke using Al airplane in the sky. You gotta drawer the only right sweep, the splash panel. That's where Thing. So he Barks out we're making just a hard for firm for Daisy.
And when he wants to do the thing for Al Scrooge,
set that out
writing. That's all. I'm gonna
draw your facing this sky. And of course,
clouds
crashing to his smoke rotting, making it look like a monkey or a short.
Severino
and a snake and a donkey even. So the audience listening to Scrooge about his
speech. Yeah. Imagine is
I not with them at all
because they don't like this smoke right. I think it's
provisioning the city. So
when I see he head getting into all this, like, oh, he's a short. He's a don't oh. I think it's funny.
Love it. It doesn't really fit the formula in that way it doesn't really
show his profession in the store. It just like I'm doing it. Oh this the screwed. And then he's, like that the first time. Yeah. That's true. It doesn't... Doesn't quite fit the bill. It does have some really great visual gaps. I like. Absolutely.
And I remember vividly it's... I haven't read in ages but I remember that
Scrooge is campaigning, he's asked about air pollution, and and he says I'm for. Buster, I think. I'm not not knowing what it is. And
Barks was really interested in, like, ecology
and and pollution. And and that's something you got really interested in and is later
career. So that that was kinda cool to see. So
Yeah. There's there's arguably,
like, really only four of these stories that, like, perfectly
fit the Al. But... But it's a pretty good run. There's definitely a handful of them that mostly or partially were. And again, like, it's an adventure your story, but no such environment is is kind of in that same vein too.
I I don't know if you guys
Recall it, you probably do. But Don Rosa did a really awesome r
on on this. He did the master Al landscape
or landscape is. I can't remember that title. Yeah. The master landscape
is like a pitch perfect
take.
But
Rosa clearly knew. He clearly was like, yes, This is Barks formula,
I wanna give this a try and tell this type of story because he was doing the exact thing and What what what are your thoughts on that one ruben? Well, I just wanna say a little quick fun fact because I just quickly flick through it in my Al of fame Barks earlier today. And that is actually the first story on rosa did for Ag. How nice?
And I believe nineteen.
Three maybe... I two. I
that. Maybe.
I like that's right. Right. It's a great take. And also,
There also many on
taking this formula and made other stories with it. I know Yeah That's I
ask you guys, can you think of any other artist who have who have done this specific like brittle mastery
thing? I I also
I love the master landscape campus. I think, you know, Rosa, I don't know if he... Is quite as comfortable doing the ten pager. I feel like sometimes he didn't him because he felt like
He needed to also do ten pages,
but it wasn't like, what are he preferred to do. But that one is just about as good as it gets, I think. So so... Yeah, other other artists?
And I know that I didn't need to and in the norwegian production. Tms has Al least made one. This master stories. I don't remember it that clearly right now with the long is making
cheap setting think. Because, yeah, I believe they and a region production team actually Have made a handful of these stories or at least they proved done Al lot of jobs. But in the same way as if with box Barks stories, I don't recall if they fit the brick master mode or if it's just done
any mold because I know it's like a cake delivering man. Yeah
and the something like. And it also also
where his great ricardo player if that okay? Yeah Yeah. Yeah. You like a big pile of stores and have to pull one out without making the whole pile collapse. And so it's a up... Right. That called, that might be called pickup sticks in the states. Yeah. Okay. Because he's a great pickup stakes Ricardo blair Nice.
And then he uses the ability when
loosening up like when with
largest
timber
same maria timber
have
been stuck in the river. So they look like a big pile of And then it stopped and I just
crashed to server and make this big part. And then download knows exactly which one it has to pull to make you Al the again. Nice. That that does sound like a a good. That sounds like an interesting one I should check out. And I believe it's a food review in one That may be the to potato chip one. And also the the one with the cake delivery which was written by Nylon I believe. I think that one is one move fits the mouse their formula the best
in the region stories.
Nice. Well, you guys are giving me some good suggestions for those. I have to have look those that so sound like fun. Yeah They probably don't pick exist English, I believe. Some of them, do work least, but
sadly not too many of them. I the search versus Scrooge at least translate. Yeah. Okay. And I can't think of any specific ones. But I know that
Van Horn has done enough like of the job stories where he must have done something
along those lines. Right a William Van Warren. He. He's he's done a ton of job one. So I'll have to think about that. But you guys... I I think this was a really cool discussion.
Yeah. I like this. I like this format man. I really appreciate. We had a few technical issues at the beginning of this episode, but we stuck it out.
You guys any closing thoughts
about these Brittle mastery stories? Yeah.
Before we wrap it up you guys any any
panels that you'd like to call out in any of the stories?
I'm love to call out the one we're down
last time on the first page of the master record, we're done is chewing down the pant the pancakes
Yeah. With this me
with this vehicle phase. I actually think that the master record is one of those stories where the the opening pages is so
strong that almost every panel is is just wonderful. Definitely, that first one stands out. And then you had mentioned I one you mentioned where the, I think ruben where it's on Tip toes
his his
wrecking ball, that's a great one.
And then the wind up as well. Just just to one And one of it's actually Covid regulatory.
Yeah you three four times like that exact post and it's great I level the
personalization
drawings of the
ball writing machine. Right.
Yeah. Any others from the master director? Oh, really.
It was red rerun.
What The thing I found Oh yeah. You were Inducks.
The this story was completely red with Jose.
I didn't know fun. The the the Brazilian... Well, the popular in Brazil. Characters Z C.
They they really love him there.
Yeah. Any any panels that stand out in the master mover? To you guys? I I think for me, the stand out panels tends to be the
the minor bird
being a big blow hard, you know,
trying to, like, talk as way out of the cage winding up. I think most of those are the best ones And I really like the the payoff of that bird on the last page, the second panel.
Yeah. Where where the eagle is just squeezing that bird giving him for the the face of that
at bit of that panel bell, I love it. Right. Yeah. That's a good one. Oh Miguel. Well every every time with Al little bird is
It's just a great to come itself Really like it's
self secure
policies and
this page where which I believe is
page eight
where standing on the first panel. Thing towing the nephews that they can all the
languages of all animals around the world.
Right. Yeah. That
Al least real lunch alone and that And and then for glass, you know, you guys called out. One of you mentioned
the... I think Mi Al, you mentioned those
running gag of the tools falling out of the silhouette that that is a really nice touch.
And I just like the look of I had mentioned I like to look the automobile
ent see.
Yeah. He's great. And
you see how it's just like Al
if I feel I'm a bit of a collector myself and I love building lego and stuff like that. And the
the phrase where it's just growing up loud that this eighty and ninety and nine my bulbs are
replaceable. It's just like seeing a a great collector
like
some of this collection.
And then
we can wrap it up with spare that hair. Any favorites from that one? I think we'd already kinda called out that the that the that the square is pretty fun. Right? I like that one. Absolutely. I also like
We just call up the splash panel where is this is so we all over
the... Is it a baseball thing? Yeah. They're the
crew of the y
shell in this one. But that's that means
I think that's great. It's the kinda of reminds me of when uncle Scrooge is polishing the shoes and he's using that.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. Going on all this there. I like. Any that you wanna call out Me miguel? Yeah. The... You know, the panel we're done is
fixing that that from dash of the the ring master ring this
Yeah the rim. I really like the...
I like the panel only so fixing up the the upper
the ring master. That is a good one. Yeah. With his kind of like his odd expression there. It's kind of a
men guy that you don't really know
don't really know where just go.
I right. Yeah. Yeah. It really stands out.
Excellent. Well, you guys... I really appreciate it. I
as you can probably tell, I love this type of Barks story. So I was really glad to get the chance to have a really fun conversation about it. Listeners, feel free to reach out if you wanna advocate for one of these stories or if there is a story
that we haven't thought about that
comes close to fitting
the mold of the the b mastery
jobs.
But until next time we'll...
We'll we'll catch you on another app. So the ten page podcast and for a regular
adventure length
episodes, and Look forward to having you gentlemen on again.
I would... I'll be glad to be back. I also be glad to be back and really. Thank you for having us, Barks. Absolutely.
Spectrum.
Alright. Thank you guys.