We have
Hello, and welcome to Barks Remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Inducks and writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge comics of all time. This episode is a ten page podcast, all about one of his short stories. Get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Welcome back to Barks remarks. I'm Mark Sever
Grown man who enjoys dot con, and I'm joined by Austin Kelly.
Say hello the nice people, Austin. Hi everybody. And hap happy summer to you and to our listeners. We're we're recording this in early June
almost at summer. And
we've got a summer themed
episode for today, this this episode of the ten page podcast.
Austin, how do you feel about summer? Summer in general. Yeah. I really like summer. I mean,
the weird thing is where I come from in Manhattan. Everyone seems to be a winter person just because we only get snow like, twice a year there. But I really like summer, especially because it's just three months where I get to do. Whatever I want reading Barks comics. Yeah. Absolutely. I... My my child summers were definitely filled with a lot of these. And
and I grew up in the Bay area.
So we'd spend a lot of time at the beach and And, of course, it's very natural when you
write for comments when you do our for com, you want those seasonal hook Right? So Barks, I I assume by specific request or or just this was understood to be true. You would you would submit your summer themed stories in time for publication, you would submit Christmas themed stories and time for the holidays.
And and, you know, we we've got three months of summer. So that means that we... That Carl Barks ended up doing up a pretty decent number of summer themed stories, and I think a lot of summer covers. Oh, yeah. A bunch of those. Yeah. I can think of a few famous.
I like the famous
Saint Bernard cover delivering
delivering a cold drink if I remembering. Right. Oh, yeah. That was one of his
first, I think. My have been is first for the the Walt see title, actually. Yeah. It might have been.
So anyway, I've I've been dancing around it, but I very the lead. We get to cover
among three
great summer stories. Covering one of his most legendary ten pages day, which is pool Barks.
And and I'm I'm so excited to talk about this one Austin.
Yeah. I I have to say the same. I was just looking through it today, and it is just so brilliant. Like, it's such a I made the hemingway connection before we recorded it, but it's like such a simple table with such light dialogue, but it can base such a funny message. It's a really great piece. Oh, yeah. This... It's really an art showcase. Right? So which which is a problem for an audio
format like ours. We're gonna commit that cardinal of just talking about great art. But it's it's also incredibly sharp riding and and pasting and plotting. So yeah, pool Barks is gonna be our kind of features story. But we do have a couple of other great summer stories to talk about. We're gonna be covering
as well one called swimming,
sw doors. And then another one called house boat Holiday. We've got some some nice
in those titles there.
And, of course, you know, those titles are all titles that have been made after the fact. Right? These these ten pager were originally un title. Think my original printing of pool Barks is actually called the swimming pool at the time of the Gladstone.
Reprint and Donald number two hundred and seventy four, via Gladstone
gave a lot of their own titles to the Barks ten pages for whatever reason,
there are one of course like Pool ox that are used widely now. I don't know when or by who they were conceived, but I guess if they were around by the late eighties or by done two seventy four Gladstone for whatever reason just use their own title. Yeah. I I think they ended up qualifying them.
I always laugh a little bit because I imagine like, a bunch of Barks sk sitting around a a table and debating. Okay. That the statue story who's got a good statue plan Statue spend trips.
But I think they were like quote
around
publication of the Carl Barks library, but... But I'm not sure. I I... I know I asked someone about that and had answer some point forgotten about it. But let's see. Swimming sw. My my reprint of that one calls it
hun
advice, and yeah. I think swimming sw wears is a little more solid. Yeah. Hunt advice is a little more straightforward.
Swimming sw just sounds,
which is deserves the title for a goofy story. Right. And then the house holiday by the time I read that in the Disney comics
publication, that's the title that they landed on, and that that one Barks it straightforward, but it's alert
literate.
And and of course, there's a bunch of other great Barks
some stories that weren't not gonna get to talk about in this one. You and I debated
Lifeguard
days. Do you wanna mention kind of the notable thing about that one really quick, so we just kinda check it off. Yeah. I actually haven't read it before, but I remember hearing about
this female lifeguard that was in the story, who bark Drew like very largely like the chest was clearly
inflated to the point of like there's a scene a famous scene where she's kissing Donald and like, her chest is touching his and he's like oh, you know, like, frozen and stuff and stuff. And you can actually look at the drawing and can see like they cut it down. So she's like, very skinny and tiny, like, the published version, which is, like, super weird. Yes.
Yeah. I mean, it's weird I think in in both since is right, this, like, duct character that's given
given a bust and then the awkward sensor version.
Yeah. You know, I don't that one either? I think I... I've seen I've seen that talked about and that, like, as an example of censorship,
but I've never read it. I don't think I've read it myself. So since the of us has it, we don't get to cover it today, but
unfortunately.
Yeah. Although I do think it's probably worth checking out because I think there's a senior where he beats up a shark or something. Which would probably be good to look at. Yeah. Yeah. I I know the cover of that one, I've seen it. I've seen the recovery produced. It was the one picked for the Barks Library Album that that story was featured in. So happening. Yeah, I'll I have to keep an eye out for that. And then let's see. There's a number of other great summer stories. I covered the vacation time, of course and one of the regular
episodes. That's an all time great summer story that we won't be covering on the ten page podcast. Probably a number of other ones that would fit the definition. But but for our purposes today, those are the three that we're talking about. They were all of course, originally published in walt Disney comics and stories.
So let's go ahead and start. We are... We are giving pool Barks
the
the headline story feature, the main story feature. So we're gonna we're gonna start off with that one, which was published in Walt Disney Conference and store one hundred and twenty nine in June of nineteen fifty one.
And this is a very highly rated ten pager
Inducks, it gets a seven point six out of ten, which right now is good for number one hundred and seventy one out of all forty one thousand some Disney comments. That are rated. Right. So the this may not be current.
Right. But
some months ago, I kinda pulled out the ten pager that were highest rated one Inducks. Just to see kind where they compared it against each other. And at that time,
pool sharp so, yeah. This is probably pretty close because it was one seventy three at the time. Pool sharp crack the top ten for all time greatest Pearl Barks ten pager. It was the tenth greatest when I made my little spreadsheet sheet. I think that that's totally accurate. I think this is an all time class. Absolutely.
You know respect. So I'm gonna run my hands together in anticipation.
And I'm gonna open up the story. Austin, this this first page of of the story pool Barks is I think a masterpiece piece. It... The the whole story is great throughout. But the the first page might really be the stand page.
We've got the basically, the story opens with Donald
just frantically
working in his garden.
It's it's all of the worst stuff about being a gardener. It's fitting pests. It's it's trying to keep ver out of your gardening and and every every panel
in this has Donald in some sort of like wonderful
friend motion.
It is
so funny to see him
fighting off weeds
spraying for bugs kicking out of chicken
pursuing a go for with a sling shot.
And and the whole time his thought process just
complaining about how unpleasant this is. And at the end of the page, he starts to ponder the fact that smart people don't have gardens
they use their backyard to play in.
They have tennis ports and swimming pools and you you see that he just hasn't a epiphany.
Right there, and he thinks from himself did I say swimming pools?
Well, what what your thoughts about this. The so austin. I totally agree that, like, this is one of the stand pages. I always loved Barks has sense closing
and just every pose here is so powerful
and, like, so exaggerated
And it is really funny. Like, it's just set up that he's like this typical
tired, like working guy. Like, all he can do is, like, run around and complain. And I think it sets up the story perfectly
like, really well.
Yeah.
It it strikes me too that not to get deep. This is a very surface level story but I I feel like it's also really at the outbreak of the fifties, this is about, like, modern suburb.
Right? And the and the things that people do with their backyard
one of the first Barks stories that he ever did was the victory Garden. Right? And that's like this
utilitarian look at how to use your backyard and And here he's like, well, I I can use my backyard for fun. And that's what was really happening. People, it was kind of the the dawn of, like, barbecue culture and lawn care culture in the American suburbs.
Yeah. Tell us about tell us Tell us about after Donald has epiphany. Yeah. So Donald standing around in the garden, and he's thinking really hard and you guys is great image of a pool in his yard, and there's a brilliant device by bark to get rid of the nephews for the story because they really just wouldn't fit where they're off summer camp for two weeks.
So they walk off and they noticed that he's off a trans thinking about something.
And Donald starts frantically pointing around and a great multiples sort of smear posts,
you know? Kinda and I think of that before, the diving board can be there where the cabbage are the dressing rooms in the artichoke show. So he picks up the phone. The calls a guy over and he selects the the pool type that's oh June moon Leg lagoon.
And he gets ready for it. He starts to get building. And what I find interesting
is, like,
I always wanted how Barks could pack in so
much like an in of story and character in ten pages.
And it's like, in the last three alone, Like, he calls up a guy, and there's no, like transition or anything that says like, later or like, soon, like the guy just shows up and he selects the pool and he's off building, like, what didn't mess around, like, everything happens so fast especially in pool Barks to the point where like, it's real... It can be hard to keep up with the action, which I think is like, speaks to his skill for storytelling.
Yeah. You're They're absolutely right. You get like some real web whiplash in this story. But made in a good way. The pacing
is amazing. It's frantic. It gives you an idea of how quickly Donald had this idea and how quickly he wants to put it in action and and you're right that that salesman like shows up there. For just a single panel that I can see his whole backstory.
I can see that he's like you you can see the delight written on his face that he doesn't need this sell. He need to convince this guy. He's just gonna sell him this
super deluxe.
The June moon look lagoon. I mean, that's sounds
perfectly brand. That's absolutely
something that one of these
companies would have in their catalog.
And and you pointed it out, you're you're so right. Bark needs the nephews
to be away, both because it it it sets up the great kind of comedic premise
of of the story and it and it's gonna set us up for the the ending
but also, they're they're the voice of reason.
Right? And and without them around,
Donald is kind of free to make these mistakes.
And
we're also free to see Donald dealing with like one of the worst things
a parent can deal with. Other people's children.
I I I am a parent,
and and I I also work with kids. So I love kids, but then
sometimes, other people's children are just so unpleasant
because
you don't have to deal with them. You're not responsible for them. So A lot of the comedy and the rest of this is gonna... Is gonna
show, you know, showcase how Donald deals with that. But but you had mentioned in that first page all of those poses
in service of hit his frantic
dealing with the the garden.
Now we have all of these wild poses that are reflecting his excitement and and it's It's just amazing, which is beautiful. I mean, it's just I can to look at.
Like, Barks new, it's just so lovely that he could draw a pose that told the story as much as the dialogue told the story, which I think is really cool. Right. Right. Like, like, take the take the panel where he's reflecting
in this, like, days
a swimming pool. You know, Barks
he does. He puts so much.
He packed so much into that panel, that realization that Donald has
that epiphany that, like, far off look where he can imagine and enjoying himself Al summer. I so great.
So on the third page, you know, things continue to move quickly, we get a couple of great panels showing
construction.
Of the pool Barks
really
summarizes it as the artichoke choke go and in their place and their places rise Cabana.
How we get a really lovely
panel
showcasing his new
backyard.
It looks really cool. It it's definitely got that fifties look.
It looks like it cost a small fortune.
I thought the same thing. I was wondering where Donald even got the money to do this in the first place. Right. I almost thought I I read over some sort of x explanation, like you know, like, my uncle screws left me some inheritance or something.
But, you know, whatever logical plot
Right. Barks needs
needs money to not be an issue. Usually money is like a limiting factor in and these stories it's it's not gonna be here.
And and so Donald gets really excited. He had admire, this gorgeous just new pool and he gets ready to jump in.
And and he talks about putting on his suit as he starts to take off his sure. We definitely get some of that like the thing that everyone loves to point out, you know, Donald Inducks wearing a bathing suit and any time that he's
everyone's fascinated with the idea that Donald Duck doesn't work pants. Right. So there tend to be people who who noticed so he's gonna put on a swimsuit.
And and just as he's about to go in, he gets interrupted by
Couple of just
adorable
harmless looking little children and one of whom speaks willow lisbon says,
mister Dot
and and they plead to have one teeny wee little swim in his awful party pool.
And and so Donald, you know, ru
says okay. Which I find interesting because it seems a little out of character for him to be that willing.
But I it does have a hard after all.
Sure.
Sure. Yeah. I'm wonder about that. Right? Is is this
is this a typical thing around the... I mean, I I remember swimming and neighbors pools when I was a kid in the eighties.
So
I guess I guess is not out all that far out of character. But
but, yeah, this is gonna be Donald
big mistake. Tell us about the next bill. Yeah. I mean, actually on the next page, there's sort of an explanation where Donald says well, No there's only two of them. I should have told them to wait till next week, but there's only two. So I guess that is sort of justified.
But he gets in his film suit he comes out. And it's like dozens and dozens of kids just crammed into this pool. And it's a great flash panel by Barks. So it's even one kid
trying to drown the other. And I also find really weird that he mixes in the dog face children with, like, the pig face children.
And like, some of them look really creepy, like the pig under the diving board. Yeah. I I feel like Bark doesn't
like
the kids that are about that older kid age, I don't think Barks life's kids about that age. Right? Because he usually, Huey, usually represents them pretty obnoxious. It's especially in this story.
Right.
Exactly. And speaking of which one of those older kids
bumps donald off the side of the diving board and jumps in.
So Donald is screaming and screaming till the kids to get out.
But there's no use because they can't hear a word that he's saying, which I find interesting because, like, in a lot of, like... Speaking someone who's about a lot of Dell stories
like the plot
device that most stories are hanging on is so, like, illogical
that the whole thing is null. But like, in this situation, he really can't get the kid down. Because they can't hear him at all,
and he can't, like, individually rag them out one buy one because he's not that crazy. So what I like about this story and this page in particular is it it is very believable.
And like, I could see myself in this situation, really not being able to find a way out of it.
Yeah. Absolutely. This is just a huge crowd of other people's kids, and if they're not gonna listen to you,
what can you do? And and, you know, this is like that baby boom one,
when neighborhoods were just overrun with children
playing outside all day, they weren't on the Internet. So, like, I... My parents talk about how kids kinda just ran wild
during those days. So I I think this is it's it's obviously hyper
exaggerated with it's believable as far as these things go.
And so we transitioned to it's just an awesome narrator box on the next page
hours pass hours hours.
Hours.
You know, Barks is just setting up how, like, desperate donald fields, and and he he... All he can do is wait until the kids eventually leave at night, one
saying, thanks for telling me about this pool butch and he says thank Josie. She told Pug and pledge told me Well, I love that name that random p.
And and we get this neat Al little bit of missed action where Donald finally gets into his June moon lagoon
at night and we see some splash around, but it turns out that it's just him
clearing out the the d tried and Al litter that have been left behind by the kids swimming all day, and he's had to like, mostly drain the pool and get... He eventually gets it scrubbed and filled up by midnight.
And...
He
mh. Tends to wake up early in the morning to get a swim
and references that he didn't sleep at all thinking about the pool. And he he pulls himself out of bed, really tired preparing to do a nice jack knife dive. And when he gets outside, he sees this joker or who has led his, like,
four big span dogs.
Paddle around in the pool saying that I he was taking them for a lock when they spied you pool. Those dogs sure love water.
Which isn't exactly preventing him from getting in. And... But I guess it is like a sanitary thing. Like, I probably wouldn't be in wanna be in pool a bunch of.
It's pretty... It's pretty gross. It's a great panel of these delighted dogs
paddle around.
Yeah. My Barks was just so great like, just funny drawing. Just very simple, just goofy stuff. Like, even that guy in the background looks kinda funny.
Usually, like in the Barks stories, this is just dawning on me. Like, there's a very specific reason for the punishment that he gets
Like you want yet that's like deserving of this absolute torture
that he has to go through.
Yeah. You're right. This is this is a different story. This is not one of those where he's gonna get any, like, real poetic justice
This is just one of those occasional stories Barks does where it's kind of the universe
the universe against Donald. And things just go wrong.
Which is awesome because it's just hilarious and it is.
So, anyway, Donald is
All I the manuals,
and he's walking off and he's counting up to ten.
And then all the kids come back and they rush in with the dogs.
So then Donald takes the count more and more and it comes new, and he's up counting to ten thousand
three hundred and ninety seven. And it's only till evening where he's counting to twenty thousand six hundred and three when p and Joe and all the kids are running out of the pool. That Donald has to... Has to clean it up again, so he builds up a gate and he keeps the dogs out, Keeps the kids down. And he comes up with this great idea to frees them out, which is so donald.
Like, that's just so Huey,.
Now at this point, he did does sort deserve anything he's getting to feet really one stuff frees out like a bunch of kids.
I I mean, I I still think like this is...
Is it justified
maybe not? But like, it a man can put ice in his own pool if you wants. You know, like,
I don't know. I guess there's some argument that it's Al attract nuisance But
but, yeah, it's it's that panel where he has the brain's form Al great. I've got it I'll freeze out.
And so on to the next page, you know, he orders up an ice company to dump a truckload load of ice
in the swimming pool immediately.
And in the morning, he's greeted by the sounds
of
presumably all of the kids the neighborhood.
Saying y ouch. I'm freezing
bur. Let me out of here. And any kind
struts his way out. And this is such a great joke. The only way to really present it is just to read out what Donald says you he thinks himself. It just takes a few brains
to figure out ways and means as he prepares to take that he says
He says, he he thinks to himself, they're gone. And now as if fits the gentleman of leisure, I'll take my dip And as he jumps off the diving board, he thinks. It just takes a few brains to figure out ways and means,
And of course, he lands directly into the chill pool
with these giant Barks of ice and and
yells to himself brains,
where was I when those things were handed out? As he's completely forgotten about the ice,
that that drove the neighborhood kids out.
Yeah. I mean, he's not wrong because you really have to be stupid if you purposely put that ice in, and you jump right back in, you totally forget about it. Go ahead. You just trade this as the next page?
Sure. So Donald is sort of back to that, like grumpy old man vibe on the next panel,
where he's going down and town to get a book on pest control. And all the kids in the town's spot them and they start booing him, trying to spoil our fun. Who he think he is? So they all... One kid goes a tomato,
and all the other kids get the same idea to do the same thing and they all chase out of town.
And so Donald comes home slashing,
covered in tomatoes and everything he says himself I'm sure popular with every kid in town. But I'm gonna get at least once women my pool if I have to fight a war. Though he literally hasn't gotten a swim yet other than his like, five seconds in his pros pool. I like that one of the kids is named Bradley.
That is a good name. That's very Barks.
And and so our our last sort of upping the steaks of what can go wrong is is gonna be a sequence with the mothers of the children.
We transitioned
to one of the moms
complaining that her little h attendance is un burned to a those. From swimming and Donald pool.
A little kid
looks so funny to me. Austin. She's she's standing in the classic sun burn clothes where you don't wanna, like, move, you know, you keep your body rigid.
And she just looks... She just looks so goofy. It's so funny. It is funny. She's got, like, three teeth hanging out.
And like, all her proportions are, like,
shrunk to the extreme
Right. And and all of the moms look really unpleasant
very like
p and they're all going around complaining about how various kids,
you know, one of
another skin is me on the diving board, and they're working themselves up into a ladder
to
call on Donald Duck
where they're going to threaten him. They wanna inspect his pool.
They they wanna make sure he's got a lifeguard to protect they're a little darling unless they have him tired and feather.
That's a pretty great threat to make to Inducks. Right?
Classic.
And
and, yeah, take take us home.
Barks so calls... Donald all worried because now he's gone
everyone in the neighborhood had mad at him. So he figure he's just gonna stand up for himself, I'll just go out there and swim and dare him to get tough with me.
These screams dang way, I'm gonna do a jack knife dive, and he gets out in the diamond one. This might be the best moment in the story.
All the mothers that have come out to yell at him are now in the pool
waiting with their feet lifting up their little dresses.
And one of them yells out drain out more water gertrude, it's still too deep for waiting, which is just awesome. And donald pose.
He's like skid to a stop at the end of the board just like this
jaw drop, which is awesome.
So anyway, days pass and the boys are home from summer camp,
and they wonder what donald doing with the garden and they show up.
And there's there is certainly a garden in the place, but it's
inside the pool, which is that all the water drained out of it and they look in and they see it's a sunken garden.
With tile sides.
One of the f these points out he's even got a springboard for something. The other one went out, maybe it's a stand on when he dives
die bonds a cabbage moss,
and that's it. We don't see the only again. Yeah. It's a it's an interesting closer. Right? The, like, the whole comedy of the way that he closed it is that we don't need to see Donald like,
resignation
giving up
We just... The implication is that he literally never had a swim Inducks.
It his wonderful pool things just went. So
donald duck wrong that he completely gave up.
And
Yeah. I I love the structure of the story. I love the Nephews leaving and coming back the idea that everything that the reader just read
is totally
unknown to them. I find that very funny.
Yeah. It it... It's a very
story. Like, I like the way you put it as donald against the universe.
Because, like, like I said, it He doesn't do a lot at first to deserve what he got with all the kids getting in the pool. He gets it later when he he just becomes, you know, he throws the ice in and and he has to kick them all out like that. But it's interesting in the sense that like
Barks and star is usually perfectly structured, but, like, there's nothing that particularly
perfectly sets the whole story up and, like,
if you had to set it up in some way where he did something to deserve it all, it might have been more flawed just because that might've have messed up the formula but I don't know. I I do think it is still is a great story and probably one of the best ten pager. Yeah. I think this one is pretty close to perfect.
I think it's hard to top.
You know, it's it's interesting to me that if you just, like,
summarize this one for someone,
It would sound so
conventional,
you know, Donald gets the idea to replace his garden
with a backyard pool
and things go wrong.
It's it's
someone would just really have to take your word
that it's an all time classic because it sounds so bland.
Right.
But it is very annoying.
Yeah. It's it's but in its presentation, it's so lively
and so fast paced a lot of these stories that are among his best
really have this incredibly fast paced
structure to them. I think it's... It it really gives me something to chew on, you know, as I'm like
I have Dreams of being a creative person and and writing and stuff. And and sometimes you don't have to, like, pace every
transition.
Okay. And and and and explain every step because Barks really successfully just throws you into that sequence here. Yeah. I mean, it is just such a a masterpiece piece of the storytelling in that sense. And you're totally right in that. It's just so
simple sounding, but it's so deep at the same time. Like, I think I said it at the beginning.
Like, they're simple stories, what like, such a power to them, which, of course is Al do a lot
because of the story, but also the art, I mean, the art is just so fantastic and the hoses
are so powerful.
Like we said, it's like each post tells the story as much as the story tells the story, which I think really great. Yeah. Any any favorite stand out panels for you? Because there's just so many of them in this Austin.
Yeah. I would say
Probably that whole first page has to be like a favorite...
Course all the kids in the pool if I had to pick one would be all the kids in the pool.
On like, the fourth page.
Yeah.
Any of the panels that, like,
span the page, the splash panels are all great in this one.
You know, I I I totally forgot to point out too that the the two little kids that do the initial
request. That panel is great because it shows
two more kids behind them that the reader can see the Donald clearly can. They're kinda smiling a little bit sm because it's it's clearly a little bit of a con. The neighborhood kids have sent, you know, the the two
most innocent looking little kids to make the request and and they specs to all
barrel their way and.
But yeah, you're right. All of those the first two pages
are just full of amazing reaction shots I think my favorite one is where he's handling those two sickle
on the first page to clear weeds.
And he's thought this just wild
twisted friends pose. That is a great one. It's hardly to favorite. But I love them all. And that is a great one as well, though. I always love to see the old fashioned
bugs spray.
Scrooge things too. That feels very, like, classic comic and classic cartoons to me. Oh, yeah. Excellent.
Alright. So, we've
talked about pool,
definitely our stand story here, but we've got a couple of other great ones to go over.
So we are gonna transition next
to the story called
swimming sw.
This is a really interesting one to me because it's it's a kind of story that Barks doesn't
actually tell very often. This one was a pretty early story. I haven't covered a lot of these, but this was published back in August of nineteen forty six. So Barks isn't been doing it long enough to you know, definitely like hone his
craft. He he had done a number of these at this point. But the the art style still looks a little bit a little bit rough a little bit earlier
than some of the others, and he told some different stories around this time. And and in the case of this one, it's gonna be the story that features a bully
as a very prominent character,
which which is is interesting and interesting to
This one is pretty well remembered. It's not like a super highly rated one, but a seven point four is good for four hundred and sixty six,
out of all forty one thousand some disney comics So that that puts it, you know, certainly
in the upper half of, like, Barks stories as far as how people rate them. So,
essentially,
this is a story that hinges
on the nephews. That this is really more of a nephews story, right, than a Donald story specifically.
It's gonna highlight Huey, dewey Louie. It's gonna differentiate them a little bit more than these types of stories usually do. And so we open on them
really despair that they can never beat their uncle.
In swimming races, swimming competitions.
And they've basically given up
and they have an encounter with this neighborhood bully named butch.
So
butch is basically egg them on. This says that they need to
they need to beat him his uncle by being
smart. And that he could teach
them
how to out smart him.
But they they understand this to me that they should cheat. And
and and Donald kind of here. He notices that they're talking
to him and they're so desperate.
To get the upper hand. They they kinda let themselves get talked into it. They kind of agree. Maybe we wouldn't have to cheat very much. And so butch has what what's actually a pretty clever idea. Right. I I think it's pretty smart. And and if this was presented in another story, I think it could have been presented as just some comic mischief
where they're essentially gonna challenge him to only be one of the nephews and a race, and they're gonna pull the old triplets switcher
where they they run relays with one of them hiding the leads.
Instead so that they only have to swim one lap each against Donald. It's right. It's pretty clever. They're kinda dress that they they start out the store dressed very differently in a way that they usually aren't
so that we can see them dress, you know, be to size later. And so since Donald hears that, he thinks initially he thinks he's gonna teach him Al lesson about cheating and he's going to and their hides.
But then he talks himself so he actually says I... I'll beat them with a brass handle cad nine scales.
So we had a little corporate punishment joke in there. Those haven't aged that well, but that was, you know, totally common place in the late forties
And so he reconsider and he
he decides
instead to basically out smart them and out cheap them.
By making this this device that I I think is is pretty cool. What did you think about? His his device there Austin?
Yeah. It's it is pretty cool. Like this little bicycle wheel that allows him to exert no energy.
But what I found really interesting at least at this point in the story,
like, especially upon
reread because I had read it before
we were gonna record
by a couple months. And what I find interesting is that, usually,
Donald is the one who would be cheating. Right? And he is actually as far as we can tell,
On that first race in the opening,
playing fair square, he is winning fair square. Right. But the nephews are cheating here and then so is donald.
So there's no particular way that the story could go in the sense that no one particularly
deserves punishment.
Since they're giving each other what they're getting, right? In the race, the nephews are cheating on Donald and Donald thinks, you know, he's cheating on the nephews. And so it's interesting in the ending that, of course we won't get to for a little sort of punishes
all parties in a way that's sort of unique to the Barks Canon. Yeah. I mean, I read this...
My reading of this is a little bit sympathetic to Donald. Right? He's justified it in his own mind as he's
He's allowed to cheat because he's teaching them Al lesson.
Right And so I think the story is meant to be sympathetic to his cheating because he's not like trying to cheat for glory. But I I think that's a valid
too. Right. And he is taking that more parental stands. Now you mentioned it it doesn't make more sense for him to be able to cheat.
Because he is sort of able to teach them that lesson as like their guardian figure in these stories. Yeah. And as as someone who has kids, you know, this is one of those things that drives them crazy how effortlessly if you're swimming together how however, Is parents can beat kids
when they're swimming
because, you know, swimming is like everything to kids keith love to swim so much. And so like, I I think it rings true how much at the beginning it it pains them that they can't out swim grown. But it's interesting to see Donald in this, like, very parent role in this story. You know, we don't we don't have to think about that very often, but he is their guardian and Huey,. He's not just their uncle. He's their parents. And then I mean, also it is a very early so like the overall. In overall Barks career. So nothing was really set in stone as far as the formula between these guys when. So it was sort of anything goes in a sense.
Right. And I mean, I think he kind of... He followed the lead of the cartoons that showed them in comp partition Al lot, but he definitely softened it. So, you know, the rest of the... The the race itself kinda goes the way you
expect it too. Right? They've made a wage that if Louis wins
that Donald has to do dishes
and vice versa
and
the kids
take off and they put their plan in place. It's very funny to see them doing the hand off a little relay baton sort of switching and donald thinking to himself snugly, which Nephew, it is each time
It's neat to see Donald
launch onto his cool little
underwater cycle thing, which we know that that like would be totally impractical.
As a kid, I was totally sold. I was like, wow. That's so cool. I'm I'm sure if that would work. And and so because Donald has this like
device, he never gets tired
and the if
eventually have to give up and and the bully catches them in the next day
with dish water hands,
which I found interesting because, like, that was not something I Severino heard of before. Yeah. I think in in the days of everyone having a dishwasher,
you know, that's not a cli
anymore. But I guess if you had to spend an hour scrubbing dishes, that was always the punishment. Right? Back in these stories is washing dishes.
That was the medium tour everyone had.
Right. And it it's interesting to think about, like, how that would show on the hands. But I guess this would have made sense to people, you know, seventy five years ago. Yeah. Absolutely.
So so Butch tells them, you know, their problem is they weren't mean enough. And because they've already suffered this in. They're allowed. They allow themselves to be taught
into...
Setting up a new race that's gonna be even
dirtier.
Than the first one. And Donald not around over here. There are plans.
So
when they launch into that race, he thinks that they've already learned their lesson.
And as they leap off the diving board, Donald
finds that it's quoted with glue and the nephews,
you know, point out, Hey, you can't prove it,
which was which is very devilish.
Like, even for them, like, of course, they're willing to cheat as they have. But, like, the... It seems very nephew to be that
outright and like, evil
right off the bat without even trying to give him a fair chance. Yeah. Then there's definitely some like Barks needs the nephews to be more vis mischievous.
Sometimes. This is like one of the farthest on that end of the spectrum.
That he's ever had them get. Right? Like, there there will be times where they're really brat. Right.
And and so their next phase is that they un deferral a net for him to get caught in,
which struck me down this latest reread as pretty dangerous.
Right. I mean, I I thought a lot of this, like
especially just swimming in like this random river. I also thought was kind of dangerous.
But it was a different time, I guess, people just think about, like, things like that very seriously.
Right,
especially.
When your river
has a random
world robust strap of a whirlpool.
This is one of those cartoon things. You know, I I know that
reading comments and watching cartoons
gave me the impression that whirlpool were much more common
than they really are.
Right. And I do wanna make a note that, like, when I was reading, I almost thought that they're this ending
like, if you think about it doesn't really fit,
because
each each party the nephews and on have cheated on each other and it feels like
This sort of punishes both of them
unfairly in the sense that like the nephews don't really deserve that and the whirlpool pool of course is a major cli just to show up on the second to last page anyways. Yeah. I mean, I think I think it's fitting just because, you know, in the cartoon lodge for these stories, we know that they're gonna be rescued
They you're alright. It does seem like a pretty big sort of poetic punishment for cheating.
Right
But, yeah. The the nephews get swept into this whirlpool pool. It's it's a pretty frightening sequence. Right? Because it looks very scary
They're caught up, donald has this real look of alarm on his face he's
stuck in that net and and can only bust out of it once it gets caught on a snag.
They make a reference to no one knows where the water, you know, where the whirlpool comes out And as the story ends, the nephews
get,
you know, pulled down,
deep into the whirlpool pool. One of them is saying this is what we get for cheating.
And and just in the of time, they've got their uncle there, just really heroic
str the hole in the rock that would have Ducktales them down.
And which is interesting because, like, we were talking up, like, Donald is never this heroic and any story that I could think of by Barks, you know? Like he never takes this role. Yeah. It's true. He almost never lets him be like a genuine hero. And he... And he almost never lets him get any real triumph without doing something to deflate him
immediately
afterwards. I guess, in this case, you know, something is deflate him right beforehand.
But... But, yeah, it it is un
of Donald. I liked this. I like seeing Donald be like a genuine protector. I you know, the other time that comes to mind is is that other summer story vacation time when when donald is.
Make a priority. That one is just an all time class. So So there's some great hero.
I yeah some great hero in vacation time to. Another somerset
story. And
And and it's nice. I don't need to see Donald act like this all the time, but it's nice to see him like that every once in a while. Definitely.
So the story ends with the nephews
basically
profess that they're Severino gonna cheat again and in fact, that they'll be so good they won't even fight, and then they they correct themselves as they see butch and his gang
and
say that it's it's a little early for that. Promise and and they just weigh
on those kids.
In a way that's kind of not typical. Right? Like, because there that's a real fist find there.
Right. And each one of the kids that they're pursuing has
massive
sweat and tears, like
so
speeding off of their forehead, which I find so creepy. Like this is a weird last panel. But it is a funny one. It is. And and Donald is saying docs will Inducks and the old boys will be boys
saw, which is an expression that has aged very well. But, you know, poetic this, this ending does fit. It's nice to see them stand up to the bully. Right. So what do you think overall, I think I think this a pretty fun story.
It's a good one.
I thought the highlight was probably the climax
because, like, I know in the addition, we're probably both reading, which is the glad stone,
like the shading, especially really helps on, like, the blackness of the depth of the Whirlpool pool. Mh. Also, so Barks was generally just pretty good at rising stakes and stuff. Yeah.
Beyond that, though, I thought it was fine.
Probably won't revisit it until maybe next summer. Or like that. But it was it was pretty good for what it was, obviously. Yeah. So that was
swimming
sw.
I I I took bleed on that one, and we're gonna have you take the lead on our last story here. Austin. Sure. K. I have a quick question. Does this guy have a name this neighbor? Yeah. It's that interesting. He's
it's not Jones. Right? Just a generic random neighbor Yeah. This is a... This isn't neighbor Jones. Just some random neighbor who actually does have a really cool if basic, you know, dog classic dog face design with big old wrinkles, and he's towing a corn cob pipe and He's just kinda talking with Donald about it's summer, and this guy seems very, like, sad and down and He... It... It's reflected in the conversation because all he can talk about is how the nephews are gonna keep donald worried,
trespassing on properties, swimming and dangerous places,
you know, sounds like a party to be around this guy.
But Donald says he's come up with at least a very confident look on his face, very well drawn by Barks.
He's very confident that he's got a list of everything the kids could get themselves into, and he's gonna take them to a spot
outside of town,
where the... In ten miles out in Lake erie on a Sand,
where they can't get into any trouble at all. And the neighbor just can't believe it. He says well you know what? If you can keep them on of mesh shift, I'll buy you at Turkey dinner. And Donald says he'll buy the neighbor Turkey dinner if the kids don't spend the quiet safest
good summer vacation of their lives, which is... This is a very interesting setup. Right? Because
The nephews are already established and we haven't even seen them yet. As, like, just mis makers and, like, they havoc everywhere they go, which is very reminiscent of the cartoons and not the comics the Barks did. Hold on.
So it's interesting that he took this stance with that story in particular
two interesting results as we'll see. Yeah. I and you know, I think this one goes really well with pool Barks not just because of the summer thing, but both of these stories the sub text is like, what do we do with our kids.
Because, like, this is the early fifties. Both of these were at the outside of the fifties. This this is the baby boom when there were like, so many more kids, all of a sudden being born. That neighborhoods had to, like, think about this, and I think there was more of this
preoccupation with, like, kind of kids running wild. And what do we do with the kids and, like, just with the notion of children having more of a child
Right. And, of course, it was just a crazy different time where kids could just, you know, go out in the morning and then people would yell out the door and they would come home for dinner and everything. So, I mean, obviously, that's sort of still here in this story where they're out on the sand Barks,
and Donald says there's total freedom you can go fishing, you can go swimming.
Still very confident.
He's figured it all out Right. And and nephews are very excited. They go. You know, they try to decide if they can swim swim or efficient and they get into a little bit of a fight, but Donald tells them, you know, remember, I'm here and I can watch you kids every minute. So that it got to be common and peaceful with each other, which is interesting, and he's standing there with a very
nicely drawn men pose on the side. And And that's a strap. That's like one of those
isn't that like just specifically for corporate pro punishment? Oh, wow. You might be right. I think that's what that is. You know what also just occurred to me. Is that this is like a
somewhat local
So so I'm in Pitt pittsburgh and, you know, it's driving distance from Lake Erie. I mean, it's a bit of a drive. But
have you been... Have you ever been to lake Austin? Yeah. I think it was there once or twice. It is kind of a cool place and it is nice to have Barks give this sort of
sense of location in this story where it's... Otherwise usually just in, like, sub suburban or whatever else.
So the nephews are...
That we have a nice narrator box the problem is settled peacefully and the boys go fishing. And donald is
very happy. He gets to relax and a very nice looking hammock. He turns on the radio and this is a very odd line with, like, some gibberish
football player name that I can't even I don't even wanna try to read it.
It's a it's a parity of, like, It's supposed to be an Uber polish name. Oh, okay. It's so we're supposed to, like think. I don't know if it was p a that that there were a lot of polish players at the time. But as far as I can tell, that's supposed to be an over the top. And then the other players is like generically Italian name. Right. That one, for sure. So anyway, the nephews are over fishing and all they can get is a little fish. And they figure well they can
make them grow if they put them in water. So they just put them in this barrel. That's full of water. Don't really think about it. They Gottfredson they jump in the water, which they realized Donald mentioned was very shallow is really too shallow to even swim and they'd all just come out. Covered and mud. And they talk about making a dining hole, which is interesting. I never heard of this where you shovel out a hole in the water that so it's deeper you can dive into, which is... I guess just the thing of the time. I mean, when people used to go swimming just didn't wherever they could in Lakes in Rivers stuff. Sure. And kids love digging. Right. So they go in and they
cut the top off of a gasoline can as one of the nephews suggest to make a good sand Scrooge they're making some good progress and Donald is thirsty.
He's listening to some more baseball with names and He goes over to the barrel and he notices the fit,
which is sort of just sitting there. Right? And we've gone this far in the story. We're at the end of the fifth page and, like, and not much has really happened. Right? Just to draw that cartoon comparison, like, there would be a lot of times in the cartoons where they would just be a lot of, like nonsense for the first half with no real deep character moments. This is this is a fairly placid one until it until it picks up, definitely not a character piece. So the nephews come out and they see Donald and shot to the fish, and they ask what what's wrong with the fish being there and goes well it's our drinking water. So they're like, fine you clean everything and Don goes clean my, he could be covered with millions of germs, which is interesting because you would think the Nephews would have caught that. Right? They're kind of like the more logical ones. But anyway, they... Donald has to boil the water before he do drink it. So he goes to light the stove, and there's no gas. So he throws out the match and the window. And this is very typical of Barks where the staging.
When I was reread this story, I didn't remember how it went. And even just by looking at this panel where he's throwing the match out the window, The window is isolated on the left and Donald is walking off on the right.
So it's like four foreshadowing like something's gonna happen by drawing specific attention to the window on its own where you can clearly make out the match lit is thrown over. Yeah. That's a really good point. You're if you're right on with that, like, pacing and and the signaling that he does there. Which is cool, I mean, of course, it speaks levels about Barks art and how it mesh so well with this storytelling. But anyway, he goes to look for the gas, and the nephews, of course, used it for a scoop. So they ported it all out over the side of the boat and Donna realize and he just realized he also threw a lit match out the window, and we get a very cool splash panel of the boat and the water around it being on fire.
Austin, how about his beak when he realizes...
Yeah. That's almost I at a one eighty angle. It's yeah. So that is crazy. It's great. Yeah. But
typical Donald is sort of just screaming whatever he can screen, get the motor started. Pull up the anchor, grab or gotta get away from here. Hurry up marie. The boats catching a fire.
So they get some water and they're clear the blaze, they're pulling out and Donald still angry though.
Nephews wonder why, and it's well they have no drinking water. They've got no gas to used but boil the water, and there's no gas to take to shore to get more gas. Right because he's had to pour that water barrel
out He can't even boil that water now. They've had to extinguished that little bit of sm though. Exactly. Which is this is very very cleverly
conceived. I mean, even with this story, which is just comparatively
weaker and not not necessarily weak we're just not as deep as Barks as other stories, like, This is pretty smart how they get themselves into this, like, believable
predicament again, going back to pool Barks where like really couldn't be able to pull out individually.
Those dozens and dozens of kids just populating your pool. Right. And I I would say this one's kind of just like solidly average,
maybe even slightly above average
and my book did I mention
this... The rating for this one? Left it out. Didn't I think Yeah. I do think you left to. That's fine. But I'll just mention here really quick. It was published
Walt disney Comm storage one forty two and July of nineteen fifty. Two, and it's a seven point three on Inducks induction but for six hundred and two. So, like I think I think if you looked at the median rating
for a Barks story, it would be either a seven point one or a seven point two I end. It's kinda where most of them are.
That's that's good. You know, it's fine.
Right Exactly. And also, like, a couple people,
men are on Inducks
voting things to the bottom, like the masterpiece
post.
A hot take there. Yeah. Well, not
not a masterpiece piece, but a really cool story. If I... Do I need to... Do I need to put you down for that one a couple of years in advance.
Yeah. Sure. I can advocate that's
twenty twenty seven. Correct. So anyway, Donald is going classic donald is going crazy while the Nephews user totally calm with whatever. So he goes to the drinking barrel and he figures you know what, even if there was a dirty term covered fish I've just got to have a drink. And he's trying to reach in and he totally slips in the barrel And I guess she supposed to see me he's just knocked down there. You know, you've got the classic car too star over the head you hear the thud and on a on of Pee Barks with the gl. Right. Mouth. And then after are around the corner, they're doing a little inspection.
You know, it's kind of our fault that things are in a mess. Maybe we should do something to help him out. And this I thought was, like, very cartoon Nephew
because
they do a lot of things. And just generic like, you know, pesky nephew niece, arch type,
where they do something that they think is very intelligent.
Very smart move one, it isn't. Right.
Which I thought was very weird for Barks because I don't know and he ever did something like that with the nephews in another story. I'm sure there's a few, but you're alright. He he he definitely dumps them down a bit for this one. Right. So they figure it's it's a great idea to
throw Al Sos in the barrel, which they somehow
throw in without noticing their uncle, you know, passed out unconscious at the bottom,
and they're also able to lift it over the side of the boat and throw it in. Thinking on will be mighty pleased when he finds out what we've done. Right. They go around and they try to find him. They realized these actually disappeared from the boat entirely. And,
yeah. I mean, it's all very convenient. I do like the way in the story. Kind of everything.
This is this is a typo pathology of story that bark really lights. Things
escalate through these like you know, it's just the sequence of one one bad event after another. Right. But anyway, we go to Donald,
and he's in the water, and I just notices since you were talking, but these talking gibberish actually one of the things that he says like the random symbols Barks puts is a salon
if you can make that out, which I thought was
super random. I think.
Yeah. This that is interesting thing. I think it's a man or might mind you. So the
the sw
and the me
are kind of opposed to each other. Oh,
like sort of mirror
images, the reason.
And that's just like an old symbol
that
was like, commonly used before, you know, it got per by the not So I don't think that meant. I don't think it's meant to be a sw cook because I think the sw goes... Yeah. The sw goes the other way. So that's a man. Oh, interesting.
Okay. Yeah.
Anyway, we we've reached the end
not a lot happened there.
But Donald sort of just in the barrel and he's floating along, and he thinks I should pass close to a city soon. There's Buffalo and lack wan and Niagara falls. And he's just sort just floating along and just out of nowhere, he's just shooting down the bottom of niagara falls and is just screaming help with this really cool splash panel where there's a a magnifying glass over the image of the barrel just to help you put their by Barks
sort of to looking on that. It's funny that going over in niagara falls and the barrel was a cli even at that point. Right? Because of the fisherman
reaction.
Right. Yeah. The fish mint says don't tell me another joker gone niagara falls in barrel, which is interesting.
Sorta to to draw the cartoon
comment comparison we could say. Couple of years later, would Wood packer went over in Niagara fools and a barrel, and a couple years after that, Dick Kin wrote a story a comic story. With Feather Dunkin and Donald were feather, I think when over niagara falls and a barrel. Nice. Yeah.
So one week later and we're back home.
And we have the classic bark silhouette of Donald withholding of Turkey handing it to the neighbor, and the neighbor goes all oh. So the perfect spot was a flop. Something happened to the kids, wait... I don't know what he's asking that because he should be be
able to see that Donald is walking around in a cast and and he's got a candy he goes. Now.
Nothing happened at the kids, but what happened to me, oh brother to close out the story. Yeah. And it's a fun ending. You know, it is definitely a little con contract because as you the neighbors should be able to see that.
But it's well paced and it's another
another example of the book ending
that bark likes to do a lot. It's it's a good way to kind of get get that little comedic sting there. Right. Full circle. Perfect. Yeah. So, yeah, it's a fun. It's a fun story. I don't think it's like a master or anything.
It's just a good solid example of a Barks ten pager that did happen to come
in them out... I think it it compares kind of poorly
to some of the stories that it was like, published,
you know, in sequence with. Right. Like, the trouble with dimes
was that... Yeah. That was just a couple months before. Yeah I think that was spend through.
Unfortunately it is it's it's a well crafted,
but it is very forget
coming out in the year nineteen fifty two with only a plural man, obviously.
Right. It it came out the same month as Golden helmet.
Oh my god. Yeah. Every every... I'm just looking at the list of stories on with Pd. You know, they have them sequentially. And you're right.
We have just a few months before we've got the screaming cowboy,
which is not one of my favorites, but I know a lot of people love and is pretty pretty invent.
We've got statues
spend f and Rocket wing saves the day and Gladstone terrible secret,
which is I think is Al all time as is the think box bo which was the previous story. You have the pair of beagle boys stories and knocked
November and December of fifty one. Right? Right. Yeah. Just a few months prior. So, like, this is a good solid story there are just
so many great stories surrounding. And A lot of them are the ones that are gonna get, you know, their own episodes are close to their own episodes of of the podcast here. So So... Yeah.
That that was
that was fun though talking about these three stories and figuring out some of the parallels.
It's nice to be able to be seasonal with these and kick off summer with these summer themed stories. What do you think? Should people...
I think people should check out pool shots. People should definitely check out pool Barks
if you've got other better Bark stories to go to, like Golden Helmet,
I would not go to the other two first but they do make very interesting reading for someone who's already well educated on. How good Barks could be when he wanted to
and how even the most average Barks stories are, like, super superb crafted. Right. There's a lot of really great stuff. And those other two stories. But
listeners go it yourself to save pool Barks because it is an all time classic. It's one of his ten page masterpieces.
Absolutely.
And. Any closing thoughts sauce Go re pool Barks and have a good summer, I guess. Yeah. You said it. Alright. Take care of everyone. See.