we
Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Mc Ducktales writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge con of all time time. This episode is a ten page podcast, all about one of his short stories get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Welcome back to Barks remarks. I'm Mark Sever a Grown man who's still enjoys comics and yet managed to marry a woman who will put up with that.
And
we are recording a special
valentine's themed
episode of Barks remarks today, and we're gonna talk about two Carl Barks ten page stories, So who who better to do a Valentine's podcast with and my wife. Why don't you introduce yourself? My wife?
Hi, everybody. I'm Suzanne, Aka missus Mark. I am not a a comics fan,
but I am an art lover. Yeah. And and a Barks lover. No. Well, yes. Those without saying. Al. Happy Valentine's day. Absolutely. I got you an episode of the podcast. Oh, good. Thanks. This just what I wanted. Well, we're we're recording this
about a week before. So, you know, still still time. So listeners,
you should send Barks some good Valentine's day gift ideas. Oh, don't worry. It is well in the mail. I'm not making that mistake again.
So
Valentine's stay is is one of those holidays
right where someone who's contributing to a monthly comic book they have a hook,
they feel, like they've gotta do a themed story.
But I don't think that Carl Barks was ever into the Valentine's day stories.
The way he was into to, like, Christmas, and even halloween
because the list of Al valentine's themed stories it doesn't include, like, a lot of very esteem.
Stories. And and the two that we're gonna talk about today, I think they're perfectly fine but
they're not classics, like some of his Christmas ones or even some of his Halloween ones. So I should know that neither of these stories really contain any romance at all. I I think that especially
an audience of probably young boys who were reading these bottles com. We're really not interested in Donald romantic T prevail. But, you know, both of these stories
managed to kind of stick with the formula of being very action oriented and mad cap and a random
kind of happenings and you know, Valentine's day is really just a v over these stories. And they're they're really... I would say very much in the vein of the other stories I've read.
Yeah. That... That's a very good point. Barks knew his audience.
Valentine's day is a romantic
holiday,
but these are not meant to be very romantic stories. They're meant to me mad cat they're meant to be funny and entertaining. I and and they certainly are.
I should mention the actual stories because I haven't said the titles yet. We're gonna be talking about My lucky Valentine
and wild about flowers. And you'll notice that wild about flowers is not actually
like, a valentine valentine's story, but it is a roman romance story. Right? And my my lucky Valentine
really is not.
So I wanted to kinda get a good mix here. And so, I think that one of the the other things to keep in mind about Carl Barks is that at the point He was writing these,
which were in
nineteen
forty nine
and nineteen fifty two, I believe. Right? He was like forty eight or fifty one was just finishing up an unhappy marriage.
His his second marriage, you know, he used a few years away from his third final marriage, which by Al accounts was very happy, but this one wasn't So I don't know if Carl Barks really
re list
doing valentine valentine's or or loved themed stories, but that's just kinda something that's in the Barks of my head
now as as a grown up. And he also was before before this comment career, he was a gag man, doing some of the stories.
The ga writing gag for the old donald duck cartoons.
You know, compared to those cartoons, these are, like, practically
enlightened in their treatment
of of romance
if they're still very like,
opposition
and the woman is a prize.
But in the cartoons, I would say it's much sure. So that's kinda what's in the back of my mind. So
for the for the ten page podcast, these are much less researched. We're gonna be a little bit looser and more free flowing with I would like to talk first about the earliest comment which is wild about flowers.
Before we talk about the comic, it's also notable that both of these stories are gonna feature
donald in a rivalry with his cousin Gladstone gander. Were you familiar with Glad gander beforehand? I was not. Gladstone is new to me. What do you what do you think about him?
You know,
a lot of the media from this time kind of had this trope where there was a a male character who was kind of a bit of a squash,
a guy who could do no wrong.
And, you know, is was considered very attractive and kind of put in
kind of the standard role of romantic rival.
So I I instantly kind of recognized him as a type. Actually, I will say in the first panel, I was kind of shocked to see how kind of visually similar.
I think he he looks to donald, and I had to kind of do a double take to make sure, Okay, This is a different character.
So, you know, in the arts style. Obviously, they're both Inducks, but, you know, they they both very much kind of come from the same apologies. So, you know, in order to kind of differentiate, they kinda give him a little bit of different kind of hair and the eyes are john slightly differently
and Gladstone seems to be a little bit haul than Donald.
We're even kind bringing those ideas of the ideal human ph over to Docs. Yeah.
Know I don't know if and if, you know, in the the natural kingdom is being taller dog
has considered
Al advantage in their beauty standard. When does you think about his his luck? That's that's the stick with wisdom stone. Is that he's he's very lucky. And in this story,
you know, it's it's
I gotta see. It's a little bit of a reach to hang this much luck on one character. It's... I I have to say I found this story. This is the the story about the flowers. You know, I found it fairly hard to believe because everything that happens,
in in every action, Gladstone manages to ruin Donald flower that he was trying to bring to Daisy.
So... But it's it's it's a cute little trope. Sure. Yeah. Gladstone
is is fun, I think in like some of them... Some of the adventure stories his luck is a little more over the top.
I really enjoy glad stone in kind of small doses.
But you you can tell when you read a lot of the stories that have him that Barks really doesn't like Gladstone.
He's just really meant to be that foil
Donald, you know. And so that's what he's gonna be in in this one writ large. He's very much that type of, you know, the the character who's always a little bit better than we are.
And, you know, Donald is charming be in part because he has
his flaws because he gets a little too angry lives too quickly, and he falls down a lot and, you know, he's kind of it's kind of a goof and
But that's what also what makes him in engineering. And, you know, Gladstone just obviously doesn't have any of that, you know? Yeah. He's really meant to be a kind of a stand for
anybody who's is, you know,
better than anything.
Yeah. Alright. So so let's do it. Let's talk about wild about flowers and this this one is... I would say that this is like almost a kara
version
of a little boys. Cartoon ish understanding of Romance.
Absolutely.
Right. Like it romance, what do you think about Rome when you think about romance do you think about giving girls flowers,
you think about being like, a a night whoop in rescue
a helpless woman. So So in some ways, I think I think Barks really knew his audience here because it's almost cartoon
Juvenile. It's very much that old school cord. Yes. It's very old school and and it's gonna commit
the sin that makes stories like these not hold up very well of having
the female interest be nothing more than a price
to be one. And and daisy is, like super passive. It fails the Barks tax.
Yes. Yes. These are all gonna fail for that dell test.
Because
the the number of female characters can generally be counted on on one nothing. But...
Well, the other
thing that really stood out to me about this character
about this story specifically is that Daisy character
is basically oblivious to everything that happens.
In a way that I have just never
found unbelievable. You know, this is another very common trope in the this type of romance story. It where, you know, there's this huge rivalry of all of this action that takes place and the innocent woman
doesn't even notice any of it happening. It's
so incredible
that
that to be honest, I've never really been able to enjoy these kinds of stories because they just don't
seem relatable in any way. Yeah. She She really might as well be furniture in this one.
Alright. So let's talk about this ten pager.
We don't need to detail every bit of the plot, but Basically,
this sets up a contest in Ducktales
during spring, there there is a club called the Duck wild flower club, and what they do is they head to the hills to hunt for da. And and the premise is that the first Fellow who presented a daisy
to a girl gets to be her partner for the picnic lunch. And, you know, so Donald the course is very excited at the prospect of being the one to deliver that daisy too daisy, which is cute right? Like, it's it's neat that he's looking for a daisy for Daisy. And
we get these like first three panels that are, like, over the top She's got like the ke pose and long batting eyelashes and he's he's kind of jumping
in in that sort of loves truck manner, and he heads off to hunt four flowers along the Creek bed, and he gets interrupted by Glad stone who
who who wants in on this deal as well. And everything
that, you know, Donald does where he'll find it daisy and be headed towards daisy duck to bring it to her, you know, Gladstone will do something. Like, I think he toss this his watch or something. And, of course, the watch lands right on the daisy that Donald was bringing. So, you know, the the the trope is is repeated a number of times during the story that Glad stone
and his good luck interferes
Donald. Yeah, and I think we get the rule of three here. I think that Barks is pretty good about about following that sort of comedy rule of three because but like you were saying, Gladstone not bothering.
To actually search for a daisy.
He just stands next to her bragging about how great he is bragging about how thanks to his luck he doesn't need to and the boys to side that they're gonna help Donald
because, you know, they can't stand to see Glad stone bragging about his his
his good luck.
And and so the first incident, you're right, he tossed is you wanna tell us what he does the first time. He toss
I believe it his watch.
On a chain. Oh, the first one is just his oh just a rock. Okay. In the first one, he toss Gladstone over his shoulder.
And the stone lands right on Donald tan that's clutch
the flower and it sm the flower. Right. The the boys have successfully found Correct. And then he does the same thing with a stick over his shoulder,
which hits a hornet. Nest
and
donald, but... Yes.
And, yeah, it's it's gonna be the rule of three. It's gonna be that quick the the third incident is gonna be the watch that you mentioned because... For a key chain.
Oh, yeah. Yeah. Key chain. He decides that because of an ensuing rains storm, he's gotta get rid of it. So he he throws the key chain. It lands on Donald tail, and then lightning strikes Donald tail. And it doesn't deliver a flower this time, but it delivers the umbrella that but trying
because, you know, girls always need to have umbrellas. Right.
I I like the little
flo he did here of just showing, like, in the panel borders
hey daisy, and then these weird puns with some other flowers like a butter cup and a cow slip that was kinda neat. So
anyway, there there's some fun very like spring. It definitely evo spring to me this story. Absolutely.
I have to say this panel of Donald getting getting shocked and getting it by the lightning is pretty funny. Is pretty funny. Yeah. There's some really nice individual funny panels the the devilish looking be that Chase Donald was pretty funny. But
the the story gets serious pretty quickly. Right? After the after the little rule of three, where Gladstone shows him up three times.
The Nephews are convincing Donald to give up.
When this flash flood has been triggered
by the cloud burst that's broken the damn. And so we get this
we get that scene that I alluded to where
Daisy is going to need to be rescued,
which is, you know, every... Again, I I feel like that's every little boys kind of juvenile mind
idea of rome hints is rescuing your damn. Absolutely.
And what what do you think about Glad stone
taking that tree to safety?
And and not really thinking about Daisy there at all.
It seems very on point for his door. Yeah. Gladstone is is about Gladstone.
So daisy immediately like reg into just
completely helpless
running in place and screaming. And the the flight is pretty cool. But Donald has to, like, help her out of the way and on to a a tree branch. And and again, we get these little comedic bits where they're occupying a tree branch with the bulldog on it that Donald has to fight. And so she keeps saying help speech help.
Is is the little repeated element with Daisy.
And and Gladstone very conveniently is able to rescue her from that log in a gon that happens to to flow by and And susan this was a pretty early comic for me, I I read this one quite often because it it was in an album of Donald and Daisy comics that I had as a kid and I never wondered at that time how he happens to get a gon
in duck birth. Maybe Duck is you know, just down the coast from venice. And it couldn't tell. I mean, the Gladstone luck, you know? But but the boys also conveniently have gotten a
speed boat, and they grab donald and all of the Inducks and encounter again daisy screeching while Gladstone is Al lazy in his gon because they're both heading for a waterfall,
and Gladstone rep is thirties like calm down, You don't... You're not gonna come to harm as long as you're with
Lucky Gladstone.
You know it did occur to me, though? What's that? Duck can fly. Inducks can't... Well, yes.
But we're... As always
we are meant to think of these characters as humans.
Boy. Yes. They you know what else? They can swim.
They swim pretty well.
Just Daisy never lets up either. She's just so helpless and so worthless the whole time. That they they end up getting pushed over the waterfall
anyway and s into the into a lake or whatever. It's a pretty cool panel of not damaging changing in the way. And Gladstone gon ends up in a tree. Yeah. Very dane.
Totally on Ruffled hold. And and Donald just by the end of the story, Donald has had enough. He can't take it and and he's gotta inflate some violence. Right. I'm Gladstone.
It might be time for him to work on a few things? Yes. It definitely needs to work on himself. This is a great panel here. Where we're Daisy and the nephews are are listening
hearing the fight in the background.
They... And they're all clutch plugging their ears to the violence.
Daisy is win and the nephews are all just beam. It's ridiculous. They are so messed up from the that donald that Daisy doesn't wanna have anything to do with either of them and she storms off saying, I'll eat with the first gentleman.
That finds me a daisy. And we've read a really cute little calls them disgraceful ru in. Yeah. Yeah. It's very like, very high minded.
It's a cute little closer so. What how does the story end?
She ends up eating with the the three nephews. Right. They they conveniently find three days he's there and so... And and they're not... They're obviously not interested in the romance. I don't think any of them are they're really interested in the delicious picnic. Right. And they have a good time, and Daisy gets to
actually finally eat a meal after her very busy afternoon. You know, obviously one of these stories where the romance will really just have to come later.
Seriously.
The daisy Barks
I don't think he ever really knows what to do with Daisy. You know, She's not she's not very appealing to me and most of these stories. She's at her most appealing when she's like talking to the nephews.
But I definitely... I'm not a big fan of these stories where she's like, a prize and it and it... The story just calls for her to be helpless and stupid. And like you said, kind of Al oblivious. Right. Like, can she not see that Glad down is kind of on his own supply of.
Yeah. And I mean, in the story, she's, like mostly turning her nose up at him, you know, in this specific story, but but this is I'm sure you can tell there there's a pattern of these stories where Donald Gladstone.
Right. Constantly
competing. And I also want be, like, girl. There's more than two choices. Yeah. Like there's not only two boy docs in the world. Right. Or you could go for no doc and just be... Girl be single. It's okay. Well, you know, nineteen fifty. Right. No. Not not gonna happen.
Although,
she is... She is dating someone who is the word of his three nephews. So there's that little bit of stopping to modern.
Alright. So you told me that you enjoyed this next one. Better. Hey. This this one is you know, about four years later. This is the
Valentine's story. Yes. This is the proper
valentine's story. Although it's really only peripheral about the holiday. Right. Which is why I felt the need to throw in one that actually was kinda focused on romance. And in my lucky Al valentine's, this is a fun one. This this kind of throws in a few elements
because we have these, like little Parallel stories here. We have Donald doing what he very often does, which is like frantically looking for a new job. You know, so he's got that like anxiety about how he's gonna support himself, and that propel a lot of stories. And then we have the fun element of the Nephews.
Practicing for their junior wood checks merit badges.
Because what what do they want? They want to become exalted Ducktales.
And this is an element that Barks uses a few times these like over the top
promotions in the junior wood checks, which are obviously a stand in for for boy scouts of America, And then Don Rosa is gonna really take this to the extreme.
It's a fun element. There there is one thing I wanted to point out on this page that is a small detail that I actually really enjoyed. Mh One of the things that I really enjoy about kind of period pieces in general are the little visual details that
that artist or set designers will put in that kind of give a sense of time in place. Mh. And you know that when we go to the movies, sometimes I point out things as small Al lamps shades or
or furniture,
and and I really enjoy looking at that stuff. Well, anyway, the light fixture
that
is on Donald desk as he's studying for his
mailman exam. I just find so charming.
I think it's such a a pretty little
detail then it obviously resembles
kind of a classic bankers
brass lamp. I just found that to be a a really kind of small and and delightful little
element in a couple of the panels. Yeah. You're right. Thank you for pointing that out because that's the kind of thing I'd gloss over when I take a look at that. I'll I'll definitely reproduce that for Facebook page because that is cool. There's there's kind of some neat accessories that go along with both of what they're doing. You know, Donald is he's in the process of studying to become
a mailman,
And so he's got all these, like postal law books and forms and and even in Ink well, I think, in front of him. And then the junior... The the what using a pencil, He's not using Yeah. That's true. The the wood checks are
using a a practice dummy because they're looking to pass the drowning test. So, yeah, he he gets some of these details. Right? And I like the element where if they get to if they get the promotion to exalted Ducktales, they get to move the little
the little tail on their cap to the top instead of hanging down in the back. And it's worth mentioning, this is a very snowy day It's gonna end up being a blizzard in Duck burger. And
we... Much like this snowstorm that we just experienced that true here in here in Pitt pittsburgh. We are we are pretty pretty snowed in. Currently. So very seasonally appropriately. Many of the American listeners have encountered the storm in the last week. Right.
And many of our scandinavian
listeners
are... And they're laughing at us. Yeah. And so Donald, you know, they all head out to do their stuff. Donald
is delighted to find out that he's past his test, and he can actually start working that very day. And
meanwhile Al the post office,
Glad down shows up. You wanna tell us about Glad stone
gets to the post office and and wants to send a Al to Daisy.
And so I had the postal worker who's is not donald. The postal worker who's at the window tells
tells Glad stone that it's a bad day he can't guarantee that the mail will go through because
It's so snowy and and difficult to deliver the mail. Yeah. And I I like the closer of the page. He he kinda glare Al Gladstone because he says it's a terrible day to ask some struggling mailman to deliver a valentine.
For foreshadowing, by the way. Yes. Very effective for Foreshadowing. Donald
first assignment is to deliver a bunch of special deliveries.
He's very eager and, you know, it's noted that there is a valentine valentine's I like that the Al is bad. And again, there's some really nice little mid century details here
that again, you know, I think really kind of help create the sense of time in place. The first special delivery that Donald
delivers is a pension check to an older lady.
And, you know, you can see the kind of the way Barks has rendered the siding on her house.
And
the panels on the door that obviously kind of set it in this kind of north
Mil you.
You know, I'm not sure if zuckerberg is actually placed on a map anywhere, but
it's obviously very
very much in that kind of kind of apology.
You know, that kind of post war. Yeah. Definitely post for. Mh. And she's
with some patches.
On her dress that show her as very impoverished. Right. And then the next the next
special delivery is
to another older lady, and it is a letter from
her soldier son overseas, and the the woman thinks Donald for for bringing it through this terrible snowstorm
and, you know, the brick and the tree and everything is kind of nicely drawn and kinda Makes it... I think the the panels are kind of nicely composed in this one. Yeah. And and we get this neat rule of three. Right? Again because he
He very satisfying
gets these rewarding two deliveries
and tell about his third delivery. The third one is to
and angry. I'm not sure if that's a... If he's supposed tough guy. He's a dog. Yeah.
But a grumpy man who says another bill from my wife's Christmas presence, and you walked all the way out here in a blizzard to deliver it. I could ring your noble neck I laughed at this because how is Donald? How the mailman man supposed to know what's in the mail? Yeah. He's not reading the mail. It's literally Al literally an example of kill a mess.
I I like this sequence a lot. I think this is my favorite rep. Really kicks donald in the booty. Yeah. Donald is seen in the last panel on this page rubbing his butt. Yeah.
Yeah. That... I I like that. This is like, very Barks that is best. So, anyway, Donald closing out his day and he's come to the last delivery.
Which he is horrified to realize is a valentine
to daisy
from. He realizes it's from Gladstone, he specifically
recognizes Gladstone hand handwriting.
And it's two miles away.
Know, a distance to cover and he does not look like he's wearing boots.
He doesn't appear to be
properly dressed for the weather? He also doesn't have a mail truck. No. No. He definitely doesn't. This... This is this is the mailman man Trope. Right? Bark wants us to think about the the, like, rain or snow or of night.
And so, you know, he's in this really
frustrating
situation where he's struggling to deliver
a letter to his girl from his rival. We get this funny a little bit here where there's a statue of a brass monkey and the ears snap off, and I'm I'm ninety eight percent sure that that's Al old saying it's cold enough to break the years off of brass monkey. So So Donald does
what we expect he might do in this situation with the letter. Donald is flawed.
Yes Yes. Donald, Donald toss it into the blizzard and and lets the wind carry it away.
And he stew as he walks back to the to the host office. He says let the wind blow the darn thing clear to China. I'll go back and tell the post master I lost it. And we get this great sequence here where he passes a very convenient statue that's been erected and honor of mailman man Mike who never lost a letter, certainly not on his first day. Yeah. And and, you know, this is again that trope. A noble male carrier who who delivers the mail at all costs and and so glad...
So Donald feels like a complete heel.
And he resolves that he's gonna go back and get it. You know, I I don't know that there's anything too interesting
in the next couple of sequences where he's struggling to to get the letter back. He gets...
He gets covered by snow from a snow plow.
Nearly gets the letter the letter is being blown away. And so Donald trying to get it. He climbs
like a street light or a signal to go get it, and then it gets blown away, and at the very end, it gets blown out into the river.
Right. And and again, we get that rule of three. Right? Because you had, like, three of these little disasters, and he almost gets it And again, it's very action packed so there's a lot of sp and sp It's... Reminds me of Kathy Comics and egg.
Sure her.
So,
anyway, Donald is... It's very mad cap and poor donald by the end of the page in the very last panel.
He says, well, nobody can say I didn't try to deliver it. Right. And Pour Donald is just covered in snow and very cold. So he he's console sold himself, you know, at least he gave it. He gave it a go, and So you
the old college charge.
The old male your post office try.
And so he resolves to do the next best thing, which is to go and tell Daisy
about what happened. He tells daisy
that he had a valentine
for her I I love how she lets him warm up.
In the oven. Because. He's he's sitting his butt facing in in the oven.
And he leaves out that it was Gladstone.
I don't know if he just hasn't gotten to it yet. But Daisy
immediately turns sop. Wondering who send her a special delivery
Again, she she barely shows up in this story that's nominally about Valentine's day. But, you know, I I'm not sure I read that exactly the same way you do. I see a little bit of suspicion in her eyes. Wondering she says Gee, I wonder who send me a Al special delivery. I feel like Donald should clue in. And maybe she was waiting for him to take credit don't know. But to to me, I'm reading her is just kind of clueless and and a bit of a prize here. But that's a that's generous reading. Mh. And then we get she's visited by another.
Group of people it turns out who have a special delivery for Daisy up. Yes. She hears the doorbell ringing and is the three nephews,
and
they say special delivery, and they present her with a valentine from Gladstone gander. Right. And Donald is, you know, shocked and a gas. He's asking how how in earth did they get that letter and they they tell him that they've got quite a story. Apparently, when the Nephews went to the river to practice the life saving and drowning
resuscitation test
and
the letter, the the valentine
got caught on the dummy.
And so when they pulled the dummy out of the river, the letter came with Right. And and as they're telling this to Donald, he's shu them so that he can ea drop on daisy who's telephone, glad stone to think him for the special delivery.
And there's this little, like, insult to injury bit where she hears him
where Donald hears daisy
saying talking about how he walked clear down to the post office in this horrible storm just to mail at how you must have suffered. And Donald just has to has to leave and discussed. Well, I also have to know Daisy could have been a little class. She could have called after Al left. Yes. That's true. It didn't didn't... The phone call did not have to be made right at that moment. Absolutely
not. And so the last page is basically
dedicated
to the Du walking home
and the Nephews are just pro on and on
about how
now that they've passed their drowning test, not only are they high.
But when did it... What else do they become? They became chevrolet of the on guard for making the rescue
during a blizzard, Right. And and they're now rear add animals of the arctic snows.
And for saving the government mail, they became common don's of the high hills hall of heroes.
And and the story closes with Donald,
grip and g and he yells at the nephews. He says I was wondering when those found junior would chuck are going to run out of titles,
which is a great closer. It has nothing to do with Valentine's day. I enjoyed it though... But but yeah, I love it. This is something again that Don Rosa is really gonna run with an every story that he does about the junior would checks
Barks does this a few times, but this this is kinda what everyone knows about the chips. And, yeah, that that is my lucky valentine.
And
that's a fun one. I I I really enjoy that one, it's not like one of my all time favorites, but I think it's a pretty strong Barks story. Absolutely.
It's it's very much in that formula of, you know, the the kind of mad cap action based
story and given a little bit of a Valentine's Day here. Check out their their high deals. Oh, they're already at the top of there. They're very very cute. You know one thing that I always
kind of think about is you know, I think it's... I don't know how common I would say, but I know that a lot of men don't really enjoy Valentine's day. And it's kind of seen as the thing for women. And, you know, so I wonder if this was kind of an effort to make Valentine's day seem a little bit more fun.
For boys.
But again, as we've noted, there really aren't any romantic elements to right. Well, I mean, Like you said,
valentine's in this story is only for the women. Right. They're the ones who get the the Daisy the one who gets the card, the the daisy is given to her, you know, that one's not about Valentine's day, but it's about Romance. Right. It's a spring story about Romeo. So you like this one. You prefer the second one. Little old one. I liked the jokes about the... All of the different titles.
For the junior wood checks. And, you know, I thought the panels were prettier in this one. You know, they have a little bit more detail. I like how the blizzard is represented. And some of the the little details about, you know, like, I mentioned the lamp
and Donald
getting kind of kicked in the in the tail feathers by that one angry.
Right. Customer customer. Yeah. I like that that seen
that was probably my favorite page of all of them. Awesome. So let's just really quickly
see where these stories actually
land.
We do like to check with Inducks.
The first story, the earliest one wild about flowers,
it gets
seven point two out of ten
and is ranked nine hundred and ninety six out of all forty
almost forty two thousand
Disney stories. So fairly low as far as Barks stories go. Maybe not the most memorable one, but a good example of just a generic Donald and Da
ten pager. My lucky downtime does rank a little bit higher. That one gets to seven point three out of ten and is good for five hundred and ninety ninth. Think there's a whole lot more
to say about this one
about either of these other than them, you know, hopefully,
this can be your your reminder if you need to get your
Valentine's something for Valentine's day because we'll be releasing this one
at least a week ahead of time and the run up. Any any closing thoughts
No. I I guess I would especially note that, you know, we do really enjoy our Al valentine's and we do enjoy flowers.
That.
Donald really was on the right track. Huey, needs to kick his efforts up and notch Yeah. He he's gotta show up Gladstone there. Absolutely.
That intended to be directed to me? Is the sub? Not even Okay. Good.
Excellent. Awesome. Well, thank you listeners
for enjoying our valentine's episode. We'll be back next week with
one of the regular
regular episodes, but you can always reach out on the Facebook page or Barks remarks at g mail dot com. Thanks. Bye bye.