we
Hello, and welcome to Barks remarks. The podcast where we talk about the stories from the legendary Carl Barks creator of Scrooge Mc Ducktales writer and artist of the greatest Donald and Scrooge con of all time time. This episode is a ten page podcast, all about one of his short stories get ready to enjoy our remarks.
Welcome back to Barks remarks, we are here with a new episode of the ten page
podcast I'm Barks Sever.
I am a grown man who likes talking about Stuck Comics and I am joined.
By a new guest, another grown man who
also likes talking about them and
and and has other involvement. So don't introduce yourself? My name is Fay Ko,
and I am a twenty year or so veteran of the Disney comics as a professional. Yes. I did work on them when I was a key teenager. And
Carl Barks has remained my all time favorite cartoon.
And I'm throw the b here Barks excellent. Yeah. Thank so much for joining that. I I really appreciate it. I have delusions of Grandeur, so it's it's great to get to meet people who've got some involvement with the comics
and and just to chat with long time Barks fans. I should mention our our story that we're covering today is is.
Oh absolutely.
We've got the classic ten pager the hair of the beagle boys. But before we get into it, that... Do you mind telling us a little bit more about, you know, your involvement with the comics? Well, it's interesting. I did not read the Disney comics really lot as a child. I got into them as a teenager actually.
Because of my interest in the classic at Hollywood would New York animated cartoons of the golden age. And I was starting to run out of cartoons to watch so I went to the comics,
and I sort of found out what a lot of other people did that the Disney comic universe is a lot Richer, then its animated counterpart. As far as actually engaging characters.
And of course, Carl Barks
rose to the top of my list.
And as I said before, he remains my all time favorite cartoon. I I should add I didn't need car carl as a child at a show with my father, but I had no idea who he was at the time
and could not appreciate it. I just saw this ancient
ancient man there. And he was just very warm and you know, when when you're a child, sometimes you're like, you know, wow
who is this guy, you know? And and it's sort of stayed in my mind a little bit, but It it pushed out it pushed out because, you know, he... You know, when I was a kid, you know, was like, okay. This guy wasn't involved with Loo too he wasn't involved with the mu. I don't know who he is and then it came back and couple years into my re reread of the store like, I think I met him and I asked my like fog hair you like, I think you did too when me check and out, yeah. You did. We don't have any... I don't have any photographic evidence, unfortunately, but
and I did not get to have any conversations, but as I was a child at the time, I don't wanna have any delusions of grandeur that that would have been a very important conversation. Bill. That's Al that's a pretty big, like a retroactive
thrill. Right. You you can say that, and and no one can take that away from you. No. No. They can't. So that's that's awesome.
I I like what you said about the the Disney cartoons, you know, and and the the difference between the comics
and
and the cartoons. I I grew up small child just consuming the Disney cartoons. I loved them.
Watch them over and over, you know, it's how I got into the comics, and Mh. But but like you say, once you kinda make... Once I made that transition, I was like, wow. There's
there's just this. This golf between the two of them. And and it wasn't until much later that I had not a good idea of just how much involvement Carl Barks himself actually had with some of those cartoons. Oh, yes. Absolutely. He was...
In fact one of the main writers, of course, is discussed of the Donald Cartoons for at least seven years or so. So you mentioned, like, the classic New york cartoons,
you know, that you that you're a fan that Is is that stuff like like the fl?
Yes. The prices. Yep. The B studio
by Me and Dave yes, They were the main competition for Disney and the thirties
Right. You can totally see why you pop by a sale it clips the mickey mouse.
Oh, man is
I... Every couple of years, I have to watch
send that.
Oh, absolutely. I Al send Barks. That's that's just... So and you have your own podcast, right, that you... I do. It's sparingly updated, we actually just put up a new episode. It's called cartoon lodge. I c it with my long time friend
animation director
Jake's who was the animation director on Running S
And we actually did do cartoon by cartoon breakdown of all the slice your top eye shorts
that was behind a pay
on our pay site, but we do plan on making those pop podcasts
public. Yeah. I'll be sure to check that out because I I have I'm the kind of person who has the appetite to listen to a couple of grown men talk about the plastic pop by card. She might be to guess. Right now they're
that they actually help me appreciate them even more.
Especially with Bob because an animator of his caliber, it's usually always owed Disney Disney Disney. But Bob is all about the Fl and what they brought. Very cool. That... That's great. I I will be sure to check it out. Let's let's go ahead and transition into Al. As I said, tear of the beagle boys. This one, it should be said right away is very notable. Bad, why don't you tell us? Why this one is so notable. Well, Al listeners may have guessed, this is the very first appearance of the beagle boys. The arch drive also Scrooge Inducks, the ones who are always trying to rob him. And they only a appear at the very end of the story. It's all about the threat of them in this ten pager.
And it's one of the more ingenious stories that Carl parks did because Mark as you... As I saw on your notes, this is very much stage like Al play because almost the entirety of the story takes place in one room. And with only the two characters donald and Scrooge.
Exactly except
two walk guns of a messenger boy and the beagle boys at the very end. Yeah. Absolutely. That that nails it. It's it's
great. It's it's the kind of staging
that you can picture
theater notes for right stage or four. And it's very much the kind of staging that I did not appreciate as a kid.
Right? Like, I I went back to this one later on, and I was like, oh, This is hilarious. This is genius. But as a kid, this was an incredibly frustrating.
It it would be like taking a small child to see waiting for Good dough. Yes. Exactly. Well, that's the brilliant thing about Carl Barks is that he's clearly writing these for kids where, you know, you might be a little frustrated kid, but there's still funny stuff going on.
Little bit of slab stick or actually quite a bit of slaps like towards the end. But Carl was writing these for smarter kids,
which we
as we grow up. And, you know, you just keep going back and back the these and this is definitely
firmly in Carl's golden age
which was roughly
forty eight to fifty four fifty five or so. Especially these ten pages. I'm glad you're doing episodes on them. Because they're almost consistently all little jumps. Yeah. For sure. I, you know, I I really changed gears a bit, and and I had to almost force myself to start by the ten pager.
And no regrets because I I would have missed so much if I didn't cover these and and, you know, they don't require as much preparation
which is nice. So it helps me keep up my my crazy brake neck release schedule, but but they're they're so fun to talk about. So you mentioned Golden age, no arguments there that's a good segue for for the little the background details. This one came out in the the publication date is November of nineteen fifty one. And it it was, of course published in walt Disney comics and stories for the states. There been a decent number of reprint counting the original, we've got
seven printing.
But but that... I I noticed something interesting scrolling through in index is that this one has, like more countries of publication
than these stories typically do. There's like countries that I've never seen.
Listed like Fe Islands
and
Latvia.
Turkey chimes in Huey, lobby I see the lobby occasionally, but a lot of these don't make it to to this many country So I think it's fair to say that this is kind of like one of the uber. Uncle screwed stories. Right? This has a bunch of hallmarks of the character.
So so it it just... It's a good one to print because it's it's kind of the essence of the character.
Correct. And I would... And I think to a lot places into it is
you don't need to understand American culture realty to get at all of the humor. This is purely about the characters
all throw throughout. Yeah. It's it's very character driven in the... In the way that the best Barks stories are. Let's see. Sometimes I'll cover trivia and and other interesting facts about these, you know, we can we can talk about that kind of organically and we've already mentioned
the first appearance. But anything that you'd like to Huey, up or mention before we kinda dive into the story itself.
Not particularly,
but this always seems to be a go to story when
new licensure comes into the American publishing of Disney Comics. They'll run this story was in the very first Gladstone uncle Scrooge issue. And and I believe it was in the first Gems
uncle Scrooge issue as well. Nice. Yeah. I didn't... I don't have the first gen. I do have. It it might it I might be off on that. I seem to recall that, but, you know, I have a no fact checking rule for the ten page
podcast. Of course, this became the title headline story for the Fancy graphics collection that rep the Kinda surprising when you consider some of the heavy headers that that that are yeah i they're looking Al. I was I... That's the version I have in front of me right now because that's the one with dangerous disguise and old California and no such environment in it. So you figured they would wanna use one of those for, but. Right. I kinda... I I gotta give them credit that they did use their of the beagle boys because it really it it Well, I'm just looking at it, and this is a very strong book.
If you were trying to convince someone of Carl Barks greatness this would be a good one to point them to. Oh, yeah. But yeah, You got hand it them. I appreciate the bold of that choice. Yeah. It's definitely an essential story. I did forget that I I did wanna cover some of the... A couple of the foreign language titles
So we'll do that before we jump on in. I like to pick a couple of these to panda to the listeners from around the world but especially in northern and Western Europe. So let's see why don't I
start off with
Swedish? Alright. So in Sweden, this one is called Khan vac,
which just means the Canon guard. And then Italy, this is called Lab Day,
the band of Hounds.
Which I think refers to the beagle themselves. Yes.
And then I'm gonna I'm gonna go with German. They're sell.
The the self shot. I really like that one. It's it's a bit of a spoiler, but not until you realize what happens at the end.
And in France, This is known as laser,
two. The rapid take everything,
another spoiler.
Yeah. And I think the rapid two are the beagle in in France. Right. Kinda interesting. I I think in Italian, you you've... You've done some of the local icing. Right? I In Italian, the beagle are, like a different dog. Right? Are they doc consultants or something like that? You know what? I don't know that offhand, but I can't really fault anyone because one of my questions is the beagle boys look nothing like beagle,
So you know, that's a low utilization Liberty. Yeah. Hound works pretty well. Alright. So that, we're gonna we're gonna get into it where each gonna describe a a page and and offer up some some indecisive
commentary on on the page. That, I I love how the this story opens. Oh god. Yes. It's one of the best ever... It it is a classic opening.
We've got Donald
Clearly and Scrooge office.
He is pacing,
and he is
be morning,
or w.
He... He is clearly
concerned. And and what what this page does, so wonderfully is that it it kinda throws the reader in, We just see Donald looking worried and pasting back and forth and it
us, and then we pan back and we see Uncle Scrooge, bus accounting his money.
And Donald does asked king. He's saying that he's been pacing the floor for four hours
and he asks his uncle if he can stop and rest,
Scrooge tells him he can't rest
because he's being paid thirty cents an hour.
To do his worrying
for him. And and again, it's this great setup because you're like, drawing the reader in first off. What is Donald doing?
Oh, and and then explains. He's Scrooge has outsourced is worrying to him. Right. Which again just leads to some more intrigued. Yes. This is a yes. As I said this is one of Carl's most and ingenious stories and that we don't really get the plot until a quarter of way in because because this is all just leading up to it. This is completely unnecessary,
but it's brilliant in every way. You're you're right. Though it's all in intrigued.
Very beginning. So Donald continues
and Scrooge in one of the great Carl Barks systems says put more woman in those grown.
And when I pay a non big money to worry for me, I expect them to scream and holland and tear his air. And screws goes on saying that's better. You know, Al donald pour on the
some more. And he's saying how, you know, for thirty cents he expects the works. And Donald brings up something the reader probably wondering You haven't told me what I to worry about. And screws, of course, is losing his mind because
Thanks. This has all been for nothing if he's just been paying Donald for four hours. It's a dollar twenty wasted. And download
forgotten Yes. He's forgotten what he was paying Donald to worry about. And that's a Al a classic. Again, another classic Barks does as we'll Severino later stories where Scrooge is
preoccupation with his fortune has made him forget about more pertinent matters. It's so classic. That that idea that he's outsource worrying so he doesn't have to think about it. And then he can't even
can't even remember what he's supposed to have worried about. It's it's awesome. I do love how Donald really throws himself at this point. Into the worrying. This does reminds me. It does evo Barks to the cl deck, right where he he he has trouble with his memories. So this is kind of around the same era.
Fairly close. So we
year or too before. But... Yeah. So... Because this is when this is when Bark is really hone screwed into his own and he's not just a supporting character for don all these become his own character, which is why he's sort of Al overtake in this story and when gets reprinted, they b it out donald about and put on Scrooge.
So a lot of people wouldn't know the difference
Exactly. Yeah. This is one of those where either a character could technically get get billing
So on the third page,
they're interrupted by a knock at the door. And we get another classic Scrooge touch where he's gonna... He's kinda greek
in intruder by an almost lit canon. And it's followed immediately by another. Super classic Barks
where a messenger boy opens the door and it's one of these just utterly ancient messenger boys
that I love Bark, like over the top old man messenger boys. Oh, yes. This is this this goes back to a lot of Carl
animation routes and crank cartoon roots and the thirties because this is a trope that would show up danny the messenger boy is really this ancient weird at old man.
Listeners if you're familiar with a Frank Cash Pork pig ka pork Al the crocodile arrow.
It has... That has a similar gag in that one as well. So you know, it's it's something, you know, Carl is a pure gag cartoon said hard sometimes and yeah, this is just something he throws in for a jeep laugh, and it gets the laugh. I definitely. It definitely does. I appreciate you mentioning that. Because I'm wondered how loud before when I did the episode for super snoop. Right? I assumed that this is a long running trouble right but I couldn't think of, like, another example, and this is the third time in the course of doing the podcast that I've seen can do it. Yeah. So so the the messenger boy sunny as he calls him, you know, asks him what his tell telegram is, and the guy reveals that it's from the chief of police. And and so again, the camera is sort of pulling back more. So we're we're we're getting this information dripped. He learns that The chief of Police has told him the beagle boys have alluded the police
Beyond guard and that's what Donald is supposed to be worrying about the terrible beagle boys and and we got a a a nice classic shot of Scrooge kicking donald in the bun and and cha him to get back to worrying in. Mh. Of course, Donald is going back into the,
but screw just telling him to do several things at once. You know. Think of a way to stop those drivers. And that's a big plot hole in this story, they that is kind of Carl's joke. You know It's like, where are the guards for this fortune that he just keeping in his office? It's it's it really is just... We're we're supposed to believe it is just in, but that's that's the beauty of carl Barks. You know, you don't really think of that until, you know, your eight or ten three reading of the story. And of course, there's the this other joke of that would become a long standard
much money if you Gottfredson Scrooge? How would I how would I know? It take thirteen years to count it? And since donald Barks worrying, and Donald gets the idea Well, why don't you use the canon, you just almost shut the messenger boy with and Scrooge apps and minded.
Oh, why what why didn't I think of that? And he's ready to fire it Al that will. And and I love that. Again, that in itself is a great gag that he was like, ready on a moment notice to obliterate.
Whoever might randomly call on him and didn't think to use it against the B boys. Mh.
And this next page is awesome because it's It's really about the canon itself.
Yeah.
Which which is kind of this like little, it's it's one of the tote.
Of Scrooge Doc, not as much absolutely.
Like, not as much as his his number one dime or or or the fan sell for the bennett itself three awesome and kane. But... Right. But but it's what we bark fans we love this detail. Right? And and and it's not the first time that he's used this canon. I think that was in the pixelated
parrot.
Right. Not too long before this. But this is the first time that he's he's referenced.
Donald asks him if the powder in it is fresh.
And and he says, well, sure. I bought it loaded right after the war, and Donald asks him which war and he says the borrower award don't you Al on dumb. Yes. That's one of my favorites. I've tried to work it in. Any story I eyes with can, and I always try to make sure but there's a Bo war reference. And, of course, Donald being a smart Ass here just... Because he knows how frugal his uncle is, like, you know, he does... He definitely did not fill this after World war two. So
what which war is the legitimate question Right. And and it's such a great reference for the reader. Right? Like World war two was was pretty darn fresh at this point. But clearly didn't have canon.
Of this type and and the borrower war, if if listeners don't know is just before the turn of the twentieth century,
It's like just obscure enough to... I feel... I feel like it's a perfect punch line. Right? It's like it's like the old
comedy
about the words that are funny. Right? There are just some some words with with the certain types of sounds For whatever reason, the idea of this Canon being from the borrower war is inherently funny to me. Yeah sad.
Oh, sounds like it's a great prop. And so is the Queen's victoria of royal dill? Yes. Yes. He he he starts to get nervous. Right? Scrooge gets nervous because donald pointed up the powder it might be low and as you say, he we see it labeled as as such Queen victoria's,
So as Donald leaves rubbing his aching came back from his
hour four hour and ten minutes work where you earned a dollar twenty two cents.
Scrooge is just utterly loading the canon full of powder, not not knowing how much is necessary.
And so... And so we continue this play like story with screws waiting for the beagle boys here. Here we go. He's waiting for a good go.
Yeah He's waiting and falling more and more sleep and he's it's long past time and those lazy routers haven't showed up yet because, you know, he's just itching for a fight because he went through all of this,
and he can't hold his eyes open much longer. So he phones
board donald look for help, and donald threatened him that he's not getting out of bed for any less than fifty cents an hour.
Scrooge cuss them out and balance right over and he falls flat on his face asleep as soon as he gets there and screws, oh, you're gonna be a lot of help. But both decks that that the expressive
in this story.
They they're both just the the very picture of exhaustion.
The previous pages, you know, we're Scrooge is looking looking nervous and desperate and the Donald
phone
desperation.
It it's it's Great. It's why this story is great. So so both Ducktales are basically fighting to stay awake and they're, like stressed out about Scrooge especially is stressed out about how to stay awake and and so he he tells him to go back to worrying to figure the best. Yeah. Yeah
And Donald gets another
another epiphany.
He says I've got it. I figured it out and Scrooge just him what? He pratt falls a asleep immediately. It just just perfect timing. Yes. It's that's it's... It shows how Barks missed this medium. You know, he... You know, he's he's eager to tell the idea any immediately false flat on his face so and he's so pissed doubts crew chest to dump a bucket of water on him. Right. And what was the idea?
And so when Donald does wake up, he tells him his idea is to rig the canon like a like a spring gun so that the first person who opens the door has is obliterated.
And, of course, you know, this this is a comic book. This is the Disney comic universe. So screws thinks it's genius idea despite again, if anyone takes a moment think about this, We've got some pretty major issues of liability.
And in treatment here,
but we are we are in that universe. Right. And so they... And so they rig up the canon,
and this is very cartoon it's going back the Barks is days is a gag cartoon too
at both the studio and then print and it... It's of course, a glove hand what's striking the mask. So Just, we know that we're in a Disney comic. Yep. You know that we could the fuse, the canon shoots and blue goes to beagle boys. And i, now remember. Don't open it to wide. You know. It's just foreshadowing what immediately is follow. And as they leave for the night, diamond nine,
Yeah. Still only twenty five cents for the half hours work. And u oh.
Yeah. Of course. And, of course, since Scrooge just pre preoccupied with paying Donald. He's not gonna remember what he was just old. Right. We we've just basically,
the prospect of paying some money is is going to, like, etch sketch his brain. And so
so on onto to the next page, Scrooge turns to unlock his office while Donald catches a quick snooze. Yes.
I left that detail he's already passed up. And he passes through the in sewage shenanigans. And screws just opens the door with such confidence in just just so determined and so wide, and the reader knows immediately what's about to happen. And the shot of Scrooge, the perspective jump drawing of him facing yes canon
is just just fantastic.
And And so the predictable happens. Right? He he sets off the canon. He a claims
in in fear and then he slammed the door closed.
As though as though, that's gonna do anything.
Fortunately, he manages to duck before the Canon
smash.
Straight through the door,
straight through the wall of what what is still the Inducks office building. Not already been. Right. At this point, And then because of the x excessive of powder that he used.
We see it go through three additional
rex three additional buildings, and there's a great word balloon with of the under understated... Heaven's the best to Betsy. Yes.
We don't we don't see him use that kind of explanation much I don't think going forward, but but this is a great moment. And on the final page, it shows a pretty con controlled bit of card tuning. With the bouncy beauty mattress factory being the last building the can goes through, and it brings it back goes right back into the building. Scrooge explains my lands the gotcha
and, of course, destroys the safe wall destroys the back of the bin wall the classic bin wall and Myself safe. My home money bin has been bus like a paper bag, and it spills onto the street where we see for the very first time, the beagle boys shoveling literally shoveling the money away off the street on the public property.
And Scrooge is chasing, donald off. Know, you and your bright ideas, and Donald is preoccupied with his own concern of never mind to Barks K is still owe me twenty five cents. And I think this is about is perfect to ten page story. Carl ever did. You know, because, you know, we we would get the we would... It's kind of like a disappointment sometimes. I guess when you're a younger reader and you're told... Oh, this is the first. This is the first legal boy story is like they don't show up to the very last panel and they don't show up until the very last panel of the next story there in either. And I just think that I I don't think he could've ended it anywhere perfectly because it was really, you know, just titular
error of the legal boys that... That's the star the story. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I perfectly said. I I totally agree with you. Right?
What you said about this being kind of disappointment to a kid is true, especially, like in the era of reprint right. Yeah. Where you're reading these out of orders. So like I I have that experience where I I had read a couple hundred stories before I read say Christmas on Barks mountain.
Mh. And and really became
preoccupied with how weird that like very first version of
Scrooge that I was so familiar with was and and it takes a few reread to kind of get past it if you're a kid and and to be able to appreciate the story
itself. And and in this one, the beagle boys, there they're one little post script appearance. I look... They look so goofy and so weird. Sad, what what what is so weird about them in this one? Oh they almost looked like generic villains, you know, the more like the thugs that were in the pixelated pair at the Prototype type beagle boys there. You know, the original coloring
make sure to
give them all different color shirts.
They don't have the prison numbers on their
shirt just yet. Right But, of course, this is, you know, this is still big it's the first story ever with them. And you've just got
appreciate it for what it is. And what it it... It... What it is, is just about donald and Scrooge on Psyche and relation.
And with... And because it
that relationship so spectacularly well, it's sort of like patty to yeah how, well, the vehicle boys aren't actually really in this.
This is just a brilliant bit of story telling in cartoon.
Yeah.
Absolutely.
Right? They're
completely incidental. To the story except as this like looming
threat I imagine it might have even crossed his mind who knows to, like not even have them at the end. Right? Because you don't really need them. The point of the store is not the beagle was. Right. They also have hats like caps kinda like the matthews.
Right. Right. Right. And I'm I'm wondering, you've got the fan graphics, which is like a reprint of the original. Does it say B boys like incorporated on their their buckets. It just says beagle boys. The
incorporation hasn't been established. Yet. Okay. Yeah. Because I I saw a reading a little background. I guess some reprint they would like erase the incorporated for some reason.
Like you said, it probably hadn't been established at this point. They they have... They have there's a lot of inconsistencies in the printing.
The Fan graphics just for the record for all listeners
They do try to make it as close to the original Western
publication as possible.
And that goes for some of that
particularly crappy coloring,
but I digress. Yeah. I mean, I I agree. I I get what the mission is. Right? They're trying to reproduce them for for that type of collector, but
boy there. Some just lovely coloring additions of these stories by, like, people like sue devil each. Oh, yeah. The believe the bleach and the lights Scott Rockwell.
They did fantastic jobs with these printing. I tend to not like when they use gradients and the reprint. I just don't think it looks particularly right. But
Reader should be aware that the leech are
intermittently. And the leech are involved more now with the fan graphics sucks. And even using think the limited Al they've done a lot more taste and they look a lot better. I just wish that they got involved Al lot earlier. Well, that that is good to know. I... I'm glad to hear that. I I was thinking to myself a few weeks ago in the course of this project that, like, I might have read more pages
of
reach work than like any other creator when you
What you think about it. Yeah. No. Soon Gary.
Yeah. They're they're they're heroes of mine,
just like Scott. And, you know, I think what they do is appreciated by a lot of fans
Yeah. Hiring very under appreciated. Well... And I'll I'll go on record of saying that...
Well, there might be know, arguing
online over it. Carl Bark himself is very appreciative over what Glad and onward
did with his story. Goes, he always despise the western coloring.
Yeah. That... That's another good point to make The the coloring on those stories really
elevated them. Oh.
So, you know,
we're we're in we're in agreement. Right? This this story is is a tight
and
incredibly well paced. Bit of character study
slaps stick buff.
It it is.
Super funny, and I'm I'm really glad to have, like, gone through it in in this kind of excruciating
detail No. It's just to keep repeating ourselves. It's a just
famous story, and it's just really the two characters donald and Scrooge and their element and and as we've discussed and, hopefully, you've realized this is why the publishers keep going back to this story as a high like... Yeah. For sure. And this is definitely one that I've, like, developed, you know, a new
appreciation for in the course of doing this. Because I I remembered it pretty well, but as I revisit and I was like, oh, yeah. Oh, yeah. This one, this is amazing. And the community is in in wide agreement with this one, you know?
Huey, be has... They definitely should be. If if you look it up on Inducks,
you'll find that it is one of the very highest rated of of all the ten pages. I made a little list at one point where I pluck those out. Tear the b boys ranks as the fourth highest rated of Barks ten pager.
Now now overall, it gets seven points seven, which is good for a hundred and fifty nine out of all forty one thousand some
Disney comics. So
very high theme, I don't think it's... I don't think it's inflation. Right? Because of that first appearance of the bill boys. I people are just remembering this. They're just remembering it. And as you said at the top of the podcast, this has been reprinted in places that usually don't see reprint So it's
everyone every faithful reader of the dot com knows it and, you know, it it just shoots up just like the... What's story and
oh
the Hit no gun story and a few others. Mh. And they just remember that is the classic
of the.
Yeah. Just we remembered legendary,
lot of fun. So we we've had a great
conversation.
The
best way to wrap it up is is to do our little favorite panel feature. We got a ton of them and we've highlighted a few, but that, are there any that you would like to call special attention to? Let me see. The the borrower don't be so dogg on dumb.
Just this just like in my permanent Lexi just that line. And, of course, the the shot of the
the buildings being destroyed by the canon with the understated evans to Betsy seat. Those are just two of my favorite Barks panels ever. And, of course, as you said, the perspective shot of Scrooge looking into the camp man. Yeah. That that one is is definitely a winner. The pen ultimate panel of the money porting out of the Bin is quite lovely. It's a nice art,
not the first time. That not the last time that won't see money pouring out of the Bin. I have kind of a weird one, you know? Because I grew up in the era of reading the Gladstone con,
They used one of these panels as like one of their
you know, in house ads,
and it's the one of Donald
at his most
dramatic saying
ski reach
Wow the beagle boys yeah. And it there's a reason that they use that one, you know, He's like, curled over practically horizontally.
Really giving giving his job of being screwed his warrior.
His his absolute best. He's... He's earning that thirty cents an hour there. Mh.
Yeah. I love that one.
Let's see.
Sometimes I do talk about, like, references
to other
sql.
Right? Like, it... I guess it bears mentioning that the beagle boys are going to be a character that has, like a pretty long after life. Right? Oh, yes. They'll be used in dozens of stories by Barks
and other creators
they will be adapted
into the Ducktales cartoons.
They get their own pretty
crummy comic book line
into the seventies under the whitman
imprint. I And I'm sure there's some decent stories through that. There might be. I wouldn't count on it. But they did... They even got their own nephews, the beagle brass.
Right.
And no they're... I I just think they're the perfect
series for screws, you know, they're they're stupid
and they're on on they're sla, you know, but they're also an organized crying family
and you know, that's Scrooge just worse nightmare.
And I think you know, Carl just came up with something really brilliant with
and, you know, paying homage to all the crooks and bandit of the comics he grew up reading or rad Al. He was a professional cartoon illness. And, you know, this one holds up very nicely. Sometimes I talk about how these have aged well or poorly.
Apart from, like references to the Borrower War Canon, this is such a timeless story you could... It's it's very universal like we've already said. Honestly, c elements like that bo war, you know, that well, kids you gotta go reach something else time. Why you to look up what that thing just to look it up, You know, you you weren't something that day and
but, yeah, this just... And I think that goes without saying why it was so heavily reprinted like we said earlier, there's nothing that dates it. There's no real cultural
aspect do it. It's just very universal all the way around. Yeah. And and I I think that we we did a great job with this one. I think we covered what we needed to. So, yeah, listeners, thank you for joining us. Hopefully, you took the opportunity to revisit this great ten pager
Listen to the other great episodes
comments on the Facebook page,
and we will hear from you next time, just, you know, Ducktales
you ring our doorbell.